Humans don’t make good pets part 1

by guidosbestfriend

Understand this is my first time writing anything, so any criticism is appreciated (or if its just awful you can say that too). Also, because it was originally what gave me this idea, this story is set in the same universe as The Tale of Kevin Jenkins (Thank /u/f3lbane for the good quality), but happens shortly before Kevin Jenkins' tale does, and is distinctly apart from it.

Dear journal,

Fuck. My. Life.

I'll start with what happened right before my life decided that I wasn't getting enough excitement. It was 2:00 in the morning, the bar had just closed . . . at least for me, so I was making my not-too-steady way towards home. I think I made a wrong turn somewhere, unless the way from the bar to my house had suddenly decided to include a dark alley. There was a bright light. I blacked out.

I woke up strapped to a gurney. At least, that's what I would have preferred it to be in hindsight. Nurses usually look a little better than what was at my bedside, and I've seen some nurses with quite a bit of personality. Rather, waiting to wish me a happy good morning, was a creature straight out of science fiction. It was about three feet tall, papery skin the color of ash, a bulbous, elongated head far too large for its thin body, and large amber eyes the size of golf-balls. Just to make my well-wisher that much more comforting, its eyes didn't appear to have any pupils.

Given the circumstances, I was somewhat discombobulated as to my current location and as to the nature of my visitor, so I politely asked him to explain. What came out of my mouth may have sounded more like "What the fuck are you, where the hell am I, and why am I strapped down," but I don't think he understood what I said. I quickly stifled those last two questions as he raised an odd looking syringe and stuck it in my arm. I hadn't finished my uncomplimentary statement about the circumstances of his birth before I was out again.

I swear I don't pass out this often on most days. I really wished I hadn't passed out that last time because I opened my eyes to the bars of a cage. Upon surveying my surroundings, I found I was in a kennel with quite a few other creatures which, if the little grey Yoda hadn't been enough, were evidence that I had been abducted by aliens. It wasn't long before I realized that I was being studied, along with the rest of the animals in the other cages. At first I had hoped they were sentient. Then I saw one of the other inmates ignore his perfectly acceptable daily nutrient supplement in favor of his feces. My aspirations for the other inmates died in similarly disgusting fashions. The other thing that told me that I was different from the rest of the creatures was my cage. All of their cages appeared relatively simple to open, or even break. I was reasonably sure that most of the cages wouldn't have been able to hold a sufficiently determined chihuahua. My cage, on the other hand, was fort Knox without all the gold. Aside from the traditional vertical bars, there were thick horizontal supports, braced by a mesh, encased in a glass box. I was flattered that they thought I warranted such high security, but I doubted it was necessary.

They apparently did not share my opinions, and every time they decided to take me out for testing, they gassed my box with something that put my lights out like a two by four, except without the bruise. That was my life for the next two weeks or so. I can't say exactly how long, since I couldn't see the sun, and I didn't have my watch or any of the other things I'd had in my pockets. By the second week I wasn't looking too good. That, coupled with the fact that I was gassed unconscious every two sleeping periods, made my mood something south of sour. By that time I was starting to be able to recognize the different xenos by height and build.

I counted seven different aliens who would come into the room and either gas my box or do something to one of the other animals, and from the aliens behavior, I could see they were all jerks. All but one. The others seemed to enjoy inflicting pain, or at least didn't feel bad about it, but the shortest (I called him Stumpy) seemed to try to create as little discomfort as possible. If, on the rare occasion, one of the animals had to be put down and he had to do it, Stumpy always seemed sad as he injected the blue syringe of death (my name for it again) into the doomed creature, petting it as it faded away.

That's why I was slightly more than alarmed when, at the beginning of the third week, he entered the room with the blue syringe of death in his hands and started walking towards my box. He hit the button and gas began to leak into my chamber. This time, I didn't take it sitting down. I actually stood up and started attacking the bars with more energy then I'd shown for a while. Stumpy seemed stunned by my sudden outburst, as I'd never been this frantic before. Maybe it was because my heart was trying to escape the body it thought would not need its services much longer. Maybe there was less gas, but I wasn't knocked unconscious, only paralyzed. Waiting until he was sure that I wasn't able to move, Stumpy opened my chamber door, and knelt by my head. I tried to move, but wasn't even able to lift a finger as he inserted the needle into my neck. The lights faded.

I didn't die. Shocker, I know, since I'm writing this, but when I woke up, my body felt like the static from an old TV and I was, once again, on a gurney. The only difference, though, was that the alien by my bedside wasn't a meter tall and grey, but towered over me to something to the tune of four meters, had four legs, two arms, light blue skin stripped with a darker blue, and was making frantic clicking noises to another one. As I looked around, I saw there were quite a few of these new aliens by my bedside, all intent upon the heated clicking battle between the first two. These others were somewhat shorter than the two who were arguing, and also appeared less . . . developed. Or maybe they were more developed, I don't know how these things age. With what happened next, though, I would have given up a bath and some good food to have known what they were saying.

"I want that thing off my ship this instant!" Tnnxz shout-clicked. "We don't know what happened on that Corti ship, and I say it's best not to borrow trouble when you don't have to." He had been in favor of giving the doomed ship a wide berth, but Xkkrk, his favorite mating partner and second in command, though she liked to forget that at opportune moments, had thought differently.

"That ship was transmitting a distress beacon, venting atmosphere, and well on its way to complete hull failure." shouted Xkkrk. "We're the only ship out here for light-years, but you would have had us act as though we hadn't heard it? If we'd done that we might as well have murdered them ourselves!"

Tnnxz snorted. "They didn't need any help in that regard. Do you honestly mean to tell me you think the crew of that science vessel died by naturally tearing their own limbs off and bashing in their own skulls? I don't think a one of them was fully intact, and that's just the ones you could recognize as having once been alive. The others were just smears, if the records about there being a full crew of seven were to be believed. What do you think did that? The animals who were all in their cages, or the one, living, breathing, uneviscerated abomination on that ship?"

"You think this killed them?" Xkkrk motioned toward the strange creature on the ship's one medical bed. She had to admit one thing, it was rather strange to look at. Its pink, squishy skin was covered in a sparse black fur, except for its head, which seemed to be compensating for the rest of the body in the hair department. It was short, somewhat less than half her height, yet it looked dense. She suspected it was stronger than its size suggested, but not so strong as to be able to turn the crew of a Corti zoological vessel into a pulp. "It may have been breathing when we found it, but it wasn't doing much else. Do you think it slaughtered the crew, then fell asleep in a ship which was leaking atmosphere? It's been awake since you started yelling," Tnnxz jumped and quickly looked at the creature in alarm, but she kept going, "and it hasn't moved a muscle. If it were going to attack us it would have done it by now."

"It's a dumb beast, it didn't know the ship was compromised. And it was right next to that headless body holding an empty RotGut syringe."

"Oh, so aside from being able to turn a Corti crew into a fine mist, it's now able to survive a bio-engineered pathogen able to kill every known organism in a few seconds. Next you'll be telling me it can make you last longer than a few [minutes] next time we're alone together." The comment obviously stung him, but Xkkrk could see he knew she was right. The children, who had been listening intently to the conversation, could also see that she had won. Xkkrk could see the youngest, Vtv, was about to ask the same question he had when they'd first found the creature.

"So." He clicked, "Can we keep him?"

Next two

All chapters

Humans don’t make good pets part 2

By guidosbestfriend

Dear Journal,

I’m a xeno dog.

Believe it or not, that hasn’t helped my self–esteem issues. Good thing I don’t have any. I came to the revelation slowly. After the two blue–giraffes (I’m rather proud of that name) finished up their spitting argument, one of the underdeveloped ones, which I’m now sure are children, clicked a few times. Apparently it was a sentence, because the larger two looked at him, then, despite the fact that it was just a bunch of clicks, one of the adults, a female I think, delivered what was unmistakeably a mother’s lecture. The little one jumped up and down in his excitement, not listening to a click she was saying. Eventually she finished up, and it seemed as though something had been decided. Everyone vacated the room, except for the smallest one, who I quickly named Dinklage (not my best, but I was rushed). He moved closer, and I suddenly began to wonder what these creatures ate. They looked harmless enough, but then so had the grey Yodas.

Dinklage looked down at me, and once again I tried to move my limbs. Their only response was to twitch my smallest finger. Thanks guys. I needn’t have worried though, because Dinklage suddenly scampered out of the room with the all the grace of a dying gazelle, where I was left to contemplate my immobility and the nature of my position. By this time I was pretty sure I was in space. I hadn’t seen a window, but unless the Men in Black films had been documentaries, I doubted I was still on Earth. It was a shame, too, since no one would be looking after my house.

I didn’t have much time to ponder my ruined estates, because Dinklage explosively burst back into the room, holding what looked like a speckled blue and yellow palm frond, which he promptly shoved unceremoniously into my face. I looked at him, hoping for some explanation, but his only response was to shove it further. We sat in that position for awhile, myself, lying prone upon the bed, palm frond in my face, child blue–giraffe looking at me expectantly. After about a minute of that he deflated, then turned and flailed out of the room again, returning a minute later with what looked like a black and rotting fungus. The newest plant specimen was also displayed for my inspection. Unfortunately the fungus smelled about as revolting as it looked. This process was repeated several times. After I was shown a lovely flower the color of bird shit, Dinklage, who had been growing increasingly frustrated with the proceedings, snorted like a horse, and seemed to wither in defeat. He shuffled out of the room, and I was finally left in peace.

Vtv, shoulders slumped in defeat, sulked onto the bridge. Xkkrk, who had been worried this would happen, turned sympathetically towards him. “He won’t eat any of the things I gave him,” Vtv mumbled. “He even turned down the aged zrrks, and even Yxrrq will eat those. Why doesn’t he like any of our food?”

“Maybe he just wasn’t all that hungry. Maybe he was scared of you. Just think of what you look like to him. He’s so much smaller than you. You loom over him. He just has to warm up to you. Why don’t you go into his room and play a game of warrens with Piiqrrt. Maybe if the creature gets used to seeing you he’ll trust you enough to let you feed him.” Xkkrk smiled as Vtv, presented with a new course of action, regained his excitement and tore out of the room, the picture of a youth with too many things to do.

My peace was once again disturbed as Dinklage walked purposefully back into my room, followed by another child carrying what looked like a small metal clam. This new blue–giraffe was significantly larger than Dink, and I doubted the extra bulk was muscle. Both he and Dink sat on the floor with the clam in between them, and as the new child sat, his excess weight bounced, confirming my suspicions and earning him the christening of Jiggles. Jiggles opened the clam, and a holographic projection of what was unmistakeably a game board leapt into existence between them. It was a grid of hexagons, with different colored pieces on the two of the opposite sides, closest to the players. Dink seemed to have an unfair advantage over Jiggles, though, because his side had well over twenty pieces while Jiggles only seemed to have three.

It didn’t seem to make much of a difference. Within minutes of the game’s start, Dink’s body language began to tell of a losing battle, which was confirmed by the quickly diminishing number of his pieces. Seemingly at random, certain hexagons on the playing field would glow brighter than the rest, then dim several turns later, for reasons I couldn’t understand. Neither the glowing hexes, nor the greater number of pieces saved Dink. After only seven minutes of game play, all his pieces had been systematically removed from the board. The game was reset, yet this time Dink had the three pieces, while Jiggles had the army. I soon realized that the player with three pieces had to capture all the pieces of the other players before the other player was able to reach one of the glowing hexagons with one of his pieces. The glowing hexagons seemed to appear only in positions that were difficult for the defensive player to reach, and soon I was engrossed in the game, trying to parse out any remaining rules. Jiggles won most of the games, which allowed me to see how the game could be won by both sides.

It wasn’t the most complex of games, but it did include a strategy. After five or so games, I began to see the flaws in Dink’s strategy, and decided he wasn’t the brightest blue–giraffe I’d ever seen. Jiggles wasn’t even that good. I wished more than ever that I could speak to him, if for no other reason than to yell at him in frustration. His pieces were once again eliminated, and the game began again. I couldn’t let him lose this one. I struggled against my paralysis, and managed to shift my arm until it fell off the bed, hanging limply by the side of the bed. My movement drew their attention. Dink sprang to his feet and excitedly scampered out of the room. He returned with the speckled palm frond from before, eagerly introducing it to my face.

“Get your leaf out of m–” I didn’t manage to finish my sentence though, as with the opening of my mouth, he surged forward with the frond and managed to poke it past my lips. I tried to spit it out, but he kept attempting to feed it to me. That’s when it dawned on me that that was what he was trying to do. With that realization came the second, significantly more profound realization. They thought I was an animal! They didn’t realize that I was sentient. And what was even worse, I couldn’t tell them. My speech would sound like so much grunting and unintelligible nonsense as their clicking. They didn’t use the same numeric system, so I couldn’t show them my powers of abstract reasoning through math, which, admittedly, were extremely lacking. I was an unthinking brute, and what was even worse, I had been given to Dink for him to take care of. I was Dink’s new puppy, and he was trying to find out what I ate. Well, I was famished. Don’t bite the hand that feeds you, which seemed to take on a greater significance in my new situation. I just wished that hand wasn’t blue, or striped, or belonged to a giraffe child. It would have to suffice.

Armed with this knowledge, I took a bite from the tip of the leaf. I don’t know what palm fronds taste like, but they probably would have tasted better. I spat out the bitter leaf, but this only seemed to make Dink happier. He bolted from the room, and returned with the rotten mushroom. I wasn’t about to let that get anywhere near my tongue, and I firmly closed my lips against the melting brown mush. The next leaf he brought tasted like romaine lettuce, so I ate the whole thing. It only seemed to increase my hunger. Dink seemed overjoyed and next brought me a container slightly larger than a shoebox full of those leaves. I would have objected to his feeding me if I’d been able to move my arms, but decided that food was good enough. He seemed surprised when I finished off the box of leaves, but dutifully brought me another, which I polished off like the last one. He began to look concerned as I worked my way through the third and fourth containers. What can I say, salad isn’t really something to fill a guy up.

Half way through the fifth helping my hunger was finally sated. Dink seemed to take the box away with relief, and returned with a small glass of water. After the salad I was even thirstier than I had been, and downed the water in a gulp. “You don’t happen to have anything stronger than water, do you? Or maybe just a larger glass?” He didn’t answer, obviously, and brought me another glass. I downed eight of those pitiful little things before I was quenched. Full for the first time in weeks, I contentedly closed my eyes for a nap, and Dink, thankfully, left me alone.

“How’d the game with Piiqrrt go?” Xkkrk asked as Vtv walked into her quarters

“I lost, but that’s ok. Piiqrrt almost beat Fttfk last [week], and he’s the best warrens player in the entire sector! Oh, I also found out what he eats.” Announced Vtv, not needing to specify whom “he” was.

“Excellent. See, he just had to get used to you. What does he like?”

“He really likes Cqcq leaves. Really likes them. Really, REALLY likes them. He ate four and a half storage containers worth.”

“Four and a half STORAGE CONTAINERS?! That’s enough to feed a grown Vzk’tk for a week! Why did you feed him so many?”

“I just kept feeding him until he stopped eating.”

“Vtv, you know better than that. Some animals don’t know when to stop eating, they’ll just keep going if you let them. You’ll have to limit him to half a bowl a day. If you keep feeding it a weeks worth of rations, the hydroponics bay won’t be able to produce enough to feed the rest of us.”

“But I hate Cqcq leaves.”

“Not everyone hates them, and they’re one of the best sources of energy we have on board. How the creature managed to down four and a half containers of those leaves is beyond me. Did you give him something to drink?”

“Yeah, he drank [32 ounces] of water.”

“And he didn’t drown?”

“Come to think of it, he did close his eyes after the last cup, but I think he was sleeping.”

“Well, You’ve done a good job of taking care of him. I’m proud of you.” Vtv perked up with the compliment, and strutted proudly out of the room. Xkkrk wasn’t as pleased though. She quickly sought out Tnnxz and told him of Vtv’s discovery.

“Four and a half containers!? And [32 ounces]?! I don’t care if the thing didn’t know when to stop eating, that’s impossible. It’s so small, how could its stomach even hold that much? Does food just dissolve in it?” He clicked with a snort, scoffing at such a ridiculous notion. Not for the first time Xkkrk wished Tnnxz was wealthy enough to afford a proper biomedical scanner so she could see inside this creature, but wishes were all she had.

“What if that’s actually how much it needs to eat and drink in order to live? We can’t lose a week’s worth or rations every day. We have enough water, but I think Vtv was exaggerating. Even if this thing really did eat four and half containers, it couldn’t possibly manage [32 ounces] of something as dense as water.”

“But if it truly eats that much, we can’t keep it.”

“Where would we put it? There aren’t any planets below a level 12 within a week of travel, and we might as well kill it ourselves than put it on a deathworld.”

“We’d put it down. We’d have to. There’d be no other choice.”

“If it comes to that, then I feel sorry for Vtv, he’s so happy with it.”

“He’ll have to become used to loss eventually. Has he even named it yet?”

“Yes. After he saw how much it liked Cqcq leaves, he called it Cqcq’trtr.”

“Cqcq’[eater]? Does he have an imagination?”

“He was proud of it, so I suggest you don’t mock his choice.”

“Fine, but if it lives up to its namesake, it’ll be a shame Vtv named it at all.”

Humans don’t make good pets part 3.1

By guidosbestfriend

Dear Journal,

I destroy xeno familial relationships.

Oh, and I might be going crazy.

After two sleeping periods – I’ve stopped even trying to keep track of the days – my body had finally decided to end its extended vacation, and start responding to my commands. I felt weak, probably because the only thing I’d been fed so far was fucking salad, but I was able to get out of the unnecessarily high bed. I’m only 175 centimeters tall, so I was going to have to get used to an environment where the next sentient being closest to my height was almost a meter taller than me. The gravity on the ship was noticeably weaker than what I was used to, which only confirmed my earlier suspicions about being on a ship, but it also helped with the short drop from the bed.

Once I decided that I was able to walk without much trouble, I jumped back onto my bed and waited for Dink to show up with my meal. That’s the other reason I think I’m feeling weak. Last sleeping period he only gave me one meal, if it could be called that. He only gave me half of one of those large shoe boxes, and then started to take it away. I tried to use my newly liberated arms to keep him from taking it, but they were still unbelievably sluggish in responding, and he managed to snatch it away in time. “Whoa there Dink, I wasn’t finished there. You can’t expect me to be full after a ninth of a serving of lettuce! I’m not a rabbit, damn it. I’m a grown man and I need my lettuce! Or better yet, do you have some meat? I’d love some meat if you have any.” I told you I was going crazy. Three weeks of hearing nothing but chitters from the grey Yoda’s and clicks from the blue–giraffes is bound to make a guy start talking to himself, if for no other reason than to hear something he understands.

Dink apparently hadn’t been impressed by my outburst, and he had clicked reproachfully. If he had gotten a newspaper and tried to swat me with it I wouldn’t have been half surprised, but thankfully he didn’t know how to properly train a pet. Good thing too, since there was only so much I was willing to endure in order to get food and water. I waited for what seemed an hour, but was probably only about 10 minutes before Dink entered my room with two of those shot glasses filled with water and a shoebox of lettuce. “Oh great, I was hoping for lettuce again. Nothing sets my mouth a–watering like a good crisp piece of lettuce. You even brought me a few gulps of water, just how I like it. You know me so well” I had decided since they couldn’t understand me, I might as well make the best of my situation and lace everything I said with sarcasm. Despite the repetition, I decided to eat the lettuce. It was the same box he had used yesterday, and there was no reason to try and snatch it out of his hands, since there was only half of it left. I drank every last drop of water from the two glasses, holding the second one out with a pleading gesture.

Maybe he understood, maybe he didn’t. It didn’t matter either way, as he merely clicked something at me and started retreating back to the door. “Fine then, I’ll just find my own lettuce and water.” I muttered at his retreating back. I waited a few minutes after he had left, then jumped back down from the bed, and walked over to the door. It had an oddly shaped but easily recognizable door handle mechanism, and, when tested, wasn’t locked. After all, who bothers locking their dog into a room? Luckily, I had two things dogs don’t have. Brains and thumbs. Grinning mischievously, I jumped at the handle which was about 25 centimeters above my head. To my astonishment, my jump carried me past easy reach of the handle and peaked when I was approximately a meter off the ground. Even in my weakened state, I was still able to jump ridiculously high in this lowered gravity. Adjusting for my new found basketball skills, I hopped, turned the handle, and began to explore my new home.

“Are you sure I can’t give him more food?” whined Vtv. “He really seems to be hungry. He keeps looking at the box like he wished there was more in it.”

“Absolutely not,” snapped Tnnxz. Vtv had known it was a mistake to go to Tnnxz with this question. He still seemed to think Cqcq’trtr had killed all those scientists on that ship [three days] ago, as if he could. He barely even moved. Vtv didn’t want to say it, but he was definitely feeling the excitement of owning a pet starting to fade, especially such a lazy pet. He was hoping that if he could get him more food, maybe he’d show a little more life. After all, he had certainly started moving more since that first day with the five storage containers, although feeding himself and trying to grab the container away from Vtv was not a significantly large improvement. Still, Vtv had been impressed with Cqcq’trtr’s speed as he had grabbed at the box. Vtv almost hadn’t gotten it away in time. “If you start feeding it more food, it will begin to feel entitled to it and then we’ll have it eating us out of house and hull. I’ll not have our resources drained because you don’t know when to say ’no’.”

Vtv should have just waited until Xkkrk had woken up so he could have asked her the question. At least she recognized that Cqcq’trtr was a “he” and not an “it”. Tnnxz’s comlink beeped, signaling an incoming call. “What is it?” he huff–clicked, annoyed.

Strrk, one of the gardeners in the hydroponics bay, could be heard on the other side of the comlink. “Sorry to bother you Tnnxz, but that thing we brought onto the ship a few days ago – what does the kid call it?”

“Cqcq’trtr!” shouted Vtv into his father’s receptor before Tnnxz could say anything. He glared at Vtv, but didn’t contradict him.

“Right. Well, you gave him the right name, kid. He’s in the hydroponics bay with us right now, and it looks like he’s aiming to eat every Cqcq leaf we have. He’s already stripped three whole plants, and is half way through his fourth. He’s been making these weird groaning and spitting sounds the whole time too. What do you want us to do? He looks pretty determined, and I don’t want to touch him, he’s filthy.”

“Just don’t let it leave,” growled Tnnxz, looking murderous. “I’ll be right there.” He sprang from his favorite chair, left his quarters, and stalked towards the aft of the ship, where the hydroponics bay was located. Vtv knew what kind of temper Tnnxz could have when provoked, and knew he harbored no love for Cqcq’trtr. Sometimes Vtv wondered if Tnnxz even liked him. Vtv quickly ran to Xkkrk’s quarters. He didn’t care if he had to wake her up, she was the only one who seemed to defend Cqcq’trtr, if only for his sake.

Humans don’t make good pets part 3.2

by guidosbestfriend

"Sorry about scaring you there mates, but a guy can't live off of half a shoe box of lettuce a day, can he? No-sir-ee he needs a good five boxes. That's what my mom always told me, 'five boxes of alien lettuce a day helps you keep the pangs of starvation away' or something like that." The blue-giraffes who were watching me warily didn't seem to appreciate my humor. I knew I wasn't that good, but they could have at least pretended to be amused. I think they were the caretakers, since they had been watering various alien plants when I'd peaked inside. Through my explorations I had decided this was a cargo ship, as a majority of the ship was merely massive rooms piled high with crates with blue-giraffe writing on them. One of the rear cargo bays, though, seemed to have been converted into a hydroponics bay, which hinted at how long this ship took between ports.

Thankfully, the gardeners had seemed too surprised or too scared of me to try and stop me as I found a plant with familiar looking leaves and began to trim it down. I guess each shoe box had held one plant's worth of leaves, because I went through three of them and was still hungry. I guess lettuce doesn't keep you as full as meat, which is a shame, since I was beginning to think there wasn't any meat on this entire ship. I was three quarters of the way through my fourth plant when the door burst open and one of the adults who had been arguing by my bedside tore into the room. Well, he gallop-flailed at a leisurely pace, but from the looks of it he was giving it all he had. I didn't need to understand his clicks to know that he was angry, especially since he was gesticulating wildly at the three barren plants to my right and the broken off leaf in my hand.

After a while of shout-clicking and waving his arms about, he feel silent, glaring at me as though waiting for a response. I saw no reason to refuse him one. "I know how bad this looks, but let me assure you, I'm not the rabbit-human you're looking for." Its almost like he knew that what I had said was a poor attempt at a joke, because he burst into another click-rant. Just before I was sure he was going to spit me to death, the other adult who had been arguing that night entered the room, followed by Dink.

The two adults started arguing again, which I was beginning to think was the defining factor in their relationship, and Dink shuffled over to me. He looked at the stripped plants with what I could have sworn was respect, and then turned a disappointed stare on me. I almost felt a little ashamed. "Look Dink, you have to understand, I need more than just a few hundred grams of lettuce to keep me alive. I know you don't know any better, but if we're going to live together, we'll need to get some things straightened out between us, like how often and how much I need to eat and drink." My placatory speech was lost on him though, and I turned my attention back to the arguing adult-blue-giraffes.

The situation seemed to be degenerating. I couldn't tell you why, but I got a bad vibe from the first one that had entered the room. He reminded me of my Dad, who had yelled at me when I had tried to help him mow the lawn when I was too small to safely operate the old and heavy push mower. I had been hoping to surprise him when he got back from work, since he hated mowing the lawn when he got back home after a long day. To help me move the mower, I had activated it's automatic drive function, but it had gotten away from me and driven off into the garden before I could take off the clip which held the stop lever. When he'd seen the state the garden was in he had been so furious I had hid in my closet rather than go face him during dinner. I don't know why, but I felt the same temper and reckless mannerisms from this blue-giraffe, which earned him the nickname I'd given my father when I was young: Severus.

If Severus had been angry before, he was livid now. Some of his gesticulations threatened to make him lose his balance. The other adult, however, wasn't having any of Severus' shit, from the looks of it. She was giving Severus the same look of disappointment Dink had given me, albeit a little less condescending. She was so much like a mom that I couldn't help but name her Mama Giraffe. Something Severus said made Dink's ears perk up, then led him to join the spitting contest, which served to only enrage Severus even more. He started directing his anger at Dink. I understood a father's anger all too well, and moved to redirect it onto me.

"Whoa, cool your jets there Severus, it's not Dink's fault tha-" I guess Severus was closer to losing control than I had though, because my sudden insertion into the conversation made Severus whirl around in rage, his eyes thunderbolts. Then, he surprised us all. He aimed a kick at me. I'm sorry to say I wasn't quite sure what he was doing at first, and so I didn't dodge it. It didn't matter. His three toed foot connected with my shoulder. I didn't move. It felt like a High School freshman had punched me in the arm. That wasn't what made me angry though. I was a dog to this creature, an unthinking animal that had no idea what was expected of it. It didn't matter that he was mistaken, the fact was that he believed it, which made the act the same as if any man had kicked his dog.

"Now you've pissed me off." I growled, glaring at Severus. "Your lucky I don't know how to grow these plants, or drive this ship, or take care of myself out here, or I might actually take you up on that fight. As it is, fuck off." I shoved his foot, which had fallen close to my side when I hadn't moved. My push sent it shooting out from under him as though I had tackled his leg. I hadn't meant to push that hard, but it worked out. He used his other three legs to catch himself, but the rage seemed to have been replaced by fear. Mama Giraffe and Dink were staring at me too, as were the gardeners. I didn't know what to do then, so I went back to my room, jumped onto the bed, and berated myself for making an enemy out of the blue-giraffe who was most likely the captain of the ship I was staying on.

After Cqcq'trtr left the Hydroponics bay, everyone present breathed a sigh of relief, Tnnxz most noticeable among them.

"Well, I won't say that wasn't a surprise." Xkkrk finally clicked into the silence, "But you had it coming, Tnnxz. What were you about, kicking him? He didn't know why you were angry. He doesn't know that he shouldn't pick half the Cqcq plants in the hydroponics bay clean. He was hungry, so he went in search of food. He just seems to need a lot of it, though where he puts it is beyond me. We'll just have to find a way to get more food for him, since we're keeping him." At the last part, Tnnxz spluttered.

"Keeping it! Did you just see what it did!? It acted as though my kick was only a slight breeze, then threw my leg with almost a casual push! It's ruined half our Cqcq plants! I'd be surprised if any of them grew back. It's fulfilled all the qualifications of our last conversation about keeping it and more! Did you see the look it gave me? I've never felt such a predatory glare before in my life. And with its unprecedented strength, I'm more sure than ever that it was responsible for what happened to the Corti science vessel."

"Maybe he was," Xkkrk replied firmly, "But if he is responsible then he didn't do it without reason. You know how the Corti are. Their eugenics program removed every shed of empathy and compassion they had. They're little better than the monsters they study. As for how I know any of his actions were justified, you should look at yourself. I now have no doubts that if Cqcq'trtr had wanted to do to you what happened to those Corti scientists he could have. All he did was return the exact same thing you did to him, which is rather impressive restraint for an unthinking animal, if you ask me. He only started making those threatening noises when you began shouting at Vtv. I think he's just protective of the one that feeds him. Maybe you should look at him and follow his example, such as not shouting at your son when he did nothing wrong. None of us know anything about this creature, and surprises are bound to happen, or did you forget how quickly he filled the scented waste bin we placed in the medical bay for him to do his business in? Regardless, your behavior today has ensured that we're keeping him, since I have a feeling it may one day become useful to have an animal who is protective of our son and able to knock the legs out from under a Vzk'tk with a mere push, don't you?"

With that, Xkkrk turned and swept out of the room, Vtv behind her, head down. She did not often give Tnnxz direct orders, but where her children were involved, there were no illusions as to who was in command.

Before she was completely out of the room, Xkkrk turned to Vtv with a stern look on her face. "One thing needs to change with Cqcq'trtr though, dear. You absolutely must get him a bath. I don't care if he won't let you put him in water. Throw it at him if you have to. He smells and looks absolutely revolting."

Previous three part one

Next four

All chapters

Humans don’t make good pets part 4

by guidosbestfriend

There have been many excellent ideas and comments, as well as encouragement. It means a lot to me, and I'll strive not to disappoint. Most comments given won't be seen until after part six or so, since I haven't extensively planned past that point. Special thanks to fluffysilverunicorn, whose comment on the previous part is addressed in this post.

Alien measurements are given in their human equivalents in [brackets], as are words with near human translations.

Dear Journal,

I destroy xeno furniture and doors.

After the fight, if you could call it that, I thought I wouldn't live too long. After all, these blue-giraffes had a spaceship. It didn't matter that I was physically stronger than them even in my weakened state, which was quickly receding. Any minute they were going to burst through the door with death rays and vaporize my physically superior body. My real punishment was far worse.

It started out innocently enough. Dink entered my room, moving rather timidly, pushing a massive bucket of water on a cart. Remembering how I hadn't gotten the opportunity to get a drink while I was in the hydroponics bay, I thought Dink might have been bringing me a peace offering, or, at least, a distraction to ensure my attention was diverted as Severus came at me with a ray gun. With these thoughts in mind, I was completely unprepared for when he stopped the cart right next to my bed, pressed a button on the cart's handle, which promptly dumped the entire bucket of cold water over my head.

"What the Fu-" I spluttered through the water in my mouth. I choked down my words when Dink came up with what was unmistakeably a scrubber, and ran at me with it. I wasn't paralyzed anymore, though. I jumped from the bed, sailed five meters over and another meter up, landed on all fours, and then played a decidedly one sided game of tag with Dink, who was chasing me like an old woman with a broom after a mouse. It was so easy to keep away from him I had ample time to think. I did need a bath. I would have preferred one which was warmer, but I'm not that picky when my hair is so oily that it looks like it's wet. I wasn't going to let some blue-giraffe wash me, though.

It wasn't that hard to get the brush away from Dink. I let him get close to me, then dived at an oblique angle behind and to the right of him, snatching the bush as I shot past. He looked so dejected, watching me, his hand outstretched as though he still held the brush, looking at me with the eyes of one who knows he has no chance. He perked up again the moment I started doing his job for him, furiously scrubbing my oil encrusted skin. He flail-galloped out of the room, and in short order returned with an even larger tub of water, this time being transported on what appeared to be a hover dolly capable of lifting some of the smaller storage crates in one of the cargo bays. I got in, clothes and all. They needed a washing as much as I did.

I didn't feel like stripping down in front of Dink. I know he thought I was an animal, but it still didn't feel right. Thinking about my clothes, my thoughts abruptly alighted upon an idea. I tore off my shirt and looked at the tag. I cursed my bad luck as I realized it was one of my favorite shirts, one I'd had since the beginning of college seven years ago. It was just a plain white athletic shirt without any writing on it, although it had turned a rather disgusting shade of off white during its uses as an exercise shirt, and even more so during my recent bath hiatus. It had been washed so many times the ink on the tag had faded to a few smudges which looked like ash. How convenient. My pants were a pair of black basketball shorts. I think I had gone to the bar after a run. The tag from that had been cut completely off, as well as the tag from my compression shorts, due I think to the discomfort they had afforded me while running. Even more convenient.

I looked up at Dink, and realized he was staring wide eyed at me with my shirt off. "What, you actually thought that was part of my skin? Even after how it didn't move with me like the skin on my face and arms? Are you really that thick?" He flail-galloped out the room, and I was left alone to give myself a proper cleaning.

"I gave him a bath and guess what guess what guess what . . ." Vtv shouted excitedly, bursting into cargo bay 3 where Xkkrk was checking several containers of Ooaoue vaccinations bound for the nearest Auaia planet. The inhabitants had had a recent outbreak of the disfiguring disease which only affected their kind. The vaccines had to be stored in temperatures bellow [-4 degrees Celsius] or else the weakened viral strains would be too potent to be administered as a safe vaccine. They were probably the most vital cargo on board, and every day Xkkrk ensured the seals upon the containers were in working order.

Carefully storing her diagnostics scanner, Xkkrk braced herself for even more revolting or shocking news about there newest crew member. Vtv, speaking as fast as his little mouth could, squeak-clicked "At first he wouldn't let me get close to him with the brush, but then he grabbed it out of my hands, he's so fast, and then he started cleaning himself for me, and then you know what he did next?" Xkkrk assumed he was about to tell her. She didn't have to wait long. "Then he took off his outer skin! Then he just kind of looked at it and then seemed to be upset about something but he took off his skin!"

Xkkrk breathed a sigh of relief. She had feared Cqcq'trtr had just demonstrated his ability to detach and regrow a limb, or spit poison, or some other impossibility. This time it was merely Vtv's ignorance. "You don't need to worry about that dear, many creatures on countless worlds create artificial coverings for their skin if they aren't heavily furred. Nearly every wild animal on Hecta-5 wears leaves stuck together with a glue they naturally excrete from their bodies in order to protect them from their sun's harmfully high amounts of radiation, and the [silk moles] of Ceti-3 weave and wear a natural fabric so fine that it's considered better than all but the highest quality of synthetic polymers we're able to create. This creature's outer covering is neither outlandish nor especially unique, although it is looking rather worn, as I'm suspecting it hasn't managed to find the materials it used to make its "clothes" anywhere in space.

"Oh." Vtv sighed dejectedly, deflating. He seemed to take every incredible characteristic Cqcq'trtr demonstrated to be somehow reflective upon his own ability to care for him. Xkkrk was just happy the creature hadn't developed a taste for metal. "There is one thing I think we can do for him. Your father was right when he said Cqcq'trtr has a predatory glare. I wouldn't be surprised if his primary staple where he lived was meat." Vtv looked disgusted at the thought of eating another creature's flesh, and Xkkrk had to agree with him, but it wasn't as though Cqcq'trtr was a Hunter - a vicious, carnivorous, and sapient race of beings who ate the flesh of other sapients. Whatever he was, Cqcq'trtr was wonderfully domesticated. Perhaps he had once been some eccentric's pet before.

"It's ok dear, plenty of good animals eat meat. It's only the Hunters who have taken it too far, but it's a perfectly viable mode of sustenance in the wild, albeit it an extremely rare one. I can't think of a planet below a level 12 which has more than a few carnivores on it. We should just be thankful Cqcq'trtr appears to be an omnivore, or else he probably wouldn't be alive at this point."

Vtv looked up, confused. "An omniwhat?"

"An omnivore, an animal that's able to eat almost any organic substance. They're even more rare than carnivores, since they are usually exposed to both plant-bound and flesh-bound microbes, and usually don't manage to survive very long. I'd hazard a guess that our Cqcq'trtr's immune system is rather strong." This compliment about Cqcq'trtr's abilities brightened Vtv's mood significantly, which had been Xkkrk's intention. "Our sensors picked up a Tormix merchant cruiser that will cross our path in [an hour]. Their ships are some of the most highly advanced trade ships around, and so carry some of the largest selections. You've earned a good deal of credits helping us loading and unloading the cargo this [past year]. When we dock with them to see if they're willing to trade, you could go aboard and see if they have any Dizi rats. They breed the moment you feed them, and they don't eat much, but their meat is good for other carnivorous pets, and they're used all over the galaxy for that purpose, so I don't see why Cqcq'trtr wouldn't like them."

Presented with a mission and implied permission to go aboard another ship without supervision, Vtv almost fell over in his excitement, spewing his thanks and assurance that he would find the best Dizi rats there were, and wouldn't be taken for a bad deal. "Just don't bring Cqcq'trtr with you when you go on the ship. I don't want him thinking you're in danger and attacking someone when you were merely haggling."

"Ok ok ok, don't worry, I'll lock him in his room!" And with that Vtv ran from cargo bay three.

It had taken me nearly an hour to get all the caked oil off my body and out of my clothes without soap, but I felt remarkably better. I had just finished putting on my now clean clothes when Dink flew into my room in his usual manner, flailing his legs and arms with reckless abandon. He started clicking away excitedly and kept at it for a whole minute without taking a breath. Then he flew out of the room again. I had no idea what to make of his antics, but my curiosity was replaced with horror when the sound of an airtight seal emanated from the closed door.

I ran to the door and tested the handle. It wouldn't turn. I hopped, gripping it, then braced my feet against the door frame and pulled. With a screech of fracturing metal the handle broke off in my hand, throwing me half way across the room when it no longer provided counter resistance to the pushing of my legs. I guess they don't make their doorknobs out of the strongest stuff. I threw my shoulder against the door, but apparently their thrift only applied to the door handles, and the door, held tight by its air seal, didn't even rattle as I flew into it.

I took a moment to consider why I was scared that they'd locked the door. Perhaps they had sealed the door, and were about to leak all the atmosphere out of the room. I didn't know if they could do that, but I figured there was only one reason for such a tight lock on the door. If they had wanted to kill me, I don't know what would have been wrong with the ray gun option, but maybe they thought this a better way of doing it. In the end though, it boiled down to the fact that I wasn't just some dog they could lock into a room so I wouldn't pee on the carpet while they were gone. I was willing to be condescended to if the other option was death, but I'd already been locked into a cage once by aliens, and I wasn't going to let it happen again.

I wouldn't be able to knock down the door with brute force. It had been sealed through air pressure, which meant I had however many pounds per square inch of air pressing against it from the other side. No matter how strong I was, there was no way I was stronger than physics. The only way I'd get through the door was by breaking the seal, i.e. breaking the door itself. I'd need something harder and stronger than my bones to get through it. My eyes alighted upon the tub filled with water in the middle of the room. Now that I looked at it, it looked like it was one of the smaller cargo crates, just without its lid. It looked heavier than I could lift, but so had Severus' leg, and look how easily that had given.

I had to dump out half the water before I could reasonably lift and give a good momentum to the crate. Then I walked about a meter from the door, and threw the water filled crate at it like a boulder. It slammed into the door like a bartering ram, and the door frame itself shook, but held. I repeated the process, and on the third such hit, the door buckled in on itself, coming off of its frame. One more smash with the now empty crate sent the door clean off its hinges, and I hopped happily back into the rest of the ship, reveling in my new found freedom. I looked around. Dink stood in the corridor to my left, a box of what appeared to be round purple rats lying on the ground where he had dropped it.

I looked to my right where the mangled door and equally damaged storage crate lay. I shrugged. "I don't like cages."

Previous three part two

Next five

All chapters

Humans don’t make good pets part 5

by guidosbestfriend

I am extremely thankful for all of the encouraging comments and excellent ideas. The weekend is coming to a close, so my homework load will be replenished, most likely slowing down the progress of these, but as long as you guys keep liking them I'll keep making them. As before, criticism and ideas are welcomed and encouraged.

Alien measurements are given in their human equivalents in [brackets], as are words with near human translations.

Dear Journal,

I revise my previous statement.

I'm not a xeno dog,

I'm a xeno snake.

And I'm a failure at it.

Severus almost had a stroke when he saw what had happened to the door, and I think it was only Mama Giraffe's intervention that kept him from finding that ray gun I was sure he had stashed around here somewhere. Dink was scolded too, but this time it was done the way a parent should scold a child; it was also done by Mama, which was what made the difference. Regardless of the clicks said, I was soon moved out of my old room and into an empty cargo bay. Funny thing, I had thought that cargo bay had been full last time I had gone out exploring. I wasn't going to complain though, since I now had a room half the size of a warehouse all to myself. It was a great reminder of how many friends I had up here. Still, the acoustics were good.

Dink came in a few minutes after I had found the most comfortable piece of metal floor, carrying a mat which he set on the floor, and a bucket he filled with water from an oddly shaped but easily recognizable tap on the wall. I marked how its mechanism worked and stored that away for later. It would most definitely come in handy next time I wanted to get a drink or take a bath without needing to wrestle a hose from one of the caretakers in the hydroponics bay. When he left I had assumed he wouldn't be back for a while. After all, I had my bed, I had my water, and I didn't think I was going to be getting any lettuce today after the whole door incident, so why would he come back? In hindsight I almost wish he hadn't.

He did come back, carrying one of the now familiar shoe boxes, and I was relieved that I was getting lunch. When he opened the box, it was filled with the purple rats he had dropped earlier upon observing my dislike of enclosed areas. He backpedaled quickly once he had put it down, looking at me with trepidatious expectation. I looked at the rats, then up at Dink, then back at the rats. The light-bulb turned on. "Oh that's sick. You want me to eat these raw? I said I wanted meat, and I'm really impressed you figured it out somehow, but I haven't hunted a day in my life. I don't know how to skin or clean one of these things, and even if I did I don't have a knife to do it with. Even if I managed to do all that, where would I cook it? I hope you didn't spend any money on these.

Unfortunately, I was pretty sure they had. I'm not sure if it was Dink specifically or not, but I was pretty sure by now the blue-giraffes were strictly herbivores. I owed it to them to at least try and find a way to prepare these things. After all, it was my only chance at getting meat on this ship. I picked up one of the near-spherical bundles of purple hair. They were actually kind of cute, viewed from above. Then I saw its face. It made the naked mole rat look like the kind of designer animals you want to show off at competitions. Its little excrescence of a face had three eyes, a flat, wrinkled face like a pug's, and the protruding front teeth of a beaver. It didn't help that its tongue and eyes appeared to be in full derp mode.

Deciding it was for the best that I had seen its face, so I wouldn't mind killing these things in the future, I tried to think of the best way of going about it. In the end I just slammed it against the ground. I guess they don't make xeno rats the way they do back home, because on the first hit it burst like an overfull water balloon, its last squeak cut abruptly and shockingly short. Glistening orange blood flew in all directions, splatting my white shirt and even getting on Dinks feet, who was standing a good three meters away. The splash of the little rat's body was quickly followed by the splash of Dink's vomit as he heaved all over the floor, adding to the horrendous smell, and confirming my assumptions that he only ate plants. He ran out of the room, trying with minimal success to keep his breakfast from following his Lunch.

"Sorry!" I called after his retreating figure. There wasn't much left of that first rat, and nothing that I felt like putting in my mouth, even if I could cook it. I chose a second rat, and opting out of attempting another purple xeno rat smoothy, tried to find its neck. I couldn't. It really was an almost perfect sphere, and its face just seemed to occupy one side of its obscenely round body. I didn't want to see how many flicks in the face it would take to kill it, since I was pretty sure slapping would have a similar affect as punching. Feeling rather foolish as I held this thing before me as though contemplating its inner meaning, I tried a similar approach as last time. I grabbed it by the tail and used that to swing it against the side of the shoebox, which seemed to be made of a material almost identical to plastic. I had intended for the increased ductility of the shoebox to lessen the force of impact, but at the last moment the tail snapped off, throwing the unfortunate rodent into the corner of the box instead of the side, where it once again burst, this time splattering all over its fellows, sending them into a frenzy.

I swore. Getting frustrated, I snatched one by pinching some of the excess skin on its back back and yanking it up with a snap of my wrist. To my utter surprise its entire skin flew off of its back as though I were a magician, snapping the cloth off a skinless xeno rat oozing orange blood which had "magically" appeared. It seemed almost as shocked as I was, and continued running around for a few seconds until the massive amount of blood loss finally ended its shrieks. I had to admit, it was a rather efficient way of getting all the blood out of the thing. I needn't have worried about gutting it either. It was so fragile that a knife would have been a hindrance.

I was impressed by the fact that most of the hump of the back seemed to be a fatty meat, similar to chicken leg. The back layers peeled off into nice slices like the meat of a fish. Honestly, this creature almost seemed to come pre-skinned, pre-cleaned, and pre-sliced. The only thing left to do was to find a way to cook it, as I am not a fan of Japanese food. Looking around my room, I saw the water tap. If each of these cargo bays had been built with basic utilities so that virtually any form of cargo could be stored in them, then it was reasonable to assume that there had to be some form of power outlet nearby. I couldn't see any, although I didn't exactly know what I was looking for. I looked up and saw a plethora of pipes with varying diameters.

I didn't have the fuzziest as to how FTL worked, but those Trekkies and Star Wars fans always seemed to be talking about plasma, and if anyone even had the slightest idea of how FTL might function I supposed it would be them, or someone way beyond my IQ level. I didn't have any better ideas, so I walked over to the nearest wall, which, having been made for strictly utilitarian purposes, was pockmarked with various boxes and holes, making it a simple matter to climb to the ceiling. Once I could reach the various pipes, I moved my hand close to them, hoping to feel heat. If they were going to make a pipe which was going to hold plasma, it probably would be such an effective insulator I wouldn't feel anything, but it was best to check. I got lucky, and found a pipe that I doubted I could touch without suffering severe burns in seconds.

I climbed half the way down, then fell the rest of the 10 meter drop in what I would like to say was a purposeful action. I carried the meat slices up to the scalding pipe, and carefully laid them on top of it, where they emanated a delightful sizzling sound which reminded me oh too clearly of bacon. One purple xeno rat pig didn't have much meat on it despite its odd biology, so I cleaned another one and carried its meat and another live one to the ceiling, just in case two didn't look sufficient either. I accidentally dropped that one, which only added to the mess and mayhem all over the floor. It did look peaceful, though, as if fell through the air, its mutant-pug face serene, its tongue lolling. Contented with my work, I carried my mat to a cleaner section of the floor and waited for my xeno bacon to finish up.

Xkkrk entered Cqcq'trtr's new room and immediately regretted it. After he had decided to show his displeasure with being locked into the medical bay by somehow ripping off its door, Xkkrk felt fortunate she had been able to stop Tnnxz from grabbing his pulse pistol and shooting Cqcq'trtr right there. After he had calmed down, Xkkrk had been able to convince Tnnxz that all Cqcq'trtr needed was more space to move around. He was a lively fellow, to put it lightly, and the medical bay was one of the smallest rooms on the ship. She had suggested cargo bay 9, as it had just been vacated due to a successful discussion with the Tormix trade cruiser. A mere [30 minutes] after moving into his new home, Vtv had come stumbling into cargo bay 12 where the replacement parts for the ship were stored, crying and gagging and trying to speak at the same time.

She quickly guessed the reason for the problem, and started walking as quickly as she could without looking panicked towards cargo bay 9. As she followed a trail of Vtv's vomit, she quickened her pace, not even attempting to appear composed. She took the final few steps at a run, bursting into the compartment. She didn't know if it was the smell which immediately assaulted her nose or the sight which instantly burned itself into her eyes that made her vomit, but her stomach's contents were soon joining Vtv's on the floor, along with what appeared to be a Dizi rat massacre.

Bright orange blood splattered half the floor of the compartment, most of it seeming to come from a single rodent which had been crushed into the floor with such force its body had left a blast radius a full 20 meters in diameter, to the point that there was barely enough matter in the Dizi's body to create more than the outline of the circle. Another rat seemed to have shared a similar fate as the first, but most revolting of all was the storage container Vtv had delivered the rats in. It appeared to have been ceremoniously drenched in blood, surrounded by countless glistening entrails, with the skins of three rats draped over its side. One rat remained in the box, but it appeared to have drowned in the blood of its comrades and wasn't moving. Either that, or its poor little mind had snapped after what it had seen.

Cqcq'trtr sat contentedly upon the mat Vtv had brought him, eating the charred flesh of one of the rodents. His visage was equally as horrifying as his handiwork. His front was almost completely orange and wet, and his face was covered in splatters and squirts. Xkkrk didn't think she had ever seen him so happy. She wondered why he had cooked the meat, or how he had even done it. Something orange, hot, and sticky dripped onto her snout. She looked up, and saw ragged shreds of meat draped over one of the plasma conduits on the ceiling. How had he gotten up there? How had he known those pipes were hot? Xkkrk mentally added infrared vision to the already startlingly large list of dangerous biological characteristics Cqcq'trtr possessed. Her thoughts were interrupted by another drop of blood hitting her right between the eyes.

Her roiling stomach happily grasped upon this excuse and heaved with all its might, emptying any remaining breakfast she had managed to retain and clawing for the dinner it had already discarded through traditional means. She stumbled her way out of the cargo bay, only to run into Tnnxz right outside the door. She thought for a moment that he had heard of Cqcq'trtr's most recent escapades, but then his pale, fearful face snapped her back to reality.

"Ztrkx's ship just decloaked [10 kilometers] off our port side," He breathed. "He told us to power down our engines and ready the port docking module. He's here to make good on his promises."

Previous four

Next six

All chapters

Humans don’t make good pets part 6

by guidosbestfriend

This is my first time writing action sequences, so this'll be interesting. The ideas your comments have given me are indispensable, and are what are allowing me to write these stories, so keep them up! Special thanks to /u/Elyandarin, /u/Hambone3110 (for both the back knowledge and a quote from a comment which I incorporated), /u/Lostwingman07, and especially /u/DreamingKroot whose comment was the main inspiration for this installment.

Alien measurements are given in their human equivalents in [brackets], as are words with near human translations.

The blood drained from Xkkrk's face, despite the pounding in her chest, at the sound of that name. Ztrkx. If you were to look up his file, he would be labeled as a simple merchant with a Crixa cargo vessel, just like Tnnxz. The only difference would be the [5 mile] long rap sheet detailing countless unconfirmed reports of criminal actions from petty theft, to larceny, all the way to grand murder. For those who truly knew him, Ztrkx was a pure-blooded pirate with the front of a cargo merchant, and a flimsy front at that. To make matters infinitely better, he bore a personal grudge against Tnnxz.

As hard as it was to believe, seeing the differences between them today, Ztrkx and Tnnxz had grown up together on the same moon, both children of miners. Mining was perhaps the lowest occupation, as the need for true miners had been replaced by automatons. But robots required maintenance and biological miners only required a bare minimum of food, which meant that in the worst conditions, sapient beings still slaved under masters too poor or too cheap to care about the working conditions or safety precautions. On a barren rock of a moon, Ztrkx and Tnnxz had spun tales to each other. Tales about how they would one day pool their resources and buy a Crixa. It didn't matter to the two boys that the Crixa was perhaps the slowest and most obsolete model of cargo ship still seen about the galaxy; to them, it was beautiful.

With a hope of a dream, which was more than most miners had, Tnnxz and Ztrkx pushed themselves harder than any of the other workers. They cared for each other, watched each other, and helped keep each other sane through the long hours of grinding toil. After [4 years] of hard work in the mine, which probably shortened their life-spans significantly, they were able to buy a Crixa off of a merchant who had made several bad choices and fallen into bankruptcy.

At first it was just them. Then, as Tnnxz's uncanny ability to feel subtle shifts in the markets began to increase their revenues, they began expanding their holdings and their crew. Xkkrk had been one of the first to join them. Ostensibly it had been so she would be able to escape the responsibility of inheriting a weapons manufacturing company from her father, but in reality it had been because she had been drawn to Tnnxz and Ztrkx, at the time attracted equally by both.

As she spent more time with Ztrkx though, she began to see the arrogance, jealousy, and utter contempt for the "weak", which Ztrkx harbored inside himself. His lust drove her closer to Tnnxz, which only exacerbated an already tense situation. Ztrkx had been in favor of looting cargo ships which had been set upon by Hunters. After all, the crew had been unable to repel them, and therefore were most likely dead, but the Hunters cared little for most commodities, so left those untouched.

Tnnxz resisted him at first, but then agreed it would have been a shame to let the goods go to waste. On the first derelict ship they boarded, it seemed Ztrkx had been right. Blood from various species had been evident in great quantities, but no living souls were to be found. Then Ztrkx happened upon a wounded child. It was most likely beyond saving, but Ztrkx was more worried about what Tnnxz would do if he discovered someone alive on that ship. So he shot it in the head. Tnnxz saw.

The majority of the crew were loyal to Tnnxz, though some few fanatically supported Ztrkx. A fight broke out between the two factions, but Ztrkx was overwhelmed three to one. Tnnxz didn't feel right in killing Ztrkx as he had killed the child, so left him, and his supporters, on the broken and dying ship where he had committed his first murder. Before the airlock had closed, Ztrkx had screamed that he would find Tnnxz again, and for the betrayal of his trust would take all that he loved. Ztrkx's final, bloody gaze before the airlock hid his face had been fixed upon Xkkrk.

He hadn't died as both Xkkrk and Tnnxz had hoped. Instead, reports of a group of pirates who masqueraded a cargo vessel began to surface. There was no way to be certain it was Ztrkx, and the pirates themselves seemed more myth than fact, yet Xkkrk had felt the reason behind the stories. Now, it seemed, Ztrkx was done biding his time.

Dear Journal,

I'm a monster.

I don't know which kind yet.

I was finishing up the last slice of purple xeno rat pig when Mama Giraffe had stumbled in. She barely even took one look at the room before she added to its olfactory experience. I sure hoped I wouldn't have to sleep in here. She lurched her way back out the door after glancing at the ceiling, stumbling into Severus right outside. Perfect. He was going to suffer from apoplexy the moment he saw this. My fears were soon confirmed as I heard rapid clicking from the blue-giraffe. Then I checked myself. There was a different tone to this clicking. A more frantic, panicked cast which had been absent during Severus' previous rants. I quickly took the last bite - it really did taste like chicken if you closed your eyes - and hurried over, although what I was going to do I had no idea.

Before I was half-way across the room, the entire cargo bay, and I'd surmise the entire ship, Lurched alarmingly as though it had struck an obstacle. Moments later the sound of shrieking metal being ripped apart came from the bow of the ship. It was pretty clear to me that we had hit something, but instead of running to where I'd seen the bridge so he could efficiently take care of the matter, Severus hit a button on his belt and then spoke with the faraway look of someone on the phone. He lifted his finger off the button then started gallop-flailing to the aft of the ship, which was towards the hydroponics bay and, I assumed, as I hadn't seen it yet, the engine room.

I doubted Severus was such a bad captain that he neglected his duties whenever he hit a piece of space debris, so I quickly revised my hypothesis as to what was happening to "pending". When I began hearing screams which sounded frighteningly like the screams of horses accompanied by noises which sounded remarkably like rapid pistol fire, except from a ray gun, I decided Severus must have the right idea in mind and high-tailed it out of my cargo bay and towards the hydroponics bay. I'd never been in a firefight before in my life, and didn't think the attackers would be willing to disarm themselves so I could fight them on the familiar ground of bar brawling, or even a friendly game of darts.

I saw Mama a few cargo bays behind me, herding a multitude of the children as fast as the slowest could run. Fucking Jiggles. I made sure they passed me, looking down the long corridor which allowed passage from the ship proper to the long line of cargo bays. I couldn't see anything, but the screams had also stopped. I think I had almost preferred them to the silence. Jiggles finally got his last vestiges of flab though a door just beyond the one which led to the Hydroponics bay, and I followed suit, covering a distance in 2 seconds what had taken the child herd 20. Adrenaline's a hell of a drug. Good thing too, because they had been closing the door the moment Jiggles had gotten inside. I slammed into the half-closed door and flew into the room.

I guess I slammed into the door a little too hard, since it snapped off the its hinges and was flung out of Severus' hand to strike the wall to his right. Both of us looked at the door which we had been counting on as a shield as it slowly peeled itself off the wall to fall with a clang to the floor. "Do you make your hinges out of purple xeno rat pig bones?" I shouted, as I lifted the door and fit it back in place, using the door frame and my shoulder to keep it set. Then it started taking hits.

I was impressed with the solidity of the door, especially given the fragility of its connections. From this side of the door it sounded as though someone was merely slapping the other side. Granted, they were hard slaps, the kind you get after having a threesome with both your girlfriends sister's - dating identical triplets is hard - but they were slaps nonetheless. The slaps began getting faster and slightly harder, and the door began to vibrate alarmingly. Silence suddenly fell as the shots stopped completely, and then I heard clicking from the other side of the door. I looked to Severus, hoping for some kind of recognizable signal as to what to do.

He was pretty clear when he started trying to pull me away. I hoped for all our sakes that he was being gentle on purpose, or else any fighting we'd have to do would be even more one-sided, but I eased up on the door and set it beside the door frame. Another blue-giraffe strode into the room. This one had seen some fights before. One of his arms and two or his legs were prosthetic; his stripes were marred by countless small frosty scars. He had the bearing of one used to command and very harsh in discipline, but I couldn't decide if it was of the just or cruel variety.

I had been preparing myself to fight for all I was worth, but there was one thing I hadn't expected. This new blue-giraffe wore a uniform. As did his shipmates, I saw, as three of them filed in behind him. Now I had a dilemma. Were these the police? Was this a lawful boarding? For all I knew, my newest family could be a family of thieves and smugglers. I wouldn't have minded too much, but the law's the law, and I wouldn't want to attack these intruders if they turned out to just be men doing their jobs. I observed, trying to catch every detail which would tell me what was going on.

"I'm gone for [10 years], and the only modification you make to our old ship is another 5 cargo bays? Also, what happened in 9? It looks like someone took an anti-tank pulse-gun to a box of Dizi rats," clicked Ztrkx, striding confidently into the engine room. He looked to his left, and saw the ugliest little creature watching him with bright eyes. "What have you got here, my old friend? Another weakling? You do love them so. Why even now you hide among them while the rest of your crew lies bleeding and dying about your ship, having protected what they thought was a worthy life. Shame. I could have given them so much more. I could have given them pride." He motioned towards the uniforms, a recent acquisition from a cloth trader made specially for this occasion.

"Neither am I your friend, nor is he weak," stated Tnnxz, attempting to sound calm, but ruining the illusion by allowing his back leg to shake. It had always shook when they had been friends, and it galled Ztrkx to no end that it was only through his motivation and his determination that Tnnxz now stood here, proud among the stars instead of rotting in a crater on the moon they'd left so long ago.

"You're right," Ztrkx retorted. "You aren't my friend. If you were, I would be standing before you as an equal, rather than a conqueror. I'm glad you tore everything away from me and sent me tumbling through the stars. If you hadn't, I might still be stuck here with you, refusing opportunity after opportunity because of your cowardice when we could have been living like Kings!" He finished in an angry rush, panting as the fury he had kept under control for so long threatened to overflow.

"Why are you here, Ztrkx?" Tnnxz asked. Fool. "Is it to gloat?" Not so much a fool then, but still a sizable one.

"Partially." Replied Ztrkx. "But not entirely. I'm here to keep my word, because I, unlike you, assume my promises to be binding."

"I'm not going with you, Ztrkx," spat Xkkrk, beautiful Xkkrk. "I will throw myself out of the first airlock before I willingly spend a [picosecond] in your presence." A shame, that was. If she had been willing to come with him he would have gladly accepted her. As it was, he would not let her dampen his moment of triumph by making him show his disappointment. He laughed, hoping none had noticed the momentary pause, and clicked, "I don't want you, anymore. Look at you, a mere shadow of what you once were, and a poor one at that. Stay with Tnnxz, I don't care. I came for what will hurt him the most."

His eyes searched among the children and alighted upon the shortest, the one with the stripes so thin they seemed to nearly disappear when they reached his face; just like his father. Tnnxz saw Ztrkx's eyes light up, and understood his purposes. A growl was the only warning his men had before he flew at Ztrkx, Xkkrk on his heels, having attacked a moment later. These were the best of his men, though, and they had quick reflexes. One grabbed Tnnxz while he was still in the air, bearing him to the ground, while the other managed to catch Xkkrk before she could tackle Ztrkx. He smiled without amusement, then heard a much lower growl resonate from the small ugly creature to his left. My, he had quite forgotten it was there.

Ignoring it, Ztrkx motioned for his final man who wasn't holding someone to grab the smallest child, while the other two kept his parents in check. The man grabbed the smallest one's arm. Then the world exploded.

I had been watching the incoherent conversation like a hawk, but couldn't understand a thing from its participants' body language. Something the alleged police officer said threw Mama and Severus into a rage, which almost made my decision for me, but two of the pending-policemen detained the pair without harming either, which is what I'd expect police to do. They seemed rather unnecessarily rough, though. "Watch it." I growled to the two holding them down.

The officer then motioned towards Dink, which didn't make any sense. What would the officer want wi-

The third blue-giraffe began pulling on Dink's arm, dragging him towards the door. I didn't need any more proof that these giraffes weren't police, and if they were, then I joined the rebel cause instantly. I dive tackled the scum holding Dink, slamming him into the opposite wall. His rib cage exploded like a watermelon upon the impact, covering me in a purple sludge. The giraffes scream or curse was cut short as though with a guillotine.

Ztrkx's man suddenly disappeared in a blur of orange white and brown. It took a moment for Ztrkx's mind to process what had happened. By the time he looked to where his second in command lay with his chest pulverized, the small ugly creature had jump-flew through the air to land on top of his chief engineer, snapping his spine with a sickening crunch. As the ferocious beast tore his chief medical officer's throat out, Ztrkx drew his pulse pistol and fired.

I managed to take the other one down before anyone knew what was happening, and scored a lucky hit as I swung an outstretched arm which caught the third ex-police-candidate in the throat. I had been too slow, it seemed, because I turned around to find the fake officer pointing a gun at my face. There's a reason bartenders of rowdy pubs keep shotguns under the counter. Guns end the fight. Period. He pulled the trigger, and I saw a blinding flash of light as it struck me right between the eyes. I didn't die. It hurt, believe me it hurt, but it wasn't the kind of pain to incapacitate me. It was the kind of pain which was only going to piss me off. "My turn," I growled, advancing on the officer.

Ztrkx fired. It didn't die. His final thought before his skull collapsed was so it wasn't weak after all.

I bodily picked up the officer and flung him from the room, jumping after him so I landed above his head the moment he hit the ground. I hadn't realized how angry I was until I started bashing his face with my fists like a deranged gorilla on crystal meth. His head was a purple mush after only a few hits, but I continued to vent my anger on it, obliterating his skull until it was merely a purple stain. Someone slapped me hard on the shoulder. I looked up and was slapped again in the face. Three enemy giraffes stood 10 meters away, firing ray pistols. Those things were useless. Why did they even both shooting them? They might as well use them as clubs.

I sprinted towards them, feeling as though I were wading through a sea of small angry children as WEAK. ASS. RAY. PULSES. dissipated harmlessly against my body. As I flung myself into them, mindlessly laying about with my legs and fists as I had oft done during many a senseless brawl, I reflected that I might need to start using cover on my approaches lest I end up with a nasty bruising, or even a bloody nose. I shouldn't have lost myself in thought, though, because when I checked back into reality I saw that I had been kicking the lifeless body of one of my opponents, needlessly and systematically breaking every bone in his body for the second time.

I started hunting, stalking through the ship, searching every cargo bay. The officer's crew hadn't been merciful to my new family, and the lifeless corpses of several of the ship’s crew members lay strewn around the ship. I found one of the gardeners missing an arm, and another without his head. The next few opponents I found suffered similar yet more profound injuries before I allowed them to expire, although there wasn't much worse I could do than take off the head, so I used a grammatical loophole to achieve the same result without instantly killing him.

I finished with the cargo bays, and came into a large room which housed the port and starboard airlocks. I could see how the criminals had gotten in. The port airlock hatch had been shredded by what could only be a large drill, which was mounted on a mechanical arm in the enemy’s ship. The drill had been retracted so that the enemy blue-giraffes could easily move between ships, which they were doing when I found them, carrying crates from our ship onto theirs. Seeing them formed the word which had already been growing in my mind: Pirates.

I slammed into the closest pirate-giraffe in the middle of his long back, breaking his spine and neck through whiplash. I picked up the small crate he had dropped and flung it at the next closest pirate, who had apparently skipped both leg and arm day, resulting in his expiration due to his inability to catch a storage crate. The other seven in the room had noticed me by now - they were so freaking slow - and had drawn their piddle pistols. Another five joined their brothers in the void when they tried to use their party poppers as weapons. The last two learned faster though. The sixth tried to use his gun as a club. I gave him kudos for that, but he was still slow and weak. I caught his wrist, disarmed him, turned his gun on him and pulled the trigger, which was oddly on the back of the handle rather than under the barrel.

Nothing happened. I guess these guns had security measures to keep someone from doing what I had just done. The security measures weren't all encompassing, however, since they didn't prevent me from hurling the gun into my victim’s face, where it stuck. I was pretty impressed with that, as the butt of a gun isn't strictly made to be used as a knife, but the seventh and final giraffe pirate had another surprise in store for me. As number six crumpled to the floor, number seven drew a sword from a sheath on his back. The double edge of the blade came alight with burning red heat the moment it left its scabbard. Their guns may have been ineffective, but I doubted my tender skin would appreciate being attacked by an alien lava sword. He swung at me, and I back-stepped. He swung again, and I repeated. He lunged at me, driving forward with a stab.

Even though he had a weapon that would have worked on me, I still had him out classed in the speed department. I sidestepped, grabbed his arm as it passed, then broke it over my knee. He howled, but didn't have long to contemplate his pain once his sword found its way through his chest and then his neck. I was so happy with my newly acquired sword that I didn't notice the drill powering up until it was almost too late. A solid beam of energy shot towards me, narrowly missing my head as I ducked, and struck the inside hatch of the starboard airlock of our ship, burned through it, then went through the outer hatch. An explosive crack sounded from the ship, and both ships, being connected, began losing atmosphere. I felt myself flying back through the port airlock, but grabbed the edge that was the outside hatch of the port airlock and braced my legs against the edge of the inside hatch, wedging myself into security. My drill-happy friend, however, wasn't so fortunate. Oh, he grabbed the edge just like me, he just didn't have my grip strength, and his hands merely brushed the edge before he flew into my ship and out the other end.

Even with my enemy gone, I still had the small problem of a large hole leaking all the oxygen, which I had grown rather accustomed to, out into space, where it could hardly be appreciated. I didn't know it at the time, but I had already fixed the problem. The mangled door to my previous room flew into view, having been sucked into the docking bay from somewhere further inside the ship proper. It was too large to fit through the hole, and, bent over upon itself by my ministrations, was strong enough to create a temporary bulkhead.

Suddenly released from the gravity defying force of atmosphere under pressure, I eased myself down from the airlock frame before my arms gave out. I searched the pirate ship to see if there were any more, but it seemed as though the raiding party had included everyone on board, except for twinkle-toes the trigger happy jackhammer specialist. With the battle, to give it a kind name, over, a wave of weariness washed through me, though more from the adrenaline than any actual physical exertion. It was only now that I was able to survey my handiwork.

Oh my.

Previous five

Next seven

All chapters

Also, /u/Hambone3110 has started writing HFY again, and as a continuation of TKJ. It's as awesome as it sounds. Run, little monster.

No man, I like the ideas and its a good one. I just wanted to give him a sword because I thought of it all of a sudden and went with it. I hadn't even considered it as a writing impliment, but you're right, that'd work out. I set up the chess game for that purpose, mainly because I hadn't even thought of prime numbers as an option. But now that this episode is over, which is pretty much about as far as I had pre-planned out, he's going to be working towards fixing that other big problem which is being a pet.

The reason I set this story to be slightly before its inspiration was because in TKJ Jenkins had a universal communicator implant, which apparently needed to be painstakingly crafted to each species biology. Jenkins had one, but it was crude, so I worked off the assumption that it was a first gen, and not able to be anywhere else. Since this is set before that, a universal translator doesn't exist for humans yet. The other reason for setting it before TKJ was because Jenkins caused a massive media anomaly which nearly everyone would have heard about, which would make one wonder why these traders were so oblivious to what a human was. Also, TKJ made it so that humans were classified as sapient beings so long as they had developed calculus. If they were officially recognized as sapient, and already had their biology checked out, then there would be no way for this story to begin in the first place.

The Kevin Jenkins Experience Part 1.1

By Hambone3110

“Next!” I ordered. I did not at first bother to look up from the desktop in front of me where the standard security systems were scanning the being in front of me for weapons, pathogens, parasites and other such contraband. I only looked up when the machine flashed a message I had never seen before: “ERROR: Unknown Species”

It was small. Barely tall enough to see over the top of my customs desk, in fact. A quadriform biped, forelimbs ending in five manipulating digits. Much of its body was covered in obviously synthetic fabric, with only the forepaws and head visible. Much of the head – the top, around the ears, and down under and around the mouth and nose – was covered in short, coarse fur of a brownish hue, apart from where this had been shaved in front of the ear to accept a cybernetic of some description. My desk registered this as the creature’s Interspecies Communication Implant, though it seemed like a shockingly crude example.

It met my surprised stare with the level binocular gaze of a species evolved for predation and the hunt. Small, but powerful and dense–seeming. Despite its lack of height, it had strapped a pack to its torso that looked larger and heavier than I could have comfortably carried.

“Abductee 907–42–96–53–3.” It introduced itself. “Name – Kevin Jenkins.” Fortunately, the crude cybernetic seemed to be functioning perfectly, and I had no difficulty in understanding the thing’s speech, or the subtle body language that spoke of a cocktail of bored resignation and weariness.

I had never had to deal with an abductee before, though I had been trained and knew exactly what to do. I closed the booth, stood up and gestured for the alien to follow me with my second right forelimb. “I will need to interview you in private.” I told it. Him.

He picked up a second bag, and strolled – strolled! While carrying more than I suspected I could physically lift! – after me. Whatever this thing was, it was from a high–gravity planet.

“I know the drill.” He said. “Pretty sure I’ll be leaving this station before long, too.” “Why would that be?” I asked politely as I ushered him into the private interview corral and activated the privacy field. The sounds of immigration control evaporated as a sudden fuzzy silence engulfed us. He dropped the bags and they landed with a solid, dense noise that told me they were exactly as heavy as they looked. “It’s only a matter of time before your colleagues in security prosecute me for vagrancy” he said. “Why would they do that?” I asked, to make conversation as I prepared the official forms. “Article 227, paragraph 16 of the Galactic Treaty of Laws.” He said, stretching out and rolling its head. His endoskeleton issued a loud clicking sound and he issued a sigh that my implant interpreted as pleasure. He laughed, a sound that served the exact same purpose as it did in mine, though this one was tinged with bitterness. “Technically, as a member of a pre–interplanetary species, I am a non–sentient specimen of indigenous fauna and therefore cannot be legally employed or own property.”

I indicated my understanding by nodding – another gesture our body language shared in common– and raising the fur at the nape of my neck.  “The Corti abducted you, didn’t they?” “My kind call them “Greys”.” he replied.

I nodded. The Corti were small – even smaller than this being – grey–skinned but with large eyes and oversized brains as a result of a centuries–long eugenics program within their species which had vastly expanded their intellect. Most other species suspected that their sense of empathy had atrophied as a side–effect of the campaign to make themselves smarter. They were known for abducting specimens of a pre–Contact species, experimenting on them to acquire biological data, then using that information to be able to sell cybernetic technology to the newcomers that was appropriate to their biology the second they were welcomed into the galactic fold. Unethical, but the species as a whole could not be prosecuted for the actions of a few and so the sale of the implants went ahead anyway. Kevin Jenkins had clearly been one of their victims.

“Apt.” I said. “Why not have the implant removed and return to your homeworld?” “Because I’d never be able to keep the secret, and so the Office for the Preservation of Indigenous Species won’t let me.” he said. “Can we please start with the official stuff? I haven’t slept in two standard Diurnals.”

“I apologise” I said, chagrined at my own lack of professionalism. I activated the corral’s recording function “Interview begins, interstellar convenient standard date/time 1196–5–24.4. Civilian trade station 591 “Outlook on Forever”, Customs and Immigration Officer krrkktnkk a’ktnnzzik’tk interviewing immigrant pre–Contact abductee. Could you repeat your identification for me, please?” “Abductee 907–42–96–53–3 Male. Name – Kevin Jenkins. My species refer to ourselves as ’Human’. Our homeworld is a category twelve temperate at co–” I interrupted him. “I must ask you to take this interview seriously. Your visa will be denied if you continue to mock the immigration system.”

Its facial feature twisted up into an expression of amusement.

“I assure you officer, I am not mocking the immigration system. My species homeworld really is a category twelve temperate. You will find documentary verification of that fact on this data storage.”

I ripped the data from the storage and attached it to the recording. True to his word, a full survey of the “human” homeworld revealed that it was indeed category twelve – a death world. Hostile, vicious and forever primordial. Experimentally I tried to enter this fact onto the paperwork, which of course threw up an error code.

“It is considered impossible for sentient beings to evolve on category twelve planets” I said.  “As I explained off the record, according to Article 227 Paragraph 16 of the Galactic Treaty of Laws I am, legally, not a sentient being.” it raised its forelimbs and the torso joints moved in a complicated way, denoting resignation. I gave this some consideration, and scrapped the form. He was quite correct and that status made properly navigating him through the immigration paperwork impossible. The recording would just have to do.

Jenkins nodded, and our implants eventually decided that he meant that a prediction had come true.  “You can see why the administration on station 442 kicked me out.” he said. “I’m a bureaucratic anomaly. The whole system is far too rigid to accommodate me and mine.”

I caught myself nodding my agreement and shut the gesture down. It would show up on the record and negatively impact my next performance evaluation. “I get the impression that station 442 is not the only place where you–”

I was interrupted by an alarm. Three short howls of noise – the attack alarm.

“Impossible!” I exclaimed as I leapt out of my chair, and registering the motion the corral shut down our privacy field. The remaining passengers from the shuttle that we had been processing were responding with varying degrees of calmness. Some, more skittish species, were beating a hasty retreat to the shuttle’s airlock, while others waited for instructions.

I had not finished gathering my thoughts when there was a sudden violent lurch that knocked me from my feet. I saw Jenkins sway with the motion and remain upright, despite the fact that he was balanced precariously on only two legs. A second alarm began to sound – the long wail of a station damage alarm. This was then followed by the angry growl of a hull breach alarm, but oddly not the decompression alarm.

That could mean only one thing.

“Them? Here?” I asked of nobody as I struggled to my feet and trotted to the weapons locker. “Them?” Jenkins asked, loping along easily next to me in what was clearly much lower gravity than he was evolved for.

The locker reacted to the security codes my station security officer’s harness was broadcasting and opened, spilling out a pair of pulse guns, two personal shield emitters and a magazine of coin–sized nervejam grenades. I slapped the shield emitter to the power dock on my harness. There was no visible change, but the sense tendrils along my back felt a tingling as the shield came online. The pulse gun configured itself for my species as I picked it up and connected its power cable to my harness.

“Hunters.” I whispered.

The Kevin Jenkins Experience Part 1.2

By Hambone3110

Jenkins didn’t seem especially frightened by the news, but then I realised he had almost certainly never heard of the only carnivorous species in the galaxy that preferred the meat of fellow sentients.

I didn’t have time to explain. There was the sound of pulse–gun fire and a squealing being galloped into the customs area before being caught from behind by a kinetic pulse that hurled it to the ground, broken and dying.

Jenkins sprinted for cover, and I followed. Despite my longer legs, he covered the ground faster and threw himself behind a customs booth as another kinetic pulse missed him. I turned and shot at the Hunter that had aimed at us. My shot evaporated harmlessly against a protection field identical to mine. There were three more behind it and I ducked into cover next to the human as their return fire threatened to overwhelm my defences.

“We’re in trouble...” I whined. All around us, fleeing and panicking immigrants were being smashed to the ground by Hunter firepower.  Jenkins popped his head above the countertop and ducked again as a volley of shots targeted him. “Six of them” he said. “Ugly motherfuckers.”

I had to agree, as I fired a few suppressing shots around the corner. While judging any species by the aesthetic values of your own species doesn’t make a lot of sense, Hunters were ugly. Their skin was ceramic–white and wet, and seven eyes, each blinking independently, provided them with exceptional depth perception. On six legs, they were extremely stable, and their forelimbs were cybernetically fused into their heavy pulse guns, making disarming them impossible. These ones were wearing full military combat harness – my own light security harness was no match. Our only hope was the magazine of nervejam grenades, which I realised with a falling sensation of failure I had left in the locker.

“The grenades....” I swore.  “Only hope?” Jenkins asked. He was holding himself low and hunched, and I could see those dense high–gravity muscles tense and ready under his lightly–furred skin.

I nodded, fighting back the urge to excrete in my terror. If they took us alive, we would be food. By the time I realised that Jenkins had taken off at a flat sprint toward the locker, he was almost a third of the way there.

I knew what I had to do. The Hunters were turning to fire at him as I popped up from cover. They saw me coming but I put three rounds into one and its shield failed against the third. It collapsed, what passed for its face shattered by the impact, and I ducked as its fellows returned fire. One ignored me and kept firing at Jenkins, but he was so fast, so small, and the rounds smacked into the deck plating around him. He threw his feet out ahead of him and slid the last few strides to the locker. He popped up to his feet, looked at me as he raised his arm, and threw, accurately and much, much further than I could have thrown them.

Then a pulse round took him in the torso and flung him against the wall.

I had no time to mourn. I caught the grenades, slipped one from the cylindrical container, counted two light pulses from the indicator around its edge, and threw it toward the enemy on the third. A second later there was a flare of light and shrieking, but it was not enough. Two of the Hunters rampaged past their convulsing comrades, rushing me. I fired, but fear took my aim and the best I managed was a single round that impacted harmlessly against a shield before their return fire broke my own shielding and ruined my arm.

I collapsed, shaking from the pain. The Hunters trotted round the corner, chattering in their deep, guttural language that I couldn’t understand. I stared at their twin heavy pulse guns, too afraid even to close my eyes before the end.

It didn’t come. Instead something black, blue and brown hurtled into the flank of one of the alien warriors with a crunch and a hiss of pain. It staggered, collided with its comrade and fell.

Jenkins – somehow, impossibly alive despite taking a kinetic pulse round to the chest – wrestled very briefly with the Hunter, and then there was a horrible organic splitting noise, the hiss became a shriek, and the gun was in hands, blood and mangled meat dripping from the cybernetic interface.

The second Hunter snap–fired and Jenkins dropped the gun as the shot winged him. He didn’t seem to notice – instead he pounced and a second shot barely missed him before his forepaw lashed out, balled up into a hard knot of gravity–densened bone and flesh which he drove into the Hunter’s eye cluster.

It shrieked and flailed, swatting the human with its hindlimbs. He didn’t appear to care – instead he caught one of the flailing limbs, braced one of his own feet against the Hunter’s flank, and heaved with a roar. There was a grim tearing noise, and the Hunter’s leg came away. Its blood sprayed thick and fat through the air, coating the man from the death world but he ignored it. He didn’t spare the fallen alien a second glance as he charged at the lone survivor.

It was suicide. The Hunter had a clear shot and took it. Then it took a second. Then a third, and a fourth, and though every single one was on target, Jenkins just kept going, apparently completely impervious to impacts that would have pulped any other species.

Hunters don’t wear inter–species communication implants, but I didn’t need one to recognise the fear and panic it briefly had time to show before it was beaten to death with another Hunter’s severed leg. Jenkins just kept hitting it, again and again, snarling and shouting, ordering it to die and declaring improbable things about its parentage before finally he stopped and stepped away from the broken thing he had made, gulping down great shuddering breaths of what, to him, must have been very thin and dry air. Then he apparently lost the strength to stand and his forelimbs folded up underneath him. His head sank down until the pointed bottom of his jaw was resting against his torso.

I swallowed my pain and staggered to my feet. My arm dangled useless by my side and every slight movement was agony, but I had to know if he was alive.

The all–clear alarm sounded just before I reached him, and he moved in response to it. One of his eyes had swollen and was turning a dark red–purple. But the other blinked at me and his mouth curled upwards at the corners. I saw that one of his teeth was missing.

“Tough bastards.” he said, and spat bright red blood onto the Hunter corpse next to him.

I couldn’t help it. I had to laugh.

Humans don’t make good pets part 7

By guidosbestfriend

As a forewarning, I’m now moving into unplanned episodes. I’d been thinking about writing this story for about two weeks before I actually started, and had already planned out most of the major plot points up until what would later become HdMGP [VI]. The only solution to this is more ideas, which the comment section has contained in great magnitude. Thank you for all the support and encouragement.

Alien measurements are given in their human equivalents in [brackets], as are words with near human translations. Thoughts are italicized and enclosed by “+” symbols.

Tnnxz struggled against Ztrkx’s thug, but to no avail. The pirate’s arms seemed to be bands of steel, and showed no sign of strain or even exertion as Tnnxz writhed desperately against him. He watched, helpless, as another of Ztrkx’s cronies walked confidently over to Vtv and roughly grabbed his arm. He began to pull him towards the door. He only made it one step.

Cqcq’trtr, seemingly having sprouted invisible wings, flew at the pirate like a dervish, ripping the man away from Vtv and carrying him with momentum to the far wall, where the brief journey ended in a wet crunch. Now covered in gore, the nuisance – or savior, Tnnxz amended – used his new found avian abilities to spring atop the brute holding Xkkrk, killing him with his weight. Ztrkx had already begun drawing his weapon. A flash of pale tan which Tnnxz took several moments to realize had been Cqcq’trtr’s arm shot through Tnnxz’s captor’s neck, ripping it out completely.

The loss of this rather important biological asset seemed to be too much for Tnnxz’s restrainer, and he expired in a gout of blood, which, to Tnnxz’s disgust, covered him. Tnnxz found he didn’t mind at the moment, because at the same instant Tnnxz was covered in blood, he saw Ztrkx – who was considered an extremely quick draw but seemed slow compared to Cqcq’trtr – finally aim his pulse–pistol directly between the creatures eyes and remorselessly pull the trigger. The gun fired. Nothing happened. The pulse slammed into Cqcq’trtr’s face and he didn’t even move.

Tnnxz’s jaw dropped, until blood found its way into his mouth and popping eyes and he started spluttering while trying to clear his vision. +How had he survived that?!+ thought Tnnxz. +Never mind how he survived it, how did it not even touch him?+ Tnnxz knew of no biological asset which would have allowed any living thing to survive a pulse–pistol shot in the head at close range, let alone emerge completely unscathed, unless Cqcq’trtr’s entire body was that strong. Tnnxz finally managed to wipe his eyes clean, and opened them to an entirely new world. Ztrkx was no longer standing in front of him, but laid prone upon the ground [5 meters] from the doorway minus his head, which appeared to prefer the company of the floor rather than his neck.

Even more terrifying was Cqcq’trtr. He was charging three of Ztrkx’s henchmen. Tnnxz almost felt pity for them as they fired round after accurate round into the enraged monster, striking him multiple times in the chest and head. The only thing their precision achieved was further aggravation of Cqcq’trtr until he was a veritable blur as he moved down the hall, bellowing in hatred. The blur reached the group of panicked pirates, and a fine purple mist suddenly engulfed them.

Tnnxz suddenly remembered that the children were seeing this. Heck, He was seeing this. Tnnxz, with the help of Xkkrk and two of the older children, lifted the heavy door from where Cqcq’trtr had carefully placed it . . . on his own . . . and fitted it back into the door frame, pushing and shifting it until it stayed without assistance. Tnnxz quickly turned off the lights so the room’s occupants wouldn’t have to look at the staring eyes of Cqcq’trtr’s victims.

Even though the sights were hidden, the door, fitted imperfectly into the door frame, couldn’t block out the sounds. The screams of Ztrkx’s crew members and frantic pulse–pistol fire erupted from somewhere mid–ship, but was silenced nearly as soon as it had begun. Their ordeal wasn’t over yet, for several [seconds] after the screaming and shooting stopped the entire ship shuddered, its hull emitting an ear–splitting crack. The door, which had essentially been balancing in the door frame, was suddenly sucked flush back into position. Judging by the sounds coming from the other side there’d been a major hull breach.

“Why aren’t the emergency force–fields turning on?” asked Rccw, who was nearly old enough to be trained as an engineer himself.

“This ship’s old,” Explained Tnnxz, his face grim. “I’d be surprised if any of the emergency force–fields of even half of the security force–fields worked anymore.” The moment he finished speaking, however, the door was suddenly released from its death grip upon the frame and promptly fell to the floor for the second time that day. Tnnxz wished it hadn’t. The ship . . . well . . . was there.

It would have appeared disastrous enough with the copious amount of blood and entrails which seemed to have been thrown about the ship as though by a psychopathic interior decorator. With the hull breach having moved anything light that hadn’t been bolted down, however, Tnnxz’s precious Crixa seemed to be as dead as it’s one time co–owner, who now seemed to be attempting to introduce every [milliliter] of his blood to the floor as well. As Tnnxz picked his way through the wreckage the carnage only intensified. Cargo bay 9, which still bore the marks of Cqcq’trtr feeding himself, now appeared to be one of the cleanest areas of the ship.

The docking bay was by far the worst; The walls appeared to be more purple than grey. The starboard airlock had been reduced to scrap and the hull breach was being contained by +What the fuck?+ the medical bay door. Surrounded by it all, Cqcq’trtr stood in the middle of the docking bay slumped in slight fatigue, holding a Fusion Blade of all things, and, Tnnxz could have sworn, looking more pleased with himself then Tnnxz had ever seen him before.

Dear Journal,

Who the fuck am I kidding, I don’t have a journal. I’m just narrating this in my head and prefacing it with “Dear Journal” because it helps me keep my verb tense and sentence structures the same. Why am I even bothering to narrate this? I should just stop.

⋯

⋯

Ok Journal. I’m sorry. Pretty please come back?

Dear Journal,

I’m a strategic genius.

Oh, and I think I’m one of the good ones.

To answer that last question.

I swear I hadn’t meant to make the ship look like that. And really, if we were going to point the finger at anyone, then it would have mostly been Twinkle–Toes’ fault. I wasn’t the one that shot a Drilling Laser at the bulkhead of the ship which was keeping all the oxygen in! I may have been the reason that he pulled the trigger, but I can’t be blamed for other’s actions. I heard myself coming up with all these excuses as Severus surveyed my handiwork with the slack–jawed expression of a cow staring down a semi on the interstate.

My fears were unwarranted, however. I won’t recount all the disgustingly “heartfelt” details, but apparently the blue–giraffes figured out why I had done it. At least, I think Mama knew it right away and had to enlighten Severus. That guy did not have the intellect of his namesake. The worst part about their thanks was when I discovered that their equivalent of a hug involved twisting their neck around that of the fortunate recipient. My neck wasn’t quite as flexible as theirs, and when I tried to replicate the quarter twist movement they were demonstrating I ended up nearly crushing Severus’ windpipe between my chin and shoulder.

Once that misunderstanding was cleared up I settled for just standing there awkwardly while they twisted their necks around mine in a brief hug, looking as though I was on the receiving end of the strangest and most inefficient attempt to strangle someone. I considered adding a new definition to the term “necking” to UrbanDictionary when I got home.

Home. That thought sure put a damper on my mood. Once the blue–giraffe necking session was over, those who had been taking cover in the engine room began looking for survivors throughout the ship. I guess the weapons the pirates had been using weren’t that powerful even by alien standards +Thank. Goodness.+ and the only wounds that were fatal were those to the chest or head. There were still an alarming number of such wounds. Only a third of the crew had survived, and of those, half were unable to work. That made the task of restoring the ship back to working order nigh impossible.

Wouldn’t you know it, there seemed to be a bigger, better cargo ship docked to our port airlock whose previous owners showed a decided lack of interest in its continued use. Not wanting to waste such a generously given once–in–a–lifetime opportunity, the crew readily relocated into their newly acquired vessel. There was very little to move from our cargo bays, as most had been destroyed when their holding crates toppled over during the hull breach. Only a few commodities which were stored in such heavy crates that they had not been affected by the sudden redirection of atmospheric pressure had survived, as well as some oddly colored crates which Mama had seemed to fawn over.

There were so few things to move that even the few crew still able to work were able to transfer everything in two trips. I had been meaning to help, but by the time I saw how they used the larger versions of the crate–transportation–bed that Dink had used to move my bath, they were finished. I thought about pushing one of the blue–giraffes aside and forcing them to see me help working, but decided that if I was going to attack one of them in order to prove I was sapient I might as well just enslave them. I considered that for a moment too, but then rejected it out of principle.

Once they’d settled the wounded, transported the cargo, and completed logistics, the crew looked more tired than I was, which wasn’t saying much, so I’ll revise that by saying they looked darn tuckered out. They were done working for the day, and the crew that wasn’t sleeping or tending wounded were relaxing in the common lounge – just one of the creature–comfort rooms that the last ship had lacked. I walked in just as two blue–giraffes I had not yet had the pleasure of naming were sitting down at a table with a familiar silver clam between them.

Eager to watch real blue–giraffe chess players at work, I pulled a chair up to the table and stood on top of it so I was tall enough to see the game board from above. The two players – one which I named Dippy on account of his face’s natural expression, and the other Whip on account of his physique – at first looked at me in curiosity, then in amusement as I gazed upon the glowing board. They probably thought I was mesmerized by the pretty lights. Morons.

“Hey Fttfk, check it out. Cqcq’trtr’s mesmerized by the pretty lights!”

“Strrk, you’re a moron.”

The game started, and I could immediately see both players were better than Dink and Jiggles. Then I started seeing their mistakes. Whip seemed marginally decent, but Dippy was only better than Jiggles because he planned a couple moves ahead. Neither seemed to be using the board’s programming to their advantage, and both failed to deploy their pieces in formations utilizing even half their potential. It was a game of patterns, and these two were painting the board like toddlers given a year’s supply of crayons and a blank white wall. It was better than Dink and Jiggles, but it was their three year old crayon scribbles to Dink and Jiggles’ game play, which held the elegance of a chipmunk dunked in paint and then set free on an acre of acorns.

After they finished their first game, which took three times as long as it should have, they started a second game. Not being able to bear the thought of watching them blunder through another travesty of a game, I decided to enlighten them with a didactic demonstration. Flicking Dippy’s hand away – a slap might have injured him – which had been about to move perhaps the only piece on the board placed correctly, I tried to move a holo–token that was so far out of position that for all intents and purposes it might have well been dead.

My hand went right through the board without interacting with the piece. Apparently you had to be a blue–giraffe for the clam to allow you to interact with the pieces. Whip and Dippy were making odd noises and shaking in their seats. Laughing at me, were they? I looked Dippy in the eye, pointed to the offending piece, and then pointed to where it should go. His laughter increased. Exasperated, I grabbed his hand and forced it to move his piece.

That got his attention. Both idiots goggled at me as the board registered Dippy’s move and signaled Whip to take his. They couldn’t take the move back, so Whip moved his piece, looking at Dippy apologetically and clicking something. Dippy glanced at me nervously and slowly started to move his hand to the same piece which didn’t need moving. I grabbed it again and forced it to another woefully placed piece. Now the players were getting mad, clicking at me in anger and making shooing motions with there hands, and there I stood, not understanding a word of it. Whip took his turn again, and the moment he finished Dippy flung his hand towards one of the pieces I had just moved, trying to put it back out of position.

He wasn’t fast enough, and I grabbed his hand before it could touch the board, forcing it to do my bidding. Dippy went into a frenzy, and Whip made a motion as though to close the clam. I blocked his hand, then glared at him, willing him to take his turn. Anger now replaced with fear, Whip complied. Not even bothering to let go of Dippy’s hand, I took his next few turns for him. Then a hex lit up. I had barely managed to get the bare minimum of Dippy’s pieces into what I thought to be a decent position, but the results were noticeable. The hex was a full three spaces closer to several of Dippy’s pieces than it ever had ever been. Whip and Dippy blinked. Whip’s pieces were out of position, and I easily managed to get a piece onto the hex before he could stop me. I just needed to do that 6 more times before I could win.

Dippy’s reluctance to allow me to borrow the use of his appendage evaporated, and I was able to move my pieces without hindrance. Six more hexes lit up, and for each one I managed to get there before Whip could stop me. It really wasn’t that hard of a game. So long as I had enough pieces to narrow down the possibilities, I could reasonably guess which hex would light up next. After I moved Dippy’s hand in its first victory move, I looked into their dumbfounded faces. “One of these days I’m going to introduce you to a real strategy game. It’s called Chess.”

Humans don’t make good pets part 8

by guidosbestfriend

Alright, we're back and, well, not refreshed after yesterday, but it's been long enough so let's get back to work. The ideas and suggestions after last episode have been overwhelming and incredible, thank you!

This episode brought to you by: /u/Elyandarin, the conversation between /u/Folly_Inc and /u/TheJack38 in episode [V], another fierce biological debate by /u/Cerberus0225, /u/f3lbane, /u/someguynamedted, /u/Henghast, /u/Ekaros, /u/Sp4ceTurkey, /u/Aresmar, and /u/Maltoron in [VII] (Whew, sorry if I missed anyone in that debate), /u/I_hug for a message I did read but did not respond (sorry about that, consider this my response), and finally /u/Jalapenyobuisness, who contributed the most in the way of actual story quantity inspired for this installment and the next. (<-- that's all one sentence)

In one of the upcoming sections I am sorry if I messed up any of the technical biological details. I am not a bio major.

Alien measurements are given in their human equivalents in [brackets], as are words with near human translations. Thoughts are italicized and enclosed by "+" symbols.

"Hey Fttfk, did you just get your ass kicked at your own game by Cqcq'trtr?" Strrk asked, stupidly.

+No, he just decided that he wanted to hold your hand and you managed to find enough sapience in that empty skull of yours to beat me all on your own. Of course Cqcq'trtr beat me.+ thought Fttfk. He couldn't believe the words had come out of his mind's metaphysical mouth, but Cqcq'trtr had indeed managed to beat him in warrens. Not only beat him, but completely destroy him. Fttfk, not for the first time, considered quickly and quietly silencing Strrk before he could tell anyone else.

Too late. Strrk's idiocy, easily outpacing all rational thought, prompted him to open his mouth and shout "Everyone, Fttfk just lost. And he did it to Cqcq'trtr!" If there was one thing that could be said about Strrk, it was that he was honest. He really didn't have the sense to be anything else. So when he said something, even something as ridiculous as his last utterance, everyone came to see what he had misunderstood to believe something as ridiculous as Fttfk losing to Cqcq'trtr.

The board-emitter, seeming to revel in Fttfk's defeat, cheerfully started another game, beeping the signal to begin the torment. Fttfk could have sworn that beep sounded like the maniacal laughter of a slave reveling in the downfall of its master. He mentally kicked the emitter, which didn't seem to care in the slightest about his imagined abuses. The crew members relaxing in the newly acquired ship's common lounge gathered around the odd trio encircling the board-emitter.

Fttfk considered not starting the game. After all, the first move was his, and he could plead exhaustion. Glancing at the numerous spectators, though, he realized he couldn't turn back now, or else everyone would think he had somehow lost to Strrk. After all, how could Cqcq'trtr have beaten him? Almost trying to answer that question himself, he moved his first piece. The game spiraled into the abyss from there. Cqcq'trtr demonstrated even more skill with the predatory pieces than he had with those of the prey. Nearly every turn Fttfk lost the maximum number of pieces he was able to lose a turn, resulting in one of the most expedient and humiliating games in Fttfk's memory.

As Cqcq'trtr, through a Strrk who was all too happy to give up the need to think, mercilessly exterminated Fttfk's last few pieces, Fttfk looked into Cqcq'trtr's eyes and saw for the first time the intelligence lurking beneath, parsing together the most efficient and ruthless way to annihilate any remaining chance of Fttfk's victory. Others in the crew were noticing it as well. As the oldest, albeit grouchiest person on board, Fttfk wondered how he'd never seen it before. Even worse, however, he wondered what this creature would do. Not only to this ship and everyone aboard, but to the galaxy, once his species reached the stars.

Fttfk immediately stifled the overly preachy and humorless thought. Damn, he was getting wishy-washy in his old age.

+I'll have to watch out for tha-+

"You ok Strrk?" asked Rccw, interrupting Fttfk's cautionary thought. He looked at Strrk, who had been growing progressively quiet as the game had progressed. He had just assumed that Strrk had finally started realizing what Cqcq'trtr's actions implied, but as he looked at him, he could see there was something wrong. Strrk's eyes had started to water, although he could have been crying over his ill-fated genetics. His nose was beginning to run as though clearing the remnants his brain had left behind upon its departure, and he continued to clear his throat with a vigor that suggested he had stuck an entire Dizi rat down there. Then it got worse.

Dear Journal,

I'm a walking petri dish.

From Earth.

After I finished the first game, Whip looked stunned and sour at the same time, but he'd looked sour since I'd first laid eyes on him, so I think he was just stunned. I smiled at him - it was not a smirk; I'm not that kind of guy - saying, "Care for another game?" I don't think he did, but Dippy click-shouted something excitedly which brought everyone in the lounge over to our table, trapping Whip into another match as the clam ruthlessly started another game. I dominated the board from the first turn, and the game was over in a mere 5 minutes. I smiled as I heard shocked and incredulous clicks from the onlookers; at least, that's what I hoped those clicks were. My thoughts left the game and surrounding blue-giraffes when a sound like that of a cat with an entire mouse and its extended family lodged in its throat made me glance back at my unwilling assistant.

Dippy looked awful. He hadn't said much, and I had assumed this to mean he had accepted his fate, but now he was hacking, sniffing, wiping his eyes, and trying to click at the same time. He had started to shake, making him look even more like a heroin addict. I let go of his hand as he got up, watching as he tottered towards the exit in the direction of the living quarters, when his entire body convulsed. At first I thought he was pitching backwards, head-first, perhaps attempting a back-flip. He suddenly whipped his head forward, which had nearly been on his back, and expelled what was unmistakably a colossal blue-giraffe sneeze, barely managing to avoid slamming his head into the ground in front of him.

This was followed by a second sneeze, and a third, each time throwing his head from one extreme to the other. At first I hoped that he was merely expressing his previously repressed passion for heavy metal, but as sneeze after sneeze racked his body, I thought his obsession had perhaps gone too far. I didn't think he'd survive a metal concert, anyway. The others watching apparently seemed to be of the same opinion. Several rushed over to Dippy, who I quickly renamed Drippy on account of his nose's desire to join a marathon. Helping him stand, as he'd just fallen to his knees in rapture for his love of music, several yet unnamed blue-giraffes led him toward the direction of the sickbay.

"Odd that. So, about this game you guys have here. Do we need to play another one, or have I made my point?"

The doors to the medical bay opened, admitting Rccw, Nxt, and Qcpt, supporting a weak-kneed and wheezing Strrk between them. He made a terrible spitting sound and his head exploded into motion, first flung back in a massive inhalation, then whipping forward in an arc and slamming into the ground in front of him where he left an imprint of his face in snot and tears.

"What happened to him?!" Asked Xkkrk, helping the other three carry the shaking Strrk to the primary medical bed, which had a built in bio-medical scanner. Xkkrk had been so excited that she would finally be able to see every cell and pathogen in any organism able to fit on the bed, and now she had a chance to use it, although she would have wished she did not have to try it out on one of her own crew mates.

"We have no idea. Cqcq'trtr . . . " Xkkrk inwardly groaned when they said that name in relation to the current emergency, but didn't interrupt " . . . was destroying Fttfk in a game of warrens . . . " Now she did interrupt.

"Excuse me? I misheard."

"No. You didn't. Cqcq'trtr played Fttfk a few minutes ago. Not only did he somehow know the rules of the game, but he played to a degree I'd never thought possible. The game was over in about [5 minutes]. Fttfk never had a chance. I don't even want to think about what this means."

Xkkrk did. It meant they'd been horribly, irreparably wrong. It meant Cqcq'trtr wasn't an animal, but a thinking, sapient, though perhaps primitive, being they'd merely been treating as a pet. Tricks, behaviors, quirks, those could be taught by a persevering previous master. A game like warrens - especially warrens - was a game of abstract thought and advanced forethinking, something no animal possessed. Crap.

Strrk seemed to be having a seizure, so Xkkrk moved the matter to her "Do-immediately-once-someone-isn't-dying" list, which had become alarmingly full in the last [few hours]. The bio-medical scanner came online, and within seconds had analyzed every cell in his body. It also immediately noticed the unknown organism rampaging through Strrk's body. It alerted Xkkrk to its discovery. Xkkrk almost wished it hadn't. It was a virus, but unlike any virus she'd ever seen before. Most of the viruses throughout the universe, though easily contracted, were fought off in a matter of [weeks] if not [days]. Most viruses weren't like this virus though.

It seemed to have two layers of protection for its destructive RNA; a capsid, though composed of proteins Xkkrk had only seen in some of the strongest bio-materials, and a second layer of what appeared to be a phospholipid bilayer, as if it were a cell! It also seemed to have three times as many glycoproteins on its surface, as though it thought it would be destroyed in seconds if it couldn't find a cell to bond to.

"I'm an engineer, Xkkrk, not a microbiologist. I didn't understand a word you just said." Xkkrk hadn't realized she had been speaking out loud.

"Fine. Say your standard virus is a gricka" she said, referencing an almost galactically known predator which had been taken from a deathworld [millennia] ago when the galaxy was still largely unexplored. No one remembered which deathworld it had been anymore, and the gricka had changed dramatically as it had been introduced to other planets either on purpose or by accident. It was a majestic beast with a sleek body, pointed ears, and a dexterous tail with which it could display nearly sapient levels of emotion. It was even kept as a house pet by those who liked exotic and dangerous beasts. If you managed to domesticate it, it was one of the most rewarding pets due to its soothing, rumbling purr it would produced if you mastered the art of petting it; a skill in and of itself, although all who owned them said the first lesson was to never touch the belly unless it was presented to you, and even then with extreme caution. Indeed, the gricka hated having its belly exposed to the point that if you dropped it with its back towards the ground, it would twist itself so as to land on its feet. Some people went so far as to say gricka always landed on their feet. Superstition only.

"This virus would be a gricka in military-grade body armor with an autonomous heavy pulse-turret mounted on its back." The room fell silent with this ominous description.

"Will he live?" asked Rccw after [several long seconds].

"I don't have the needed facilities here. We'll need to get him to the nearest settled planet. I might be able to slow its progress down. It would help if I knew how he contracted it." She looked at the three not attempting to eviscerate themselves through their mouths.

"I think he got it from Cqcq'trtr," Nxt said. "He was holding onto Strrk's hand during the game with Fttfk since he couldn't directly interact with the game board. Right after the game Strrk was acting all fidgety and then started throwing his head around like a madman."

Xkkrk could have guessed as much. Not that Cqcq'trtr had been holding Strrk's hand, but that it had come from Cqcq'trtr. Anything unbelievable seemed to originate with him. "Bring him in here. If he's immune to this plague then we may be able to see how to fight it or even cure it. You should be safe from the virus so long as you don't touch him." She suddenly remembered with a sinking feeling the way in which those whom had been protected by Cqcq'trtr in the engine room had thanked him. "Get Cqcq'trtr in here now, I think he may have infected quite a few more people than Strrk."

Her worst fears were realized when Piiqrrt stumbled into the medical bay, dry retching as he attempted to spew the contents of his stomach which appeared to have already been emptied down his front. "What's the matter!?" Xkkrk asked with growing horror. Piiqrrt opened his mouth and such a disgusting smell reached her nose that she too vomited all over Piiqrrt's front.

She had Strrk's caretakers move him to a nearby bed as Piiqrrt took his place on the bio-medical scanner. It soon revealed that an unknown form of frighteningly durable bacteria had invaded his tongue and beneath his gum line, giving his breath a monstrous odor. She had never before seen a bacteria that did this. Of course she knew hundreds of pathogens which lived in the mouth, but she had never come across one which made its victim never want to open their mouth again.

She was relieved when Cqcq'trtr was escorted into the medical bay and placed himself on the bio-medical scanner after Piiqrrt had been laid next to Strrk. Not wanting to be distracted with his incredible physiology, she set the scanner to search exclusively for dangerous microorganisms on par with those infecting Strrk and Piiqrrt. The computer would beep when it had found one, if Cqcq'trtr was carrying any more. She initiated the scan, and the computer immediately beeped. It kept beeping.

It turned out I hadn't made my point. After Whip left it seemed every blue-giraffe and his second cousin thrice removed wanted to play a game with me. I happily obliged. Then I just kind of obliged. Then I started unhappily obliging. It was rather annoying playing games with beings that seemed to have the strategic capacity of a hamster. After about the tenth game in so many minutes, the three who had helped Drippy out of the room reentered and clicked at me, motioning for me to follow them. Not needing anymore of an excuse, I brutally ended the game I was playing, hopped off my seat, waved goodbye to my most recent unwilling assistant, and followed Drippy's entourage out of the lounge.

They brought me to the ships sickbay and motioned me to get on the largest bed in the room. I looked at the other beds and saw Drippy. His sneezes had become even more alarming and exaggerated. Even as I watched, his chest heaved and his entire upper body skyrocketed off the bed. His head hit the ceiling with a dull thud and he collapsed on the bed, knocked unconscious. Stiffling my laughter I looked to another figure near Drippy and recognized Jiggles. He seemed to be crying, two variations of sick on the front of his robe.

"What's wrong with him?" I asked, more for my own benefit than anyone else's. Jiggles seemed to want to talk to me though. He opened his mouth, and I added a puddle of my own to the foot of his bed. His breath REEKED. I had had some nasty cases of morning breath before, but halitosis had this giraffe by the balls. More as an excuse to back away from Jiggles, I quickly hopped on the indicated bed. Mama Giraffe, who was standing nearby, began punching buttons on a console I couldn't see. The whirr of a mechanism in motion emanated from the bed at the same time a faint but rapid beeping began to sound from Mama's console.

I could tell by the light of the console playing over Mama's face that it was gathering some form of information from me. Her face began to pale. "That bad eh?" I chuckled nervously. She looked up from her console and my eyes locked with hers. Oh. Shit.

Previous seven

Next nine part one

All chapters

"We don't take ourselves seriously here at HdMGP Inc., but gosh darn it we are going to make sure our plot points are semi-realistic. George, what's on the itinerary for the next episode?"

"The human which was abducted by aliens and kept as a pet until he showed them his intelligence by playing an alien chess game and has just infected multiple members of the ships crew with trifling human diseases in a humorous manner will now sprout wings and fly while fireworks go off behind him and the American national anthem plays from a 2000 piece orchestra."

"This is why we pay you George."

Humans don’t make good pets part 9.1

By guidosbestfriend

Tnnxz was happy. Why wouldn’t he be? He had his old ship, it wasn’t being destroyed by an alien they had picked up off of a Corti zoological science vessel, he had lots of money, and his life was simple once again. Then someone woke him up. After he learned why Xkkrk had done such a cruel thing, he revised his last thought and assumed he’d entered a nightmare.

“We need to set course for the nearest category 10 medical station and push the engines to their limits or else everyone on this ship is doomed,” she clicked. Excellent. Great way to start the day. Why couldn’t they all be like this? Several [days] ago, Tnnxz would have asked hundreds of questions before he even considered a detour so far out their way, but now he leapt out of bed without a word and sent a com–message to the bridge to find the nearest category 10 medical station. Category 10’s were few and far between, and none were currently under construction as far as Tnnxz knew. They had been built during the Robalix war [20 years] ago, and had been built under the assumption that the Robalins had managed to create the [apocalyptic] bio–weapon they had been attempting to perfect before they lost the war, an inevitability unless they had actually succeeded in creating it. They had been defeated before they managed to finish, but the category 10’s still stood as a monument to the terror the Robalix weapon had instilled.

Medical facilities given the designation of a category 10 were specifically made to treat and study subjects infected with a disease or diseases or plague proportions. Not only were they possessed of some of the most advanced microbiological laboratories, provided by the Corti, and an arsenal of their most potent injections, the facility could also detach any room from its main hull if containment of a disease was breached. Each floor was also able to detach from the main station, fly a few hundred kilometers, then self–destruct. It was a station that assumed that if you were a patient you were essentially already dead, and the only thing you had left to do in your life was offer scientists a chance to study your disease and prevent others from sharing your fate. This was why category 10’s had another name. Death Hospitals.

Only after he received word from the helm that the new course was set did Tnnxz turn to Xkkrk. “Don’t tell me. I think I can guess at this point. A plague has suddenly descended upon our ship and infected nearly all of our remaining crew. This plague is unlike any we’ve seen before and exceeds our worst microbiological nightmares, or at least yours – I don’t have any of that nature – and we have none other to thank than our illustrious guest who can’t seem to decide if he wants to destroy our ship, splatter it with gore, splatter it with gore while saving our lives, or kill us with a disease even the Robalins would have envied.”

“Correct on nearly all accounts. Only half the able–bodied crew have demonstrated symptoms, and we aren’t suffering from just one plague. Those infected so far have shown symptoms of five different epidemics, but the computer has identified more than 794 dangerous micro–organisms on our plague ship of a guest. The only reason we weren’t infected to this point is due to a joint effort of our old ship’s biofilters and what appears to be the remnants of the Corti front–line inoculation. The diagnostic reports we still have which inspired us to cut it loose and take this one show that the biofilters were on the verge of failing when we left. It seems they’d been absorbing so many foreign microbes they were unable to kill that they were becoming bacterial nurseries as the pathogens had started colonies on them. The only reason we didn’t notice it is the early alert system had broken a while ago, like most of that ship, and we didn’t notice it among all the other major systems failures Ztrkx’s attack caused. I doubt this ship’s bio–filters will last longer than a few days, and they’re only able to stop airborne contraction of the diseases. Too many crew members have come into contact with Cqcq’trtr for that to even be an issue. The inoculation the Corti gave Cqcq’trtr when they abducted him seems to have worn off sometime last night, which is why we’re just now experiencing these problems.”

The Corti front–line inoculation – usually just called “the inoculation” – given to all life–forms upon their unwilling admittance into a Corti science vessel was an ingenious biological invention. Rather than kill all microbial life forms within a subject, which would affect any experiment’s results and more often than not hurt or even kill the subject, the inoculation blocked the pathogenic and viral contagion factors. In viruses the inoculation would bind to its glycoproteins, stopping its ability to affect a cell. For bacteria it used a bio–engineered virus of its own to insert a kill switch into the reproduction process of the bacteria. Every time the pathogen would undergo mitosis, the parent cell would be killed the moment it split, ensuring the bacteria colony wouldn’t be able to expand beyond its current population size.

The inoculation even included a phage which temporarily edited the genetic instructions of a subject’s immune system so it would not take advantage of the sudden pathogenic and viral neutralities and completely clear them from its system. The only problem was that the inoculation had to be re–administered every [other day] or else it would begin to fail, completely vanishing after [three or four days]. It seemed Cqcq’trtr had reached that point. Tnnxz let out a long sigh.

Dear Journal,

I have become Death, the destroyer of worlds.

At least, for worlds composed entirely of blue–giraffes.

Which sucks, by the way.

The Death thing, not the blue–giraffes.

Not that I wouldn’t mind being back on Earth, you know.

Mama’s console was still beeping rapidly when she hurriedly pressed a button that was apparently the machine’s power button. The console turned off mid beep. Her actions and the near panicked way in which she completed them did nothing to abate my growing unease at the situation; especially her hitting of the power button. You don’t do that to your computer unless it’s done something horrendous, such as freeze up or murder your family. As it hadn’t frozen up, I assumed it had delivered news of imminent death, the assumption of which seemed to be confirmed by Mama’s actions. I looked about the room.

Several more blue–giraffes had entered during my examination, and they seemed in similar if not worse condition than Drippy, still unconscious, and Jiggles, who also appeared to have fainted, although I couldn’t tell if he’d intentionally stopped breathing so those passing wouldn’t add to the puddle at his bedside or dehydration had gotten to him. The newest admittances appeared ready to faint as well. Several of them, children, appeared to have what Jiggles had gotten, which hadn’t improved the smell by the slightest. Several other adults, including the unwilling assistant I had used when Drippy had left, seemed to be following in his footsteps and expressing their adoration for heavy metal even as they were shown to their beds.

One was being his own independent blue–giraffe, exhibiting traits from neither of the two fads gripping the crew – DeathBreath and Death Metal Enthusiasts – but rather was starting his own trend: Acne from Hell. At least I hoped it was Acne. I was pretty sure I was the reason for this current hullabaloo, and was infecting the crew with diseases and conditions that I was immune to. As such, I sure as hell hoped I hadn’t given this hipster–blue–giraffe smallpox. If Drippy had fallen into a coma – he looked like he had – from a common cold, I didn’t want to think about what a real disease would do to these poor souls.

Newly named Pimples seemed to be screaming, and, upon seeing him, I think I might have joined him. His face and arms were the stuff of nightmares, completely covered in the kind of zits that you go to the hospital to get speared by a professional. He looked like he’d been on the receiving end of an attack from Satan’s personal bee collection; I’m sure they’re one of that jerk’s favorite pets right after wasps and other nopes.

Drippy’s entorage, which seemed to have been recruited by Mama as traffic control, tried to show Pimples to a bed of his own away from the DeathBreaths and Death Metal Enthusiasts, but he cried out in pain the moment he tried to sit down on the bed. I felt sorry for the bloke, but was simultaneously impressed that he’d completely given himself over to this new trend. I’d never known anyone to give up their sitting–parts to the normal variation of Acne, let alone the Acne from Hell. Eventually Pimples just stood by his bed, propping himself against it with his hand, although even that had suffered his newfound infatuation.

Mama, by way of hand gestures, motioned me to a bed farthest away from the trenders. I walked over to it and hopped on, looking at her for more instructions. She grabbed a syringe the same shape as the Corti, and I immediately began to feel trepidation. My unease waned somewhat when she put a small amount of clear red liquid in the syringe, but I still backed up when she approached me with it. She started clicking at me in a no–nonsenese “I’m–your–mom–and–you’re–going–to–do–what–I–say–just–because–now–don’t–talk–back–to–me–mister” kind of way. It wasn’t the mom–tone she used which persuaded me to allow her to approach me with the syringe, however. It was the fact that she hadn’t said it to me in a condescending way, as though she were talking to an animal. She knew!

She stuck the needle into my arm. As I watched the red fluid enter my bloodstream, I began to feel a little drowsy. That was it. “Was that supposed to put me to sleep?” I asked. She seemed about as confused as I was, and got another dose of the red stuff, this time filling the needle half–way, which I estimated to be about 20cc. She injected that into me, and the drowsiness increased, but I was still awake. Exasperated, She filled the syringe to my estimated 40cc and stuck that into my arm as well, which was starting to protest. That knocked me out, albeit slowly. Before my vision faded completely to black I saw Mama hit a button near my bed which erected a shining blue wall of energy around my bed.

As Xkkrk left Tnnxz’s room, which he had exited a moment before her, heading for the bridge, she thought back to the amount of sedative Cqcq’trtr had required before he’d finally fallen into unconsciousness. She had made the assumption he would require more than a Vzk’tk, and had readied twice the dose she normally would have. He’d sloughed the double dose as though it were nothing. The quadruple dose had had similarly minimal effects. She’d finally gotten him down after applying eight times the recommended dose, for a total of fourteen times the usual amount. That much sedative was enough to easily kill four Vzk’tk, and probably a few more if you were careful with your administrations.

At least he was behind a dedicated security field. It wasn’t a true quarantine field – those were hugely expensive and were only on the more advanced mercy ships – but Ztrkx’s engineer seemed to have done a good job, and the security–field–turned–quarantine–field would hopefully stop some of the larger pathogens and all of the multicellular parasites the bio–scanner had detected. Remembering the scanner’s findings after it had scanned Cqcq’trtr sent another shiver down Xkkrk’s spine. How could anything live with so many plagues living inside them.

It seemed her crew were only infected by the weakest and most versatile of diseases Cqcq’trtr carried. She had refrained from telling Tnnxz of the extent that those on this ship were screwed, but now, with a moment to herself, she decided to be honest. The diseases Cqcq’trtr carried, if discovered by a species of ill–intent, could be used to create bio–weapons capable of scouring nearly all life from the galaxy. When Cqcq’trtr’s species discovered FTL propulsion, the galaxy would need quarantine suits just to interact with them, unless a species like the Corti came up with an injection which could kill off all of the microbes carried by Cqcq’trtr’s people.

Maybe that was why the Corti had been studying him. After all, they knew more about up and coming sapient beings than any other space–faring species, and she doubted the Corti, with their expanded intelligence and advanced biological technology, would have thought Cqcq’trtr another dumb animal like she and the rest of the crew had oh so foolishly assumed.

Or perhaps they had been trying to develop a new technology. As worrying as Cqcq’trtr’s microbial abundance had been, it was nothing compared to his immune system. Xkkrk, barely able to believe it herself, had restarted the bio–scanner to ensure it wasn’t making stuff up for the fun of it. It hadn’t been. An immune system consisting of Eucaryotic cells which literally ate offending cells!? What the fuck!!? Vzk’tk admittedly had one of the weaker immune systems of the galaxy, but it was still of the standard bacteriophage plus viral adaptation model seen almost exclusively in the [Milky way]. Bacteria which infected Xkkrk’s body would soon find their genetic code under a viral assault. The only difference was that the bacteriophage would inject the offending pathogen with RNA which would not only reproduce more of the phage but also neutralize its dangerous characteristics. Offending viruses, on the other hand, would have their way for several days, until her cells modified their genetic markers to which the virus’s glycoproteins would bind, making her immune to it. She doubted that would work for Cqcq’trtr’s virus, as it seemed to mutate too quickly.

Compared to Cqcq’trtr’s immune system, though, the Vzk’tk and indeed nearly all known sophant’s immune systems seemed childish, if such a word could be applied to immune systems. Xkkrk shuddered at the thought of what would happen if one of Cqcq’trtr’s t–cells found its way into another being and then decided that being was a disease in need of destruction. Squaring her shoulders, Xkkrk walked back into the medical bay, looking about the mayhem which greeted her. It had gotten worse.

Humans don’t make good pets part 9.2

By guidosbestfriend

Several hours later I awoke from the unconsciousness Mama’s poor little sedative had worked so hard to achieve. The situation in the sickbay had somehow managed to fall further down the declivity it had started down when I had been sedated. Pimples had gained a sizable hipster following, a group of which now stood in a circle around their leader, whimpering in pain as they suffered for their beliefs. DeathBreath was having membership problems, for which my nose was thankful, and only one more had joined Jiggles ranks. Drippy’s Death Metal Enthusiasts were by far the most popular, having nearly doubled in size, head banging away in what I hoped was euphoria. Two new groups had also formed during my forced but by no means unwelcome rest.

The first new group seemed to have liked the sneezing aspect of the Death Metal Enthusiasts, but not the head–banging part of it. They were all lying on their beds, hacking away like walruses during mating season. Their coughs seemed to be just that, rather than the head banging variation of the Death Metal Enthusiasts sneezes, and their heads were staying decidedly unbanged as they lay on their sides, attempting to attract each other with the lush tones of their sensual barks. Or maybe they were just dying. It was one of the two, so I decided to go with the happier option. Mama would find a way to fix them up, because I had no ideas. I’d probably infect someone with the black plague if I tried to help. Judging by how they were holding up to the smaller infections, if I did that they probably wouldn’t show any symptoms, just go from perfectly healthy then keel over dead, or maybe they’d spontaneously explode. I wasn’t going to find out, so I turned my attention to the second of the new fads.

I think the other group was composed of masochists. It looked like their founder, whoever he had been, had seen the other groups and decided none of them featured enough suffering for his tastes, so he started his own that outclassed the others in every way, juxtaposing explosive vomiting, diarrhea, extreme fatigue, heavy sweating, and, unless I misinterpreted the reason some of them were shaking, chills. I think they also had the worst kind of sore throat you can get, unless they were massaging their throats because they thought it would help stop their vomiting. This group truly was the most pitiful of the recent cults.

Several of their members had succumb to the crushing fatigue of their faction, but this hadn’t stopped the other characteristics of their chosen people, and they slept, wheezing, as their overactive GI systems spewed forth their essence where it could begin its olfactory assault upon my senses. I took a moment to step outside of my humorous defense mechanism to take an honest and objective look at the scene around me.

It wasn’t good. The crew was in a bad shape and I doubted they would last much longer. The worst part of it was that this wasn’t something I could help them with. I wasn’t a microbiologist, or even a scientist, or even a smart person. I didn’t know anything about fighting off diseases. The only thing I could protect them from were physical attacks. I felt helpless. This was the first time I’d been helpless since I had escaped the grey Yodas, and I hated the feeling. I wanted to punch something. That wouldn’t have helped anyone, though, so I settled for punching the diseases with my imagination. I don’t think it did anything.

The sickbay had a window, and my attention was drawn to it when something other than the endless void of space flashed by. The window was too small, and I was too far from it, but I could see it was the hull of some other spacefaring object, whether it was station or ship I couldn’t tell. 30 seconds later the ship lurched in what I had come to recognize as our ship docking with something. Without another word Mama and the Drippy’s entourage, which amazingly hadn’t contracted any of the factions beliefs, began helping cultists out of the sickbay. Soon I was the only one left, my energy field glowing around my bed.

“Thanks guys, I didn’t want to leave this room anyway!” No one heard. I tested the energy field around my bed. It felt as solid as a wall. I pushed against it experimentally. It didn’t budge. I threw my shoulder against it and achieved the same result. Not wanting to throw my all at it, I sat dejectedly on my bed and waited. It wasn’t long before Mama came into my room, wearing a grey hazmat suit. I felt a little uneasy, but understood why she was doing it. It just made me feel like I had stayed a little too long in Chernobyl or something similar. She lowered my energy field and motioned me to follow.

We walked through the eerily quiet and empty corridors of the ship, which satisfied my curiosity as to why it had taken so long. I really was a plague ship. Now I knew how the rats who had either carried or chaperoned the black plague around the world had felt, and let me tell you now with my new found expertise. It sucked. When we arrived at the docking bay I could see by benefit of a bay window that we were docked to a large station about the size of a football stadium. It was the sterile white of a hospital.

Entering through the airlock, it was like no hospital I’d seen. Every room was a calming shade of white and blue, which tried unsuccessfully to distract from the seemingly unnecessary amounts of air vents set into the ceiling, or the large glowing blue columns on either side of the walls which hummed with energy which made my skin tingle as I passed them. Paired with Mama’s hazmat suit, I assumed the columns offered another level of sterility to the environment. We walked into large room where I stopped a moment to stare. It was huge, and filled with such an array of alien equipment that I couldn’t even begin to parse together the reasons for a single one, except for the stations which seemed to feature alien microscopes.

The microscopes were my only clue that this was a massive research facility, specifically one dedicated to studying dangerous diseases, since every xeno in the room was wearing a hazmat suit. The diversity of the lifeforms in the room was another reason I paused. There were so many. The suits made it difficult to see the differences, but the heights and breadths alone were enough to show me the differences. Most of the xenos seemed to be taller than me, and nearly all were as spindle limbed as the blue–giraffes. There even appeared to be another variation of blue–giraffes amongst the researchers, except these blue–giraffes were taller and moved with a greater grace and elegance than my new family members, if grace and elegance could be ascribed to four meter high beings with two more arms and legs than the version I was used to.

I also noted that there didn’t seem to be any of the common form of blue–giraffes among the researchers except for patients. What that implied I didn’t know, but I remarked upon it nonetheless. I didn’t stare for long as Mama ushered me around the room and into another about the size of the sickbay back on the ship, except this room appeared to only have a bed for one, and the rest was occupied by an array of equipment which I could only assume was to be used to ascertain the extent of my destructive nature.

I didn’t need to be told where I was going to be staying, so I walked over to my new bed and hopped on. I immediately leapt off again. Despite the fact that he was wearing a hazmat suit, it was unmistakable as a grey Yoda walked into my room carrying a tray filled with an array of syringes filled with different colored fluids, one of which I quickly noticed was a familiar shade of blue. I quickly shot a glance at Mama. Why wasn’t she worried, or afraid? Why didn’t she shout in alarm as that creature entered the room? I doubted I’d been abducted by rogue scientists, so assumed they had worked with their species knowledge and consent. Didn’t Mama know what kind of monsters these things were?

Even if she wasn’t going to act, I sure wasn’t going to let that thing work over me as I lay prone on a bed, especially with the blue syringe of death. I wasn’t as adverse to having it get close to me when I was on my feet. In fact, I welcomed it, which was why upon seeing its ugly oversized alien monster head I not only leapt off the bed but leapt off the bed in its general direction, bellowing as I shot past Mama and landing mere feet in front of the Yoda. He didn’t seem to have the abilities of his namesake, and only managed a pathetic dry squeak as I flung my hand towards his head in an open palmed slam which hit his face plate, shattering it and flinging him three meters where he landed heavily on the floor and slid for another four.

I threw myself after him, preparing to finish the job when an energy field sprung into existence in front of me, which I promptly slammed into and confirmed that it was as solid as it felt. I wildly looked around, not wanting to lose my advantage while the Yoda was down, well, I didn’t really need more of an advantage but I didn’t want to make him wait. That would be impolite, and I try to be courteous when I go about revenge, I mean, self–protection. This wasn’t about revenge, and if it was then I guess I’d think about it later. Right now my blood was up and I wanted that Yoda gone.

My eyes landed on the blue column in the wall which was lined up with another on the wall which the energy field made a straight line in between. I decided this meant they were the emitters responsible for the field and leapt towards the closest one. Half of it was on my side of the field on half on the other side. I supposed that it had been created to keep diseases and other pathogens contained, which is why it was ill–suited to prevent my hand from hitting it and smashing its casing.

I probably should have thought about just what an energy field emitter would exactly contain in order to be emitting an energy field, because it broke, releasing a massive amount of force which picked me up and threw me across the room, slamming me into the base of my bed. On the upside it took the field down and I was alive, so I figured it was a win win situation. Dazed, I ran drunkenly towards the Yoda, who seemed to be unconscious as he hadn’t moved yet was still breathing. I was halfway there when I was slammed in the side by what felt like George Foreman coming to give me something other than a sandwich. I had been unsteady enough that the unexpected blow had knocked me from my feet, and I rolled with the blow – a move which had saved me from enough cracked heads that it had become habit – coming up in a crouch facing my new attacker.

It was Mama. From the pounding of the blood in my ears I hadn’t heard her shout–clicking, but now she released a torrent unlike anything I’d ever heard from her. She wore what looked like an alien bullet proof vest into which was plugged an alien ray gun, significantly larger than the one the blue–giraffe pirates had used. I wondered wryly for a moment if she’d just tried to kill me, but then ignored the thought when she did not continue shooting and instead put the gun down to allow her the use of her other hand so she could gesticulate even more in her tirade.

I didn’t know what she was saying, but I didn’t think I needed to. Now that I was taking a moment to think, I realized that she wouldn’t have taken me onto a station so I could be experimented on and generally abused. I doubted she would have thought that anyone could have done that to me even if they wanted to, anyway. If that had been her intent, then she would have sedated me again and then let the Yodas do their thing. This Yoda might have been a defector, a scientist who had grown weary of his races atrocities and decided to join the nobler alien races. Or maybe those really had just been rogue scientists. Either way, I shouldn’t have attacked him, though I still thought my actions had not been entirely unjustified.

I bowed my head, somewhat ashamed of my behavior, and Mama’s tirade stopped suddenly. I realized that this was the first time I’d shown any remorse for what I’d done. After all, I felt like all my actions up to this point had been completely justified, since I wasn’t the animal they took me for. Now they knew I wasn’t, or at least some of them did, and I would have to show them that I wasn’t a sapient killing machine, which probably would have been worse in their minds. The psychopathic part of me which I’m sure everyone has really liked the idea.

Squashing psychopathic me, I walked calmly over to the where the still unconscious Yoda had dropped his tray of syringes and picked the blue one up from the ground. I showed it to Mama, just so she knew what had specifically set me off – I had not just rage thrown the Yoda – and snapped off the end of its needle, putting the syringe in my pocket. I didn’t know if smashing it against the ground would be bad, so I decided to just keep an eye on it. I hopped back onto my bed and waited calmly as Mama went and carried the still unconscious Yoda out of the room.

Xkkrk left the room, still wearing the military combat harness she had found in the storage locker in the main lab, which, now that she thought about, it was rather odd thing to keep in a hospital, but she wasn’t about to question it. Why did the head researcher on this Death Hospital have to be a Corti, and what the fuck had he been doing carrying a rotgut syringe for a preliminary examination. She supposed she shouldn’t have assumed the heavy pulse–gun would have merely knocked Cqcq’trtr down, but after he had only been been dazed by the full discharge from a quarantine field emitter, she had lit into him with the heavy pulses without a second thought when he began charging towards the idiotic Corti. He had been moving so fast she was lucky she had hit him. He hadn’t been hurt, which would have normally shocked Xkkrk, but at this point she would have been shocked if she could find anything that could hurt him.

She was mainly happy that he’d listened to reason. She knew he hadn’t understood a word she’d said, but it felt good to shout after all the frustration he’d caused these past few days. It seemed Cqcq’trtr had understood her tone, and, more importantly, saw the truth in it and felt ashamed for his actions, at least that was her assumption she firmly believed was true, despite any solid evidence. This action removed any remaining vestiges of doubt left in her mind that he was intelligent. Animals feel guilt when caught in wrongdoings. Intelligent, and more importantly, moral creatures feel shame when they do something wrong, regardless of whether they are caught or not.

It took a while to explain why she was carrying the unconscious body of the lead researcher while wearing a military combat–harness and why the Corti’s hazmat suit’s face plate was shattered, but the matter was eventually cleared up. The more important outcome of her conversation with the stations security officer and second–in–command researcher was that they were alerted to the threat Cqcq’trtr could propose if he was threatened, and how to avoid doing so, mainly by not being Corti or carrying a rotgut injection, although the former had hardly been the lead researchers fault. They didn’t seem to believe her, but she was enough of a nuisance that they finally said they would do as she said.

The second–in–command scientist prepared to do what had previously been the lead researchers job, readying a tray of syringes that was pointedly not containing any injection of the color blue. Under the protection of four guards in full military combat–harness’, three with heavy pulse–guns and the last with an anti–tank gun

+Why do they have an anti–tank gun in a hospital?+

the examination of Cqcq’trtr began. The acting lead researcher was even more amazed by Cqcq’trtr’s immune system than she had been, which was saying something, as she had sworn several times when she found out. The scientist, a Rrrrtktktktkp’ch whose name she learned was Qttvrr’xxkxtvn’zztktkqn’qr’zvpptrnmct, but he said she could just call him Qttvrr’xxkxtvn – so kind of him – nearly had a [nerdgasm] as he perused the results of the Mark III bio–scanner and an array of tests which had taken nearly an entire ric (30 minutes). She wouldn’t have been surprised if he had started moaning.

The Rrrrtktktktkp’ch were evolutionary cousins of the Vzk’tk, but, as loath as Xkkrk was to admit it, they had a significantly greater capacity for intelligence than all but genius level Vzk’tk, of which there were very few in living memory, now that Xkkrk thought about it. She was about as intelligent as a Vzk’tk could ever hope to be, but she still had only been able to grasp the bare fundamentals of microbiology. Aside from their intellect the Rrrrtktktktkp’ch had one more pair of arms and legs than a Vzk’tk, and skin that was unstriped. They shared a common language though, on account of their similar vocal chords, except the Rrrrtktktktkp’ch’s was hopelessly complex compared to the Vzk’tk.

“The immune system of this creature is incredible” Qttvrr’xxkxtvn gasped. “I’ve infected him with one of the viruses we keep at the lab–”

“You what!” Xkkrk shouted, but Qttvrr’xxkxtvn didn’t stop. “And his body has completely eradicated it in five minutes! I infected him with Sipulari plague –”

“YOU WHAT!” Xkkrk screamed. Qttvrr’xxkxtvn was too excited to hear her thoughts about his hastily made decision. She guessed it didn’t matter. The Sipulari plague had been cured decades ago, and the developed serum had been compatible with every species’ immune system so far. There was no reason to assume it wouldn’t work for Cqcq’trtr either, she hoped at least. It appeared the serum wouldn’t be needed, though, as Qttvrr’xxkxtvn continued.

“And his body just turned into an antigen deathworld!! I don’t think we’d be able to kill him with any bio–weapon on record, not even rotgut. I don’t know half of what happened, but his body suddenly heated up as though it were an oven, and then it secreted a hormone that opened up previously small capillaries so they could be invaded by carnivorous Eukaryotic cells which ate anything tagged by another unknown protein, whose sole purpose was to find the antigen and then hold on to it as the Hunter Eukaryotes found it and ate it by turning into a macrophage, and all the while another kind of specialized cell with fucking arms started snagging offending viruses left and right and holding them while the Eukaryotic monstrosities were eating them and it was beautiful.”

He took a deep breath, for which Xkkrk was thankful. His white skin had started to turn blue during his speech. The moment he had his breath back he started up again. “I wonder what would happen if we infected it with a multicellular parasite. It already has several but they seem to have a symbiotic relationship with the creature and are ignored by the immune system.”

“Absolutely not,” Xkkrk interceded. “You’re here to see if we can adapt any of his biological features into a cure for my crewmates, not satisfy your curiosity.”

Qttvrr’xxkxtvn stiffened, suddenly a professional rather than an overexcited researcher. “I am well aware of my purpose in studying this being, but as it stands, anything we took from his body and tried to use in one of the other patients would invariably kill them the same as if we had put a pulse–gun to their head. His immune system would eat them alive. But maybe, if I study how it works, we’ll be able to bioengineer similar cells which could be specifically made so that they would not kill the patient we injected them into. But before I can do that I need to study how his immune system works. I feel as though I’ve hardly scratched the surface.”

Xkkrk didn’t want to concede the point, but Qttvrr’xxkxtvn was right. The fact of the matter was, if they didn’t figure out how to adapt Cqcq’trtr’s immune system to her crewmates, they would most likely die. Forcing his immune system to work so they could understand its process was something any moral sapient being would allow, and if Cqcq’trtr wouldn’t allow it . . . well, they couldn’t understand what he said and vise versa, and she was willing to take advantage of that fact if it meant saving her family.

“Fine,” Xkkrk said. “Continue as you see fit.”

Humans don’t make good pets part 10

by guidosbestfriend

One day I will submit a post without a foreword, but it is not this day. This subject matter of the story has started to become more serious, and the amount of humor I've been able to incorporate has started to wane. Sorry about that to those of you who read these primarily for that reason (I know that's why I write them). bare with me for a little longer and then we can get back to the jokes.

Since I've been getting impatient with how these have been turning out, I've decided to take drastic action with this installment. The only major input for this story was /u/Hambone3110, a comment by /u/Lord_Fuzzy during the last section (no there aren't any dragons, sorry to disappoint), and a message by /u/sober__counsel sent when this story was just being written; specifically to /u/sober__counsel I'm sorry I didn't message you back, but your message was a life saver to me and really helped with the cohesion of this story.

Alien measurements are given their appropriate names with equivalent human measurements in (parentheses). Alien words with Human equivalents are put in [brackets]. Thoughts are italicized and offset by "+" symbols.

Dear Journal,

I'm killing them.

I don't know what to do.

I'm . . . scared.

Shit.

The experiments weren't going well, at least that was what I assumed. After all, I'd been lying on this freakishly uncomfortable bed almost non-stop for what seemed like weeks now, and the scientists that were studying me didn't seem to be doing anything different from what they had done the first day they started studying me. I think the grey Yoda was the lead researcher, and I think he was mad at me. Any injections I needed to be given were administered by him, and for a lead medical researcher he either didn't know how to use a needle to save his life or he made it as painful as possible on purpose. My arm hated him. I didn't give him the satisfaction of a grunt.

And despite all of their tireless work, little progress was being made. I'd fall asleep to their working in the lab and would awake to them doing the same thing. I don't know much about research, but I think finding a cure requires more than just enjoying the show as the disease in question kills all the cells on your test slide. I guess we had more time than most situations like this one, but the researchers could have at least tried to look as though they were in a time crunch.

The reason we had more time had come as something of a shock to me. I had been in my special little room for so long I hadn't really seen how the rest of the crew had been faring. I was finally allowed to stretch my legs, which was an arduous process as it required everyone to put on hazmat suits before I left my room, and I saw that nearly every single member of the crew were sealed in little pods along the wall. I didn't need to be told what the pods where. I could see from the condensation on the lids that it was cold inside, and yet I couldn't see any of my crew members breath. They'd been put in cryo to keep them alive while the cure was found. The only crew member not in cryo was Mama. Coincidence, that.

It was the sight of the condition the rest of the crew was in that gave me the will to lie still for hours on end as the mechanism in my bed beeped and whirred, gathering information on me of a nature that I couldn't even begin to fathom. It also helped me scarf down the nutrient supplements they'd been giving me. I felt better, and I assumed that meant they'd figured out what my body needed, but they could have at least made them taste better, right? After the second week of virtually nothing happening, my worst fears were confirmed when Mama had a heated conversation with the grey Yoda. The tones suggested that Mama was angry at the lack of progress, or perhaps was accusing the Yoda of intentionally slowing down the process. I wasn't as used to the Yoda's tones as I was to Mama's but I could tell he was denying it.

The research assistant to the Yoda, a white-alpha-giraffe (that's what I called the not blue-giraffes that almost looked like blue-giraffes) seemed to stay out of the argument, but if I were a betting man - I actually am but that's none of your business - I would have put everything on him being guilty. Then there was the other lab assistant. He was an oddly shaped fellow, with green scales for skin and six limbs: three legs and three arms. He looked like a lopsided lizard-ant crossover, hence the name I gave his species: lizard-ant. He was the only one of my researchers I didn't trust. He had a shifty look about him if I'd ever seen one, and I whenever he was in my room alone he would work with machines I'd never seen the other researchers touch, but only when they weren't in the room.

I know it's odd to say that I actually trusted a Yoda over the lizard-ant, named Shifty, but it was true. Sure, Good-Yoda was a jerk, but he was an honest jerk as far as I could tell. He hated me because I had nearly bashed his skull apart. I could understand and respect that. After all, I couldn't talk to him and apologize. Shifty, on the other hand, legitimately seemed to hate me, but he only expressed it in looks. I assumed they were threatening looks, as they made my skin crawl when he gave them to me and I was the only one I'd seen him use them on. I couldn't really find a solid reason for why I disliked him, it's just a vibe I got, but hey, I'd gotten a similar if more honest vibe from Severus and I'd been pretty spot on as far as I could tell, so I decided to go with my instincts. If they weren't able to detect danger, then what were they good for anyway?

After what happened at that station I decided I should listen to my instincts more often.

"You aren't even trying! You've done nothing but stare at your damn test slides since we've been here while my family is dying! You're telling me you haven't discovered anything of use? You have the most sophisticated equipment the galaxy can offer you and yet you can't figure out how one little being's immune system works despite having a machine that can literally give you live video of it doing it's job??!!" Xkkrk knew she was shouting, but she didn't care. She had discovered the true nature of these "researchers" work several days ago, although she hadn't let on that she knew. In essence, the plight of her crew had been put on the back burner, if not completely discarded as insignificant, as the "security risk that this species represents to the rest of the sapient life in the galaxy is investigated". Essentially, nothing had been done for her crew. The science crew of the "hospital" only seemed to want to understand how to make Cqcq'trtr bleed.

She could foresee the use of such research in a coldly logical way, but it was wrong to do it without Cqcq'trtr's permission and especially immoral when her crew was frozen in cryo so they wouldn't die while these scientists attempted to find a vulnerability in Cqcq'trtr's physical and immunological physiology. She could say without a trace of guilt that she was glad they were as frustrated on that front as she was with them. From what she could tell, they hadn't managed to inflict anything but a mild response from Cqcq'trtr's immune system, and physical scans had revealed that he probably could survive several shots from an anti-tank gun.

The memories of those discoveries brought a cold smile to Xkkrk's face as the Corti explained to her why they really did have her crew's well-being in mind, and how their work was essential to saving their lives. It had been near the end of the first ricta (1.5 weeks) when the entire research station had been shocked to find that Cqcq'trtr had bones composed of a mix of what the scientists told her was hydroxyapatite, calcium phosphate, and a protein they'd never seen before, but Cqcq'trtr seemed to have in abundance. The apparently a similar mix, except a different protein, had recently been proposed for use in the exoskeleton structure of a new generation of combat harnesses for use in the ongoing war with the Celzi alliance, but the idea had ultimately been rejected when it was discovered that the costs to actually find and mine that much calcium would have put the Dominion in debt. This creature seemed to have one of the proposed exosuits built into him, rather than the galactically standard skeletal system composed of silica based composite.

Not even mentioning his bone structure, his muscles were a study in compacted death hardened in high-gravity and then with a little chaos thrown in. Xkkrk hadn't understand most of the things the researchers had been saying as they enumerated the destructive and defensive capabilities Cqcq'trtr's muscles afforded him, but from what she understood they were laughably simple in their composition, except that this simplicity allowed them to be stronger than any living organism in the known galaxy.

From what she understood the only way his skeletal muscles could move was by contracting. Since this afforded an extremely limited range of motion, he required an astounding 650 of them just to give his body the range of motion of a normal organism, as opposed to the average number of about 150. Because they were so simple, however, and their movement so restricted, they were able to be composed of extremely rigid materials which aligned themselves into an interlocking polymer mesh that was nearly impossible to break, explaining Cqcq'trtr unfathomable durability. The potential energy able to be contained within them was astounding, and made Xkkrk wonder if he'd even been trying when he'd protected them from Ztrkx.

On the immunological front, the scientists efforts to discover a viral or pathogenic organism that Cqcq'trtr's immune system couldn't tear to pieces was also failing. Xkkrk didn't think Cqcq'trtr had noticed that over the past two rictas (three weeks) he'd survived fifty of the galaxy's most infamous plagues, usually more than three at a time. The first success the scientists had thought they had only showed them how far they had to go before they could find a biological deterrent for Cqcq'trtr's species.

After infecting him with a cocktail of the Victen virus, Xilix plague, and Daz-5, a biological weapon outlawed in the peace accords of the Sassinal massacre . . . err, war . . . the researchers had been overjoyed when the onslaught of terminal illnesses were not immediately stifled by Cqcq'trtr's overpowered immune system. His body flew into a fever and released the Hunter cells, but the trifecta of galactic antigenic superpowers held on, but only just. Then the researchers were introduced to what they would later call the Hunter helpers.

They started appearing after the fever was unsuccessful in slowing down the infection. Then they wouldn't stop appearing. The smaller hunter cells began augmenting the Hunter cell's attacks in any way they could, shepherding the protein markers to where they were needed the most, even halting the infections advance by sacrificing themselves to create a nigh impregnable physical barrier the infection could not pass without being blocked or consumed by the shear number of hunter helpers. Within two rics (an hour) the hunter helpers had become so numerous the scanner was having difficulty picking out anything of the terrifying swarm. After only one ricto (two days) the deadly cocktail had been beaten into submission with the elegance Cqcq'trtr had displayed while gifting off the pirates.

The worst part of the experiment, according to the scientists records, was that once an infection was successfully rebuffed, Cqcq'trtr couldn't catch it again. His body remembered. They had started running out of biological monstrosities to infect him with and had started mutating their own so they could even continue. They were also unaware that Xkkrk knew of their activities, especially their immunological "studies". She had to admit, it was sometimes advantageous to be a part of a species that was always discounted as unobservant and unintelligent. It may be true to a certain degree, but that didn't mean she had been born yesterday. Since they had thought she was still buying their lies, they weren't bothering to watch her. If they had, they would have seen her discretely copying their records every time they weren't in the lab.

She hated what they were doing to Cqcq'trtr, but as of yet they hadn't managed to do anything in the slightest to harm him, and she knew she'd only be able to help him escape the facility once before she was either declared infectious and shoved into a cryo pod, or perhaps merely killed. At first she had doubted the research crew were truly doing this out of malicious intent, and she'd been right. After one ricta and two ricto's (approximately 2 weeks 1 day) she had found a message from none other than the Dominion Intelligence Agency. It seemed that they had been informed of the potential security risk and ordered the research station to investigate ways in which Cqcq'trtr's people could be dealt with if they reached the stars and turned out to be hostile.

The only thing that had kept Xkkrk from rushing to Cqcq'trtr the instant she read the message and doing everything within her power to get him off the station was the end of the message which dictated that the research crew were still to try and find a way to cure the infected Vzk'tk, but for it to be a secondary priority. After all, they were people in need of protection and that was what the DIA aimed to provide, they just had to also consider the future, and the future was grim if Cqcq'trtr's people found the rest of the galaxy's sophants to be vulnerable in every way and fancied a galactic conquest.

That message had been tearing at Xkkrk for the past three rictos (6 days). The researchers who had been dedicated to Xkkrk's family, who were admittedly the third string researchers on the station, still legitimately needed comprehensive scans of Cqcq'trtr in order for their research to continue. Without him, they wouldn't have a cure. If she "rescued" Cqcq'trtr from those who wanted to find a way in which to hypothetically destroy him, that would spell the almost imminent death of her crew. She found herself damned if she did and damned if she didn't. Sometimes sapience was real bitch.

"We have made some progress." The Corti's words snapped Xkkrk back into the moment. "We've just finished the development of an implant we can subdermally inject into . . . uh . . Cqcq'trtr's . . . body that will prevent him from infecting other beings he interacts with. It is essentially a more permanent version of the front-line inoculation our zoologist give to potentially hazardous creatures." Xkkrk decided to not point out the flaws in the Corti's wording about his people use of their inoculation. She had to admit that this invention would be terribly useful, but she also knew they'd managed to make it after the first ricta (1.5 weeks) of studying Cqcq'trtr, and it had primarily been made to be inserted into kinetic projectiles which would prevent hypothetical Cqcq'trtr-esque prisoners from killing their guards by breathing on them.

"We would have already taken the liberty of injecting him with it, had it not been for his reluctance to allow us to approach him with anything other than minor injections." Said the Robalin researcher. Xkkrk didn't like him. He seemed slimy, and that wasn't just because his skin naturally secreted a thin mucus covering over his soft scales. His entier personality reeked of ulterior motives, something she had learned to sense as a cargo ship crew member. She knew she shouldn't distrust the Robalin. After all, their people had been brought into the Dominions fold after they had failed to create their apocalyptic bio-weapon, but something about this one just didn't sit right with her. She wasn't speciesist, was she?

"He seems to trust you, for reasons I still cannot fathom," the Robalin purred. "If we could have but a single standard cubit of blood (50cc) it would aid our efforts enormously. Scans of his chemical composition can only achieve so much, and seeing how his blood would react to different stimuli outside his body would be invaluable."

"I have already told you, Dr. UtMot," snapped Dr. Triv, the Corti researcher, "It serves no practical purpose for us to have a sample of blood outside of his body when we have his body here in our lab. I don't know why you are so insistent on this point." He took a moment to consider Dr. UtMot, then seemed to snap out of his consideration and turned back to Xkkrk. "However, Dr. UtMot is correct in one respect, Cqcq'trtr does seem to trust you. If you could inject him with this permanent front line solution, it would allow him to walk about the station more often. He does seem to be rather restless."

"Why, Dr. Triv, I didn't know you cared for our patients well being." Xkkrk simpered in her most scathing voice. Dr. Triv huffed. A very dry huff.

"I don't, he nearly killed me, but it makes it difficult to get a good scan from him when he's shifting around on the bed."

Fair enough. Xkkrk really didn't need convincing that the permanent front-line solution was a good thing for Cqcq'trtr to have, she just didn't want Dr. Triv to actually think he could get away with pretending he cared for him. Walking over to where Cqcq'trtr sat on the bed, she could see that he did look restless. He showed his teeth to her, which Xkkrk knew was the exact opposite of a threatening gesture despite all appearances. She attempted to copy the gesture, and Cqcq'trtr started giving his equivalent of a laugh. Xkkrk assumed she looked ridiculous.

Cqcq'trtr had become her only companion after everyone else in the crew had been put in cryo, and they had created an extremely rudimentary form of communication between them based off of gestures, body language, and tone of voice. She could see Cqcq'trtr's face become the picture of wariness the moment she raised the subdermal injection apparatus in front of her. She quickly used the gesture that roughly translated into "It's ok this won't permanently harm you. You need to take it", at least that's how Xkkrk used it, and it got the results she desired, so she assumed Cqcq'trtr thought it meant the same thing.

He relaxed, and she placed it against his forearm, lined it up with his bone, and pressed the button. The apparatus made a loud click and Cqcq'trtr gritted his teeth in discomfort, but was otherwise still. Dang he had a pain tolerance. The apparatus had been made especially to get past his tough skin, and was strong enough it probably would have sent the transplant into any lesser being's bones. She wasn't as amazed as she would have once been however. It was somewhat comforting to be friends with a creature that could fight his way through everyone in this station. It meant that if she had to get him out for his own good, all she'd have to do was point him in the right direction.

"Excellent," rasped Dr. Triv. "If your services are needed we will not hesitate to call for you. Thank you." Clearly dismissed, Xkkrk left the room to grind her teeth in peace.

The events which would lead to my life's third alien upheaval started during the night of in the middle of the third week. After that thing Mama had put in my arm I'd been allowed to move about the station without everyone having to act like I'd swallowed Uranium, which was great because I was feeling weak. My muscles were being destroyed by this weak gravity and I needed to keep my shape up. I'd started doing pushups, situps, and generally any exercise I could think of that didn't require any equipment. I could do nearly twice as many as I'd been able to do on Earth, but I figured it was still a workout, although I wish I could adjust the gravity.

After my second workout of the day it was bed time. The station dimmed it's lights approximately every eight hours I guessed, so that everyone could sleep - these creatures did that a lot, they got tired so fast - and I would usually roam around during these times, or exercise, or sleep, depending on what I felt like. I decided to sleep during this sleep period because I had exercised during the last one and again about an hour ago when they gave me a break from being scanned. I was suitably tired, and would have gone to sleep the moment I lay down, if the hairs on the back of my neck hadn't stood on end the moment I entered my room.

You know that feeling, like someone's breathing down your shirt, or maybe staring at your soul. It's the feeling that makes you sure there's someone right behind you waiting to take you wallet, if you're lucky. I've felt that too many times in my life, and each one of those times I could have avoided something I'd want to if I'd only listened to it the moment I felt it. I listened to it this time. Lucky for me. Shift came dropping down on my from the ceiling - freaking lizards - and I only avoided him by dropping and rolling - I told you that was a good move. He leapt at me, but I was already on my feet and he'd lost the element of surprise.

I could see the panic in his eyes as he attacked me and I evaded him with laughable ease. I got a chance to see what he had tried to stab into the back of my neck when he'd dropped from above. He was holding a purple syringe of sleep. It was a syringe they'd only started using last approximate week. None of the sedatives they'd given me were working, until they came up with this new one which put me down like a horse. Why did he think he had to attack me to sedate me, and why did he have to do it now when no one else was around? I assumed the two were related, and looked at him to see if I could find any other clues. He had a belt on with two other syringes on it, one was empty. The other was the blue syringe of death. Ah.

I hadn't given this freak my blood, because I wasn't giving these scientists anything until Mama proved to me that it was okay, since I was starting to get the feeling they weren't really working on a cure for the rest of the crew. I'd felt sick a few times after they'd given me some injections, and every time I started feeling better they started freaking out. I didn't like that, but I hadn't quite figured out why. It's not like they were trying to get me sick. I didn't think Mama would let them do that.

That left this guy. He had tried to get my blood on multiple occasions when no one else had been in the room, and each time I'd taken the empty syringe from him and thrown it against the wall. He'd gotten the picture pretty quick. It looked like he'd decided to stop asking me. Thankfully, it really didn't matter one way or the other what he wanted.

He saw my eyes alight upon the blue syringe of death and turn dangerous. That made him freak out. He started running for the door. I caught him in after about a meter. Why does no one jump in this low gravity, it works so much better than running. I picked the blue syringe of death from his belt. "Now I'm pretty sure I know what this is, but I could also be wrong. A blue syringe is just a blue syringe, and I don't know much of what you guys are doing. If you're supposed to be here, then I doubt you were ordered to kill me, either they'd have brought an army with the biggest guns they had and waited until I was asleep. But, on the off chance you're just doing your job, I'll let you try this syringe out first. If it's not what I think it is, you'll be fine and I'll let you go get another one and I'll inject it myself. If it isn't . . ."

I stuck the needle into his arm and he started struggling harder than ever. Didn't really bode well for him. It looks like I was right, because ten seconds after I injected him his struggles became less and less, then finally his breath stopped. I had left a little in the syringe so that I had an explanation as to why I'd done it, but I doubted he was here on orders. That started my wondering. Why hadn't he just waited until I was asleep. I usually slept when everyone else was asleep, just, only every other sleeping period they took. This move of his spoke of illicit action combined with a time crunch. Why would he have needed my blood so soon?

My thoughts were interrupted as the door opened once again. I leapt to it's blind side and waited to see who was entering. It was the Yoda. I snarled. Coming to see if his friend had been successful, had he? He heard my growl, and I prepared to leap at him.

"I was not responsible for his actions, and if you kill me your Vzk'tk friend will die along with everyone on this station."

My jaw dropped. It had been so long since I'd heard another recognizable voice other than my own that it took me a moment to figure out what the Yoda had said. "You can talk to me?" I spluttered. "How? Why haven't you done it before? Why just you? Can the others understand me?"

He held up a hand. My questions ceased. "My race is perhaps the most unethical sapient species among the stars, but we're also one of the most intelligent. When the searchers, excuse me, zoologists find an up and coming species that will soon reach the stars, we abduct several of their number and study them for a number of reasons. First and foremost so we can create common galactic items fit to their physiology, but that wouldn't really require an abduction of more than one of two people. The other reason we abduct a large number of the species in question is so that we can learn their weaknesses so that, if we're ever threatened, we can exploit them. Such experimentation is difficult when the species is a recognized sapient, so we do it before legal matters interfere with our self-preservation. Our advanced understanding of other species and our prowess in cybernetic implants have allowed my kind, and my kind alone, to implant a two way translator into the language centers of our brains, along with a device that allows me to download any pertinent research conducted by my kind regarding any known species I should happen to encounter, or perhaps escaped research subjects that should be dead," he coughed and looked at me pointedly. " I and others like me can understand you. If I wanted to I could even act as a translator between you and another, so long as I could understand both. I refrained from doing such as it was advantageous for me to withhold this information from everyone on board. After all, if you could talk, I would have had to ask your permission before I continued my people's work on you. You gave them quite a bit of trouble, didn't you?"

"You son of a-"

"Actually my mother was quite normal, thank you. The researchers who abducted you were quite entertained once they discovered what that little saying meant. I'm not here to gloat, though, I just need you to understand that I 'hold all the cards,' and also so that you can know why the unfortunate Dr. UtMot," he motioned to the dead lizard-ant on the floor "attempted what he did. He is of a race known as the Robalin. Approximately twenty of your years ago they attempted to create a biological weapon capable of destroying any organism that displeased them. Thankfully their ambition was greater than their intelligence and they failed. They were quickly defeated and assimilated into the Dominion, of which my people and the many others you see here on this station are a part of. Then you show up at this station. A member of the a species that is a gun pointed at the head of the galaxy. You are the only race my people has not yet been able to find a satisfiable exploitable weakness for, you especially. Your immune system is extremely good, even by the measure of your kind, in case you were wondering."

"I eat my vegetables." I said through clenched teeth.

"Very wise of you. The reason I tell you of this is that Dr. UtMot appears to have been a part of a faction within the Robalin that are still looking for their illusive 'dooms day bio-weapon', at least I hope it's just a faction. The important outcome of this, however, is that an old Robalin class-4 biocruiser has just decloaked 300 of your kilometers from the station, and has been sending comlink requests to Dr. UtMot every fifteen 'minutes' to check on his progress. I do not believe he will be able to make his next check in, do you?"

I looked at Shifty's - what kind of name is UtMot - body. I think Dick Yoda here had the right of things. "So why are you telling me this? What do you want me to do?"

He looked at me, apparently annoyed that I wasn't getting his drift. Dick. "They are here because it is time for them to pick up the last installment of Dr. UtMot's delivery. It appears he has been attempting to develop a bio-weapon by himself. I have become increasingly suspicious of his activity as of late and so I assume, being frightened that I was on to him, he called for an extraction, which is waiting outside. Even if UtMot is dead, it is too much to hope that he had not already sendt all his work to his friends. With him dead, however, they will know that he has been compromised. That will mean they have a good deal of clean up to do. If the Dominion learns of this, any hope these Robalins have of this plan succeeding will be crushed. They've been jamming communications for an 'hour' now. With UtMot's untimely demise, they'll need to kill everyone on this station and abduct you. They've no doubt been informed of your . . . tenacity . . . and will most likely take advantage of the compartmentalization of this station and obliterate all of it except your room, which they will then drag into their cargo bay, cut into it from multiple directions at once, and then fill it with anti-tank fire. You will be subdued. I know this because that's how I'd do it, and the Robalins are better than I am at strategy."

"Wow. Nice pep-talk. You should really try coaching t-ball, you'd do wonder's for those kids self esteem."

"At least they would be able to shut up and listen when I'm talking to them, now . . ."

"I doubt it. Did you download any files on human children dude?" Dick ground his teeth. I smiled. Taking a deep breath he continued.

"The only way we can prevent your capture and the death of everyone on this station is if UtMot is successful in his mission."

"You're not making me feel any better." He ignored me.

"If he was successful, then he would have dragged your unconscious body - probably with a transport bed from your cargo ship - into one of this stations shuttles and taken you to his friend's ship before anyone was the wiser."

"Why not just eject this room and then let his friends pick that up?"

"Because that would sound a containment breach alarm which would wake everyone up."

"Do they really think people aren't going to start wondering why Dr. UtMot and myself are missing when they wake up?"

"Of course we would. If they're successful in abducting you they'll still destroy this station, but it's significantly easier to do so with you off it and everyone asleep. If a containment breach was sounded the computer would go on high alert, and if anyone fired at the station it would detect the shot before it hit and raise the shields. Biocruisers aren't known for their weapons, and if the shields were raised they'd never get through, so they'd just run away with the information they have so far, hide from the Dominion, and resurface a century later, possibly with their completed weapon. But if everyone is unaware of their presence, they can just use the shuttle UtMot stole to board the station and kill everyone in their sleep, then destroy the station and make it look like a reactor breach."

"This is ridiculously complex."

"You tend to make things that way. Also, this station was made to be resistant to the main forms of weapons the Robalins use. This is probably the safest place to hide from them."

"I still don't see how I'm going to stop the imminent death of everyone on this station".

Dick smiled. "I'm thinking we should send UtMot back to them, and give them what they want. The only difference is you're armed with knowledge and UtMot is somewhat less than healthy. They'll will not be expecting UtMot to have been so heavily compromised. If a shuttle approaches they'll allow you to enter, and they shouldn't be ready for you. After that, do what you do best."

"Drink beer"? He gave me a flat look. "I'm really good at that you know."

"You didn't seem like it when we first picked you up," he shot back. Ouch.

"I still won that contest, the other guy was just really good too." Dick snorted. I became serious again.

"How many are there on that ship."

"A traditional class-4 biocruiser can hold 75 Robalin."

"Great. What if I can't kill that many." Dick reached into a pocket of his garb and took out a small white capsule.

"This is what your species use when you suddenly take the urge to self-terminate. I believe you know it as a cyanide-pill. If you feel you are about to be captured, take this. It has a little something extra which should dissolve you from the inside, making it nearly impossible to study your corpse."

I put the pill in my pocket where I still had the first blue syringe of death I'd fist taken from Dick here. "Heck if you have something that can dissolve me then I think you found your weakness."

"It only works if you ingest it, and I don't believe it would be a good battle strategy for my species to need to walk up your soldiers and try to force something into their mouths."

"Good point. If I succeed, how will I come back?" I asked.

He paused. "We'll figure that out if we get there."

"If I don't make it back, will you still be able to cure the crew of the cargo ship"? He gave me a long, considering look.

"You actually care for their well being?" he asked, incredulous.

"Yes. They were good to me, even though they didn't understand that I was sapient -" he snorted in derision, "and I don't want them to die on my account. I'm doing what you suggest because not doing it would end in their death, I don't give a shit about you."

"It will be difficult, but we may be able to complete a cure for the various diseases they have contracted without your immune system actually present. I give you my word. We do not have much time. If we do not start soon we will not be able to-"

"What that fuck is going on- [unintelligible clicking]?!" Mama burst into the room. I think she'd heard me talking. Dick had turned off his precious little two way translator though, and I was back to hearing nothing but clicking as Mama moved her mouth in anger. I would have punched Dick in the face if he hadn't been right in what he had been saying right before Mama interrupted us. It would take too long if we had to explain everything to her. Sorry Mama, I hope Dick explains to you why I did what I'm about to do.

I grabbed the purple syringe from Shifty's limp hand and leapt at Mama. My weight bore her to the ground, and I hated myself as I inserted the needle into her arm and I injected the smallest amount of sedative that I could. It worked. She fainted mid-click, but continued breathing.

"Thank you. I would not have been able to do that myself and we are pressed for time." Screw him. I threw the syringe at him, hitting him in the face.

"Mature. Follow me to the shuttle, and bring Dr. UtMot with you."

"Wait." I said. I grabbed the empty syringe from Shifty and found a vein. Heck I was better than Dick here. I drew a full syringe of my blood and placed it next to Mama. "So she knows I didn't just abandon her."

"How chivalrous of you." Dick sneered. "Now come, we must hurry." I picked up Shifty and followed Dick through the station. After a quick jog we entered a cavernous room with several small ships in them. Dick opened up the nearest one and started punching orders into the console. "I'm setting the ships course to the correct location. Once I open the shuttle bay doors, hit that red button to lock the course and the ship will do the rest. Once you land, you won't have long before they realize something's amiss, so I'd advise attacking them sooner rather than later. You have the pill?" I showed it too him. "Whatever you do, do not allow yourself to be captured, or else we gave them everything they needed. This is our only chance to destroy any hope they have of ever succeeding. If we mess it up, they'll still have the research UtMot was able to already conduct."

"I know, you've already said all of this". He smiled.

"Just don't want your nerve failing you and forgetting what's at stake."

"Believe me, I know exactly what's at stake," I said, thinking of Mama, Dink, heck, even Severus; bastard.

"Excellent. Don't let me die," Dick said with a greasy smile. Fuck him. Too bad I couldn't save everyone but him. The shuttle door closed and he walked into a room and closed the door. I could see him at a console through the large window that composed nearly an entire wall of the room he'd just entered. He pushed a couple buttons and the cargo bay door began to open. He stopped it when it was open enough and then pointed at me, which I took for a signal. I pressed the red button, and the shuttle lifted from the ground. I hope Mama would know why I left. Really I wasn't abandoning them. They were safe, right? Why do I still feel guilty?

Previous nine part two

Next eleven

All chapters

Humans don’t make good pets part 11

By guidosbestfriend

Dear Journal,

What did I do to piss God or whoever off so badly?

So there I was sitting in my little shuttle as it zoomed through the empty void of space. It had a great view out the front window, and a convenient little view screen where I could see my starting location, ending coordinate, and current position. I was moving way too fast for my tastes. It was only going to take me about five minutes. I start talking when I get nervous, and the only one who was there was Dick, so I guess he’d have to do.

“So, once I get there, what do I do”? I could here him sigh over the loudspeaker.

“As I said before, kill everyone on board. It shouldn’t be hard for someone of your particular physiology.”

“But there are 75 of them!”

“That’s only how many the ship can hold, not the number necessary to crew it. There could be as few as 30.”

“That still sounds like a lot.”

“I didn’t want to tell you about this before you left, since I didn’t feel like arming you while you were right in front of me – just call it sentimental quirk of mine –, but if you look in the compartment to you left I believe you’ll find an old friend.”

I looked to the compartment he had indicated and opened it. “Aww yiss.” In the compartment was the alien lava sword I’d been given from enemy number seven of the pirate blue–giraffes right before Twinkle–Toes had decided to see how space felt without a spaceship. Next to it was one of those vests that Mama had been wearing. There wasn’t a gun like she’d had, though.

“In case you don’t know, that’s your fusion sword you had when your ship docked–” I don’t care what he called it, it was an alien lava sword, “and a military combat–harness mark 2. It’s equipped with one of the later models of personal shield generators this station has to offer. Pulse–guns–” nope, ray guns, “have to be genetically sequenced to their users, and while I was able to do that I didn’t think your particular fighting style would really utilize a gun all that much. Thankfully the combat–harness merely needs to be on you. Put it on and hit the large blue button at your left hip. That will activate the generator. The sword I did genetically bind to you. To turn it on press your thumb to the indentation you see in the middle of the hilt. Turn it off in the same way. Any other questions?”

“Yeah, what are these guys probably armed with?”

“They knew you were here, so I’d expect that after the initial shock of your attack wears off they’ll start grabbing anti–tank pulse–guns.”

“That sounds wonderful. Reminds me of a walk I had in a park once. Or maybe it was a slum in Chicago, I can’t quite recall. How many shots from an anti–tank ray gun could I survive?”

“Probably just one, and that’s only if you aren’t hit in a vital area.”

“Okay, how many shots can my shield take?”

“About the same.”

“Excellent. Any other good news you want to share with me?”

“I project your chances of success to be about one in five.”

“Aww, don’t lie to me Dick, you wouldn’t want me to become too overconfident.”

“You’re right. Lying is wrong. One in ten.”

“Ok you can stop now.”

“That’s good, because our communication will start to be noticed even by their paltry sensors if we keep talking much longer. For my sake, good luck.”

“Fuck you.”

“I’d rather not.” And with that final remark he cut off communications. Dang it, I had a bad but snappy comeback to that. It may or may not have included the words “your mom”. My anger evaporated when my communications lit up again, this time with a distinctly alien voice. I had no idea what they were saying, but it sounded similar to the way in which Shifty had talked, albeit in a slightly deeper, more threatening voice. Whoever was talking to me suddenly stopped, and the silence was just begging for a response. To bad Shifty on the floor wasn’t going to be much help.

I decided that the best course of action was to deal with this situation in the same way that humans in space had dealt with similar situations. In this particular case my mind went to the heroic actions of Han Solo. I pressed my thumb to the alien lava sword. Its edge burst into a red light – that unmanly giggle of delight did not come from me – and I stabbed the speaker the voice had come out of.

I guess that console, which was the only console in the small shuttle, held a few more things than just communications, because a whole lot of lights when out the moment I stabbed it. The sword worked like a light–saber though, and I was so happy with it that it took me a moment to see what else had happened. Thankfully I was in space and I had momentum so I wasn’t going to slow down. I just hoped the voice on the other side of the speaker could tell I’d just had a massive systems failure and would come pick me up, because I sure didn’t know how to do anything in this ship except push the red button and open the left hand compartment.

Apparently they could, because my ship lurched in a direction uncharacteristic of it’s previous vector, and a black ship significantly larger than the blue–giraffe’s cargo ship suddenly appeared above me. Holy shit it looked intimidating. It reminded me vaguely of the shape of a grub, except this grub would have had six arms at the bow, aft, and mid–ship, arrayed in a star–burst formation around the hull, each sprouting what was unmistakable some form of gun, although I hadn’t the slightest idea as to what kind of weaponry they would be sporting. Thankfully, none of the weapons were pointed at me, and my shuttle was being dragged by some invisible force into an opening in the ships belly.

All that I needed now was C3–PO to start shouting that we were all doomed because my main reactor was down or something. That’s what it felt like as my ship was swallowed by the lizard–ant death–grub (I have a way with adjectives I know). The bay door closed and the lights of the shuttle bay turned on. I remembered that the shuttle’s window was heavily tinted in case you looked at a sun, but I still swore and ducked beneath the console when the lights revealed a group of 20 or so lizard–ants running into the room, all wearing combat–harnesses, although they looked a little more battered up than mine, and ray guns that looked similar in size to the one Mama had used on me.

They apparently couldn’t see me though, because they passed my windshield, with me staring out of it, and even looked right at me, but still crowded around my door in relaxed poses, holding their guns to their sides. They obviously where here to expedite the massacre of everyone else on board the station. That thought got my blood boiling. They didn’t even look like they were bothered by the prospect! Several of them seemed to be laughing.

Their actions urged me to a charge, and I pushed against the door to begin the destruction in my righteous anger. It wouldn’t budge. “Now, wait, how does this open?” I looked around a while. I think it had closed on it’s own when I was in the cargo bay. Stupid Dick, he hadn’t told me how to open the door! Well, I had a light–saber. I stabbed the door and began making my own door. I heard panicked shouts from the other side. Oh right, they thought they were going to use this for a return journey. Holes don’t make for the most space–worthy of crafts. I had only finished half a side of my addition to the shuttle’s hull when the door was opened from the outside. Right, doors could do that too.

The door had been opened by a brutish lizard–ant, which is hard considering they already looked rather barbaric. He looked at me, looked at Shifty’s body on the floor, then back up at me. I don’t know if he was ever able to complete the thought, because the moment he looked at me for the second time I got over the shock of his rather unpleasant visage and launched myself at his face, lava sword sweeping in an arc parallel to the ground that culminated in a beheading. The shuttle bay erupted into chaos. Ten of the closest lizards apparently had gone to the pirate blue–giraffe school of close–quarters combat, and they thought it prudent to whip their guns and attempt to draw a bead on me rather than giving themselves room.

Three full armed swipes was all it required to pacify those who hadn’t backed up upon my arrival in the middle of the group. The remaining nine had taken cover and were now firing at me behind barriers. I was hit several times. Ow. Those shots hurt. Shaking it off I leapt for the nearest lizard–ant, hiding behind a large crate. Two more leaps put me on top of it, from where I sprang atop the unsuspecting lizard–ant from above, leading with the sword. I cleared the remaining targets in the bay in a similar manner, jump–flying about the cargo room in great 4 meter leaps. There was one smart guy who kept changing his position on me. When all his crew mates had been eliminated, he was still up and sprinting across the room away from me, firing over his shoulder with surprising accuracy while he talked at a device on his shoulder. Crap.

I had grown up in significantly greater gravity that this ship, though, and I had adrenaline. I sprang after him, not bothering to run but merely leapt, even using a wall at one point to extend my jump to an astounding 7 meters. I caught up to him in 4 seconds and jumped over him, landing in front of him and driving forward with the sword, which found its way into his gut. He made a gasping sound and raised his gun with his last strength. I did not want to be hit with that thing at this close range, so I desperately yanked the sword up, splitting him from his gut through his neck. One thing about this sword is that it cauterized the wounds, and I was blood–stain free even after going through 20 of lizard–ants.

“Heck, if all my encounters go like that I’ll be done with thing in no time.” Journal, let me give you a hint. If things seem to be going your way, never, under any circumstance talk about it out loud, and avoid thinking it if you can. The moment the words left my mouth the ship made a sound. It was the kind of sound that made one think about something extremely powerful turning on. Then an ominous hum began to emanate from the entire ship. I knew that sound. That was the sound the cargo ship made when it was traveling.

+Shit that’s the FTL drive!+

Why they started moving I’ll never know, but I still had a job to finish, so I couldn’t really worry about it right now. I moved into the next section of the ship. I only realized after the fact that I’d forgotten to turn on my person energy shield Dick had provided. Oops. Silly me.

Captain YecTal sat on his bridge, comfortable for the first time since this mission had started. UtMot had apparently been successful in his mission, seeing as how his shuttle was even now being stowed in his ship’s hold. He had to admit, his engineer’s had been right. This old ship was still suited to this kind of task. The Robalin may not be known for their ship’s weaponry, but when it came to bio–weapons and stealth they were some of the best.

“Shuttle is docked Captain,” reported BecMeq. He was new, and overenthusiastic, but he knew what he was doing. “Eraser team on are entering the cargo bay.”

“That will be fine, Ensign. There’s no need for me to know what order they are entering the shuttle.”

“Sorry sir.”

“Sir.” Commander VulHam’s voice issued from the bridge’s speakers. YecTal sighed. Couldn’t his crew do anything without his guiding them through every single step?

“Go ahead.” YecTal groaned.

“Our sensors were right. The shuttle seems to have gone through heavy systems failure before it reached us.”

“Any idea why?”

“None that I can tell sir. We’ll open it up and . . . hold on . . . what the fuck is he doing! We need to fly in that thing!”

“Excuse me commander, what’s happeni–” sudden screams and curses issued from the speakers.

“He just flew out of the shuttle”! “Take cover”! “Back up back u– oh shit”!

“What’s happening someone tell me what’s going on! Ensign, give me video feed of the cargo bay!”

“Video feeds went down when we got too close to that solar flair. The engineer’s haven’t fixed them in the cargo bay yet.”

“Well get me something I don’t care! Thermal imaging, UV anythi–” a voice that was doing something other than swearing or screaming leapt out of the speakers.

“It was that creature UtMot was supposed to be bringing in sedated! It’s up and it killed UtMot and now it’s killing everyone in the boarding party! It has a fucking Fusion Sword!” A tell–tale scream issued from the speakers. “He just took out WilHelm!” the voice shouted. “We keep hitting it and doesn’t die! It doesn’t even slow down! We’re just pissing it off, we need back u–” the transmission cut into static. The bridge was silent with fear. YecTal couldn’t allow it to show, although he himself was frightened. UtMot had said he knew the correct dose of sedative! Now he botched up and dropped demonspawn into his cargo bay!

Controlling his fear and anger, YecTal stood up, allowing his men to see him proud and tall. Calm. “We were prepared for this eventuality. Everyone get on your combat harnesses. Officers arm yourselves with the anti–tank pulse–guns. Flood every compartment of the ship with Yavim–8, I don’t care if it won’t do any good.” Thankfully every member of the crew had been given immunity to the deadly virus Yavim–8. UtMot had expounded in length upon the creatures incredible immune system, but every little bit would help. Besides, it couldn’t be completely impervious.

“Ensign, set a course out of this star system. I don’t want to be detected while we’re dealing with this mess. Once we’ve cleaned it up we’ll come back and deal with the crew still left on the station.”

“Where should I set it, sir”? Gosh darn it. Had he not said out of this star system?

“I don’t care!” YecTal roared. “Set it for the other side of the galaxy for all I care, we’ll be done with this in two hocs (5 minutes) anyway!”

Turning on his heal, YecTal, already in his advanced Mark V combat–harness with personal security–field and shield – a gift from his wife – plugged the anti–tank pulse–rifle he had set aside for himself. Adjusting the sheath of his ceremonial Fusion Scythe, although he might have to use it soon, he set to trying to clean up the mess UtMot had left for him.

The first corridor I entered outside the cargo bay was empty. That boded well for Dick’s theory that there might not necessarily be a full crew compliment. I sprinted towards what I was pretty sure was the bow of the ship when something that looked like steam started issuing from air vents in the ceiling. I couldn’t escape the colossal amount of it, but it didn’t seem to hurt me, so I just ignored it. It screwed with my visibility though. I suddenly wished I wasn’t carrying a glowing sword. I turned it off, running as quietly as I could. A noise up ahead made me pause and crouch, willing myself to become one with the steam. I suddenly wished I’d taken Yoga or something.

A group of 5 appeared out of the steam in front of me, but didn’t shout in alarm the moment they rounded the corner. They couldn’t see me! Yet. One of them had a significantly larger ray gun, to the point that it had to be supported by a shoulder strap rather than have him lifting it only with his arms like the other in the group were doing with their smaller counterparts. Not wanting to lose my advantage, I leapt at the one with the big gun, turning on my lava sword and bellowing as I flew through the air. I landed 50 centimeters in front of him and laid about me with my sword like a infant given a wooden spoon whilst playing with his siblings. In case you were an only child, I basically just whacked everyone over the head with it, but when you’re using a lava sword instead of a spoon, it’s rather effective.

The small group never stood a chance, as they were too close together and too unaware of my pretense to be of any real danger. The problem arose when another group heard the commotion and entered the fray before I’d finished up with the first group. I was finishing up with the only remaining member of the first group when he was liquified and a massive energy pulse shot through him and took me in the waist. At least, it would have had I not been wearing the lovely personal shield Dick had given me. I wasn’t wearing it for long. He had been right about it’s capacity, the thing shorted out after one hit, at least I think that’s what the smoke and sparks meant. It didn’t matter though, they had kept me from getting hit by one pulse, and that was all I needed.

I jump–flew in a zig–zag patter, avoiding the shots they threw at me. They were so slow, they always seemed to be shooting at where I had been a second ago. I felt like a movie action hero but in real life. Once again I went for the one with the anti–tank ray gun first, then finished off the auxiliaries. They kept making these convenient little clumps for me, all I had to do was swipe around with the lava sword a few times and I had nearly gotten everyone one way or another.

The next hallway had another group of five which I finished off in the same way, except for one little guy armed only with a pistol – poor bloke – who broke away from the main group, which earned him a quick sprint and the failure of one of the doors in the hallway that he tried to use as a barrier. I don’t know what they make spaceship door hinges out of, but they need to find a better alternative.

The next room was a common lounge like the one in the cargo ship, except it was significantly larger and had a group of 10 ant–lizards spread out in a semi–circle around the door I’d just come through, all waiting for me, their guns pointed straight at my chest. Dang, this one was going to require a lot of jumping.

The search and destroy parties had been an absolute failure, and YecTal had lost 15 good men because of his foolishness. He’d basically split his men into serving sizes! Now his men were fighting a defensive battle, digging into strategic fighting ground or choke points.

“I can hear it in the hall outside.” PitRuk, YecTal’s tactical officer, said over the bridge’s speakers. “What was that? Did you hear that sound? Did he just rip a door off it’s hinges or something”? Normally that would be a joke. It wasn’t funny this time. The sound of the door opening could be faintly heard, accompanied by PitRuk’s shout.

“Open fire! Shit, someone draw a bead on him! Fuck, hold still! Friendly fire friendly fire watch you’re aiming! Don’t aim at where he was you idiots! Ha! Take that yo– crap he’s still up! Someone take him down take hi–” PitRuk’s yell was cut off mid–word. His radio continued transmitting, but other than a few shots and a quickly stifled yell, there wasn’t much more to hear.

The remaining bridge crew had all turned a garish shade of grey, even though their skin was green. YecTal hoped he didn’t look the same. Making his voice as confident as possible, he shouted for no other reason than to snap the bridge out of its collective trance. “Well? What are you all staring at? It’s coming from the starboard side of the ship! We know which door he’s coming through.” The bridge had four doors, two leading to opposite sides of the ship, the other two leading to the halls where you could access the escape pods. It spoke of the valor of this crew that none of them even glanced at either of those two doors. “Find your cover and prepare to deal with this abomination which thinks it can cross a Robalin crew and live to talk about it!”

As the bridge crew began setting itself up, YecTal surreptitiously began entering his command code into his captains wrist–console, readying the automated self–destruct, setting it to the voice activation setting of the shortest countdown available: one hoc (2 minutes 30 seconds). If this creature was going to kill him, which seemed likely, the least he could do would be to drag it down with him.

After the common lounge I hit the engine room, at least that’s what I assumed. A massive glowing tube stood in the center of the room, making the sound that eminated through the ship as it propelled it in speeds defying rational thought. There were also a total of 15 lizard–ants arrayed around the room, all too far apart to score a multikill on any of them. The moment I entered the room they opened fire, and I did the exact same thing I’d done in the last room. I did my best impression of a Mexican jumping bean. I actually don’t know what those look like, or what they even are, but the words form a picture of little kidney bean wearing a sombrero bouncing around like an entire bag of unpopped popcorn contained in one bean, and I figured that’s pretty much what I looked like, minus the sombrero.

I was actually getting really tired, but I jumped my little heart out. The number of pulses coming my way was ridiculous, and I had to be careful I didn’t jump into any. As it was I was hit multiple times by smaller pulses, but I was mainly just avoiding the big ones. There seemed to be three lizard–ants with anti–tank ray guns, and they were the first I went for. Flying past one I scored a slice across his face. Leaping down to another I bore him to the ground as the lava sword stabbed down through the crown of his head. The last guy was on the other side of the room, so I decided to take a roundabout way of getting to him. Wrong move. Halfway through my first leap one of his shots hit me. Well, half hit me, but it was enough to drive my breath away and fling me off course. I hit a wall of consoles and fell to the ground.

I rolled – see there’s that move again – and the wall behind me was obliterated in a shower of sparks and debris as it was assaulted by 12 heavy ray guns and an anti–tank ray gun. I sprang to my feet and made a jagged bee–line for Tanko–the–crazy–demolition–lizard. He missed on his next few shots, and his failure to score a successful hit on his fourth shot lost him the privilege of taking a fifth. And to keep his life. After Tanko it was relatively simple to get through the rest. I think I was so bruised that I wasn’t even noticing the heavy–pulses anymore, although if I lived this, which was looking more and more likely, I was going to wake up in some serious pain the next morning. Thankfully my abuse of alcohol had made me very accustomed to pain in the morning.

Once I was finished with engineering I looked around. The FTL drive had stopped humming. I guess shooting out all the consoles in engineering affected it or something asinine like that. Whatever it had been, we weren’t moving again any time soon. Counting up in my head I figured out how many I’d gone through so far. 60. Dick you lying little whore!

Letting my rage fuel my flagging limbs, I set off to the last pair of doors ahead which I hoped would be the last room.

In a desperate ploy YecTal had ordered the bridge door’s sealed. He had felt a moment of hope until a Fusion Blade suddenly appeared through the door and began melting it down. Oh. right. The thing had a Fusion Blade, because that’s all YecTal needed. It seemed life heard how disgruntled he was with it and suddenly decided to throw him a bone. The Fusion Blade shorted.

+That’s why they aren’t supposed to be used to cut through bulkheads+ YecTal thought smugly. Then the door shook in its frame and a massive dent appeared in the door.

+Are you fucking kidding me!+ he shouted in his mind, but outwardly he set his jaw and waited for the door to buckle. It didn’t take long. One of the storage crates kept in engineering suddenly burst through the door. It looked like the thing had used it as a battering ram, which wasn’t an encouraging thought since those crates were extremely heavy. The crate flew into the room and fell on YecTal’s chief science officer who had been crouching too close to the doorway. The creature flew into the room a second later. It literally flew, soaring in a dive and tackling a hapless lieutenant.

The bridge crew opened fire, but it was just as PitRuk’s one sided shouting match had indicated, the thing was too fast. It would jump to one officer, crush his neck, steal his gun, and then throw the gun at it’s next victim. The throws were insanely powerful, and YecTal watched in amazement as it’s throws were shown to be just as deadly as it was, which didn’t help as most of the projectiles hit him. His personal security field, able to block solid objects, was overwhelmed after two hits. Soon YecTal, bloodied and firing with only one arm, the other two broken, and Ensign BecMeq were the only two alive. The Ensign didn’t fare any better than his crew mates, but to his credit he continued firing until the end. He did offer one thing to YecTal that the others hadn’t, however. An opportunity. The creature was slowing down. Ha! It had taken on 67 Robalin warriors alone with just a Fusion Blade and it was tired! Apparently 68 was one too many. Killing BecMeq, it stood still a moment longer than it should have and YecTal finally found his aim.

He pulled the trigger and the anti–tank pulse–gun responded with a massive kinetic pulse which took the creature full in the gut, flinging it across the room where it slammed against the wall and slid down to the floor behind the helm’s console. YecTal could see the bridge was in flames due to the multitude of sparks coming from broken displays broken by pulses which only seemed to miss, but he would deal with those later. YecTal walked around the console, limping after being hit by several of his crew mates pulse–guns, to where he could see the creature gasping for breath as it lay on the floor.

+Good heavens. It’s still alive+

He wasn’t one to gloat, and aimed his gun at the creatures head to finish the job. He let his gun get a little too close. The creature, suddenly alive again, though YecTal couldn’t explain how, yanked his gun from his arm, snapped it in two and threw the pieces at him. YecTal grunted as he forced one of his already broken arms to take the brunt of the impacts, which hurt like hell, and knocked him from his feet. He scrambled to his feet as quickly as he could, seeing the monster charging him. YecTal drew the curved blade of his Fusion Scythe and swung it at the creature. It dropped to the ground, the sword whistling over its head. It kicked him from it’s lying position, sending it’s foot up into his midriff and flinging him across the room in the same way the anti–tank pulse had to the creature.

As he flew through the air, YecTal’s mind, sharp despite the pain, knew he had lost. Before he crashed into the wall and unconsciousness, he managed one word: “Activate.” The computer registered it’s Captains final order.

I took too long taking out the second to last lizard–ant remaining on the bridge. For my pains I received an anti–tank round straight to the stomach. It picked me up and flung me 6 meters where my flight was abruptly halted by a wall. Ow. Ow ow ow ow ow ow ow ow ow ow OW! It kind of hurt, but I shook it off. Really I was fine, it was nothing, it just felt like it’d put a fucking hole in my gut. Thankfully I had fallen behind a console and Captain ’Roids had to walk around it in order to get to me. I was happy to see he was limping. The guy was tough, I’d give him that. Most of his fellows had buckled after getting hit in the chest with one of the their friends guns that I had thrown, but this guy had taken 4 and was still up. Then he stuck the gun in my face. Rookie Mistake. Sensing that the battle wasn’t over yet, my adrenaline surged once again. Whew, that felt good.

Grabbing his gun I broke it and threw the pieces at him. That knocked him down and I rolled back to give myself some breathing room. When I finally got to my feet and the world stopped spinning – maybe I should start rolling less – I could see ’Roids standing up. I charged. He pulled a Lava Scimitar from a sheath on his back and swung it at me. Dang I wish I had my sword still, we could have had a light–saber battle. He was too slow though, which is why I was able to dodge his very well timed strike by dropping to the ground. I didn’t think I’d have enough time to get up, so I kicked him from my position on the ground. It was significantly more effective than I thought it would have been, flinging him across the room. Heck, maybe I should have been kicking guys all this time.

As he flew through the air he croaked out an unintelligible word. I guess the computer understood him, because red lights started flashing all over the place and a bunch of symbols appeared on every display that wasn’t leaking sparks. It was similar enough to the few science fiction movies I’d seen that I didn’t stop to question what it was. Self–Destruct sequence.

+Shit!+ I had to find a way off the ship, and fast. I grabbed Roids’ Lava Scimitar – I doubted he would be needing it anymore – and ran to one of the doors that I didn’t know where they led. You could call it coincidence. Or maybe it made sense, since I hadn’t seen any escape pods during my entire time here, but when I went through that door I entered a long hall that ran the entire length of the ship, and on the right wall was the entrance to escape pod after escape pod, at least I assumed that’s what they were as each was like a little cockpit with two oddly shaped seats. I clambered into the nearest one and looked for anything I recognized.

My eyes found the red button. I knew what to do with that. I had just placed my finger on the button when a bellow sounded behind me and ’Roids, all lively once again, flung himself into my pod and started hitting me with a flurry of kicks and punches, even from his fractured arms. He hit my elbow and my finger jammed into the button. The pod was ejected in a quarter of a second of pressing the button and we were shooting through the stars away from the ship in another quarter second. As he fought me, my respect for him grew, but at the same time I pitied him. He was even more hopelessly outmatched than if he’d been carrying a ray pistol. Still, I wasn’t going to humiliate him, and I reached up past his furious but weak blows and snapped his neck. Now I had the problem of limited space and a dead Ant–Lizard. Great.

You know, they don’t make escape pods with comfort in mind. Or engines. I could just float. Waiting. Without water. Or food. At least I had life–support. Yeah. I was getting pretty thirsty by day two. I passed out after that. I really need to stop doing that. I miss a lot when that happens.

“Soldier Manthlel! Get up! you have a new bunkmate.” Manthlel groaned. Why did squad leader Trxcl seem to try and find any excuse to wake him up? He hadn’t meant to spill the bleta broth all over the commander’s favorite book, really. Ok, maybe he hadn’t tried all that hard to stop it, but it wasn’t something he’d purposely planned out and maliciously executed. But Trxcl actually seemed to hate Manthlel for it. After all, a new bunkmate was hardly something worth waking him up over.

Manthlel changed his mind when he saw his Bunkmate. He was the strangest, smallest creature he had ever seen, although he’d heard the Corti and a few other species were shorter. Never seen them for himself. Pink skin, brown hair, short but . . . dense, and thin. It didn’t look too healthy. “May I inquire as to what it is Sir?” Manthlel said carefully. He wasn’t supposed to ask questions but Trxcl wasn’t that strict, just a jerk.

“I wish I knew myself. We scrapped it out of an escape pod about a ric (30 minutes) ago. Medic says he’s never seen the like before, but it’s not like he actually has a medical scanner. We found a Fusion Scythe and a dead Robalin in the pod with him. The Robalin was wearing the insignia of a ship Captain from the Robalix war. We don’t know if this thing is a criminal or a patriot, but at this point it seems like command is so desperate for men they’ll take either. It didn’t have any identification, or even a translator, but it can obviously fight, so they told me to find a room for it and unless it’s an idiot it can be used for cannon fodder. I told them I’d take it and thought you’d be the best to look after him.” Trxcl smiled. “He’s your responsibility now.”

“What if he attacks me!” protested Manthlel. “We don’t know anything about him! What if he’s a psychopath?!”

“You think he’s too much to handle? For you? A hardened Dominion soldier? Please. I don’t want to hear about this again.”

“Yes sir.” Manthlel intoned with an inward groan.

“Good.” Trxcl turned on a heel, shaking his head as he retreated. “Poor thing. Doesn’t even know it was just drafted into the army.”

Humans don’t make good pets part 12

By guidosbestfriend

Dear Journal,

I am xeno King Arthur.

Except I have an alien lava scimitar instead of some piddly steel sword.

So I’m pretty sure I win.

But at the same time, fuck my life.

Again.

I woke up, which is more than I had assumed I would manage when I had gone to sleep. I think I remembered something about the human body only being able to survive 3 days or so without water, and by my estimate I had been in that escape pod with Captain Roids for a good decade, so pretty close to the 3 day mark unless I missed my guess by much. Once I had woken up, however, any expectations I had had from that point on went out the window.

First of all, I was on a ship, but not a ship I recognized. I was pretty proud of myself that I could recognize the humming of a FTL drive without even trying. What can I say? I’m a quick study when it comes to street smarts. The only problem was that this ship which I didn’t recognize did have some rather disturbing similarities to another kind of ship I’d seen only in the movies. A troop transport. From what I could see of it the ship appeared to be merely one massive room, divided into sections with half–walls. Each of these sections contained 10 bunk–beds, most of which were occupied by aliens of all shapes and sizes, each wearing nearly the exact same thing. Well, not the exact same thing, since the participating species couldn’t seem to agree on the correct number of arms or legs or, in a few cases, heads, but the clothes were the same color at least.

Those clothes were a black shirt and red pants, and I have to say, it was pretty sharp. At least, it would have looked sharp if it weren’t for the numerous sweat stains and the fact that not everyone seemed to be wearing a shirt, but at least the potential was there. I had bigger problems other than the blatant fashion crimes taking place right in front of me, like where was I and why hadn’t I been given such a dapper uniform. I could have pulled if off better than half of the xenos there.

Then the thing I’d been trying to ignore hit me like a fly on the windshield of a Japanese bullet train. I was on a troop transport. I was on a troop transport! I was a troop being transported! Will Smith’s voice entered my mind, helping me out with the words I couldn’t properly say. “Aw Hell no!” I couldn’t be drafted into the army! I had won! I had beaten back the evil lizard–ants and had even managed to survive getting hit by 1 and a half of those anti–tank rounds, and now I wasn’t even allowed to go back and be adored as a hero again? I had just started being able to talk to Mama too! Really! Who did I piss off so badly upstairs that they wouldn’t even let me do a victory lap once I had done the right thing!

It’s fine, I’m good, I’m not mad. I just need to take a deep breath and calm down. I’m going to be fine. How bad could it be, anyway? I was alive, which is always a good start, and they had given me a bed, which meant they could see right off the bat that I was sapient, which was better than could have been said for the experience I had endured last time I had awoken on an unfamiliar ship. It wasn’t like the blue–giraffes had been my home, anyway. I was trying to get to my real home, and if this way was faster than I embraced it. I’m ok. I really am. Deep. Breaths.

As I wasn’t dead I could assume my new hosts, whoever they were, were friendly, or, at least, non–hostile. They had even given me my new alien lava scimitar and its sheath! They weren’t studying me like Dick and Shifty had wanted to, either. What did they want from me then? I knew it looked like a troop transport, so maybe they wanted me to be a cook? Perhaps a worker? I didn’t exactly know on what level these aliens waged war, so I could be something as preposterous as a trench digger, although that would suck to an endless degree. But regardless of what role they wanted me to fulfill, why would they have given me a bunk with the rest of the soldiers?

My eyes fell upon the lava scimitar again. Oh. No. You have GOT to be kidding me! Seriously? They wanted me to be a soldier? It’s not like I wouldn’t make a damn fine one if the soldiers were anything like the xenos I’d fought so far, but the powers that were had no way of knowing that! What kind of idiot would draft someone they found, metaphorically speaking, on the side of the road and just decide “Yeah, he looks kind of mean, he’d make a great addition to our army.” “But sir” the other guy would say, “He’s drunk and passed out and sleeping in a pile of his own feces. And look, there’s a dead guy right next to him. It looks like he just up and murdered that lizard–ant with a sword. You want that in our ranks?” and then the commander would just smile as he slowly nodded, murmuring “He’s perfect.” Who does that? I can tell you right now, no one in their right minds.

Maybe you’d do that to a guy if you were going to training. I mean, I had been in a pretty bad shape, and if someone had offered to let me join the army or stay in my pod with Roids I would have taken up arms right there, but I obviously wasn’t on my way to training. The aliens around me moved with too much confidence. It wasn’t bravado. They were just sure of themselves. They each looked like a fit specimen of their own species, and the way in which they handled themselves as they moved spoke of training and discipline. I also saw quite a few weapons out of weapons lockers and in the hands of their owners, so that might have helped out my observations as well, just a little.

My brooding was interrupted when a sound issued from the top bunk of the bed I was sitting on. From over the side a long, thin face with orange skin and what looked like a multitude of warts poked into my view. It had slits for pupils in its red eyes, and I have to say that I probably would have peed a little if I’d any water to pee. It said something, and I was almost relieved that it wasn’t a bunch of unintelligible clicks. If I closed my eyes I could almost believe that it was some language from earth that I didn’t know, rather than an alien tongue. This was encouraging, since it meant that I actually had a chance at some basic communication with this guy, so long as I was going to be spending a good deal of time with this guy, which I had a feeling I was.

The reason I’d never tried learning any of the blue–giraffe’s words was because I physically couldn’t. I didn’t think they were even able to talk in the same way I was, and I knew they had made several sounds which I would have been hard pressed to replicate. I couldn’t have even told them my name, since it would have just sounded like grunts to them. But this guy knew I was sapient and had similar vocal chords to me. My time here was already off to a better start than it ever had before. I still couldn’t understand what he said, though. Where was a Yoda when you needed one?

He seemed frustrated that I couldn’t understand him, but at the same time as though he had confirmed something. He hopped down from the bed, where I could see the rest of him. He was about 50 centimeters taller than me, and a good deal thinner. He had five legs and 4 arms, but a normal sized neck and, as I had noticed before, orange skin. The warts also seemed to be a general skin feature as well. Poor bloke. He spoke to me again, but this time as though one with the understanding that I couldn’t speak his language and vice versa. Using all four hands to motion towards himself, he said one word. “Manthlel.” Dang it! Now it would have been rude to call him Toad. I was pretty proud of that one too; it was one of my best. Better than Warty, at least. Fine, I guess I could call him by his real name. I might as well get the pronunciation correct as well. “Manth . . . lel?” I said, looking to him in askance. He nodded which I hope meant the same thing to him as it did to me. Confirming it once more in my mind I said it again. “Manthlel.”

Now it was my turn. I learned my lessons well, and I remembered clearly the words my mother had said to me when I was just a boy. “Son,” she said, “Never give your name to a stranger you have just met on the street. School is fine, but outside of school, and to people who aren’t your own age, they don’t need to know your name, and if they ask, just tell them something else.” Well I sure as heck wasn’t in school, and I had no idea how old this guy was, so I wasn’t giving him my name no siree. I decided not to lie to him, however. Lying is wrong, that’s another thing Mother said. Gesturing to myself in the same way he had – except with only two arms – I told him as much as I was willing. “Human.” He mouthed the word several time, then said it back to me in the same way I had when I’d heard his name. “HUman. HumAN. HUman.” I gave him a thumbs up without thinking. Then he reciprocated the gesture.

It was so unexpected that I burst out laughing. I hadn’t seen such a human gesture in so long it felt like I’d gone in for a brofist and he’s returned one with a secret handshake. He smiled at my mirth, or maybe he was getting ready to rip my throat out since I had insulted his ancestress with my laughter or something, I don’t know. He didn’t attack, so I guess smiles meant the same thing to him as they did to me. I was so happy with the progress I’d already made. “Manthlel, you’re already a better friend than any alien I’ve ever met. Just don’t try to feed me lettuce or lock me into my bunk and we’ll be off to a good start. As it is though, you don’t happen to have any purple xeno pig rats do you? I’m starving and I would love some if you happen to have any.” Apparently he didn’t, but he had something even worse than lettuce it seemed.

He took me over to what looked like a bird feeder in the back wall of our cubicle which was also the hull of the ship. In the little bucket, which appeared to be the end of a chute that disappeared into the wall and an area unknown, was a multitude of grey spheres each slightly smaller than my fist. I looked at Manthlel and the spheres, nonplussed. He motioned towards the spheres. I continued to stare at him. Exasperated, he picked one up and bit into it. It looked like it had the constancy of bread dough. “You know what? I’ve changed my mind. Lettuce is what I’m craving right now. Please?” Manthlel just stared at me, encouraging me to take one of the spheres. I was starving, and there seemed to be nothing else, so I picked one up and took a bite.

It tasted like nothing. Not the nothing of water, which is actually something, or the nothing of cucumbers bought from Walmart; this was literally nothing. I had been right about the texture though. It was the feeling of bread dough in my mouth with absolutely nothing registered by my tongue except that there was indeed some form of matter in my mouth. It was disgusting, but at the same time, palatable. I ate it, and it seemed my body was in the mood for food more than it was for satisfying my craving for something with a taste. I ate another one. They were actually filling, despite their size. Still, they were about as large as a small apple, and I hadn’t eaten in days. After the first two I guessed how many I would eat and grabbed six more.

After I had as many as I thought was reasonable I looked back up at Manthlel. He was gaping at me, mouth open significantly wider than I thought his jaw should have been able to go. In fact, I think he had disconnected it like a snakes, and it was quite a horrifying site. I swore and backed away from him, but he just continued to stare. I looked around at the other aliens in our cubicle. I don’t think they had noticed me until now, but they were staring at me with similar expressions as Manthlel. I looked and saw that most of them were holding partially dissembled spheres, except not a one held more than three. “What, I’m hungry!” I protested, “Just because I’m fat doesn’t mean I’m not beautiful.”

Oblivious to how rude their fat shaming was, they continued to stare. I pointedly ignored them and sat down to enjoy my quite literally tasteless meal. I had been very accurate with my guess and felt contentedly full when I had finished off the last of my spheres. I looked up, and sure enough, each and every one of the men – some might have been women – were watching at me, even more shocked than before if that was possible. It seemed like a couple aliens from adjacent cubicles had come to stop and stare as well.

I decided to just ignore the haters, and moved back to the wall where I thought I recognized a tap similar to the one that had been in my cargo bay all that time ago when I had thought I was going to stay there for longer than about an hour. I remembered how Dink had worked it – dang I hoped the kid was alright – and was rewarded by a steam of water running into a trough in the wall next to the sphere depository. The moment my lips touched the water I realized how thirsty I was and drank for nearly two minutes, taking just enough time between drinks to breath and make sure I didn’t puke. They were still staring when I got up and wiped my mouth with the back of my sleeve. “Don’t you guys have anything better to do?!”

It seemed they did, because no sooner had I spoken than an electric buzzer sounded throughout the ship, pausing everyone in their movements. It was eerie. Everyone in the entire ship, it seemed, stood still a moment as the buzzer sounded. Then a collective deep breath ran through the entire ship, as though it was time to face the inevitable. When everyone started moving again, it was with a new sense of purpose, of things to do that could be put off no longer. All the soldiers in my cubicle, or squad I guessed, took out guns from storage bins in their bunks, checking over them with a practiced and efficient ease, although I’m pretty sure I’d seen most of them checking the same weapons only a few minutes before. Combat–harnesses were being donned, and I had the distinct feeling that I was missing out on some serious preparation. The purpose with which everyone was moving did nothing to assuage the fear that was slowly rising in my chest.

Manthlel, quickly got on his gear, then motioned for me to follow him. We walked a short distance to a small booth in the middle of the hall between all of the cubicles. He punched a few keys on a console and a mechanism within the booth clanked and ground as it responded to Manthlel’s request. A gun and a combat–harness were presented by two mechanical arms which came out of the booth. Manthlel grabbed the gun and harness and handed them to me. I knew how to put on the harness, but I think the ray gun was broken. It was all bent up as though for storage, and it didn’t look as though it was supposed to be able to be reconfigured. When I had grabbed the handle and nothing had happened, Manthlel also seemed confused. I looked up when someone else approached the booth, getting out of the way. This new arrival just needed a gun, and when his new weapon was presented to him, similarly bent as mine, he confidently grasped it about the handle and walked away content. I could see why. The moment his hand grasped the thing it seemed to melt and fold upon itself, reconfiguring itself until it seemed to have been custom built for that particular alien.

“Ah.” I said, understanding. “The computer doesn’t know what kind of creature I am, so it doesn’t know how to change to my physiology, and I doubt it’d even let me fire it if it did.” Manthlel seemed to have reached the same conclusion, but he looked a little more put out than I did about it. I tried to reassure him. “Don’t worry about it man, I don’t need a gun anyway. It’d just cramp up my style. All I need is the lava scimitar I got back at my bunk and I’ll be good.” Manthlel didn’t seem convinced. Ok, he just hadn’t understood a word I had said, but even if he had I doubt he would have been convinced. There was nothing we could do, though, so we walked back to our cubicle where I slung the lava scimitar’s sheath over my back, where it fit surprisingly well. I was lucky I still had the sheath, or else I wouldn’t have had a way to turn the thing on or off since it wasn’t genetically sequenced to me like the last one had. Too bad Dick wasn’t here to do that for me. Did I just wish Dick was here? Must have been my imagination.

After everyone in the squad had had time to check their gear and suit up, one of the members, who was perhaps the most fit blue–giraffe I had ever seen, stood up and started delivering a speech or a pep–talk to the group. I hope it was really inspiring, because I missed every word. Guess I’ll never know what was said.

“Reports say the battle’s already underway on Helictor–4, and is going badly,” said Trxcl, giving his usual pre–battle rundown. “It seems that the main offensive line broke and is now fragmented over an area of about 4 bortos (8 kilometers). We’ll be dropping into the thick of it. There have also been unconfirmed sightings of a Vulza, so keep your eyes open. Our squad as well as a few hundred others have been tasked with picking up those we can find of the first offensive and then bring them back to base. We’ll be moving in a roaming defensive circle formation. I don’t want anyone breaking away and looking for their own glory. If we see a Vulza, I want an orderly retreat with covering fire in a layered switchback. Any survivors we find are to be returned to the landing zone and then we’ll go back for more. This is a pack–fight like most of what we’ve dealt with, so any enemies we come across will likely be in groups of ten. The skirmishes will be quick and brutal. Any questions?

”What does Human do? He doesn’t have a gun, and he didn’t understand a word you said.“ Manthlel probably should have kept his mouth shut, but he wasn’t going to let Human die because he hadn’t been willing to risk Trxcl’s momentary anger.

”If he stays out of the way I don’t care what he does. If he starts tripping us up I’ll shoot him myself. Any other questions?“ Trxcl glared at Manthlel, daring him to ask another. Manthlel silently promised Human that he would protect him and keep him from getting in the way.

”Good,“ snorted Trxcl. A klaxon sounded. “Get to our dropship then. You know the drill.”

Manthlel swallowed as he strapped himself into the dropship’s harness. Human seemed to have just realized something and was gibbering away excitedly. What was he on about? He better not be about to puke up the massive amount of nutrient spheres he had eaten. Manthlel guessed he would never find out, for at that moment the transport dropped out of hyperspace and into the middle of the part of the battle that was being waged above Helictor–4. The ship began to shake as its shields began absorbing shots. Trxcl’s squad didn’t get to feel the punishment the ship was taking for long, because soon after dropping out of hyperspace their shuttle shot out of the troopship’s bay and began the long decent towards the planet’s surface.

Things had gotten worse. A lot worse. I know I should have put 2 and 2 together. I mean, everyone had been suiting up for battle, what should I have thought was going to happen? It still didn’t seem real though, as I strapped myself into a seat next to Manthlel. I mean, I had woken up about 2 hours ago, had my first real meal in 3 days in half that time, and was now about to enter battle against an unknown enemy fighting for an unknown cause over an unknown planet. With all those unknowns combined, I was feeling rather confused, and it didn’t help when the shuttle I was in shot out of the troop ship like a bullet and turned its nose towards the planet beneath us. At first I had a horrible feeling as I thought the planet was Earth. Then I checked the continents and couldn’t recognize any of them, but it still looked a lot like earth. Maybe smaller, but there was no way I could be certain.

My discomfort with the current situation was only increased when shuttles on every side of ours started exploding. Every time one of them decided to see how life was as a fireball our shuttle would rock ominously, and the entire way down to the planet I was clutching my harness, white knuckled and sweating. We made it, though I don’t know how. When the shuttle doors opened, I wished we were back up in space. At least it had seemed cleaner up there.

Bodies were everywhere. Eviscerated, exploded, dismembered, you name it, it appeared down there in one form or another. I know war on Earth is terrible, but at least battlefields don’t look like the only form of firearm used on either side was some form of artillery. If someone was dead, then they were the kind of dead that left you unrecognizable. My squad seemed to know what they were doing, however, and they ran out of the dropship, formed a circle, and began trotting towards an area in the distance where the discharge of weapons could be seen. I followed after them, not wanting to get in the way. Manthlel seemed to approve of my position, because he gave me another thumbs up; I am glad I taught him that gesture. I sent one right back at him and he fell back into formation.

My first pitched battle was actually pretty boring for the first thirty minutes or so. We didn’t come across anyone. Really, it seemed like the dropships could have maybe dropped us a little closer to the actual battle. As it was we seemed about 4 kilometers distant from where the fighting was actually taking place. As we got closer, I could see that the fighting was more like a pack–fight instead, with small groups, each about the size of our squad, fighting each other whenever they met an enemy squad. It didn’t look like there was any overshadowing strategy at all, just a bunch of groups gotten together and then told to fight. I was starting to like my position in this army less and less.

I was dragged out of my musings as our group stumbled upon what I guess was an enemy group. Honestly, I couldn’t tell. The enemy group was composed of an assortment of aliens like our own, carrying guns identical to ours, wearing combat–harnesses identical to ours. The only difference was they were wearing white shirts and brown pants underneath their armor. Their group started shooting at our group, however, and my squad reciprocated, so I guess we were at war with them. Not needing any more instruction I drew my lava scimitar – it was even cooler with a curved blade – and leap–flew towards the enemy.

The first ric (30 minutes) after landing was uneventful. The dropship had been blown somewhat off course and had landed 2 bortos (4 kilometers) from where the rest of the ships had landed. Manthlel wasn’t eager to fight though, and the problem was, everyone knew it. Manthlel was a plital. A coward. He should have been dead. His old squad had been completely annihilated when a Vulza, which no one had known was in the battle, had suddenly descended upon the battle that Manthlel’s squad and the Dominion had thought was a victory in their favor. The appearance of the Vulza turned that around. Within a single ric (30 minutes) the Dominions forces had been in full retreat. Manthlel’s squad had been gladly following those orders when the Vulza had decided upon his squad as its next target. Their commander, Crimol, had told his squad to fight and hold as long as possible so that others could get away. Manthlel had taken one look at the creature, and then he had run. Run away from the screams of his friends. Run from the Crimol’s curses. Run from his duty. He hated himself.

What was worse, he had lived to tell the tale. The Dominion was losing, although it didn’t want to admit it, and was desperate for trained soldiers. Manthlel had been reassigned to a new squad to fill up some of the holes in the paperwork, but Manthlel knew it was a good as a death sentence. The men of his new squad hated him, just as he did himself, and he knew that if he ever got in trouble, he wouldn’t be able to count on any help from his team.

Fate, it seemed, didn’t care about Manthlel’s wishes. After a short time jogging, Trxcl’s encountered their first enemy squad. It was an ambush. One moment they were jogging towards where they could see pulse–gun fire, the next they were surrounded on all sides, confused and dazed as enemies appeared where only churned dirt had been before. There wasn’t a Vulza with them, however, as though Manthlel’s squad could have missed one of those and so Manthlel, perhaps not calmly, but steadily, aimed his gun and fired, concentrating his fire on one opponent at a time as he had been trained, trying to wear down his enemies personal shield. Manthlel never got the chance to finish. A blur of brown, whitish–orange, and glowing red flew towards the enemy with which Manthlel had been engaged. The blur shot passed the unfortunate soldier, who immediately stopped firing, which confused Manthlel, until he realized that the soldier had a glowing hole in his gut, left by a Fusion Scythe.

+Human?+

It was Human. Manthlel forgot about the enemy. Forgetting to keep his jaw connected for the second time that day as he watched in awe as the short, bipedal creature moved with the speed and deadly grace Manthlel had only ever seen in a Vulza. Human seemed just about as deadly. Jumping from one enemy to the other, he stabbed, sliced, and chopped his way through the ambush which would most likely would have cost Trxcl half his men if it weren’t for the intervention. Only after a third of their men were dead did the rest of the members of the ambush even realize that they were quickly taking casualties. All fire turned against Human. Nearly all of them missed, and the few that did hit were absorbed harmlessly by his combat–harness. How would they have hit something like that anyway? He changed directions so suddenly and with such precision that the only way to hit him was to shoot all around him and then some.

The enemy squad was dead in perhaps a ri (1 minute). The surviving squad was silent for about that long as well. Manthlel found himself silently laughing as he remembered his promised to protect Human in this upcoming battle. Human had probably just saved his life, and it was only the first conflict of the battle.

“Well.” Trxcl spoke slowly into the silence. “I don’t know what your new bunkmate’s on, Manthlel, but I’ll have some of whatever he’s having.”

This battle was intense. Not in the same way my previous alien battles had gone. Those had actually contained more action than any of the fights I was finding down here. No, it was intense because they just kept coming. I’d kill off one group – my squad was basically just letting me do my thing at this point – rest for about half a minute, then run into another enemy squad. I was exhausted. My jumps were a mere three meters now, and were significantly slower. During the last few skirmishes my squad had even managed to take care of a few enemies before I had been able to attend to them.

I found myself thinking these thoughts as I was wading my way through another enemy squadron. I was rudely interrupted when my personal shield gave out and I received a shot to my heart. The worst thing was, I had a bruise there, or maybe it was several. If you’ve ever gotten a bruise after someone punched you, you’ll know how much those things smart. If you’ve ever been punched in that same bruise again, you know that the pain increases exponentially rather than linearly.

The pain focused me like nothing had that day, and I got a whole new burst of adrenaline. I was really starting to rely on that so that I could just feel normal. I hacked the head off of the offending alien, whipping my sword around to slash the legs off of another xeno behind me. He fell on top of me, which was rude, but at least that gave me something to throw at one of his companions that was a little further than I wanted to run. Really, if it wasn’t for the fact that I was in a battle, I probably would have been pretty bored. I took a few more hits, which hurt, but I got through that squad just fine with only a little help from my friends. Hey, at least they were good for something.

Manthlel had been worried Human’s personal shield for the past few ris (few minutes). It had taken quite a few hits despite his blinding speed, and it wouldn’t hold out forever. Just as he had feared, during the middle of another skirmish, Human’s shield took one too many hits too fast. It collapsed, and a final shot found its way through the chaos Human had created in the enemy’s midst and hit him in the upper chest.

+Fuck, and here I had thought I might get through this battle unscathed. You fought beyond belief, little Human. You won’t be forgotten+

Manthlel hiked his gun back into position and continued firing. That’s when he noticed that Human wasn’t dead. He was in fact, very much alive.

+But, his shield went down! I saw it fail! Didn’t I?+

As Manthlel watched, Human was hit once again, but aside from momentarily causing him to stumble, it seemed to have no more effect on him than it would have against a Vulza.

+What is this creatur– Fuck! Not again!+ His jaw was really getting on his nerves today. Trxcl was shaking his head, muttering something about “what he’s having”. Cresh, one of the three heavies in the squad, hiked his anti–tank gun on his shoulder and blew out a long breath. “I don’t know what hellhole he came from, but Human fights like a Vulza, just smaller.”

“And fewer teeth.” Piped in Yicka, the squad grenadier.

“And fewer scal–” Rekt, another heavy, was cut short as the object of their jests suddenly decided to remind them of the reason it deserved their respect.

I admit it. I had said that the battle was getting bored. Why I ever let such an idiot statement into my head I have no idea, but I paid for it dearly.

Dragons are real. Check that. Space dragons are real, and they’re every bit as terrifying as they are in the stories.

I guess I’d better specify which stories. Not the Inheritance Cycle, because dragons aren’t magical and don’t talk inside your head. Not Game of Thrones, because these dragons actually show up. Not Dragon Tales, because . . . just . . . not Dragon Tales. We’re talking the original dragons, like the dragon from King Arthur and the Dragon. The kind of dragon that’s basically just a massive killing machine covered in scales stronger than steel. There’s none of that wisdom or magic shit. Just claws, teeth, and a whole lot of speed. And I was staring at one.

First of all I couldn’t believe it. Here? In this world of fragile beings who were slow, weak, and couldn’t make a serious ray–gun to save their life? Then I hoped it was like the rest of the life I had seen so far, until it jumped the 20 meters between it and our squad with the lithe grace of a pouncing tiger and in about half the time. I barely jumped out of the way, and I mean barely. When I landed I was covered in dirt thrown up by the dragon as its claws gauged massive grooves into the earth where I had been standing before. Another one of it’s claws gouged the earth at one of my squad mates feet as well, except he hadn’t had the foresight to jump out of the way like I had. Shit.

My squad started running as a disorderly mob, and I would have joined them. But I didn’t. I can’t explain it, but I felt protective of them. Even though I’d just met them, they seemed like children to me. They were slow, clumsy, and seemingly new to war, at least war as even I had seen it through my second hand experience. I couldn’t run. That would be abandoning them. This dragon was a being like me, at least as far as my new wards were concerned. Both of us were creatures of death. Faster, stronger, and harder than they could ever hope to be, sweeping away their greatest defenses as though they were merely air. Unstoppable. How could I run away from this foe? I was their only chance. I was their monster from hell. I guess it had only been a matter of time before I met another one.

I turned to face the dragon, raised my scimitar, bellowed a challenge, and charged.

Manthlel was crying. Not because of fear, but out of shame. He was doing it again. He was running from a foe that he couldn’t beat because he was afraid, even though his sacrifice might have meant the difference between the life or death of another. He had been given a second chance to redeem himself, and he was making the same mistake. This was why his tears streamed as he ran. Because he was a coward.

A sound like nothing he had ever heard before stopped Manthlel dead in his tracks. It wasn’t actually all that uncommon. It was just a yell. The battle field was filled with those, dripping with them, stained with them. The screams of the dying would haunt this battle field for days after the fighting was over. So why was this yell different? Manthlel looked to its source and saw why.

It was Human, charging the Vulza, Fusion Scythe raised above his head, challenging it in the very moment it was victorious. The rest of the squad, which Manthlel could now see had been running as well, watched in shock as the small alien charged the beast that could not be killed. The yell was different because it was an order. The shouts that filled the battle field were pleas for a savior and cries for release. The screams of the dying and doomed. This was a command. An order directed at everything in its path. A demand that every obstacle bend before it. A promise to anything that wouldn’t bow. An assurance of destruction.

The challenge shook Manthlel to his core, bringing hope where there had once been fear. The fear was still there, and in great abundance. But it was no longer the fear of a frightened creature struggling to deny the inevitable. It was the fear of a man who was fighting for the right to continue to live. Manthlel soon found himself giving voice to the shout as well, turned around, and charged back the way he had come. The squad followed suit. It was a good thing they did. Human was having problems.

I may have been a creature from hell compared to your standard alien, but even as much as I outclassed them, this thing outclassed myself even more so. What had I expected, it was a M–––––f–––ing Space Dragon (I respect my mother and you should too)! I’m lucky I hadn’t jump attacked it, or else it would have swatted me out of midair and that would have been the end of my defiance. It swung it’s left forelimb at me, which I ducked. It recovered instantly and jumped at me, attempting to crush me through shear force of impact. I dived to the side, but it clipped my legs and sent me spinning into the ground. I hit hard, feeling the vibrations in the ground as it landed, spun around and charged me, preparing to finish the job. I knew I was about to die, but who knows, maybe I still had luck. I tried my best move and rolled. It worked. The dragon ate a mouthful of dirt as it closed it’s maw about the ground where I had been moments before.

The problem after you roll is that you have to stop rolling eventually and take the time to get up. This dragon wasn’t going to give me that time. I finished my role, and could see its clawed foot rushing down to greet me. Fuck.

I was blown out of the way of the dragon’s strike by an unknown force. Actually, I’d felt that before. Someone had shot me out way of imminent death with an anti–tank pulse–gun. At least, they’d shot the ground right next to me, which was enough to send me flying several meters out of the dragons reach. It hadn’t come quite fast enough, though, and the dragon’s claws left three red gashes across my back. This was the first time an enemy had made me bleed, and I got to say, it scared the shit out of me, and hurt me more than anything I’d felt in space combat so far.

My new friends were helping me, and boy did I need it. Unfortunately, aside from the helpful push, I don’t think they were managing to do anything but annoy it. Their weapons were even more ineffectual against this beast than they were against me. Heck, I doubt they were even bruising it. It completely ignored them, jumping after me, the only real prey it had found this entire battle. I knew the feeling. As scared as I was, I’d never felt so exhilarated. Springing to my feet, I dashed to its side, ducking under its lunge and scoring a hit on its back leg. It swiped it’s tale at my feet, which was a really good move, because it worked, and I was on my back again for the second time in the fight.

It spun around, attempting to put me into the same position as before. I knew where that would lead, however, and instead curled up into a ball and somersaulted towards and under the beast, getting out of its immediate line of sight. This is how I know it wasn’t as sapient as dragons in modern stories, because if it had been intelligent it would have just smashed its body against the ground and me with it. Instead it whipped itself around like a cat trying to find the mouse it had just lost, by which time I’d gotten back to my feet and had leapt for its side. It turned into my strike, which meant I stabbed its shoulder rather than its lungs.

Roaring in pain and anger, the dragon snapped its body like a whip, dislodging me and my sword from its shoulder and throwing us 15 meters before we slammed into the ground. My trusty scimitar fell from my hand. Not so trusty after all I guess. I was exposed, out of position for a boost from anti–tank bro, and unarmed. Roaring in triumph the dragon leapt at me to finish the job. It pulled up short again, although more out of shock than anything else.

Human was down. He had lost his sword and seemed dazed from the colossal fall that should have killed him. The Vulza could see that it had won. Roaring in triumph it prepared to leap upon the exposed Human. Manthlel didn’t know what made him do it, but he was close enough, and he did. He took two quick steps and then hit the Vulza in the wounded shoulder with his gun. He didn’t even fire it; he just smacked the deep stab wound with his pulse–weapon, using one of the most advanced personal weapons as a club.

“Fight more than one of us!” He screamed. “C’mon, there’s more than just Human, fight all of us.” It actually worked. The Vulza recoiled, although it may have been in shock rather than pain. When Manthlel got a look at its eyes, he could tell that it absolutely was shock. Shock that such inconsequential a creature had dared to lay a finger upon its mighty side. Manthlel could also see that he was screwed.

Manthlel had distracted it, which was all I needed. He had also put himself within neck hugging distance of the dragon, which was not a good place for him to be. Dragon neck hugs can be lethal. I had regained my feet, and decided Manthlel could use a little boost of his own. Reclaiming my scimitar, I jumped four times to cover most of the distance, then dive tackled Manthlel. I think I broke three of his five legs on impact, but I was able to drag him five meters behind the dragon, which saved his life as the dragon closed its jaws over where Manthlel’s head had been. Pushing myself off of the now unconscious Manthlel, I faced the dragon again. We were both bleeding, tired – myself more so than it – and ready for this fight to be over. It jumped, unfurling its leathery wings unnecessarily, as it only had to cover a short distance. Screaming a challenge, I charged as well.

The dragon should have watched my hips, because hips don’t lie. It attacked with its head, thrusting it forward to sink its teeth into my soft flesh. My soft flesh wasn’t there. I had dived to the right on the final step of the charge, ending up next to the dragon’s now exposed neck. I plunged the sword as deep as I could into the back of the dragon’s skull. It convulsed, hitting me with its shoulder, ripping the sword from my grip, and throwing me another 7 meters. I have to confess; I landed in a bad way on that last throw, and blacked out on impact.

Humans don’t make good pets part 13

By guidosbestfriend

“Why is Muulk always late?” whined Yil, “Just because he doesn’t have legs and can only move using pedal locomotory waves doesn’t mean he has to make all of us wait for him.”

“I think the fact that he’s the Field General of the Dominion military is the reason he can afford to make us wait,” replied Vttmcik’ntyr’kvp’tyyqrrc’mkzcvox, “And I think you should keep your . . . tongue? . . . between your teeth if you know what’s best for you. Just because you’re not technically under the army’s jurisdiction doesn’t mean he can’t make life difficult for you.” Yil huffed, an impressive feat for a creature who didn’t stand upright, settling into a sullen silence. Vttmcik’ntyr agreed with Yil, although he would rather suffer a hernia before he admitted it. Why did Muulk have to be late for this meeting? For the first time since the Celzi had revealed their demon of a weapon, Vttmcik’ntyr felt hope. Hope that the Dominion wasn’t fighting a losing battle. Hope that would be proven genuine or false once the meeting was started.

The first glimmer of said hope had come from a minor skirmish on Helictor–4; an unimportant battle on a small planet. Apparently a single soldier, armed only with a Fusion Scythe, had managed to kill a Vulza. Never mind that the Celzi had bothered to commit one of their monsters to such a minor skirmish. How had a single soldier even survived such an attack, let alone retaliate to the point of vanquishing the thing? When the communications officer in charge first received the call from the commander of the 109th, he had assumed it was a joke, and a bad one at that. Once evidence had been provided there was no denying that it had happened, although Vttmcik’ntyr still did not truly understand how. The important thing was that he had managed it, and he had shown a Vulza could be killed without shooting it in the face multiple times with a coilgun.

Muulk’s shadow lumbered through the door before the General, appearing as though it were attempting to pull its creator through the door at a pace somewhat faster than a crawl. Vttmcik’ntyr knew that was a pointless battle. Field General Muulk was a Gordikl, a species nearly everyone agreed was gut wrenchingly horrid to look upon; It was even worse to view one in motion. Somewhere down the evolutionary chain a Gordikl had apparently decided he was too good for legs; cursing all future Gordikl to have the bodies of enormous slugs. But as Muulk oozed through the door, Vttmcik’ntyr didn’t think he had ever seen anything so majestic. They could finally start the meeting.

“I apologize for my tardiness, but I refuse to relinquish lunch for anything short of my death.” Looking at him Vttmcik’ntyr could easily believe it; although he worried the former would ultimately lead the latter in Muulk’s case. Once he had situated his bulk in the space cleared for him at the head of the table – how would he have used a chair anyway – Muulk motioned with an arm that seemed too small for his body. “Tyyvcl’lkklkzx, if you wouldn’t mind, could you bring us up to date as to your team’s most recent project?”

Tyyvcl’lkklkzx’cttvpxr’kl’nqqtcy’yz rose from his chair, straightening his clothes self–importantly, a smug grin spreading across his face. Vttmcik’ntyr didn’t really like Tyyvcl’lkklkzx. A Rrrrtktktktkp’ch just like himself, he annoyed Vttmcik’ntyr with his greater–than–thou attitude, and the belief that anyone who was not an engineer was not only beneath him in intelligence, but in worth as well. Vttmcik’ntyr had to admit one thing though. Tyyvcl’lkklkzx was good at what he did. He was the lead engineer for any specialized weapons developments commissioned by the military. As such, nearly all of his projects were classified.

“Thank you General,” Tyyvcl’lkklkzx purred, somehow managing to appear even more pleased with himself. “As most of you know, one standard cycle (6 months) ago, during a pointless skirmish on Helictor–4, a lone soldier managed to slaughter a Vulza with a mere Fusion Scythe. Obviously there was something different about him. Upon conducting a biomedical scan of the subject, we discovered that this soldier possesses a physiology quite unlike anything we’ve seen before. At least, anything we’ve actually been able to strap onto a scanner without it killing everyone in the room.”

A holographic display in the center of the table came to life, displaying a scanner readout of a bipedal creature. Vttmcik’ntyr couldn’t be sure of the size, since it wasn’t to scale, but he was unable to notice anything particularly odd about the creature. Truly, compared to Hunters, this thing looked hilariously docile. Admittedly, Vttmcik’ntyr didn’t know how to read bioscanner outputs. Something had to be special about it though, because every scientist at the table made sounds of extreme surprise, bordering on outright shock.

“As anyone who can actually understand bioscanner readouts can see, this creature’s incredible combat abilities come from an array of biological and even mental systems that have never before been seen. He is only one though, and we do not know where he came from, making it impossible to enlist more of his kind into the military. He alone will not be able to staunch the tide of Vulza and turn this war into a victory for the Dominion. Therefore, we decided to use the information gained from him to attempt to replicate his fighting abilities into something our soldiers could use. There were many excellent ideas as to how to accomplish this, as well as several . . . not so excellent ideas, one including the creation of giant robots to punch the Vulza into submission.” Tyyvcl’lkklkzx chuckled – more to himself than anything – at such a ridiculous thought.

“We decided to focus on his skeletal system and its constituent musculature. His bones are a ceramic matrix composite with a hydroxyapatite, calcium phosphate, and an unknown protein base. We had once considered a similar material for the use in a new generation of combat–harnesses, but ultimately discarded the idea due to the cost required to find the necessary raw materials to create enough for every single troop. This material, however, is significantly stronger than our previous attempt, more than justifying the increased cost which production will require. Using this incredible substance, we fabricated an exoskeletal–harness upon which we affixed a weapon previously assumed to be impossible for personal use.”

The emitter on the table flashed, changing to an image Vttmcik’ntyr instantly recognized, although he’d only ever seen them as a concept, rather than an actuality. A personal plasma rifle. Before the invention of kinetic–pulse weaponry, if one was able to think back that far, a plethora of weapons were used across the galaxy, although most relied upon a soft projectile mechanism. The allure of unlimited ammunition was too great for weapons engineers to resist. It wasn’t long before the potential of plasma weaponry was reexamined.

It made sense. Plasma rifles would be ridiculously overpowered for use as a personal weapon, but who would complain that their gun was too powerful? Even with compression technology as primitive as it was during that time, it was still efficient enough to the point that a single plasma clip would contain upwards of 10,000 shots, which, for all but the most protracted battles, was an essentially unlimited number of rounds. Researchers had assumed creating such firearms would be easy since plasma weapons were already widely used on any medium classed ship worth their salt.

Upon its adaption for personal use however, they quickly encountered several insurmountable obstacles. First and foremost was the recoil. Plasma weaponry required a magnetic coil to propel the shot from the compressor, which created the recoil effect on par with a coilgun. Such powerful weapons were only ever seen on vehicles, turrets, and smaller ships for a reason.

Backlash of such magnitude would turn any unfortunate enough to be holding the weapon upon its discharge into a conglomeration of bloody scraps. Unless the militaries of the future would be handing their soldiers overcomplicated forms of execution, the recoil would need to be solved. The other major problem was the heat. Discharged plasma was hot. Although the combat harnesses could protect from such temperatures for a short time, they would only do so for about twenty shots.

Ways in which to fix plasma weaponry so as to avoid killing its users were never found, for soon after the first prototype had been created, kinetic–pulse technology was invented. Using no moving parts, sufficient, albeit weaker damage output than that of a plasma weapon, and firing a pulse composed completely on energy, resulting in a truly unlimited number of shots, kinetic–pulse weapons were obviously the better choice, and plasma weapons for personal use were completely abandoned. Until now.

“Plasma weapons were never adapted for personal use because of the hazards they presented towards their users. They, unfortunately, conveyed the greatest amount of damage for their size, which is essential if they are to be used as an anti–Vulza countermeasure. With the advancements in today’s technology, however, we have managed to reduce the amount of heat discharge to an acceptable level. At least it won’t melt anyone standing within two borts (1 meter). As for the recoil, the strength supplied by the exoskeletal–harness is so immense that it easily holds up to the destructive backlash. We could probably mount a Mark III coilgun turret on the thing and it wouldn’t break. Such strength did, however, come at a cost. The harness is extremely heavy, though still light considering its strength. Any normal soldier who attempted to move in one unassisted wouldn’t be able to lift a finger.”

“To fix that we installed a muscular system comprised of the most advanced electroactive polymers, biomimetically engineered against the creature’s own skeletal muscle system. Such advanced systems are, of course, quite expensive. I advice that only one soldier in each squad be supplied with one. Even so, the advantage such harnesses convey is undeniably necessary. Not only will a soldier equipped with one be able to kill a Vulza from a short range, they will be impervious to kinetic–pulse fire. Coilguns will still be a problem, but that still makes the harness nearly equivalent to a tank. Questions?”

Tyyvcl’lkklkzx finished in a rush, breathing hard in his excitement. Vttmcik’ntyr knew he should be just as excited, but instead felt a sense of anticlimax. It just seemed to . . . simple. He had actually liked the giant robot idea, although he could see why this was obviously the better choice. Yil, tactless as ever, voiced Vttmcik’ntyr’s thoughts for him. “That’s it? That’s all we had to do? Just slap a big gun on a big harness and we’ve beaten the Vulza? Why the hell haven’t we done this before now?!”

Tyyvcl’lkklkzx, looking as though he’d smelled something unpleasant, graced Yil with a glance, voice dripping with scorn, “Because. We only just discovered how to make the “big harness” in the past cycle. Remember the whole “Unknown Protein” part about this creatures bones? That means it was previously unknown, as in, we didn’t know it, as in, we couldn’t have created it until just now. That material is the only reason the harness is able to avoid being completely annihilated by the recoil of the plasma rifle. Any of our previous materials would have either been to weak or too heavy,” he finished in a huff. “Now, are there any more questions that do not insult my intelligence?”

“No, Tyyvcl’lkklkzx,” Muulk replied hurriedly, before Yil could ask another. “On behalf of the Dominion, I would like to thank you and your team for your incredible efforts. You are dismissed.” Once Tyyvcl’lkklkzx and his ilk had left the room, only the military personnel and Yil remained. As loath as Vttmcik’ntyr was to admit it, the Dominion needed Yil, perhaps evern more so than Tyyvcl’lkklkzx.

It had only been through Yil’s prodigious efforts that the military had been successful in the cover–up which was the war with the Celzi Alliance. Of course citizens of the Dominion knew there was a war, but as to its true nature, they were oblivious. No reports of devastating defeats reached the public ear. Even the Vulza were a secret, amazingly. No videos of their terrible battle prowess could be seen within the Dominion, except in meetings of the highest secrecy. Vttmcik’ntyr supposed these new exoskeletal–harnesses, and the soldier they had been derived from for that matter, would remain a secret as well.

Vttmcik’ntyr thoughts were interrupted by Muulks rumbling voice. “I haven’t dismissed everyone because we have yet to decide what to do with this soldier. He’s wasted upon such minor battles as are fought by the 109th.”

“Really sir, how invaluable is this soldier?“ piped up Vttmcik’ntyr, “Yes, it’s amazing that he was able to kill a Vulza, but he’s only one. How much of a greater difference does he make that one rover with a coilgun couldn’t match?”

“I’ll assume from your question that you haven’t read any of the reports I sent you.” Muulk grunted. Vttmcik’ntyr winced. He knew he should have, but really, all the papers had just been incident reports. He had assumed they were just more accounts of the creature killing Vulza, or other similarly heroic acts. Incredible, to be sure, but nothing that could single–handedly turn the course of the war. He was soon disillusioned.

“To bring you back up to speed, over the past cycle the soldier has not only managed to kill three more Vulza, but has also been the reason his squad has been placed on the front line for every single battle.”

“What?!” Cried Vttmcik’ntyr, “That’s a death scenten – wait. How have they managed to be put on the front line more than once or twice? No one on the front survives, it’s a meat grinder!”

“Exactly,” Muulk said, grinning at the expression on Vttmcik’ntyr’s face, “Not only has this soldier successfully led the charge of fourteen battles, he has somehow managed to keep his entire squad alive at the same time. That squad has only lost three of its members since he was enlisted, on a troopship that has such a high mortality rate that entire squads have to be replaced after every battle. This soldier has turned perhaps our worst troopship into one of our most effective. As happy as I am that we no longer have such a substantial drain upon our newly trained personnel, the reason the 109th was assigned to such an inconsequential sector was because every better division was needed somewhere else.”

“We’ll send them some of the new harnesses,” Muulk continued, “Which should be enough for them to deal with what they have over there. Aside from the four Vulza that were, for some unfathomable reason, committed to such a minor front, there aren’t any rovers, turrets, or tanks over there. If these new suits are as powerful as Tyyvcl’lkklkzx says, they should only need three or four. Now that you completely understand how potent this creature is, what should we do with him? He’s wasted on the 109th. Ideas?”

Opening his mouth for the first time since the meeting had started, Ickret, a mere three star general and therefore most junior member at the table, spoke. “I’ve actually been looking into that. It turns out that the squad Human – that’s the soldier’s name – was placed into was already one of the most veteran squads of the 109th. They were considered good enough that a plital was reassigned to their squad when his original was annihilated by a Vulza. Apparently it was reasoned they would be the least affected by not having a full complement of competent members, and it made the paperwork look pretty. Now that they’ve survived more frontline charges than most 109th squads do battles, they’re by far the most skilled on that ship. I think they would survive a reassignment to the 74th.”

“Surely not,” snorted Vttmcik’ntyr, “I don’t care what kind of experience they’ve gained on the front. The 74th is the only division that we had before the war that isn’t dead now. They’re the only division we can count on giving us victories. The kind of mayhem they’re thrown into on a [weekly] basis would kill anyone from the 109th from the shock alone! There’s a reason we consider the entire 74th to be a special forces division and send only the most gifted recruits as replacements. It’s because they’re expected to go up against everything the enemy has and come out alive. The 109th gets those we don’t flunk out of boot–camp because we’re so desperate for troops. What makes you think they could even last a re (5 seconds) with the 74th?”

“Because they have Human,” retorted Ickret. “He’s managed to kill, on his own, with only a Fusion scythe, the creature that is able to crush turrets, flip tanks, and snap rovers with ease. He’s defeated the very thing that has allowed the Celzi to get this far. If he can face down a Vulza, and that squad is able to follow him as he does, what do you think could stand in their way?”

Vttmcik’ntyr didn’t really know what to say to that. Muulk made it so he didn’t have to say anything. “Well then, it’s settled. Human and his squad will be transferred to the 74th.” He seemed overjoyed that someone else had done all the legwork for him, probably because he lacked such appendages. “Now that’s settled, we can finish this endless meeting. I’ve a meal I’ve been dying to get to. Dismissed.”

Dear Journal,

I’ve found a new family.

Oh, and I think I might have messed up last time.

I don’t care though, King Arthur is better.

Who the fuck is St. George anyway?

I’m sorry I haven’t written to you in a while Journal, it’s been kind of hectic. I know I know, stop yelling. Well when you think about it in the scheme of things, does it actually matter how long it was? The point we need to be focusing on here is that I’m back and that I missed you terribly. Trust me, it’s better if you don’t know how long it was. It’s ok, I’m back now you can stop crying. That’s better. Are you ready to listen to my story? Yes? That’s a good Journal.

In case you were wondering, I have not resorted to turning my mental Journal into an imaginary friend due to the extended lack of human contact. I’m perfectly healthy in every way. In the six months (sorry Journal) since I had joined the army, that was surprisingly true, especially given the fact that I was perhaps the most popular target on the battle field. Sure, I was usually in a constantly bruised state, but considering what those shots usually did to anyone else whose shield failed, I was looking pretty chipper.

I’d also been given a new name, although Manthlel and the squad still called me Human: “Vulza’trtr”. I think it was something lame like dragon slayer, but for some reason the first few times people said it they always seemed to get a kick out of it. Aliens, what can you say? To my utter disappointment, I hadn’t been allowed to keep any of their bodies of the dragons I’d killed. I could have made some Dragon Scale Armor! I don’t really know how I would have gone about actually making it, but I’m sure I’d have found a way.

I was lying in bed, munching on the seventh tasteless alien dough sphere of my lunch when Manthlel interrupted my “meal”. I looked up as he started to flail his arms about as though fighting off an exuberant Italian salesman. I would have just enjoyed the entertainment 6 months before, but now I recognized the weird “language” the squad and I had concocted so they could communicate with me. It was extremely simple. Really, it was just a slightly more comprehensive version of the gestures used by the military for silent communication on the battle field, although I doubt their version contained so many variations upon the thumbs up.

<Pack up, we’re leaving soon,> gestured Manthlel, which came across as a finger twirl and then an open palm that made it look like he was waiting for a high five. Really, it would have been a very simple gesture if he had only done it with one of his arms, but for some reason that I had not yet been able to comprehend, he gesture–spoke with all four of his arms simultaneously, making even the shortest conveyance an alarming symphony of twirls and thumbs up.

<Battle?> I gesticulated, making my hand into a gun as I shrugged in question.

<No. We don’t have a word for it. Pack up,> he conducted in reply. I sighed. That hand motion, the same someone who’s drowning makes as they reach towards the surface, was perhaps the second most common gesture, next to the thumbs up. It had been worth it though; to create a sign which admitted a deficiency in our cat fight of a language. After several days of frustrated caveman speak, I had finally managed to get the squad to understand what I had wanted that gesture to convey. Now it was in almost every conversation we had off the battlefield.

I don’t think they quite noticed the grasping gesture my hand had been making at the end of my extended arm, because the sign was starting to look dangerously close to the Nazi Salute, although in Manthlel’s case it looked more like he was saluting hydra with twice the vigor of the usual fanatic. I didn’t feel like correcting them, although it would be great if my laziness led to the first formal contact between humans and aliens looking like a neo–nazi convention. Manthlel walked away, giving me no choice but to cram the last alien dough sphere into my mouth, sling my lava scimitar over my back, and follow him.

<Where are we going?> I motioned, hoping to get a better idea of what this not–battle adventure would entail.

<First, a transport shuttle. Then–> He seemed to struggle with his hands <The troopship, but not the troopship.> Great, now Manthlel was trying to use caveman speak to have philosophical discussions with me. I scratched the top of my head, informing him of my confusion. He seemed to have been holding his breath, hoping that I would catch his drift. He deflated. <Just follow. We’ll talk about it later.> I hated that sign; a shrug accompanied by a bewildered twist of the hands. It usually meant another tedious flail battle of confusion was in the future.

Wherever I was going, it involved a transport shuttle rather than a drop shuttle. Perhaps a barracks? Maybe that’s what he had meant by troopship but not a troopship. I guessed I’d figure it out soon enough.

“What are they thinking?!” burst Cresh for the seventh time since the shuttle had started the two ricta (3 week) trek required to take them from what had become one of the safest divisions and into the most dangerous one by far. “We can’t survive in the 74th! Sure, Human’s basically invincible, but we aren’t! We don’t have the kind of training those guys do.”

“Keep your trap shut Cresh,” Growled Trxcl, “If command thinks we can survive up there then we will. They wouldn’t throw away good men. Not with the reserves in the state they are.”

“What if we’re not being transferred to fight?” asked Manthlel into the following silence. After his stunt with the first dragon and his refusal to run away from the following, the squad had become significantly more pleasant towards him. No, they weren’t really willing to be chums with him yet, but at least they didn’t glare at him every time he opened his mouth anymore. “What if the only reason we’re being taken along is because we’re able to issue a semblance of complex commands to Human? What if we’re just being sent as interchangeable translators?”

This utterance plunged the cabin into an even greater silence than before. In fact, very little was said during the entire trip.

Oh. that’s what Manthlel had meant. It was a transfer. After what I guessed was about 3 weeks, our shuttle docked with another troopship. I would have said it was identical, except for an extravagant paint job the previous had lacked, which attempted to make the lumbering troopship look like anything other than a gargantuan beached whale. Really, these things were just massive space blimps. How do you paint something like that to look fierce? A few minutes later when I got a look at the kinds of soldiers inside the ship, I figured they could have done better by painting the faces of the personnel on the hull.

If I had thought the soldiers on the last troopblimp had looked professional, then these soldiers were ninjas. Every one moved with the stalk of a killer, something I had yet to have seen in any alien. No one kept their weapons in the storage bins under their beds either. Everyone was in full combat gear, which seemed to be somewhat expanded from the usual gear that was handed out. Lava knives, swords, scimitars, spears, and even a twinblade – maybe he’d trade – could be seen on nearly half of the crew, and those without carried boring if no less lethal non–lava versions. Ray guns were also in supply. Everyone had an anti–tank ray gun, instead of just three per group, an well as two heavy ray guns, a pistol, a backup personal shield, and a grenade.

It was the grenades that had impressed me. I had assumed them to be your normal run–of–the–mill explosive type, but they had proven to be far worse. Instead, they seemed to let off some kind of mind–numbing emission that, if you were too close, would fry you brains out. Literally. Those grenades seemed to be the only thing that could legitimately hurt me. In fact, they were even more potent against me, although I don’t know why.

I was lucky my first encounter with them hadn’t also been my last. I had seen it coming though, and assumed it to be an explosive, which would have been just as lethal, so I jumped away from it. Even with three good four meter leaps between it and myself, it had given me a stunning headache when it had gone off. Now my squad could actually do something for me instead of it just being a one way street. I’d make sure no one could shoot them, and they’d make sure no grenades got too close to me. Turns out you can actually shoot these grenades and they won’t go off.

We’d barely had a second to stretch our legs after having been stuck on that shuttle for nearly a month before an alien I’d never seen before approached our blue–giraffe leader. Yeah, I technically knew his name, but how on Earth were you supposed to pronounce something that didn’t sound like it had any vowels in it? I just called him Turkey, because that was kind of what his name sounded like and it was easier to remember than “Terksal” or however you would spell it in English.

This new alien seemed to have gotten the short end of the stick when it came to balance, although it seemed to make it work with a thick tail. Apparently someone had thought it was a good idea to give a horse the legs of a kangaroo. I will say, however, that this particular biological configuration led to an extremely entertaining form of locomotion. Instead of walking like a normal being, it jumped like a kangaroo. With four legs it created an entirely different effect. Prancing majestically to our fearless leader, horse–kangaroo said something in a coughing dialect, hacking away until I was sure he or she was going to collapse a lung. Apparently it made sense to Turkey, because he started clicking orders at us.

Turning to me, he motioned <We are preparing for a battle. First, follow this one and do as instructed. Meet us back here at the shuttle.> Giving him the thumbs up, I followed after the horse–kangaroo, resisting the urge to make a “boing” sound in time with its jumps as I followed in its hop–steps. My fabulous guide showed me to a weapons depot similar to the one Manthlel had shown me upon my first day, except this one was significantly larger. It was still recognizable though.

“Oh no, I don’t need a ray gun. Wouldn’t work for me anyway. I’ve got all I need right here,” I explained, gesturing to my combat–harness and lava sword. Horseroo jumped up and down excitedly, gesturing towards my lava scimitar with his or – nope, check that – his snout. Definitely a he. It looked like he took more after a horse than a kangaroo. I glanced to where his snout was pointing. “My lava scimitar? Wait, can you get me any lava weapon I want?” He didn’t answer, or course, but kept jumping up and down. I tried a different approach. I pointed to my lava scimitar, then at the weapons depot, then held up two fingers. Horseroo cavorted gloriously to a console near the depot. Sitting on his hind legs like a kangaroo, except with another pair of legs rather than arms.

He somehow used his ungainly appendages to hit several buttons on the console, bringing it to life. It was much more interesting to watch this time though, since it fabricated my new weapon right in front of me. I watched as the alien 3D printer gave me a new sword in a matter of minutes. As I watched, I began to consider all the wonderful possibilities this machine could provide if I discovered how to use it. That would be for a later time, however. The machine presented me with my new weapon, sheath and all. I would have asked for a twinblade, but those looked like they required skill to use, so I decided it was better to stick to my unskilled hack and slash method.

Newly armed, I was escorted back to the shuttle by my guide with magnificent leaps. The rest of the squad were waiting. They too had been newly outfitted, each armed to the teeth.

<Follow us to the dropship> Turkey gesticulated.

Taking a deep breath, I followed the squad. Here we go again.

Trxcl seemed to be having difficulty summoning his usual determination as he began to give the squad his pre–game rundown. “There’s not much to this battle as far as strategy, or at least any strategy we need to concern ourselves about. Our orders are about as straightforward as they get. Charge the enemy and punch through their lines. That won’t be as easy as it was when we were with the 109th. There will be turrets, entrenchments, rovers, tanks, Vulza, and if the boys up here don’t do their jobs we might be getting a few Darkbats.”

+You’re not wrong+ mused Manthlel, closely examining his new anti–tank pulse–gun. It was times like these he wished it could actually live up to its name. Apparently there had once been a time when anti–tank guns could actually hurt a tank, but if that had ever been true, it must have been during the very first years of vehicular warfare. Now, you might as well hit the tank with your fists as shoot it with an anti–tank gun. Except for a Fusion weapon, no handheld weapon could harm a modern tank, or even one of the lightly–armored rovers, although it could probably put a dent in those. Manthlel didn’t know how they had been used in the past, but these days they were fastest way to shut down someone’s personal shield, as long as you had the stamina to hold the behemoth thing.

Trxcl wasn’t done yet, although Manthlel had almost stopped listening. “Because of all the coilguns and artillery–pulse fire down there, we won’t be able to use our usual charge tactic.” Shame that, it had been such a comfort. When they had realized that Human couldn’t be seriously hurt by heavy–pulse fire, they had let him lead the charge, the rest of the squad following in a single file line, attempting to cower in the wake of pulse free space Human created as they ran the normally fatal distance towards the enemy encampment. It wouldn’t help them now. Manthlel doubted Human could survive the explosion from a coilgun blast. After all, those were only things that had been able to kill a Vulza before Human had showed up.

“Remember your training, and stick together.” Trxcl seemed to want to say more, but in the end decided to leave it at that, pausing a moment to give Human that odd hand gesture before sitting down. The outer bay doors opened, an open maw into space, and began spitting out waves upon waves of dropships towards the small tropical planet below.

The moment our dropship shot out of the launch bay, I could immediately tell this battle was different from the others I had fought in. The scale was just so much more grand. Ours wasn’t the only troopship. 20 other monstrosities poured a steam of dropships to fall to the planet. The Armada accompanying the troopships was larger than I’d ever seen. Before, it had always been our one troopship, supported by two or three cruisers. In this battle, cruisers were the little dogs.

Behemoths I could only assume were battleships launched plasma bolts several times larger than our dropship at each other, which were somehow deflected by powerful shields. Carriers spewed endless ropes of energy from their turrets, attempting to destroy the small fighters that bit at their sides. Weaving in between the mayhem cruisers and destroyers chased each other, firing furious barrages of pulses and explosive projectiles alike, battering each other’s shields or bloodying the flanks of battleships. Even as I watched, an enemy cruiser got too close to a battleship. A port cannon charged and fired a bolt of plasma the size of a 747. It slammed into the cruiser with a terrible force, cracking the hull with the power of its impact, the heat of the plasma cutting the ship completely in two.

With the appearance of the dropships, the enemy fighters refocused their attention, abandoning the troopships and carriers, determined to make sure not one of us reached the ground. That’s when I noticed the addition our dropship had that the others I had been in before had lacked. A turret. Cresh, one of the heavies, was in the gunner seat, and soon our hull reverberated as the whump of heavy weapons fire emanated from a massive turret on our roof.

Cresh, it seemed, had deadly aim in space as well as on the ground. I counted no less than 5 enemy fighters fall to the precision marksmanship of our veteran heavy; an impressive number considering the speed with which the nimble fighters dodged the majority of the death that was flung their way. As impressive as Cresh’s aim had been, it had no effect on the number of enemy fighters who numbered in the hundreds. That’s when our fighters entered the fray.

Our dropship shook violently as explosion that were far too close for comfort detonated outside the window, whether they were fighters or dropships we often couldn’t tell. A stray shot from a battleship flew into the midst of the minnow fight that was the dropship convoy, destroying everything in its wake, leaving a stream of small explosions until it smashed against the hull of a troopship. The troopship was made to take a beating, even on that magnitude, and its shields held.

When our dropship miraculously hit the atmosphere, the roar of the ship entering the stratosphere was drowned out by the chaos around us. While the cruisers and destroyers couldn’t follow us down to the planet, the fighters weren’t about to let a little air stop them. They harried the convoy’s flanks all the way to the surface, only breaking off when the turrets from dropships that had already landed were able to shoot them from the ground.

Our dropship had been towards the end of the convoy, and many had already disembarked upon the battlefield before us. If anything, the chaos of the ground topped that above. It was like nothing I’d ever seen. First of all, there were vehicles. There were a lot of vehicles. Quick nimble hovercrafts toting two massive guns, one on each side, zipped about the battlefield, chasing each other and squadrons of men who were foolish enough to engage one in a formation. Their massive weapons discharging shots a ghastly shade of red which exploded wherever they hit, causing colossal gouts of dirt and earth and anything else that happened to be it way to erupt as though from a geyser.

Tanks, heavy, though still hovering above the ground, roamed around the battlefield, destroying anything in their wake. Bristling with weapons, they launched volley after volley of devastating fire into anything nearby, sending anything without the armor of a dragon into the void. Actually, dragons were included in the mix as well, and there were quite a few of those. Entire clutches (herd? crapload? flock? fuckton?) roamed around the battlefield, killing indiscriminately among the troops, although I guess the majority of the ones they killed were ours.

A particular group I saw were interrupted in their hunting by an equally angry herd of tanks. The ensuing fight was a sight to remember. The lead tank drew a bead upon one of the dragons with its main cannon, announcing it and its brothers presence by engulfing the unfortunate lizard in an explosion of fire and gristle. The drakes immediately disengaged from the soldiers they had been massacring, leaping at the tanks. The herd fired as one, reducing an entire wave of dragons to ash. Then the lines met. Tanks in the front were completely flipped, smashed into each other, the sound of shrieking metal punctuated by the roars of beasts.

The tanks weren’t dying easily. Unloading everything, every tank that died went out in a blaze of glory as every cannon simultaneously fired, engulfing its aggressor in the light from four ray pulses, two death rays (the ones that fire the red lights), and a flamethrower. More often than not, the ferocity of the attack would leave the victorious dragon dazed and bleeding. The tanks gained reinforcements, and the drakes were incinerated unless they ran.

Similar fights had left the battlefield blackened with ash as the burning husks of tanks and dragon remains lit the area with a choking light. Similar battles raged, adding their own luminance with their various firearms, voicing cries of hatred and despair as they locked in mortal combat for this once flourishing land now made barren.

<Follow!> shout–gestured Turkey, and we dived into the fray. We were noticed almost immediately by one of the light Hover–Humvees, which whipped around to face us, raining down the fire of hell upon us from its side mounted cannons. Unfortunately for it, I had seen it as well. I jump–flew. I shot an astounding eight meters! The gravity here was so minimal! I was even more powerful than I’d ever been, and reached the Hover–Humvee before it had been able to loose more than one shot from each of its cannons. It may have been shielded, but unless it had a force field it wasn’t stopping my lava scimitar. Apparently it didn’t have one. The vehicle may have been strong, but the driver was weak, and as both of my scimitars cut through the windshield as though it were butter, into the driver, and out the back of his seat, I could hear the shock and dismay from the enemies within.

Throwing myself at the window, I destroyed it with my lava sword, bursting into the Hover–Humvee’s cabin where two turret operators and an auxiliary manned anti–tank kinetic–pulse turrets on the roof. It was a small space and I was a small guy. We went well together. Too bad I’m not very good at sharing personal space. The hostiles who only moments before had thought to be our executors soon found themselves on the receiving end of their own devices, and were found equally lacking in stamina. Bereft of its driver and crew, the Hover–Humvee slowed to stop, sliding several extra meters to stop in front of Turkey’s stunned face.

“Please tell me you know how to drive one of these things. I don’t want to have to keep you guys alive this entire time.” Turns out, Cresh did. That guy was just chock full of surprises. Only four guys could fit into the Hover–Humvee’s, and we had 17 guys in total including myself. My squad’s personal shields wouldn’t stand a chance to half of the shots flying around. I had to get each of them behind some stronger shields. That meant I had to commandeer more vehicles. Another Hover–Humvee, having noticed my rather less than peaceful takeover of the last one, eagerly offered itself up to become the next on in my fleet, although I guess it didn’t see it that way.

It suffered the same fate as its brother, however, with my scimitars piercing its driver, then moving on to the beings within. A third fell in a similar manner. As my squad piled into the newest addition, I chose my last victim. The fourth Hover–Humvee was a little beaten up, but that described the majority of the vehicles kicking up dust on the battlefield. It would work though, and became the final member of our flotilla. Now our squad could do some damage. Moving in a tight formation, the simultaneous fire from eight death rays annihilated tank shields in a single shot, destroying them on the next. Dragons foolish enough to approach on their own were quickly destroyed, and any infantry who attempted a rush were gunned down by the withering anti–tank ray pulse fire from the turrets mounted above.

I didn’t need a Hover–Humvee. I had two lava scimitars. Giving Manthlel, who was driving the third Humvee, the thumbs up, I charged with my usual battle cry. There was a long way to go.

Monkeys Reaches Stars

By hume_reddit

“Shoo! Woh kan i! Woh kan i!”

Xiù giggled as the little alien kid ran over chanting the familiar demand. It was morning… or, well, as close to morning as she could guess. She was sure her sleep patterns had shifted over the past month, and there was no day or night cycle here, but she had a routine and her “roommates” had figured it out. Every morning she would stretch and practice her forms, and the aliens – looking for all the world like human–sized bipedal racoons – liked to watch her do it, for some reason.

The little ones were vocal in their admiration, and they were so astonishingly adorable that Xiù couldn’t refuse them. They couldn’t pronounce her name properly, but that just made it cuter. She didn’t know what they were saying, but she’d figured out that “woh kan i” was their way of asking for her to practice.

The adults just liked having their children distracted from their horrible circumstances.

Xiù stood, having finished washing her face in the running sink of water that occupied a single corner of the large, grey room. Her clothing – a simple t–shirt and leggings – were getting grimy and smelly, and her long hair hung limply. Three weeks locked into this large, grey room without a shower was wearing her down. After the first week she’d finally surrendered to necessity and given herself the most miserable and cold sponge–bath ever, using one of her leg–warmers as a cloth, and trying to ignore the curious gazes of the raccoons as she removed her clothing. They may have been aliens, but that didn’t mean she wasn’t blushing furiously the entire time. Still, it’d made her feel better.

She probably wouldn’t need to wash so much if she didn’t exercise, but being a prisoner didn’t mean she wanted to lose her hard–earned muscle tone. It was hard enough to work up a proper sweat in the lighter gravity of… where–ever she was.

She tossed her impromptu washcloth over by her winter coat, which was folded up on the hard slate–grey floor where it had been acting as a pillow since her arrival. She looked over at little Myun and beckoned; the little alien chittered, which she had guessed was their version of happy laughter. The lights of the high ceiling shone brightly upon them as she walked over to a open area of the room and sank into a deep ma bu or horse stance. Myun imitated her, though with far less success. The aliens had long bodies and short, stubby legs, so they had a harder time balancing.

She slipped into the form, letting her arms and legs move with the confidence of endless repetition. Her pace was slow… when she’d first started these exercises shortly after her capture, she hadn’t wanted to alarm the aliens she was imprisoned with. When some of the little ones had begun imitating her, she hadn’t wanted to outpace and embarrass them. So she moved at a rate that was closer to a taiji meditation instead of the violent sharpness of xingyi or swirling movements of bagua.

Beside her Myun tipped over, but chittered in good humour.

Ayma smiled as Myun flopped over again in her attempts to imitate their fellow alien prisoner. The other three children watched in fascination as the human female stretched and contorted and balanced her body in ways that were astonishing. Yet the movements were incredibly graceful, beautiful in their elegance. They didn’t know why she danced for them, but the cubs loved it and it was a welcome distraction, even for the adults.

It helped them forget that they were all lab animals, trapped in a cage.

They’d been snatched by mercenaries on a simple trip between their homeworld, Gao, and the second colony, Gorai. A settler ship full of females and children, the males had spent their lives bravely resisting the invaders, but there had been simply too many of the huge four–armed Locayl, armed with pulse rifles that were several centuries more advanced than their own. Her species was a clever one – they’d progressed from flight to their first space stations in less than two hundred stellar rotations of their homeworld, which was apparently a new galactic record – but they were still latecomers on the scene.

The more helpful of the other species of the galaxy had warned them that it was an unfriendly place, especially for those species that had yet to join the Galactic Council properly. The Gaoians were cautious by nature… the offer to join the Council and the vague hints of consequences if they didn’t had sounded a little too much like bullying, so they wanted to carefully examine the fine–print. They’d been right to be concerned… some of the trade regulations weren’t acceptable, and some requirements impinged on their sovereignty. The sticking points had been worked through, however, and there was hope that they’d be a full, proper member of the interstellar community in less than ten stellar rotations.

It really wasn’t a surprise that some races wished to victimize the Gaoians as they could before they joined the “club”. Their captain and crew eliminated, the females and children had been herded into cages on the mercenary ship. Their own vessel – and the evidence – had been destroyed with a core overload. Trapped in the cages, they’d been taken to this installation on an unoccupied world, shoved into this single large room with its embarrassing amenities, and left to wait for their fate.

Every day, someone different would be taken. The ones who returned spoke of experiments. It was no shock to learn that their captors were Corti, the vile scientists of the galaxy. Blood was drawn, biopsies taken, fur shaved. One of the young females had returned missing an eye… another had her arm taken below the elbow. Their bodies could be repaired, if they managed to get home, but their spirits would remember. And they were the lucky ones… two of their number had never returned at all.

It made Ayma’s whiskers quiver with rage. On Gao, females were sacred, second only to the cubs. The males had many clans, but the females had only one. Every female was clan with every other, and woe be to those who harmed the clan. The males would compete and war as their instincts demanded, but they always kept it amongst themselves. A male who harmed a female would find it impossible to mate. If a male harmed a cub, he would be torn apart by every female in reach and by every male who ever hoped to have a cub of his own.

So far the Corti and their thuggish henchmen had yet to try to take one of their cubs, but Ayma knew it was only a matter of time.

It shamed her to think it, but she hoped they took Xiù first. She liked the strange alien, but the fact remained that she wasn’t Gaoian and wasn’t clan, although Ayma was reasonably certain Xiù was female… the breasts might have been large and oddly placed, but they were breasts, even hidden under the clothing.

She’d been dumped into their holding cell straight from a holding cage, just as they had been, mere hours after their own arrival. She’d been obviously terrified of them, just as they’d been of her. She’d cowered in the corner for near a day, and they hadn’t approached. She obviously didn’t have a translator, and didn’t understand a word they spoke, nor did her strange words mean anything to them. Ayma had noticed that she spoke at least two languages, as the harsh barking sounds and the sing–song words that sounded so similar to Gaoian couldn’t possibly be the same tongue.

Eventually it’d been Ayma herself who had broken the tension, offering the furless humanoid a nutrient sphere – the semi–solid grey suspension of basic proteins, carbohydrates, and minerals that was edible by all species and palatable to none. She’d had to pantomime their purpose, finally eating one in front of her and leaving another on the floor and backing away. Xiù had timidly picked it up, and finally two days of hunger had pushed her into taking a tiny bite. Ayma had chittered in laughter… disgust transcended language. But the alien female had finished the sphere, and then astonished them all by standing to move over to the dispenser embedded into the wall to consume four more.

After that they’d haltingly exchanged names in the clumsy way of first contacts everywhere: Ayma had pointed to herself and said “Ayma.” Then she’d pointed around all the others: “Gaoian”.

The alien pointed at Ayma with a long, slender finger from one hairless hand, so much like a Corti’s but with fewer digits. “Ayma.” Ayma bounced her head in affirmation. “Gaoian.” Encouraged, she gestured again.

Ayma pointed at a nearby female, “Ujali.” Then at the little cub who was currently peeking out from behind her. “Myun.” One by one, she introduced each of the members of their ill–fated voyage.

When she was done she looked at the alien expectantly. The alien realized after a moment, then pointed at herself. “Xiù,” she said. “Human.”

The `human’ was friendly enough once the ice was broken. Understandably nervous, and after a while Ayma realized it wasn’t just because of their circumstances… in fact, Xiù seemed to barely have a grasp on their predicament. After some clumsy, sign–language communication, Ayma realized that their lone visitor was from an uncontacted species. She felt even more sympathy for the lost humanoid – the Council considered species without FTL ability as barely sapient, and certainly wouldn’t expend any effort in returning her home. She had no way to tell Xiù this, and wasn’t sure it would help her at all even if she could.

She watched with them as every day the huge guards would open the door, pick one of the Gaoians and drag them off for study and experimentation. She saw how resistance was met with pain sticks, the merest touch enough to leave an adult female twitching in agony on the floor. The body language of another species was always hard to decipher, but Ayma was confident the strangely mobile and expressive face of Xiù showed horror each time.

The fright and despair was broken only by boredom. Their cage was a large, square room, with only the nutrient dispenser, the water fountain, and a single, omni–species toilet with only a single thin wall for privacy. There was no stimulation, and the cubs were understandably restless within a day. The adults had no desire to burden the children with their own lack of hope, but they also had nothing to distract them with.

Xiù, apparently, also experienced boredom. Ayma had no idea whether their `days’ were equivalent to the human’s, nor what kind of day/night schedule they had, but shortly after waking from her sleep cycle on the fourth day, the alien female had begun stretching her body in an astonishingly limber display. And once she judged herself sufficiently pliable, she’d begun… to dance.

A strange dance, for certain, but beautiful. She moved in a circle, her movements as smooth as oiled machinery. Her upper limbs would extend like wings, or thrust in front of her. She sometimes crouched amazingly low, or leaped incredibly high, and when she landed it was with barely a whisper. Ayma had thought the creature was a mammal, possibly a primate, but with such displays she had to wonder whether Xiù was actually avian.

The cubs, who had begun to become listless and left with nothing but their fear, had been delighted.

Xiù breathed softly as she traced her way through the ba gua nei gong, her hands drawing lines and circles gently in the air. Beside her Myun imitated her as best as her short limbs allowed, and Xiù couldn’t help but smile. She kept her lips shut – she’d read once that humans and other primates were unique in showing teeth as a friendly gesture, and she didn’t want to frighten anyone.

She never once thought that kind of information would be anything more than trivia… just as she’d never thought she’d be doing gung–fu in outer space with aliens.

She didn’t even consider herself that much of a student! She took the classes because her mother constantly lamented how Americanized her daughter was, nevermind the fact that they lived in Vancouver and she was technically Chinese–Canadian. Her mother complained constantly about her clothing, her music… even her accent when she spoke Mandarin. She sometimes wondered if her mother considered university to be an expensive dating service… apparently, instead of working on her degree, she was supposed to be finding a studious young man in the engineering or computer science departments with good prospects so she could settle down and marry. The fact that this young man should be Chinese went without saying.

And Mother wondered why she got along so much better with Daddy.

Xiù had her own plans: she wanted to be an actress. She idolized the likes of Zhang Ziyi, Gong Li, and Michelle Yeoh. Her mother’s complaints that she was becoming too detached from the country of her birth was ridiculous… Zhang Ziyi was an amazing ambassador of Chinese culture. Too masculine? Had her mother never looked at Gong Li? Daddy, busy as he was, was supportive, funding her ballet classes and gung–fu lessons along with her university tuition. Xiù worked hard, determined that one day it would be her on a stage, accepting a Golden Horse award, or perhaps even an Oscar… her father would be there, and he’d be proud.

She hoped she’d see them again… even Mother.

It had been on her way home from her night ballet class that she’d been taken. It had been like something out of a movie: a beam of light had shone down on her from the heavens, and her feet had taken leave of the earth. If anyone had heard her shrieks they hadn’t responded. She’d been carried up and straight into a barred metal cage, being stared at by a lone… creature, that looked absolutely like the aliens from that Roswell video hoax… except it probably wasn’t a hoax, was it? Before she could react he’d pressed something against the side of her throat, and with a pfft of expelled air something had been injected under her skin.

Then he turned and simply left. Left her in her cage, in the grey, featureless room.

She’d screamed and kicked at the bars, but they hadn’t cared. She’d cowered when two of the huge, four–armed aliens had come in to stare at her. In the back of her mind she’d understood that the subtle vibrations of the deck and her cage were the hum of an engine, an engine that was likely flinging them through space at impossible speeds. A day later she’d been dumped into this holding room, like a tiger captured on safari, to share a room with two dozen human–sized racoons.

At least they’d been friendly. And they were prisoners, like her. She didn’t know what happened each day when one of them would be dragged off by the behemoths, as she called them, but her imagination supplied a number of awful possibilities, each worse than the last. Possibilities that were confirmed as the racoons began returning – those that did return – with terrible wounds.

Xiù didn’t know why she practiced her forms in such a place. Maybe it was because the gravity felt so much lighter… she felt like she wouldn’t need wires to reproduce the amazing stunts from the movies she studied. Maybe because she wanted to feel like she still had some power, and martial arts were about inner strength.

Maybe she did it because, no matter what it was meant for, gung–fu was beautiful… and this place needed beauty.

She’d completed her routine once already and was launching into a second iteration when the lone door to the shared room groaned upward. She halted in her movements as she heard the hisses of fright from the racoons. Myun whimpered and hid behind Xiù, wide black eyes peeking around her hip.

Two the behemoths stepped into the room. They were huge, twice as tall as Xiù herself (although she would reluctantly admit that didn’t say much) and possessed of four arms that were as thick around the biceps as her own waist. Their skin was a pale beige, and their clothing was little more than baggy khaki shorts with equipment and what were likely symbols of rank attached to the belt. They looked like fat old men with oddly–angled eyes, huge goiters, and tiny holes where the ears on a human would be located. Each held two of the long metal sticks that could cripple any of the raccoons that resisted with the barest touch.

They stopped just inside the door, surveying the frightened prisoners. Their tiny beady eyes turned in Xiù’s direction, and one raised an arm, pointing at her with a fat, three–fingered hand. Her heart froze in her chest.

“What? What do you want?” she asked, her voice shaking. The behemoth stomped toward her, growling in a low unintelligible voice. “What do you want? Why did you take me?”

The big alien stared down at her shaking form, repeating whatever it said before, but she didn’t understand! Finally it lost patience, grabbing hold of her shoulder… and shoving her to the side. With its last free hand it reached for Myun.

Xiù heard the barks of the adult raccoons, matching her own shocked inhalation. “What? No! Not her!” She reached out and grabbed the alien hand before it could wrap around Myun’s tiny arm. The behemoth had been expecting it; one of its stick swung down and caught her across the collarbone, and she felt like she’d been tazed. She cried out, collapsing to one knee.

She heaved in a breath as the behemoth lifted the stick, thinking her finished, as he grabbed again for the alien child. Xiù found the strength to grab his wrist again; she saw his beady little eyes go wide. He swung the taser–stick down again, hitting her in the arm, and this time he held it against her. Fire spread up and down her arm, but she braced herself and took it.

The hand that held his wrist clenched from the shock, and she felt bone crumble inside her grip as it did. His skin tore, and greenish blood leaked out across her fingers. The behemoth roared in pain.

What?

The adult raccoons had gone berserk as soon as the little one was threatened. They swarmed the other big alien, who swung both of his taser–sticks back and forth. The slightest touch was enough to draw a screech from the raccoons and send them flying, where they’d lay twitching on the floor, limbs quivering and drool leaking from their mouths. Why was Xiù so less affected?

The answer was obvious, as plain as her pink furless skin and red blood. They weren’t the aliens here – she was.

She snarled, struggling against the stick which was still held against her arm, her dirty, sweaty grey shirt doing little to insulate her. The behemoth groaned in pain, his wrist still held by her. She let go and jumped, planting her foot in his sternum, a full–force straight kick. There was a loud crack and the big alien was sent flying, Xiù thrust in the opposite direction. Both hit the walls on opposite sides of the prison room.

Xiù stood back up. The behemoth did not.

Total silence covered the room, as every eye in the room stared incredulously at her. The remaining behemoth was surrounded by a dozen fallen raccoons, including Ayma, but he didn’t seem to be concerned about those who were struggling painfully to their feet. He didn’t have to: everyone was more concerned about the lone human in the room.

The behemoth turned and darted – well, as much as a fat, two–and–a–half–metre brute could be said to dart – toward the still–open door, abandoning his fallen comrade and the circle of disabled prisoners scattered around him.

&nbsp

He’s going to lock us in! she realized, and her feet were moving before she’d finished the thought. She charged ahead, each stride consuming metres at a pace. She covered the distance and thrust out her hands, catching him in the side with an instinctive shuang zhuang zhang, or double–palm strike. There was another crunch and he flew sideways into the wall, but she was following, leaping and catching him in the chest with her knee. Another snapping, popping sound; he barked out the last of his breath and slid down to the floor, his barrel chest warped beyond survival.

Xiù looked down in shock at the alien, dead by her hands.

“Shoo. Shoo.” She couldn’t pronounce the human’s name correctly… her short muzzle just didn’t want to make the proper sound. But Xiù had always known when she was being addressed. She didn’t respond now; the alien was staring down at her open hands, hairless but spotted with the greenish blood of the Locayl.

Ayma hadn’t seen the first brute die, but she’d been hypnotized along with everyone else as the second met his end even as he tried to escape. Xiù had crossed the room in an eyeblink and shoved him into the nutrient sphere dispenser, leaping high and following it up with another hit from her leg. The impact had crushed him against the dispenser, crumpling it and spilling a stream of round nutrient spheres across the floor.

Ayma had been terrified and infuriated at the same time. Terrified because this alien, this human who she’d allowed to play with the cubs for ten–days, had crushed two of the cruelest mercenaries available for hire as if they were nothing. Infuriated, because this alien could crush these mercenaries as if they were nothing, and yet she’d cowered along with the rest of them for ten–days as Gaoians were plucked from their cage for experimentation and death. Then Ayma saw Xiù’s face, and recognized the horror there: She’s never killed before! She didn’t know she could do this!

Of course… an uncontacted species! It made Ayma feel better and worse at the same time.

“Shoo,” she said again, carefully taking hold of the alien’s hand, making sure her small claws were retracted before she did. Xiù flinched, jerking out of her grip, and Ayma forced herself to take hold again, not thinking of what those hands could do. “Shoo, we have to go!” Xiù just stared blankly.

Ayma reluctantly let go, turning to the others to help calm the cubs and get those who were still feeling the effects of the pain–sticks to their feet. The door was still open, this was their one opportunity, and they couldn’t waste it. They owed Xiù but they couldn’t make her move nor spend time convincing her… there was always the chance the door could be operated remotely.

With that in mind she hustled everyone out the door to gather themselves safely out of their cell. Ayma had barely made it out herself when the door began to slide down, either commanded by remote or activated by a timer. “Shoo!” She made a mournful sound.

The door was three–quarters closed – just above a Gaoian’s low hips – when clawless digits grabbed hold of it from underneath. Ayma heard the motors inside the walls groan as they struggled against the obstructing force; the door still moved, but barely. The whine climbed in pitch for several heartbeats, until Xiù ducked under and let it go.

The human met Ayma’s gaze. She shivered as if cold, the thick coat she’d been captured with and used as a pillow while she slept left behind, but her eyes were clear.

“Good,” Ayma said. She turned away, sniffing at the air, using her nose to try and choose a direction. She was reasonably certain they were on a planet, and an open window was the best she was hoping for. Picking a direction, she moved forward with a confidence she didn’t really feel. “This way!”

Ayma was the eldest female, so the others looked to her for leadership… but she wished it hadn’t fallen upon her. She had no idea what she was doing, not that she’d admit that to the others. So she lead them and hoped for the best.

They got lucky in that they didn’t meet any resistance within the prison wing. Soon they found themselves in among what was obviously a lab complex; the walls were high and white, coated in polymers that helped them resist damage, bacteria… and blood stains, Ayma thought grimly. Opening the odd door revealed the labs themselves and their Corti occupants, confirming for Ayma the nature of their kidnappers.

One particular lab contained a Corti scientist that Yulna recognized, her remaining eye blazing with fury. She leaped at him with a snarl, and half of the other females followed to help; when they were done the Corti would trouble no one else except the cleaning droids. Ayma glanced over at Xiù, who had watched the massacre with wide eyes.

Shortly afterward they encountered the first squad of guards sent to recapture them. Ayma smelled them before she saw them, but when the first Mjrnhrm rounded the corner, a pain–stick held high in one pincer, it still took them all by surprise. The stick struck Ayma across the face, and she fell with a shriek of pain, her entire body shaking with convulsions. The insectoid raised the stick to hit another, but Xiù leaped in between, taking the blow across her raised upper limb. Fighting the betrayal of her own body, Ayma was still able to see the crippling blow do little to the human; Xiù screeched but didn’t fall, and her foot snapped out and crushed the joint on the Mjrnhrm’s right foreleg. He tipped, emitting a high–pitched cry, and the human spun. Mjrnhrm weren’t as big as Locayl, but they still towered over the little human; it didn’t matter as he collapsed and Xiù’s leg reached as high as her own head in a spinning kick. The Mjrnhrm’s head was torn clean from his shoulders, flying off to bounce against the far wall and putting its blood–resistant coating to the test with a splatter of beige slime.

Ayma watched as Xiù was frozen again by shock at the worst time. The Mjrnhrm wasn’t alone; another came up behind, and seeing his partner killed so easily he dropped his pain–stick and went for the holster around his thorax. Before any of them could react he pulled his pulse pistol. Xiù stared uncomprehendingly as he aimed and shot her in the chest. The human reeled backwards.

Ayma had recovered enough to cry out, but the shocked sound was cut off in her throat as Xiù recovered her balance. She didn’t fall, though by rights her chest should have been a ruin of powdered bone and bruised organs. Not only could she still breath, but she was snarling, her teeth bared ferociously as she flung herself at her assailant.

The thug was as shocked as any of them, but he aimed the pistol to try again. Xiù moved more quickly than she had even in the prison room; she swept within his reach, an open hand parrying the insectoid’s extended limb. She swept it down in a circle and her other hand snapped around against the limb’s joint. There was a crunch of chitin and the limb was torn away, the pistol still held in the now–limp pincer.

Xiù dropped the severed limb, and the Mjrnhrm didn’t even have time to cry out before her open hands slammed into his thorax, sending him flying backwards. He crashed against the wall and slid to the floor, unmoving.

The other three members of the five–sapient team, all Locayl, surged around the corner and halted, aghast, at the sight of their two dead team members. Then Xiù was leaping at them, and they had no time to think.

Xiù was becoming deaf to the crack of bone, blind to the colour of beige or green blood.

The group was advancing steadily forward… they’d progressed beyond the labs and were now in what seemed to be office areas. Some of the rooms contained the aliens who looked like the Roswellian greys, but those aliens had no desire to fight, instead choosing to run or hide. Except for the one alien that the one–eyed raccoon had had a special hate for, the group didn’t bother with them.

A few of the offices had windows, and Xiù now knew they were on a planet. A barren planet that looked a lot like a beige version of Mars. She was on an alien planet. It was amazing and momentous and she desperately wished it was someone else in her place… a soldier, maybe, or a scientist.

They’d met two more groups of soldier–aliens, slightly larger groups each time. Their enemies weren’t interested in capturing them anymore, as they always opened fire with their energy weapons as soon as they caught sight of them, spitting out bolts of white light. Three of their number had been cut down already – two fatally, if she understood the mournful sounds of her partners. It proved her suspicion that the raccoon–like aliens were just as fragile as their captors… or, more accurately, that Xiù was as far more durable. Twice Xiù had thoughtlessly thrown herself in front of Ayma and taken hits that she was sure would have killed her alien friend; the impacts had hurt, like a solid punch, but no worse.

When they met such resistance Ayma and the others would fall back and take shelter, and leave Xiù to her work.

The first encounters had been slaughters. She’d still been frightened and angry, and the insectoid aliens were terrifying… she didn’t like bugs! But she still had to defend the others, and so she’d fought desperately. Her form had been horrible; Sifu would have made her clean the guan top to bottom twice if he’d seen it! She hit too hard and barely maintained her balance while kicking. The adrenaline flooding her system had made her sloppy, and in between fights she would shiver as her heart raced.

Still she won. The insectoids were terrifying, their carapaces shiny and hideous, but they cracked like glass beneath her strikes and spewed horrible beige fluids onto her hands and clothing. She already knew the behemoths couldn’t take a hit, but every time one of the big creatures broke underneath her palms it surprised her. One had grabbed her arm and drew back two of his other fists to hit her… she’d countered without thinking, twisting her wrist, and his grabbing arm had splintered, bending where even she knew it wasn’t supposed to. Her retaliating palm–strike to his chest had produced another popping sound and sent him flying into his squadmates, knocking them down like tenpins. He hadn’t gotten back up.

Her fright had eventually turned to incredulity, and then a grim inner chill.

Xiù knew how stupid it was to wish for a fair fight… they were fighting for their lives and freedom. And yet… she didn’t feel like a freedom fighter. She felt like an executioner. There was no honour to be had, no sense of accomplishment; she stormed through them as easily as she might have kicked and punched her way through a playground at recess. Xiù was forced to revise her earlier revelation: she wasn’t merely the alien… she was the alien monster. It wasn’t as satisfying as she thought it might be.

She allowed herself to ease back, to concentrate on her technique and her breath. She’d been wasting energy and her shoulders and thighs burned from the exertion. She rested as she could between encounters, saving her strength for when battle was joined, when she would move like the wind and draw fire away from the others. She would take a few hits from the energy weapons, but once she’d jumped and sprinted into the center of the group they risked hitting each other with every shot.

A few of her enemies had drawn glowing swords (her brother would have been thrilled, he was such a nerd) and nearly sliced her in half, but she dodged the blows and had torn the weapons – and sometimes the hands that held them – from their grips. Rather than pick the swords up herself she left them for her friends, since for some reason the guns wouldn’t work for them. She still had her hands and feet.

With her newfound calm she tried not to kill. She concentrated on her form, her qigong. Her blocks had been sharp and brutal, once even tearing an arm off one of the behemoths; so instead she tried to use chi sao, guiding their blows around and away. Her strikes could crush an alien chest, so she softened, turning them into powerful shoves. Even the largest of the aliens she could fling across a room, where they’d crash into a wall and fall to the ground… down for the count, but still breathing.

She was less careful with the grasshopper aliens, but they triggered every phobia she had and she found it hard to empathize with them. Still, most of them would survive, even if many were lacking limbs when she was done. They were still the bad guys, she reminded herself.

When she forced herself to relax it actually let her move faster and last longer, and her movements confused and frustrated the enemy. It was less effective than the raw terror she’d inspired before, of course, but was also less of a burden on her own spirit. And it was funny watching the behemoths trying to hit or shoot her when she was in her low stances – they never seemed to think of kicking her. Perhaps being short wasn’t all bad.

Ayma had never thought they’d make it so far. She fought because she had to; lead because no one else would. She was lucky that her guesses so far had been accurate. She’d simply thought of how the males on Gao tended to act: concerned about image and power, seeking opulence for themselves and their friends. So she’d simply aimed their group in the direction of the offices with the most decoration, the finest carpets. So far it seemed to be working. But they’d have been stopped the moment they’d stepped out of the prison wing were it not for the engine of destruction, this human, that they’d allied themselves with.

Xiù came from a heavy–gravity world, Ayma was sure of it. It explained her strength and speed. It explained her durability, and why she ate so much… her skeleton and musculature must be far denser than the average sapient. It explained why the floor quivered when she ran, as those long legs hammered against the floor… vibrations that Ayma hadn’t noticed in their prison because Xiù walked softly, unconsciously hiding her power.

By unspoken agreement they left the bulk of the fighting to the human. Ayma had picked up one of the dropped fusion swords, and she and Hamfa and Garun stood guard over the others and the cubs. Only once had they had to cut down an attacking Locayl… the rest never made it past Xiù, who could dash down a hallway and be within melee before they could react.

Ayma had heard of tornadoes – though no sensible sapient lived on a world that produced them – and Xiù was a living version. It was all the more astonishing because Amya recognized the attacks the alien female used… although disjointed and out of order, she was unquestionably using the same movements she’d demonstrated in her dancing, applied faster than the eye could follow and with all the strength her compact, powerful body could generate. It should have been comical, to see a squad of mercenaries attacked by a little alien half their height and a tenth their bulk, but her hands shattered their limbs, knocking them to the floor. If she was particularly pressed she would jump, lashing out with her feet in sweeping arcs that crushed skulls. As she watched, Ayma could only think of the steady, elegant movements that Xiù would practice alongside little Myun.

She danced and her enemies died. What kind of creatures were these humans, that they made combat – the distribution of injury and death – an elegant, perhaps even beautiful process?

The first two squads that tried to stop them were wiped out to the last sapient, blood and gore coating the walls and Xiù’s clothing. She was a nightmare, a creature from a holovid, and though Ayma knew they needed her it was impossible to feel safe in the presence of something that killed so easily.

After the second group, though, something changed in the way Xiù would fight. Instead of the sharp, deadly movements, the human began concentrating on defence. Once the pulse pistols were torn out of manipulators and tossed away or crushed underfoot, the alien female would slow her pace, going after limbs and legs. At first Ayma thought she was playing with her victims, but it soon was obvious that although she threw mercenaries into walls or each other with force that seemed impossible for such a small body, and the thugs rarely stood up again afterward, they were still breathing.

So the humans knew mercy as well. It made Ayma feel much better. Gaoian females were expected to do whatever was necessary to protect their cubs and each other, and what was necessary could be grim indeed. But they never went that far unless they had to. Were Xiù’s people the same?

The group ended up in front of a pair of large double doors, carved with mechanical precision from the wood of a Cortian schweet tree and varnished by nanobots with durable diamond coating. Ayma knew from her limited readings of interstellar trade that such doors cost enough to supply a colony with a fusion power unit. Without a doubt, these were the doors to the administrator of the facility which had trapped them.

Her claws slid from their sheaths as her paw gripped her fusion sword tightly. Her clan and their cubs stood behind her, ready; she glanced over at Xiù and saw the human watching her, ready to follow her lead.

She actually wondered if Xiù had the strength to kick in the door as she reached for the trigger pad. Corti, Gaoians, and humans were all similar in height, so the pad was at a comfortable height. She was surprised when the door opened without complaint, and she stepped inside cautiously, her eyes and nose active.

She knew someone was inside, but she was still taken by surprise as a six–fingered hand seized the back of her neck and pulled her to the side. The Corti who had hidden beside the door used his other hand to press a pulse pistol to the side of her muzzle. Xiù made an angry noise, lurching forward, but before she could close the distance another hand from the other side of the door grabbed her lower arm and wrenched her away, hurling her aside with a whine of servos. If Ayma needed any confirmation of how heavy Xiù was she got it as the human crashed into a small table in a lounge area to the side of the large office, crushing it beneath her.

From beside the door stomped a bulky, humanoid figure. The newcomer was shaped like a Corti, but far bulkier and slightly taller. The creature’s head was slender and whiplike, looking out of place as it stuck out from between the brawny shoulders. The head had a pair of bulbous eyes and a single horizontal line for a mouth, the corners of which were bent downward in displeasure.

Allebenellin, Ayma’s memory supplied. A wormlike race famous for their prosthetics and avarice. The creature’s entire body was synthetic, mechanical… and it gave him the strength to challenge the human.

Xiù staggered to her feet, breathing heavily, but hesitated as she saw the weapon held to Ayma’s head. At the door the other Gaoian females did the same, growling and spitting in anger.

“That will be quite enough of that kind of language, thank you,” said the Corti, and Ayma’s eyes went wide as she realized he had a translator. “I’m quite impressed that you’ve made it so far, but your little escapade stops here. If you don’t wish to meet your ends so much sooner, I’d advise you to put down your weapons and surrender.”

“You expect us to calmly walk back to our cage and await vivisection?” Ayma snapped, but she let the fusion sword drop to the floor unlit as he ground the emitter of the pistol against her cheek warningly.

“Don’t be ridiculous, we don’t plan to vivisect all of you. Five, maybe six. After that, what more is there to learn? The rest of you will help with viral research, chemical agent testing, and cosmetics. Your contribution to science will be small but important,” the Corti explained calmly. “I’m afraid your friend there, however, won’t be joining you. Captain Mij here is rather put out about her crippling his mercenary company. His contract didn’t include risk provisions… he didn’t think they were needed. You know how annelids are.”

“Trig…” Mij growled warningly.

“Why did you take her? Why did you take any of us?” Ayma demanded.

The Corti, Trig, sighed. “You want me to monologue, do you? Fine. I took you all for science. You and your brethren are simply the means to fulfill my main contract. It’s just work... nothing personal until you decided to make it such. The human was for a side project. I’d heard rumours of the species, and they’re almost certainly going to end up under a quarantine, so I wished to fetch a specimen before that occurred. Their homeworld is only a small diversion from your colony, so I asked the ship to obtain one. I thought a female would be more docile.”

Ayma couldn’t believe what she was hearing. Contracts? Science? Her mouth moved of its own accord. “Docile? You really are a bunch of shut–in nerds, aren’t you?”

The pistol pressed more firmly. “Mistakes were made,” he growled. “Such is science. Captain Mij, feel free to fix the mistake.”

“Right, boss,” the Allebenellin said, stomping forward.

Xiù had watch uncomprehendingly as they spoke, but as Mij approached her she lowered her body, extending her hands in front of her as she often would during her dances. Mij swung a cybernetic punch at her, but she pushed it aside. Hopping back a step, she hooked one of the low–slung chairs with her foot and flung it at her opponent, who smashed it aside.

Trig sighed again. “Preferably without completely destroying my office, Captain!”

Xiù tried not to surrender to panic as she and the weird worm alien traded hits. He was strong, perhaps as strong as she was, and when he managed to hit her it was as hard as one of their guns. She was quicker and managed to parry most of his blows, guiding them aside and occasionally knocking him off–balance. Some of his punches got through, however, and this alien was smart enough to kick when she ducked. She kicked back, and hammered his limbs with strikes, but unlike with the other aliens he did not break under the blows. In fact he didn’t even show any sign of pain.

Was he a machine, a cyborg? A month ago she would have called it science–fiction, but she was currently fighting a worm–headed alien on behalf of sapient racoons on another world, so standards had to be relaxed a bit. Her chi sao told her nothing… there was no tensing of muscles before a strike, no relaxation when he would advance or fall back. It was like she was fighting a training dummy, except this dummy hit back, and her bruises and aches were piling up.

She’d gradually ramped up the strength of her blows against his limbs, and if she wasn’t sure before, she was certain he was a machine now. Metal rang as she kicked his knees and rained elbow strikes on his forearms, blows that could and had dismembered opponents at the start of their sudden insurrection. She’d bitterly come to the conclusion that he was too strong to hold back, and she’d best be prepared to kill again, cursing in her own mind for jinxing herself by complaining about the weakness of her previous foes. But the only fleshy part of him was his worm–like head (her stomach queased at the thought of even touching it) and despite how much faster she seemed to be compared to everyone else he was still too quick in pulling his head in, like a turtle, whenever she managed to leap high enough to grab at it. Her tries were rewarded with punches to the gut or chest, and once he even succeeded in knocking her down.

What could she do? She wished she’d paid better attention to Sifu… she’d only ever expected to use her martial arts on the screen or maybe at a forms competition. She never expected she’d ever have to actually fight!

What would Sifu say? She struggled to think. Well, probably the first thing he would say was that to keep trying what didn’t work wasn’t bagua. Continue the circle, try another direction, adapt. But how could she adapt to fighting an enemy who was all machine?

Except… he wasn’t all machine, was he? He breathed, she could hear it. His head was like a worm… was the rest of him wormlike as well? Was he a tube of flesh in a metal human–like body?

Ew. Gross.

But it gave her an idea. She leaped back, out of his range, catching her breath. On a passing whim she made her return to a fighting stance fancy and elaborate. It seemed to confuse him a little, and it raised her spirits a bit.

I’m ready for my scene, Mister Wong.

The human female had been fighting Mij the way she’d fought most of the guards and thugs who had blocked their way… with mercy, striking at limbs to debilitate rather than kill. But the annelid had no limbs... his body was a mechanical suit, a vehicle that he rode within. She was wasting her strength. Her blows made the room ring loud enough to make Trig flinch, but didn’t do much. Ayma couldn’t even tell her… even if Trig would allow her to shout advice, Xiù wouldn’t understand what she was saying.

But Xiù was clever, possibly even as clever as a Gaoian or Corti. Ayma could tell when the human had realized. As she’d watched, she saw the character of Xiù’s blows change, if only slightly. They seemed to stick a bit longer, as if they were not just hits but shoves as well. Her body motion became even more dance–like, circling Mij in his cybernetic suit, hammering him from all sides and flowing around his counters like water. The Allebenellin was knocked backwards, bit by bit, until he had to brace against the wall just to protect his rear. Xiù stopped circling and continued to punish his body… the most armoured part of the suit, but… was Mij panting?

It was inevitable in any martial art, especially in one known to be lethal like baguazhang, that a student would ask about dim mak, or the “Death Touch”. Sifu handled the oft–repeated question with far more patience than Xiù would have after so many repetitions.

No, the Death Touch didn’t exist, he said, except in fantasy and in pure raw luck and accident. But that didn’t mean that the basic concept was useless. Attack the centre line, he said. Send your force through the flesh and disrupt the chi inside.

Xiù wasn’t sure how seriously she’d taken that aspect of her training, but she applied it against Mij with desperation turned to determination. She stopped trying to damage his limbs and only worried about parrying his hits; when she struck back it was against his centreline. That was one thing about all these aliens; they did a shoddy job of defending their bodies.

He would try to hit her, and she’d guide the blow aside with bei shen zhang or some other rolling movement, trying to conserve her energy until she would lash back with either a palm or a fist, drilling into his centre with all the power she could muster. Being so close he naturally tried to kick her away, but whenever he tried she would hook his foot with her own, stretching him out and knocking him off–balance, until he gave up trying.

She slammed her hand again and again against where the solar plexus would be on a human, or the midpoint of a spine. She walked the circle around him, and he had problems keeping up. Eventually he had to back against a wall just to keep her from getting behind him. So she punished his front, and the reinforced wall he was pressed against actually began to crumple slightly.

It was working! The wormlike alien had actually paled, and though it was weird to see a worm with a mouth she could tell he was struggling for breath. He was flesh inside the suit, just very long and narrow. He was as fragile as any of the other aliens, and her attacks were knocking him around inside!

Sifu would be so proud!

“Mij, what is the matter with you?” Trig snapped. In front of him, his pulse pistol still to her head, Ayma grinned ferally.

The Administrator had been smug through most of the short and vicious fight, but then Xiù had suddenly gained a second wind. The others, still huddled in a crowd at the entrance to the room, had been watching the battle with nervousness and then elation… as if the underdog team had suddenly turned a sporting event around, rather than the ultimate fate of their lives. Their cheers had only enraged the Corti administrator even further.

“Mij, finish it! Mij!” Trig snapped. “By the stars–” Trig moved the pulse pistol away from her head, aiming at Xiù, thinking to rescue his beleaguered henchman.

It was the moment Ayma had been waiting for; her claws unsheathed and she lashed out at his extended arm. Gaoian claws were relatively tiny, but they traced a trio of furrows down his arm which immediately leaked blue liquid. The Corti cried out and then snarled, trying to bring the pistol back to shoot her, but she seized his arm and struggled. The others, almost not believing what they were seeing, hesitated before surging forward.

Trig managed to shove her off, knocking her down. He saw the angry crowd rushing him and fired randomly into it, and Ayma heard cries of pain. He looked back at her, and she saw murderous fury there. The pulse pistol swung back to aim at her head–

A fleshy rope lashed out, catching him in the wrist. The pulse pistol was sent flying, and Trig cried out in agony and fell to his knees, clutching at his arm.

Ayma looked up and saw Xiù standing there, looking as angry as when little Myun had been threatened. Clutched in her hand was Mij himself… without his power armour. She’d managed to grab hold of him, ripping him out of his suit and then using him as a living whip to strike down his boss. The annelid gurgled in her grip, struggling for breath, the long coil of his body flopping uselessly against the floor.

Ayma struggled to her feet. She glared down at the snivelling Corti. “We win.”

Trig initially didn’t want to cooperate. That was easily solved: Xiù simply took hold of his good wrist and squeezed until the researcher was quite agreeable. She hadn’t even needed to be asked, easily interpreting the argument between the Administrator and Ayma. After that, Trig was only too happy to send a distress signal on their behalf.

Nearly twenty of their captors were shepherded into the holding area where the “subjects” had been kept, stripped of their weapons and given medical supplies to treat each other, since their former lab subjects lacked the know–how. Outside the cage stood three angry Gaoian females armed with fusion swords and the implied assistance of their human ally. Mij was locked in a tank with an air–permeable lid found in one of the labs, good enough to keep the worm from somehow wiggling out and trying to get back to his armour.

Trig was allowed to treat his broken wrist, though with Xiù’s digits poised at the back of his neck. The Corti was smart enough to know that anything untoward would result in his head impacting into (and knowing the human’s strength, through…) his fine, impeccable–quality desk. The Gaoians questioned him the entire time.

Ayma was disappointed to learn that the translator even didn’t have Xiù’s language programmed into it. In fact, the installation database didn’t even have the name of her homeworld, nor its location. Trig had been careful about hiding his steps and preserving his “plausible deniability”... the location had been supplied only to the ship’s crew, and they were long gone.

Xiù was alone, and Ayma wondered if she understood that.

One planetary rotation after their successful escape and seizure of the installation they received a response to their distress call. Even better, it was a Gaoian ship! It was good news and drew cheers, even as they mourned the loss of Hamfa, Ujali, and Minin.

The captain of the ship was appalled by the deaths of the three females, and Ayma appreciated the fact that he seemed quite sincere, not merely acting for the sake of improving his mating prospects. The ten surviving females and four cubs were given berths, while Trig was shoved into the brig. The installation’s distress call was left running, as they would be leaving the prisoners and Mij for someone else to deal with. If no one came… well, Ayma didn’t care.

The ship’s crew were professional and efficient. The one hiccup came when it came to decide what to do with Xiù.

“She isn’t Gaoian, Mistress,” the captain protested. “She’s alien! She consumes nearly four times as much oxygen as one of us, and if her appetite is as you say–”

“You’re heading straight to the homeworld, aren’t you?” she demanded. “You said… what? A five rotation journey? Surely we wouldn’t deplete your consumables that quickly!”

“Yes – I mean, no – but what about other concerns? Alien beings, particularly from uncontacted worlds, carry unknown diseases! And if she’s as violent as you’ve reported–”

“She was violent in our defence, Captain!” she snapped. “If you don’t threaten us or the children I think you’ll find her quite agreeable. As for disease, she was implanted with the Corti long–term suppressor. We all were. We’ll just leave hers in place until we’re certain, distasteful though it may be.”

The captain was wilting, watching his hopes for enticing her as a mating partner dwindle as he argued. “Why would you concern yourself for an alien female? She isn’t clan!”

Ayma looked over at where Xiù sat in the corner of the docking bay. Two of the cubs scrambled all over her, but she held them up as easily as if they were made of soft pillows. Myun hung from her outstretched arm, chittering with Gaoian laughter, and Xiù responded with her own barking version of the same. The human could literally tear some of the fiercest mercenaries in existence limb from limb, yet Ayma had no fear for the little cub as Xiù bounced her lightly. The human had proven she knew how and when to use her strength.

“You’re wrong, Captain,” Ayma answered. “She is clan. And we don’t leave clan behind.”

Humans don’t make good pets part 14

by guidosbestfriend

I’m sorry this post is shorter than the last few, but at the same time it’s the cumulative work of most of this week, writing whenever I could get a spare 30 minutes or so. I probably shouldn't have ended this one where I did, but I wanted to get it out anyway because I haven’t posted in a while. If this new "write-whenever-I-get-a-spare-half-hour" routine has affected the quality please tell me. I don't want to be putting out sub-par work even if it would allow me to get stories out faster.

Special thanks to /u/Kilo181 and /u/Lostwingman07 for ideas regarding plot, /u/Jigsus and /u/woodchips24 who influenced the opening of this installment, and /u/digitalulz and /u/Kilo181 (again) for a joke I could not resist adding into the story.

Alien measurements are given their appropriate names with equivalent human measurements in (parentheses). Alien words with Human equivalents are put in [brackets]. Thoughts are italicized and offset by "+" symbols. Dialogue directed towards the protagonist using the gesture language are enclosed by inequality signs “< >”.

“Three and a half ricatos (7 months)!” Strrk shouted, “It took you guys that long to find a cure‽”

Fttfk couldn’t resist such an opportunity, especially since it was Strrk. “Actually, we figured out a cure a couple of rictos (4 days) after you were put in cryo-stasis but it was so nice without your constant mindless yakking that we only just now decided that it would have been immoral to keep you frozen any longer, despite our desires.” Strrk whipped around, staring at Fttfk with wide, hurt eyes. Fttfk could hardly contain his laughter

+The moron actually believes me!+

“Shut up Fttfk.” Snapped Xkkrk. “Of course we didn’t leave you in there for the fun of it, Strrk. Fttfk was taken out a mere ric (30 minutes) ago.” Strrk, oddly enough, was correct in one respect. Three and a half ricatos (7 months) was a ridiculous amount of time to spend on a cure for a single disease, especially with the equipment of a category 10 medical station at one’s disposal. It made more sense when she reminded herself that it had not actually been just one disease. The crew had in fact displayed the symptoms of five different contagions, and that wasn’t mentioning the dormant antigens which had been discovered upon a more thorough examination of the first crewmembers thought to have been cured. Such “sleeper” diseases had numbered in the dozens, and taken the longest to completely eradicate.

To ensure that absolutely nothing harmful remained, the entire station and the cargo ship had undergone a full sanitation. In total, the time required to undo what Cqcq’trtr had unwittingly managed in a mere rictos (2 days) had required a full three and half ricatos (7 months). In that entire time, Xkkrk had not contracted a single disease, purely out of good luck it seemed. That only meant she had had to bide her time through the entire ordeal with nothing to distract her from her anger.

Even now, after time had quenched the initial inferno, it still flared to life every time her eyes lit upon Dr. Triv. That lying, manipulative, two faced, Corti bastard! He had been able to communicate with Cqcq’trtr and had intentionally remained silent regarding his ability so that he would have no inconvenient moral or legal obstacles while studying Cqcq’trtr’s physiology without his consent. Worse yet, she had caught him. She’d heard Cqcq’trtr speaking intelligible clicks, seen him speaking to Dr. Triv, and the Corti scum had the nerve to tell her that she had been imagining things! Of course the surveillance footage from that room just happened to have been corrupted.

Worse yet, Dr. Triv had somehow convinced Cqcq’trtr of some Robalin resurgence, sending him off to who knew where, never to be seen or heard from again. Of course, the Corti had shown her the surveillance records which appeared rather convincing, but she didn’t intend to trust this wart of a creature any farther than she could throw him. Admittedly, given the doctors stature and her current feelings toward him, that distance might be somewhat greater than she would have anticipated, if she had a mind to find out. She still hadn’t decided whether or not she did. Strrk had to choose that very moment to speak. He always seemed to have the worst timing with the worst questions.

“Hey, where’s Cqcq’trtr? He’s the one who put me in here, the least he could have done was be here to apologize, or I guess in his case look sorry.”

“He left.” Xkkrk whispered. She didn’t really believe Cqcq’trtr had been fooled by the Corti. He had been intelligent – she still hated how long it had taken her to realize – but more surprisingly, he had truly cared for her and the rest of the crew. She suspected he had left in an effort protect the crew, not realizing his worlds deadly microbes had been contained. What confirmed this theory in her mind was the vial of blood he had left. He hadn’t been willing to give so much as a drop to anyone during his entire stay, but when he had known he was leaving, he had left the key to creating the cure.

She knew in her mind Cqcq’trtr was most likely dead, either from starvation or some twisted ploy, but despite her cynicism she still hoped that wherever Cqcq’trtr was, he was safe and happy.

Lieutenant Colonel Blatvec ducked. The anti-tank kinetic-pulse narrowly missed his head, flashing by close enough to ruffle the fur on his head and back. It was a good thing he had, too. He didn’t think his personal shield would be able to take another shot. His momentary union with the ground gave his mind a few precious moments to consider the battle around him. It wasn’t good. He’d never seen a fight with so many vehicles, and that was saying something, coming from him. He was one of the most experienced of the 74th, and had been to hell and back several times. Now, hell apparently had tiers, and he was several levels lower than he’d ever been before.

Major Cliip slid down the short declivity next to where Blatvec was taking a momentary rest. “We can’t stay here long sir,” he panted, “The moment they decide they don’t want to bother trying to shoot us out of cover they’re going to point the nearest tank squad in our direction, and I don’t think the guys can take on another one.” Blatvec snorted humorlessly. Another tank squadron. Before today his squad had only ever taken on two or three tanks at a time. It spoke to the superb skill of his men that they had managed to defeat such odds with only minor casualties, but now they had far out-stripped any previous record they may have set. Today they’d managed to survive not one, nor two, but three attacks by full tank squadrons, and miraculously emerged alive and victorious.

Well, a few of them were alive. Casualties had never been so heavy, but neither had the odds been so heavily against them. The 74th may have contained the finest soldier in the Dominion, and his men arguably the greatest among them, but when the enemy has as many armored squadrons as the 74th did of infantry, there was little they could do, finest soldiers of not. If the heads hadn’t had the foresight to send the 32nd and 13th armored divisions to provide support, this battle would have already been over.

Even though he already knew the answer, Blatvec decided to ask Cliip, hoping his gut was wrong for the first time. “How are the 32nd and 13th holding up?”

Cliip grimaced, “Poorly, maybe even worse than us. At least we can dive into holes when it gets too hot. Those poor bastards are stuck in big hunks of metal with the colors of the Dominion painted all over their sides. They’re impossible to miss, even in this mess.” A coil-shot narrowly missed their position, it’s sickly red light replacing the ashen cast of the battlefield for a split second before it impacted a short distance to the left of their hiding place, turning a hill into a hole. Blatvec whipped his head around, searching for the source of the disturbance. A burning husk sat where a rover had once hovered. Just a shot fired in the brief moment before extinction.

Breathing a sigh of relief that they weren’t under attack just yet, Blatvec consulted his gut. It was the main reason he was still alive. He had a sense about the battlefield. He could feel when a turning point was at hand, even though nothing seemed to have changed. His ability had led his men out of more than one tough scrape, but now he felt the current situation was one even his gut couldn’t help him out of. It seemed to be sobbing in despair, which did nothing to bolster his flagging internal morale. It was only his internal morale which was affected, however. He never let his fear show on his face. That would have admitted true defeat. He had to help his men. He had to give them something to fight so that, when the time came, they could die like men, standing up, rather than frightened prey, hiding in their holes, hoping the predator wouldn’t find them.

Searching about the battlefield with his eyes, he calmly and calculatingly scanned for anything he could exploit, anything that would give him and his men more opportunities, if not for survival, then at least for a more meaningful death. It was as he looked that the predator decided to show up. It just wasn’t the predator he would have expected.

“Sir, get down!” Cliip shouted in warning, but he didn’t need it. He’d sensed the approaching danger, although, as always, he couldn’t explain how, especially through all the mayhem of the fighting around him. To his right a small group of enemy rovers were powering towards his position. Their trajectory suggested they had nearly come from behind his position.

+Have we been beaten back so far already?+

Shouldering his anti-tank pulse-guns with his first four arms and his Fusion spears in the other two, he prepared to engage the approaching onslaught. A figure on top of one of the rovers caught his eye at the last moment. Holding two fusion scythes and caterwauling like a [banshee], a small creature Blatvec had never seen before rode atop the foremost rover as though it were a steed, howling in a language that, for some reason, his translator didn’t understand. It was covered in blood from various species, completely obscuring the colors of allegiance on its harness. He was still staring at the odd little biped when the rovers whipped past their position without giving his squad a second glance. Cliip snapped him from his reverie.

“Are those drivers wearing some of our combat-harnesses?” Blatvec hadn’t even realized, so engrossed he had been with the odd spectacle above the hover-craft, but Cliip was right. Ensconced within the rovers as they were, it was impossible to see unless one was as close as he was, but Blatvec could clearly see the colors of the Dominion on the harnesses of the soldiers in the rovers. At first he was repulsed by such a sight. How could they? They were ignoring the rules of honorable combat! They were blatantly lying about their allegiance so as to avoid notice by the enemy! It was despicable, deplorable . . . ingenious! Even as he stared in shock the duplicitous convoy approached the position of the troops that were keeping his unit pinned down. Not a shot was fired upon them. After all, to the Celzi down the range, they were on the same team. Then their own team opened fire on them.

The first volley was devastating, each craft firing every cannon simultaneously, bathing the entrenchment in a deadly light. There wasn’t much left after that first volley, except a deeper hole. Blatvec knew he should feel outraged by the blatant disregard of the rules of honorable combat, but at the moment, the only one he was furious with was himself for allowing those idiotic “laws” to make him completely disregard such an plainly effective idea. Cursing himself for his slow wits, he turned to Cliip.

“I want you to find any in the area. Tell them to get into an enemy vehicle at all costs. We’re going to win this battle one way or the other; propriety can go bother dusty men from wars long over.”

“Wait, you want to emulate them?” cried Cliip, “They’re ignoring every principle of the very foundation of civilized war!”

“And they’re kicking some serious ass because of it,” retorted Blatvec, gesturing to the small group as it approached a squad of tanks from behind. They opened fire in much the same manner as they had against the enemy infantry entrenchment, to much the same effect. Any other Celzi units around them were embroiled in their own conflicts, and were far too busy to notice that a few of their number were acting in a decidedly unpatriotic manner.

His point proven, Blatvec returned his attention to Cliip, who appeared quite impressed despite himself. “And don’t start spouting that drivel about ‘civilized war’. If you can see what’s right in front of you and still talk such nonsense you’ve got shit for brains. Now find anyone you can in the immediate area and tell them to hijack enemy vehicles at all costs. If they don’t they’ll die anyway.”

Turning his back on a spluttering Cliip, Blatvec dashed to the nearest hole which housed a cluster of his few remaining men. As a smile spread across his face, he realized just how much he had hated those imbecilic rules.

Dear Journal,

I’m a military genius.

I guess that just comes naturally with being a strategic genius.

Really, outer-space does a lot for a guy’s self-image.

I had never felt so terribly alive before. Riding my glorious metal steed, I raised my lava scimitars above my head, shouting in pure exhilaration. That was about all I was doing. Really, my squadmates were doing all the work. First time for everything I guess. If only they wouldn’t shoot from so far away. “Drive me closer, I want to hit them with my swords!” They didn’t oblige. I poked my head through a window which no longer contained glass, preparing an inappropriate and exasperating quip to throw at Manthlel, upon whose hover-hummer I was riding. That’s when I noticed his expression. His face held the unmistakable expression of one who could not believe what he was doing.

Judging by his driving, I couldn’t believe he had managed to keep us out a nasty wreck so far either, but that didn’t explain why Cresh in the next vehicle over had the same shocked look on his face. That guy handled his hover-hummer like a pro, yet he still looked like he’d just let out an involuntary laugh during the scene where old yeller dies. In fact, now that I was looking for it, every single one of my squad looked disturbed by their actions. Maybe they were just surprised they were still alive. Frankly, I was. I hadn’t thought our little tactic of hijacking enemy hover-hummers would have been so effective, but it was like we were invisible to the enemy.

Every time we approached an opposing squadron I was sure someone would notice our odd behavior and open fire, but each time we would manage to get into firing range, destroying them before they even had a chance to retaliate. Our unnaturally good luck couldn’t last us through the entire battle, could it?

Yeah, I actually let my mind conceive such a traitorous thought. I need to see those before they happen and nip them in the bud, because one of these days I’m going to think myself to death. Right on cue, as though it had sensed a being who dared conceive a hopeful thought, a dragon pierced through the veil that had been protecting us thus far. I don’t know what was up with the dragons in this battle, but they were full out flying through the air.

Through my other encounters with these overgrown lizards I’d eventually realized that their wings were more or less just for show than actual use. Sure, they provided another appendage with which to attack me, and made coming at them from the side a downright pain, but the most flying I had ever seen them use their wings for was a short gliding extension to their jumps. Their wings were about as affective as a “flying” squirrel’s.

Not these dragons, though. Apparently they had found the same source of leprechaun farts and pixie tears that planes used, because they were taking to sky with great sweeps of their wings. Well, now that I looked at them they seemed to be working pretty hard to stay up for long, but they were up none the less. One of the devils had noticed our little convoy from above. Folding its wings, the drake rolled into a dive. With the low gravity of this planet, its rate of decent seemed slowed enough to appear comical, but it would still have enough momentum to be deadly when it reached us. Just to sweeten the deal, it was heading straight for my hover-hummer.

As it approached I found myself, rather than frightened, excited.

+Finally some action!+

Wait, had I really just thought that? Where had that come from? I’ve got a fucking dragon barreling down on me and I’m excited? Am I insane‽ The dragon was fast approaching, so I stowed this newest development for later. How was I going to deal with this thing coming down on me? My mind, demonstrating more of my newfound madness, presented me with a course of action straight out of Die Hard. Well, close enough. “You’ve got to be kidding,” I groaned, but I couldn’t think of any other way. Let’s just say I’m not a clever man. I waited a single moment more, allowing the beast to close within a mere twenty meters of our craft. Then I jumped.

Blatvec knew he shouldn’t enjoy something as grisly as war, but he couldn’t help himself, he was actually having fun. Careening about the battle field in his recently acquired tank, he and a sizable group of other stolen vehicles were, for the first time that day, making headway against the seemingly endless tide of enemies. Perhaps that small convoy of rovers had been able to hide underneath their assumed colors undetected, but a group as large as the one which followed Blatvec, which was still growing as more vehicles changed hands, hadn’t been able to run rampant for long before they had started being noticed.

Blatvec could feel the rage of the Celzi as they realized the treachery the Dominion had committed in the name of victory. Blatvec had come up with a new moto, however, which perfectly characterized his feelings since bucking the old ways: “All is fair in war.” Maybe he’d become famous for it. He had to admit, as brilliant as the plan had been, he didn’t think any other division would have been able to pull it off. Nowhere else would you find a group with so many soldiers able to fight against vehicles and win, albeit with difficulty. You probably wouldn’t have found so many infantrymen who knew how to drive the vehicles either.

This was the 74th, though, and now that they had a fighting chance, they were demonstrating why they were the only division left from the original Dominion army. Turing to Gicerpt, who was manning the main cannon, Blatvec shouted over the tumultuous roar inside the tank. “How are our little upstarts doing?”

“Still up and kicking,” the heavy replied with a grin. “They’re going to have to turn back to us soon though. The Celzi will eventually get everyone on the same page and then they won’t have their surprise factor anymore, which is the only reason they’ve made it so far. They’re a little ways away, though. I don’t know if they’ll be able - shit,” Blatvec’s heart sank at the defeated tone of Gicerpt’s explicative. It was a tone he’d heard far too often today. The tone of one who is about to see another die and knows there’s nothing they can do to stop it. Gicerpt continued, “A Vulza just spotted them and is diving to interce-SHIT!”

That wasn’t a tone he’d been expecting. Blatvec took his eyes off the road ahead and looked in the general direction of where he had last seen the inspiration for the current operating orders. He was just in time to see the little creature that had been standing on top of one of the rovers jump off of the corpse of a Vulza, which seemed to have died mid-flight, and hit the ground with a roll, leaving the dragon to slam into the ground behind it. The small creature didn’t even look impressed with its handiwork, neglecting to even glance at the downed monster it had just slain in an impossible manner.

+Holy fuck it worked!+

I couldn’t believe it, I’d actually managed to jump on its head, stab it in the skull, then jump off it and roll to safty before it could drag me into a collision I doubted I’d survive. I wanted to jump up and down and squeal like a little girl while flapping my arms, but I had an audience. The occupants of hover-hummer three were watching with a shocked expression I hadn’t seen in months. Hunching my shoulders, I set my entire will to forcing myself to avoid looking back at my kill, reminding myself of the first law of any action movie.

+Cool guys don’t look at explosions. Cool guys don’t look at explosions.+

I couldn’t help it. I looked. I was glad I did. The dragon’s momentum coupled with its weight had left streak marks 10 meters long in the dirt. The impact hadn’t been kind to the corpse either. Crumpled and broken, shafts of white bone stuck from the wings, which were nearly fractured beyond distinction. It’s neck had folded over itself and under its body, nearly decapitating it.

Seeing the carnage, the reality of what I had just done came crashing back to me. I sat down for a moment, rethinking what I had just done. I hadn’t even been scared, even though I’d known I could have died. Was that normal? My introspections were interrupted when I got a face full of dirt from an anti-tank pulse striking the ground right in front of me. Choking on earth I dropped to the ground. Apparently my squad hadn’t been the only ones in my audience. I guess jumping eight meters into the air and killing a dragon tends to draw crowd. Too bad this new crowd sympathized with the dragon rather than me.

Three tanks charged my position, death ray guns charging, red light spilling from the cannon’s open maws. They never had the chance to fire. Three dragon’s fell from the sky like bolts from the hand of a dragon slinging Zeus. Bearing their full weight against the tops of the offending tanks, the seemingly sturdy armor folded under the drakes as if they were no more than aluminum cans. I couldn’t understand the sudden change of amicability the dragons were showing me until another four landed behind me. I got a look into the eyes of one of the first three. I had killed one of their own. I was their kill.

You know how, in action movies, when the protagonist is up against impossible odds, the bad guys play it fair and let him fight them one at a time while the rest just kind of swing their weapons around in the background? Apparently the dragons didn’t subscribe to that playbook. Three attacked at once, two in front, one just peeking out from my blindside. There might have been more coming from behind me, so I jumped the only direction I could: up.

I wish I could say that they all comically smashed into each other, where they promptly lay dazed upon the ground while stars swirled about their heads. These buggers had reflexes though. Eight meters up is a long way, but they could jump farther. Following like scaled homing missiles, my three attackers jumped to meet me. They didn’t make it. Midflight the two charging from the front exposed in bursts of red light, as the third was thrown off course by a hailstorm of anti-tank ray pulses. My squad had arrived. Our small fight exploded into chaos.

Rie’uo’abuie’ayu was beside himself with frustration. The battle had been progressing flawlessly, but now the Alliance’s advance had stalled when they were so close to victory. Command was gibbering about some sort of cowardice in so many garbled transmissions it was impossible to understand what they were upset about, units were being lost all over the field, and now the Vulza were out of control. Only seconds ago three tanks had broken formation, their crews screaming unintelligibly through the comms about the Dominion scum and a façade, when a pod of Vulza came roaring from the sky to flatten the three deviants.

Rie’uo’abuie’ayu had been unable to believe his eyes. This had never happened before! Sure, in their excitement the Vulza were known to kill an Alliance infantry squad or two who were foolish enough to get too close, but they had never attacked Celzi vehicles before. That was trained into them from birth! More Vulza landed in the clearing created by their brothers, and Rie’uo’abuie’ayu noticed the figure of the reptiles’ interest.

+A single soldier? They’ve attacked their masters to kill a single soldier?+

The soldier wasn’t a species he recognized.

+A mercenary at that? What could have possessed them t-+

The little creature powered up a person anti-gravity device. He must have. The alien mercenary shot into the air, followed by three Vulza. Thinking to take advantage of their distraction, a group of nearby rovers decided to eliminate the defective Vulza. There weren’t enough of them to eliminate the entire pod in one volley, and, presented with a new target, the remaining Vulza leapt upon those foolish enough to attack them. Rie’uo’abuie’ayu couldn’t abandon loyal men to a fate as grim as being torn apart by a Vulza.

“Fleezl!” Rie’uo’abuie’ayu snapped to his communications officer, “Tell the squad to attack the Vulza rampaging at our [4 o’clock]. I’m not leaving men to those monsters.” A few clipped words was all it required to divert Rie’uo’abuie’ayu’s squadron of tanks to the fight, where they charged the monsters, coilguns blazing. The situation deteriorated from there.

I couldn’t believe it. They were helping us! The enemy was firing on their own monsters! I’d thought I was screwed with the rest of my squad. The four dragons that hadn’t attacked me had scattered our hover-hummers, but I hadn’t been able to see what happened afterwards. My attention was distracted by the only one of my three attackers still alive. Enraged at the not-so-gentle-push that denied him his vengeance, the dragon leapt at me. Classic dragon opening move, that. I’d seen it a hundred times before – maybe more like four – and I was ready for it. I needn’t have been. Unlucky lizard attacker number three exploded in between point A and point B. Whipping around, I saw an entire squadron of enemy tanks descending upon our melee. I prepared to attack, but then I noticed they weren’t attacking me or my squad. They were helping us.

+What. Even.+

I wasn’t going to complain though, and neither was my squad from the look of things. I don’t know how much longer they would have lasted. They had managed to stay in their hover-hummers, which was good since I doubted the magical confusion field that seemed to make the enemy completely ignore our actions wouldn’t last if they got a look at the people inside the crafts. Aside from staying in the hummers, though, they hadn’t accomplished much else. Two were disabled thanks to dragons that had shredded their engine blocks or whatever it was that drove the whole “hover” component.

Aside from the fact that we were surrounded by apparently friendly enemies, things were going pretty well. So well in fact that it was just about time for fate to throw another fast ball our way, which arrived in the form of another clutch of drakes. Pandemonium reigned once more. I was, as per usual, a popular attraction as far as targets were concerned. Two dived for me. What the heck, it had worked once before. Jumping at the first one when it was a mere 7 meters above the ground I jumped forward and under it’s fall, slicing it’s neck and chest as I passed. That was the intent at least. I think I led a little too early with my scimitars and ended up getting it’s jaw and cheek, but I still cut far enough into its head.

Plowing into the ground the unfortunate lizard was hit in the back by the second dragon which had been coming at me from behind, crashing into the ground in a jumbled heap. It’s companion’s body cushioned it’s fall, if metal hard scales can really said to be able to “cushion” anything, and it regained its feet, although unsteadily, and attacked me with quick swipes of its claws.

Crap, I prefer it when they’re charging me. I jumped away from the first few swings, but wouldn’t be able to manage it for long. The air on this planet was ridiculously thin, and while it was thick enough for me to keep my head clear, I couldn’t keep up any kind of large physical exertion for long. I was already slowing. So was the dragon. In fact, he was having significantly more trouble than I was. Breathing great hefts of air, it didn’t seem to be able to get enough. I knew the feeling; I was starting to experience it as well. Wanting to end this fight before both of us ended up passed out on the ground to be run over by a tank, I aimed a swing at his arm on its next pass. The dragon tried to avoid my attack, but couldn’t, and it’s appendage came off at the elbow.

Roaring in pain, it exploded with new vigor. Frightened by its roaring right in my ear, so did I. Adrenaline fuelled and angry (or frightened in my case) we spent the next few minutes playing cat and mouse around the corpse of a tank. Guess which one was the mouse. Then he spoiled the sport by flipping the tank out of the way and throwing himself towards me, intending to knock me from my feet with a sweeping blow to my knees with his remaining foreleg. I blocked it with the edge of my lava scimitar.

It turns out lava swards aren’t really all that good at blocking. They tend to burn or cut off anything that touches their blade. T-rex the dragon only succeeded in loping off his other foreleg. Lucky for me too, since I doubted I would have taken too well to being smashed by the momentum of his attack. As it was I was still thrown off my feet as his arm, newly detached at the bicep, flew into legs, sweeping them out from under me and carrying me a good 50 centimeters back. Apparently dragons don’t take well to becoming wyverns, and T-rex, lacking the balance of his name-sake, flopped on the ground, attempting to balance on the forelegs that, in proportion to his body, appeared stubbier than a corgi’s.

The exertion had pushed me very nearly to the limit of my lungs, already straining to find more oxygen in this accursedly thin atmosphere, and I think I blacked out for a few seconds. When I regained full awareness, a tank had put Big T out of his misery and several more clutches of dragons and squadrons of tanks had entered the clusterfuck around me.

Previous thirteen

Next fifteen

All chapters

The Tigers Cub

by hume_reddit

I did manage to think of a bit more to write... it's a character piece, without a lot of action. Hopefully not too boring.

When the group and their lone human guest returned to Gao, Myun had hoped that she’d at least be able to skip her classes for a little while.

Alas, it wasn’t to be. She managed to miss a ten-day’s worth, but the time off definitely wasn’t fun or relaxing. It was by turns boring, frustrating, and sad. They were stuck in a medical facility, to make sure they weren’t hurt or sick or suffering from malnutrition. Myun was okay, as were the other cubs, but some of the Mothers were hurt... some badly, like Momma Benou, who’d caught the edge of a pulse pistol blast during their escape and almost died on the voyage home.

There was also the Goodbye ceremonies for the Mothers who had died, like Momma Hamfa. The females and even some males who had known her gathered and remembered the happy times with her, praising her sacrifice even as they wished it hadn’t been needed. Myun had keened loudly - she’d really liked Hamfa, who’d always been the “fun” and “silly” one of the Mothers, always making everyone laugh - but the cubs had gathered closely together and helped each other deal with their grief.

After that was physical checkups, nutrition shots, and endlessly being asked “How do you feel?” Momma Ayma had insisted the cubs start their lessons again, even as they had to wait out their stay at the hospital. Myun had been grumpy at that, but when they began she found herself paying particular attention. Things they’d touched on before - like the other species in space, their homeworlds and what kind of people they were like - were suddenly much more important. They’d met aliens, and not all of them were nice. Myun had decided that she hated the Corti.

And she loved the humans.

At first the doctors had kept Xiù in a different area of the hospital. The Gaoian females, tired from their own ordeal, hadn’t had time to think about it for the first few days of their return. Eventually it was Myun herself who demanded to know where they’d taken “Shoo”, and the Mothers realized that the sapient they owed their lives and freedom to had been missing for days, and they’d had no word of or from her. Ayma, who was nominally still in charge until the head Mother from their original commune arrived, had demanded an explanation.

“She’s an alien,” Doctor Havayo had answered, as if that explained everything. He was nice, and Myun generally liked him, but at that moment she’d have happily kicked him in the shins. “We have to be careful about contaminants, and she might have unknown but dangerous traits-”

“We were locked in a room with her for nearly three ten-days, Doctor,” Ayma answered. “It hardly matters at this point.”

“But we can’t make assumptions! There’s tests we need to run-”

“Bring. Her. Here.” Gaoian males were bigger and stronger, but nothing was as scary as an angry Mother.

Xiù was brought to their rooms, and even given a nest-bed of her own. She didn’t look like she’d been mistreated, but she was very happy to see them all again, especially Myun… the first thing the cub had done when she’d seen her was dash over and latch onto her arm. The human had dipped down and let her climb onto her back like a newborn, lifting her with effortless strength... strength not a single one of them - not even Xiù - had realized she had for the entire time they’d been imprisoned together, but strength that had been all too needed in the end.

With her return, their “observation” period was a lot easier to deal with. Before, it had seemed a bit too much like their time in the Corti’s research lab, even if the colours were brighter and they had windows looking out on gardens. They were still locked in together, and doctors would come and occasionally take someone for more tests, which was scary even if they came back healthier than before. Myun knew she wasn’t the only cub to feel that way, and some of the Mothers were edgy. But now Xiù was back, and they all knew nobody could keep her locked in if she didn’t want to be. Even the Mothers who were a little bit scared of the human were happier with her there.

Myun demanded that Xiù be there when it was her turn to get her Corti suppressor chip taken out. The human didn’t really know what was going on, but she followed when the little cub grabbed her hand when the doctor came, and held her paw as a small patch of the cub’s fur was shaved away; the chip was in deep, and the doctor had to numb a small section of her neck so they could excise it. Xiù’s suspicious, apex-predator stare had made the doctor nervous... but Myun squeezed her hand to let her know it was okay. Taking the chip out didn’t take long at all, and afterward the doctor sealed the wound shut with dermal glue.

After that she’d wanted to be there when they took the chip out of Xiù… but then they’d told her they wouldn’t be taking the chip out of her. Myun had thrown a fit, because they’d said that if they left the chip in it would weaken their immune systems and they’d get sick more often, even if they wouldn’t pass the illness on to anyone else. She didn’t want Xiù to get sick! It was Momma Ayma that took her aside and explained that Xiù had exactly the opposite problem: her immune system was too strong. The colds that could make her sick were just as strong, too strong for any Gaoian to survive… and so Xiù had to keep her implant, and the doctors had to make sure it was always working. Myun had reluctantly accepted that.

The doctors did lots of tests on the human. Sometimes she looked scared, but Myun remembered how Momma Hamfa would hold her paw when she got scared at the doctor, so Myun did the same thing, squeezing Xiù’s strange furless digits between her own. Whenever blood was needed, Hamfa would make the doctors draw it from her first, to show the little cub that it wasn’t a bad thing, and so she did the same, and found that was a whole lot easier to be brave when you were being brave for someone else.

Momma Ayma had looked at Myun proudly. “You’re going to make a very good Mother someday,” she’d said. Myun had been embarrassed and warmed by the praise.

Sometimes the doctors seemed interested in things that had nothing to do with keeping Xiù healthy, like how hard she could hit or how her species would breed. They would whisper words that Myun didn’t understand but found threatening, like ‘biopsy’ or ‘endoscopy’. Those were words Myun had heard while they’d been kept by the Corti, and she didn’t like them at all. The Mothers didn’t like them either, and by the time the hissing and snarling was done the doctors were nearly hiding inside their overalls; they still had hopes of having cubs of their own someday, but Momma Ayma made it very clear it would never happen if she heard they were mistreating their guest. After that they were a lot nicer.

Xiù didn’t speak Gaori, and so she looked upset and confused often as the arguments raged around her. Momma Garmin had looked at trying to get a translator, even though the devices were expensive, but apparently there was a big fuss with the other races… something that made asking for a translator that could speak Human a big deal, and they couldn’t get one. So Myun took it upon herself to teach Xiù. She brought her computer slate with her when she’d visit after her morning lessons, and she’d show her friend the little animated videos and read along with her as the teaching program spoke the sentences: “The laytun bird threw the seed in the water.” “Mother Maymo is wearing her warm yellow overalls.”

By the time they were finally - finally! - released from the hospital a ten-day later, Xiù was able to speak halting sentences, to indicate when she was hungry or had to use the toilet. She could say “please” and “thank you” (Momma Rumori had said those were the most important words in any language). The doctors seemed surprised by how quickly she became understandable… Momma Yulna snidely asked whether they’d forgotten Xiù was sapient as Myun looked on admiringly, looking forward to the day when she’d be old enough to use that tone of voice and not be scolded.

It was a relief to settle back into a proper commune, even if the circumstances were terrible. Originally they had all planned on migrating to a commune on the colony of Gorai, but after the tragedy of their journey and kidnapping they had no heart to try again. All of their belongings had been destroyed with the ship, but their original commune on Gao welcomed them back with open arms... even with their highly-unusual new member. Myun even managed to get back her old nest-bed in the cub’s dorm, but no matter how much she argued or spit or stomped her feet, Xiù didn’t get a nest-bed beside hers.

One of the first things they’d asked when they thought Xiù would understand was how old she was, and she’d said that she was relatively young… old enough to mate (her furless skin had turned a strange shade of pink) but never having had a cub of her own. That meant that she wasn’t a Mother, but with her adoption into the clan she could be considered a Sister, and so she slept in the dorm with the other mature females who weren’t Mothers.

Myun could tell that Xiù was often overwhelmed, sometimes frightened or sad. For the first day she didn’t leave her bed, but on the second day Myun barged her way into the Sisters’ dorm and dragged her out into the common area of the commune - the walkways that connected the various buildings, lined by gardens carefully tended by the Sisters. Myun knew that some species didn’t have time or interest in nature, preferring space stations and starships and the artificial. Gaoians weren’t like that… her people liked trees and flowers and other green things, and being out under the blue-green sky, and the soft feel of the breeze against fur.

Judging from how much happier Xiù seemed, her people were the same. So Myun made sure to drag her outside every day, even though the winter was coming and the air was getting chill (she’d thought humans would dislike the cold more since they didn’t have fur, but Xiù never complained). She also made her come to the main hall for meals, and the learning centre where they’d work together on Xiù’s vocabulary. And most heartening of all, she began practicing her battle-dance again, in a quiet area where the cubs would sometimes play, Myun beside her just like when they were imprisoned together.

Sometimes she felt like she was Mother to Xiù. Momma Ayma had declared that Xiù was clan when they were rescued, and she’d repeated it again when the doctors were looking at the alien as if she was a delicious nava grub, which is why she was entitled to stay at a female commune and was protected by the massed will of the clan.

The male clans hadn’t liked that at all. The adults hadn’t explained the fuss to her - in fact, they avoided talking about it anywhere she or Xiù could hear - but Myun would sometimes sneak out of bed and eavesdrop on the Mothers as they spoke quietly over tea after bedtime, when all the cubs in the commune were supposed to be asleep.

“What business is it of theirs?” Momma Yulna had demanded. Myun really didn’t need to sneak around to listen to Yulna… she was loud. Her missing eye had been cloned and replaced, but her fur was still white where it hid her scars, and ever since their rescue she got angry easily and often. Momma Gamin said she was hurt inside, in her mind, and that everyone should be patient with her, but Myun couldn’t help but notice that the other Mothers and Sisters tried to find excuses to be places that Yulna wasn’t, and the older Gaoian was alone a lot. But she was nearly as devoted to Xiù as Myun herself, and she was Myun’s favourite because of it.

“It’s none of their business,” Yulna repeated. “She’s female. Mammalian, even! She’s clan!”

“It’s not that simple,” Ayma said patiently. “She’s not Gaoian. There’s never been an adoption into the Clan of Females before, there’s no precedent. And she hurt their pride… she beat Trig’s thugs where the entire crew of the Winter Coat couldn’t. I think… I think some of them doubt our telling of events.”

“They want to challenge her?” Yulna’s incredulity could be heard all the way down the hall to where Myun huddled, listening. Then she began chittering hysterically. “Let them! I’d pay good credits to watch some uppity Redtail or One-Fang idiot get thrown through a wall.”

“And if she kills one of them in the process?”

“Why do you assume she would? She didn’t kill most of the mercenaries at the lab complex, not even the Allebenellin.” Yulna’s tone clearly indicated how merciful she would have been.

“But she did kill some of them.”

“So? Don’t tell me you pity them!”

“I will not mourn a single one of those butchers,” Ayma growled. “But I won’t ignore how they died, either.”

“Why would-”

“Clearly Ayma knows something we do not,” interrupted Momma Gamin, ever the peacemaker. “Can you explain?”

“It’s something the scientists learned from her,” Ayma replied tiredly. “Her people… they have - well… instincts, I suppose. They can learn a motion or response to such a degree that it becomes unconscious, without needing to think about it.”

“So?” Yulna challenged. “That’s hardly unusual. I don’t need to think about where I put my feet when I walk across a room, or how to move my muzzle when I speak.”

“You learned all that when you were barely a cub,” she replied. “Shoo’s people are different. They retain the ability well into adulthood. They can train themselves to react without thinking. And Shoo is trained in battle.” There was a pause. “I am not complaining or claiming superiority. Threaten a cub and none of us will consider before attacking, either. But we know what our triggers are. What are hers?”

“Do you think she’s a danger?” Momma Trivai asked softly.

There was another pause, and Myun had the feeling that Ayma was thinking her answer over carefully. “No. I wouldn’t consider her clan otherwise. But… have you seen her when she practices her battle-dance, her gung-fu? I don’t mean the slow, careful thing she’s teaching Myun. I mean when she goes out into the yard alone.”

“She’s very fast,” Garmin admitted. “I can see how she took apart that Corti’s brutes so easily.”

“She’s not there,” Ayma said, and her voice was sharp. “What you saw was Shoo’s body, moving without the assistance of her mind. She calls it meditation, and she says it is restful… like sleeping, except while awake.”

“But… it’s so long and complex-”

“Yes, it is, isn’t it?” Ayma agreed grimly. “And yet it’s the product of what she calls a `still mind’. It’s an example of what she’s capable of, without even thinking.”

The Mothers were all silent for long moments. “Shoo is my friend,” Ayma said resolutely. “I would be glad to call her Sister, and not just because she helped free us and protect the cubs. But we mustn’t forget that she is a complex, alien being. There will be surprises, not all of them pleasant… things she wouldn’t think to warn of us of, because it wouldn’t occur to her that we wouldn’t know. And I’d rather it not be someone from outside the clan with an agenda of his own to discover them first.”

Myun had quietly padded back to her nest-bed, confused by the conversation. It had sounded like Momma Ayma was saying Xiù could be scary, but wasn’t. It also sounded like the male clans were causing trouble. She knew that males weren’t typically dumb or cruel - the captain of the Journey Home, the ship that had rescued them from the prison, had been really nice - but the Mothers often warned that the leaders of the clans spent a lot of time fighting, trying to keep their positions against those under them.

Xiù could beat them all with one arm tied behind her. Were they scared of her because of it? Would they make her leave Gao?

Fortunately, just a few days after the overheard conversation, Xiù was visited by none other than Mother-Supreme Giymuy. It was Myun’s first time seeing the Mother-Supreme in person… she’d only ever seen her on holovid in school. The elder female’s fur had turned almost completely silver, and she radiated a stern authority that made everyone dip their heads as if they were just cubs themselves.

Giymuy ordered everyone - even her own assistants - out of the meeting room, and sat down to tea and sweetbreads with their alien visitor. Myun had sat outside the room along with the Mothers, who were all sitting quietly and pretending they weren’t straining their ears to hear any of the quiet conversation that was happening inside the room. Ayma tried to make the lone cub go back to the playground or the learning centre, but in a display of childish cunning Myun said she would go if Momma Yulna took her… and Yulna wasn’t going anywhere.

The meeting took a long time, but Myun didn’t fuss or act bored or give the adults any reason to want her to leave (which put her ahead of some of the Sisters, she noticed). When the doors opened everyone leapt to their feet as Giymuy walked out, her expression inscrutable. She turned to regard Xiù, who stood in the doorway and looked back calmly, her black and white eyes so similar to a Gaoian’s; then the human had bent at the middle, dipping her upper body toward the Mother-Supreme. It was unmistakably a gesture of respect, and Myun knew she didn’t imagine the pleased look in Giymuy’s eyes.

Momma Garmin lead the commune, so she escorted Giymuy and her assistants outside, where they exchanged a few words before the Supreme-Mother boarded her personal shuttle and set off back to the planetary capital. When Garmin returned it was with a confused look as she was nearly swarmed by the other females.

“Well?” demanded Yulna.

“She-” Garmin looked flabbergasted. “She said that Shoo likes habera cakes.”

Myun wrinkled her nose. Nobody liked habera cakes… she’d tried one once, finding it too bitter and the texture was weird. Apparently the Mother-Supreme had a fondness for them from when she was a cub, though that had to have been so long ago Myun couldn’t even imagine it.

“What?” Yulna asked, her voice subdued for once. “What does that have to do with anything?”

“I don’t know!” Garmin gestured helplessly.

They got their answer the next day, when the announcement was broadcast that Xiù of clan Chang of Earth had been formally adopted into the Clan of Females. The various male clans grumbled and spit, but in the end their opinions didn’t matter. Myun was elated.

That had all happened several months before. With the crisis done, Myun threw herself into her schooling, determined to learn as much as she could to pass it on to Xiù. After all: she was a Sister now, and barely knew anything about Gao or its people, but she was too old to come to lessons with the other cubs.

She also tried to learn as much as she could about humans and their homeworld. The clan was still looking for Earth, sponsoring the few captains who explored beyond Gaoian space, making quiet inquiries with the other races at the same time. Their investigations found some surprises: an unidentified alien had helped defeat a Hunter attack of all things at a space station belonging to the Vzk'tk Domain. His species hadn’t been identified, but as soon as they saw the holovids they knew he was a human… male, and hairier, and bigger than Xiù, but unmistakably the same species. There were also unconfirmed reports of an alien that almost singlehandedly turned around the fortunes of the beleaguered Dominion in their war with the Celzi… a creature that, for some reason, went by the name of “Human”.

Momma Yulna had chittered so hard she almost fell out of her chair.

It seemed as though that despite the obstacles the other galactic polities were putting into the path of the unaligned Gaoians, it would only be a matter of time before the human homeworld could be found, and Xiù could go home. As sad as it was to think about her leaving, Myun knew her friend missed her home clan, her sire and her truemother. (How strange, that she knew who they were!) She had decided that when Xiù went home, she wouldn’t whine or make a fuss or do anything to make her friend feel bad about it.

She also decided, equally resolute, that she’d go with her.

To Earth. Where everyone was strong, where they learned amazing battle-dances, and even a Hunter attack was a joke! Myun wanted to learn how to fight like a human, so that the next time the Corti tried to take them she could stop them. She could protect Momma Ayma and Yulna and not just stand there shaking… like she had when the Locayl had tried to take her that day in the prison, before Xiù had saved her.

That was why she was outside, on a crisp winter day, practicing the little bit of gung-fu Xiù had taught her.

She was in a small open area, a place surrounded on all sides by tall hedges and a stair that lead up to the main commune building. It was a popular place for the cubs to play outdoor games during the warmer times of year, but now it was wide and empty and a perfect place to be alone. A light dusting of snow covered the stone seats along the walls and the pebbled ground, but her fur and overalls kept her warm.

Xiù was hesitant to teach her… in her pidgin Gaori, she’d explained that she wasn’t experienced enough to be a teacher, she was just a student herself. She didn’t even consider herself a fighter; apparently what she really wanted to be was a storyteller, and she learned gung-fu to be able to tell her stories better. Myun wasn’t sure how that worked, but whatever; she begged and begged, until Xiù relented and showed her some very basic movements.

She learned those movements with the zeal of a fanatic. It was hard, as a Gaoian couldn’t move like a human… Myun wasn’t able to lift her legs anywhere near as high, and her centre of balance was higher even though she was shorter. But she adapted the movements to what she could do, and when Xiù saw how devoted she was to learning she added a few more, after checking with the Mothers to make sure it was okay. After that she was endlessly patient, and Myun got the impression that Xiù was happy to be doing something, contributing in some way to the commune.

The two would go down to the gaming area and practice, in the slow, steady manner that Xiù insisted on. Only once had the cub managed to talk her into showing her how the battle-dance was supposed to really be… when she would unleash herself and use all the speed and strength a human possessed. Too worried about accidents, Xiù had made Myun watch from the top of the stairs; the cub had watched, transfixed, as her friend became motion incarnate, even the snow rising up to swirl around her.

What Myun was being taught was nowhere near as fast or violent. It was gentle and slow and relatively easy for the little cub to emulate. Myun had protested at being taught “easy stuff”, but in a rare moment of annoyance Xiù had said taiji was how she’d started, and if Myun didn’t want to learn it right then Xiù wouldn’t teach her at all. The cub had been chastened… especially when Momma Yulna - who normally cared nothing about discipline - had stomped around the corner and voiced her agreement.

They hadn’t forbidden her from extra practice, however. So she would arrive at their practice area almost as soon as morning lessons were done and run through the motions she knew. Xiù had said there were one hundred and eight movements, and Myun had memorized almost thirty, although she still had to think and remember each one in turn… if she could do Xiù’s meditation, she’d shown no sign of it. She still tried… each night before going to sleep she would sit in her nest-bed in the dorm with her eyes closed, trying to concentrate on just her breathing and letting her mind go blank, just as Xiù had explained. It got her a lot of strange looks from the other cubs.

She had just finished move eighteen - bào hu gui shan, Xiù called it - when a voice interrupted her from behind, opposite to the stairs where the play area exited to the commons and walking areas that connected the buildings of the commune.

“Look at little Myun, trying to pretend that she’s an alien.”

Confused, she stood upright and turned to see a small gang of male cubs standing behind her. She recognized them all… they varied in age, and the most of the younger ones attended morning lessons with her. The speaker was the eldest, a big cub by the name of Riigo, and he looked at her with an arrogant expression, even the tilt of his ears showing contempt. His fur had begun to shift from the even dark greys of childhood to the steel colours and red ripples of adulthood. It would be another few years before Myun gained the white and black streaks across her arms and shoulders that indicated sexual maturity. She wasn’t in any rush… she had no desire to bear a cub and couldn’t imagine putting up with a male’s foolishness long enough to make it happen.

Foolishness like Riigo’s. He was at the age when he realized females were important, but not why. He was old enough to become interested in the power politics of Gaoian males, their natural desire to form a hierarchy, but too young to realize that females weren’t a part of that hierarchy and never would be. Soon it would be time for him to leave the nursery community and join a clan, most likely the clan of his sire, where he’d find his purpose and a firm hand to guide him to it. He’d be happier... the males of their species always were when they were pointed in a definite direction, no matter what it was.

Myun hoped that would happen soon, because he was getting really rather annoying.

He’d intended to make her angry, but the statement was just so dumb she couldn’t even process it. “I am not. I’m exercising. And I’m busy. Go away.”

“Yes, you are! You’re trying to learn that alien’s dance!” The other boys looked on curiously as he scorned her; Riigo was the biggest of them, and apparently had claimed the leader position of their little pack.

“So? It’s fun! Why do you care?”

“You just look stupid! The alien looks stupid, too, with that flat face and no fur!”

Myun felt her own fur standing on end in anger. “She’s not stupid! She’s way smarter than you, and stronger, too!”

“No, she isn’t!”

“She is!” Myun matched his scorn. “She could pick you up and throw you all the way to the meal hall! She got mad at the Locayl who tried to hurt me, and she kicked him, and crunch! He was dead, just like that!”

“So you say,” Riigo replied. “Everyone knows the females made that up.”

“What?” Myun demanded.

“You heard me. It’s just a story! An accident happened on your ship, and the males died, and so your group made up a story to make it sound like you were brave and had to fight. Everyone knows it didn’t really happen.”

“That’s a lie,” Myun hissed, more angry than she ever remembered being. She knew he was just being dumb, trying to make her angry… but he was implying that what they’d suffered, the deaths of Hamfa and the other Mothers, was nothing but make-believe. “Go away if you’re going to tell lies!”

Now he was getting angry. “I’m not a liar, you’re the liars! Why don’t you tell us what really happened?” He lurched forward and grabbed her arm, thinking to push her backwards and intimidate her.

Myun had enough time to blink and think: Did he really-? She didn’t feel any fear… in fact, she felt more curious than anything as she stepped aside, letting him keep his grip as her paw turned and rested gently against his elbow. She added a little bit of force in the same direction he was pushing.

Riigo fell over, letting go of her arm as his paws and knees hit the ground.

She blinked, and the other cubs looked on in shock. Elation and fear warred in her heart. Elation, because she realized that despite her obsessive study, she hadn’t really expected it to work.

Fear, because Riigo was standing back up... and if he was angry before he was furious now. He looked ready to hit her for real, and she could see the tips of his claws peeking out from their sheaths. Fortunately, whatever the cub might have done was interrupted by a shouted “Hey!” from the top of the stairs.

All the cubs looked up. At the top of the stone stairs stood Xiù, dressed in the long, warm coat the clan had made for her, the imitation fur carefully coloured to indicate her gender since - except for the long, black fur on top of her head - she had little of her own. The little lines of fur above her eyes were tilted in the manner that indicated she was angry. Her head-fur, so long and soft compared to a Gaoian’s, was braided and pulled forward over her shoulder.

Keeping her eyes on the cubs, the human carefully descended the stairs. As always, Myun marvelled at how smoothly she moved… she always looked like she was gliding, weightless. It wasn’t until she reached the bottom and the pebbles and snow crunched underneath her feet that her mass was hinted at, at least twice as heavy as the biggest Gaoian. And not just her body… the elder females had arranged for weights to be sewn into the clothing they’d made for her. Apparently the gravity on Gao was too light, and they were worried about Xiù losing muscle tone or bone density if she wasn’t weighed down like she would be on her homeworld. Her coat alone was almost too heavy for Myun to lift.

Myun had begun sneaking some weights into her overalls, into the cuffs and beneath the utility pouch… just small pebbles she picked up from the play area. She suspected Momma Yulna knew, but never said anything. She’d never be as strong as Xiù, but when she took her overalls off at the end of the day to sleep she felt much lighter, and she hoped that meant she was getting strong like a human.

Xiù came to a stop in front of them, and her eyes cast suspiciously over the group of boys. “Myun, what happens here?” she asked in her heavy accent. Despite Riigo’s words, most of the males were holding their heads low, their ear fur pricked with fear. Myun had to stifle a chitter of amusement even through her own nervousness.

The exception was Riigo, who glared at the human. Myun had embarrassed him, and now that an older female was present his ire had naturally transferred to her. He was almost as tall as she was, and if he’d looked at one of the Mothers with the expression he was currently wearing they’d shave his fur off with their bare claws. Xiù didn’t know she was being sassed, but even if he tried something it would be over so fast… squish!

But… that wouldn’t be a good thing, would it? Myun suddenly remembered what Momma Ayma said about Xiù being able to react without thinking. If the big cub tried to hit her, how would she respond? Would she treat it like the pathetic joke it was, or would she hit him back before realizing? And even if she didn’t, what would happen to Riigo? He was near the age where becoming violent with a female wouldn’t be forgiven. She didn’t like him, but she didn’t necessarily think he should be cut off from ever having a cub just because he was young and dumb… it was a phase they all went through.

“Myun?” Xiù’s hands were held slightly away from her body. Maybe she knew how to read Gaoian expressions better than Myun thought.

“They want to learn gung-fu!” Myun suddenly blurted. She felt a half-dozen pairs of eyes land on her, and her ears tilted back in embarrassment. “I mean… maybe?”

She turned to Riigo, who was looking at her with astonishment, his anger fizzling in his confusion. Myun forced herself to forge on, gaining speed as she became excited with the idea. There was no way he’d ever believe the lies if he actually saw Xiù in action. “Learn with me! It’s really fun, and Shoo says it can make you strong without big muscles! It’s just me right now, but it’d be so much better with someone else to practice with!”

Even Xiù was surprised. The tension in her frame disappeared, and she looked over the gathered boys with interest. The younger cubs were looking between the human, Myun, and Riigo - and did some of them look excited at the idea? Riigo looked at Myun with confusion, and she surprised herself by hoping he’d say yes.

Unfortunately the older cub just scowled and looked away. “I don’t need to learn silly alien dances! I’m going to join the One-Fangs like my sire! I’m going to fly a starfighter and kill aliens who attack us, even Hunters!”

Myun started to get angry again, but she pushed it down and let disappointment take its place. “That’s too bad,” she replied. “We’ll be here if you change your mind.”

Riigo looked surprised again, unsure how to deal with her sudden diplomacy. He sniffed, turning and walking out of the play area with his nose in the air. The other boys followed him, and she knew she wasn’t imagining the disappointment in their eyes.

“All okay?” Xiù asked softly after a moment. She was watching Myun with a concerned gaze.

She thought about her answer for a moment. Xiù would probably feel bad if she thought that Myun was being picked on because of their friendship; she’d think that the little cub felt excluded and sad. She didn’t… she felt wonderful! Xiù was the strongest fighter in the galaxy, but she need protecting, too… and Myun could do it! She was clan, and clan stuck together.

She didn’t say this; she just sniffed dismissively in the direction the other cubs had left. “Boys are dumb,” she said, and felt happy as Xiù laughed her strange human laugh.

Then the two began practicing taiji, and Myun didn’t complain, not even inside her own mind. By the end she’d memorized another two movements, and they left so Myun could do her homework and Xiù could offer her help in the kitchens with the end-of-day meal.

When they returned the next day they found Fallo - the smallest and most timid of Riigo’s group - waiting in the play area. The little cub shyly asked if he could join the two females in learning the human battle-dance.

After getting a confirming assent from Xiù, Myun gave him a welcoming hug. Then they began to practice together, and Myun felt right.

Part One

Quarantine

by Hambone3110

Part 4 of the Kevin Jenkins Experience

Jenkinsverse wiki page

“ALL of them?”

“Well we’ve not had enough time to count ALL of them sir, but… yes, it looks that way.”

“Well, what does it mean?”

Major Bartlett’s expression contorted into the open anguish of somebody completely at a loss. “Every single star in the sky suddenly becoming eight percent less luminous? The only scenario I can think of that would explain that one scares the shit out of me, sir.”

General Tremblay made an impatient noise. “Well then, start acting like a damn soldier and brief me!”

Every military man and woman in the room snapped back into the rigid posture of respect that had been ingrained into them in basic training. The general was an easy-going and relaxed man who ran an easy-going and relaxed unit - that rebuke coming from him carried triple the weight it would have from any other officer.

“Sir. The only scenario I can think of which would explain a uniform decrease in luminosity from our perspective of every star in the sky would be if we had become encased in an almost transparent shell of some kind, sir.” Bartlett reeled off.

“‘We’ meaning…?”

“The whole planet sir. Maybe the whole system. It depends on whether the outer planets have undergone a similar drop.”

“Find out.” Tremblay ordered, and Bartlett spun away with a salute and hustled to comply. “Somebody get Nadeau and whoever he thinks is his team’s premier expert on these electrostatic fields up here. And get me the defence minister.”

“He’s already on the line sir. He called you.”

“About this?”

“Yes, General.”

“How in the fuck did he find out?” Tremblay demanded.

“Apparently it’s all over the news, sir…”

++

The Abductees listened to the radio in silence for several hours. So, it seemed, did everybody else.

For those few short hours, for the first time ever, a subject commanded the entirety of the human race’s attention. Humanity forgot its wars and differences. Prejudices were set aside, wars ceased to rage. Across the globe, people gathered around radios, television sets and any device with Internet access as the world’ media collectively sifted, ground down and filtered the facts from the speculation.

There was much, much more of the latter, than of the former.

The same questions circled the globe, gaining just a little more force and passion with every repetition until, even if the individual humans may not utter the word aloud, the communication networks of an entire planet thrummed with one collective outraged cry:

“Why?”

Only a handful of people on the whole Earth knew the answer to that question. Most thought they were alone, and kept the answer to themselves. Some few were part of a convoy that had temporarily paused at a campground in Wyoming.

In San Diego, one withdrew a slim smartphone from his dapper, tailored suit and, by activating a very modern app, enacted a very old contingency plan.

++

The galaxy’s interest in the Sol system reached fever pitch with the news of the Enclosure. Official footage released by the quarantine fleet showed the experimental containment generator being established. It was an alarmingly small and unassuming little edifice - a metal ball scarcely larger than the average being, three or four meters in diameter, with an utterly featureless mirrored surface. It was guided into place by the tractor fields aboard a Confederate corvette, injected into a smooth orbit between the seventh and eighth planets of the Sol system, well inside the outer cometary cloud, and then, without fanfare or ceremony, was activated.

The only sign that this had happened at all came in the form of a few ghostly streamers of turquoise energy as the solar wind and energy output briefly battled with the field boundary, until they reached a stable equilibrium. Only scientific equipment could detect that the brightness and albedo of every object on the far side of the field edge was reduced by a small amount.

Aboard the Observatory, which had used its jump drive to relocate to orbit around Neptune, one Krrkktnkk A'ktnnzzik'tk, Councillor for the Vzk'tk Domain, gave a brief and passionate speech angrily denouncing what he proclaimed as a “miscarriage of justice against a young and vibrant species, unfairly and illegally sentenced without trial to indefinite imprisonment for the simple crime of being who they are.”

His words did not pass without support. Far from it - protests erupted all across the galaxy, and the interstellar communications grid practically locked with messages, videos, sensory recordings and essays condemning the move.

But a good third part of the traffic pointed out that if the Hunters had been similarly quarantined upon their discovery, their gruesome and horrific meat-slave raids and farms would never have happened. These messages pointed out that here too was a species that consumed the meat of even quite intelligent fauna species on their homeworld, whose history was one of ceaseless warfare, and whose physical durability and prowess in the field of violence would render them completely unstoppable should they prove to be hostile.

Footage circulated of a lone, unarmoured human slayinging Vulza with nothing but a fusion scythe, authenticated by reports from troopers who had seen the event first-hand. An expert witness - a Corti researcher with a particular interest in human biology - declared that the human in that footage showed clear signs of malnourishment, lack of exercise, and fatigue, meaning that he was operating considerably below peak efficiency. The same witness produced reports on a family of Vzk’tk who had required stasis at a class 10 experimental hospital for more than a standard cycle before they were finally able to be cured of the diseases that they had caught from only a few seconds’ contact with one escaped human specimen, and that these disease specimens had required immediate destruction lest they fall into the wrong hands and be used to engineer a viral superweapon. One brief video showed a human accidentally breaking a being’s medial spine with a single hearty slap: the contextual information revealed that the crippling gesture had been intended as a friendly one.

Countering these damning accounts came footage from elsewhere in the galaxy. A human giving her life to vent a hazardous materials spill into space and save the station she was aboard and its thousands of inhabitants, wading through radiation that would have fried the nervous system of any other being in moments. Footage of a human calmly holding down a struggling Vgork alpha male in Musth who had tried to enter a creche. The survivor account of one young Kwmbwrw who asserted that a human had carried her on his shoulders for three local days across the tundra of the planet V’chnbritz, delivering her nearly [120 kilometers] to a hospital after the passenger transport they had been on had crashed, before guiding rescue workers back to the crash sight. A Gaoian matriarch who passionately attributed her survival and liberty to a human.

Talking heads from all species tossed these facts and accounts back and forth between them, circling but never quite approaching a conclusion on whether the Enclosure had been the wrong thing to do. In the background, various governments quietly lined up alongside the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun Confederacy and congratulated them on their foresighted action.

Brooding in his office aboard the Observatory, Kirk received a message. He read it three times. He was still considering its implications when he received a second one. This, he read only once.

Then, cybernetic hand shaking, he tendered his resignation.

++

++

♪♫The good guys dress in black, remember that, just in case we ever face-to-face and make contact…♫♪

Terri had set her phone to play Will Smith’s “Men In Black” whenever her mysterious client called her. It had seemed appropriate given the nature of the job. Now, as some of the nearby Abductees gave her a strange look, she slightly regretted it. They had heard that song on the radio a LOT lately.

She walked away from the group a little way and answered.

“Terri Boone, it’s a pleasure to hear from you, ‘Mr. Johnson’.” she carefully pronounced the quotation marks around his alias. She wasn’t naive and at times like this the chance to prove it was welcome.

“And from you, Miss Boone.” Mr. Johnson had a curiously accentless voice. Just a hint of clipped British, just a pinch of DC politician, just a touch of Hollywood star, a whole lot of anywhere in the English-speaking world. “I think you’ll understand if recent events have made me eager to learn how your commission is going.”

“It’s… well, it’s gotten a little out of hand, to be honest.” Terri admitted.

“I hoped that it would.” Johnson said. The confession was made perfectly level and calm. “In what way?”

“I think we’ve picked up every genuine Abductee east of the Rockies.” she reported. “There’s some kind of a pilgrimage going on here, and I don’t quite know what its objective is. They all seem to be singing from the same hymnbook, but I don’t know the words.”

“Very religious.”

“I’m Catholic.”

There was a pause. An unnatural one - Terri realised she couldn’t even hear Mr. Johnson breathe, or laugh, or whatever he was doing. She almost jumped when he spoke again.

“Miss Boone, I think I consider your commission in the matter of finding the Abductees to have been satisfactorily completed. If you would care to leave the contact details with which I provided you in the care of whoever seems to be in charge, I have another situation in San Diego which requires your attention. Oh, leave them the credit card I gave you, too.”

“You don’t want to meet them?” Terri asked.

“I had an inkling that they would behave like this.” her client explained. “Your ‘pilgrimage’ was just waiting to happen, all they needed was somebody to set it in motion. If you could relay to them that their destination is a town called Scotch Creek, in British Columbia, then I think they will have all that we need.”

Terri shrugged. “You’re the man with the money.” She said, internally noting the “we” rather than a “they”.

“It’s always a pleasure doing business with a professional, Miss Boone. Please, call me once you’re back in San Diego and have taken a night’s rest.”

“Wait, I’m supposed to leave them the credit card AND get back? How am I going to pay for gas and motels?”

“Given that your commission has been completed,” said Johnson “you should find that your bank balance is replete. There’s even a bonus in there for travel expenses. I assume you have your own cards?”

“Well, yes, but…”

“Very good. I would prefer if you could fly back down, Miss Boone. Time may not be of the essence, but the sooner you are here, the better we can maintain our momentum.”

“I’ll... see you ASAP then.” Terri said.

“Bon voyage, Miss Boone.”

Johnson hung up. Terri stared at her phone for a minute, and then made use of the campground’s wifi to check her bank account. It was the first time she had ever looked at it and seen six figures before the decimal. And such a large six figures, too.

She glanced up at the sky, thinking. Whatever was going on up there was a mystery. Terri hated mysteries, and she could sense that the answer was wrapped up with the Abductees somehow. Was that kind of money really so important now that galactic forces had apparently taken an interest in Earth?

But then again… the world hadn’t actually ended, yet. And in light of that, it seemed probable that it would continue to not end. Mr. Johnson’s second project was clearly important enough to leave the first unsupervised, and if he had paid so well for the first, well...

A sensible, frugal woman could satisfy her curiosity all she wanted on that kind of money, well invested.

++

Perfection was a prosperous Class Three planet that had been granted independence from, and protection by, the four species whose territory encroached on the volume of space around it. Originally it had been simple neutral ground, but the Perfection system’s Platinum-rich asteroid belt and the verdant ecosystem of the planet Perfection had both contributed to making it wealthy. Interstellar trade conglomerates had taken an interest and the system was now, after several consecutive hundred-cycles of growth, a thriving commercial and industrial hub, the most densely-populated planet for some considerable distance in any direction.

The system capital city, Idyll, had long since ceased to live up to its name. Admittedly from a distance its gleaming skyscrapers, spun in glass and ultratensile steel that smouldered in the sunset, were breathtaking and the wealthy citizens who could afford to live in those buildings that caught the sun for an appreciable fraction of the day lived at the pinnacle of luxury.

But Idyll was as notorious for its festering streets and ghettos as for its glittering prosperity, and that squalid underbelly of Perfection was Kirk’s destination.

Given that his resignation was still echoing around the news channels as another act in the unfolding drama over Earth and the Humans, he had elected, rather than take a public or diplomatic shuttle, to splash on buying a new ship of his own. It had taken a bit of money on such short notice, but he had acquired an expensive star-runner that was little more than a bed, ablution cubicle and control seat bolted to the front of an enormous Domain fusion plant and the latest model of Corti black-box FTL engine. It was incomprehensibly fast, and about as safe as space travel could get: it could just outrun any interception.

Flash starships in most of the Idyll sprawl were prime targets for theft, but not where he was going. There was one specific block, he knew, where even the most expensive and rare collector’s-item ship could land and be completely safe, because the kind of beings who parked there had a reputation. He exploited that reputation to its fullest, wearing a full-length black coat with a privacy field generator in the hood. The most any witness might tell would be that they had seen a Rrrrtktktkp’ch.

Those witnesses would all know where he was going - none of them would tell. He passed a similarly cloaked figure and they exchanged anonymous gestures of recognition, and parted ways. The Contact kept to a mechanically precise timetable.

The Contact was a Corti. This particular Corti sat politely at a desk behind a modest computer terminal, and welcomed him with insincere warmth as Kirk entered.

“You are punctual. I like that in a new client.” she said.

“If only I were a new client, Vakno.” Kirk said. He lowered his hood, and the privacy field shut off. Just for a second, her composure slipped, and he allowed himself a little moment of private triumph.

“Officer A'ktnnzzik'tk. I had not expected to do business with you again.”

Kirk allowed her a tight smile. “We didn’t do business, Vakno, I arrested you.” He said. He enjoyed the way she winced as he speared her with her real name.

“Would it be too much to ask how you knew where to find me?” Vakno asked him. She waved a slender-fingered hand through the control field of her computer and it went dark.

“It would.”

The Corti hopped down from her chair and a door hidden seamlessly in the wall slid open, revealing a rather more comfortable suite of rooms hidden behind the office. “And here I thought I had learned not to underestimate you.” She said. “Please, come in.”

“Your schedule?” Kirk asked, joining her.

“On hold. When the most notorious Councillor in the galaxy walks into my office, I give him my fullest and most special attention.” She replied, a little too smoothly in Kirk’s opinion. “Are you here to arrest me again?”

“Are you trying to smuggle virus programs onto my station again?”

“You can plainly see that I am not.”

“Then you’d be outside my jurisdiction even if I was still a member of a station security force.” Kirk said, dismissively. “Just between us, and considering that the case is long-since closed and you did your time for it, what would those have actually accomplished?”

Vakno affected an air of wistful regret. “Oh, they would have got me the passwords to the private communicator belonging to a Xarx actress who was laying over on your station shortly after my visit. I had reason to believe it contained incriminating footage of her satisfying her mating urges in the company of a litter of Kwen siblings. Lucrative data, as I’m sure you can imagine.”

“And you wonder why the galaxy considers Corti to be morally bankrupt.” Kirk said.

“No, I don’t. Please, shall we get to business? I assume you didn’t visit just to reminisce?”

Kirk agreed, and sat down. “Humans.” He said.

“Ah, of course. What other subject would you be interested in right now?”

“I want to know how many of them the Directorate abducted.”

Vakno delivered the Corti equivalent of an, again, insincere and disdainful little laugh. “You think I have access to that kind of information. Your sense of humour has improved over the cycles, it seems.”

“The only thing that gets a Corti kicked out of the Directorate is directly acting against the interests of the Corti species as a whole. I KNOW you have access to that information.” Kirk retorted. “But all I want is to know how many humans are outside the containment field. That seems benign enough, doesn’t it?”

“Where humans are concerned there is no such thing as ‘benign’, Councillor A'ktnnzzik'tk. Every time one of them has escaped our zoological teams, or was released by well-meaning animal welfare officers, the results have been unpredictable and alarming.” Vakno displayed intense emotion, her grey skin flushing decidedly blue around the mandible. “The Directorate’s officialy policy regarding that species is ‘Do not underestimate them.’ Lone humans have changed the course of wars, infected whole cultures with strange new ideas, even triggered the development of whole new exotic technology branches.”

“All the more reason to keep tabs on the ones not quarantined on Earth, then.” Kirk said.

“What’s that charming expression of theirs? Bullshit, Councillor. Don’t expect me to believe that the same being who was loudly proclaiming how this quarantine is a travesty and a, quote: “Violation of their rights as a sentient race” end quote has suddenly had a change of heart and intends to help us enforce it.”

“And if I could pronounce that ‘charming expression’ I’d repeat it back to you. The Directorate doesn’t stand to profit if that field stays up. You’re the ones with all that hard-earned technology, all those products you’re ready to sell to the human market if and when it becomes available. You don’t stand to gain a damn thing by enforcing that quarantine. Quite the reverse, that’s a lot of investment written off.”

Vakno dismissed that. “Affordable.”

“Why accept an affordable loss at all when there’s a lucrative opportunity to be had? I buy that information off you and… well, we shall see where it leads. As you say, Humans are unpredictable.” Kirk paused. “Of course, being unpredictable could equally mean that they might breach that shield on their own. If and when that were to happen, don’t you think it would be more lucrative to be counted among the species that advocated and contributed to their freedom?”

“I don’t have that kind of authority and you know it.” Vakno snapped.

“No Corti does, I know. That’s not how your species works.” Kirk agreed. “But if the Directorate haven’t got plans to play both sides and put a positive spin on it when they turn out to have been on the winning side all along, well, then you’re not the pragmatists that I know you are. Especially you personally, Vakno.”

He settled back and played his best card. “Or of course I could spread the word that The Contact wasn’t able to help me...”

There was a long, chilly pause, and then Kirk’s personal implants acknowledged receipt of a file transfer.

“Just so you’re aware, A'ktnnzzik'tk, I will be notifying the Directorate to amend our official policy.”

“You will?”

“Oh yes. It seems we shouldn’t underestimate Humanity’s allies, either. Get out.”

++

++

“Faster-Than-Light travel.”

“Yes, General. Technically, a variant on the Alcubierre warp drive.”

Tremblay stared blankly at the report. Much of it was incomprehensible physicist jargon and blocks of arcane mathematics. “Alcubierre?”

“Miguel Alcubierre Moya, a Mexican theoretical physicist. He proposed his warp drive ideas in ninety-four, but there are some… issues with it that kept it purely theoretical.”

“Spare me. This is a variant on his design?”

“Well, it was never technically a design as such just the mathematical…”

“Major.”

Bartlett paused, and the rebuke finally got through the intellectual haze that he had been swimming in from the day he had first laid his hands on the alien technology.

“Sorry, sir. Uh… effectively, yes. In layman’s terms, sir… It’s kind of like walking on the moving walkway at an airport. You might be doing five kilometers per hour, but if the walkway’s doing that too in the same direction then you wind up travelling at ten KPH, right?”

“I’m familiar with the phenomenon.” Tremblay said. “So that’s what this warp drive does?”

“Kind of, sir.” Bartlett’s tone of voice suggested that the analogy was far from adequate, but he forged ahead. “The principle hinges on expanding and contracting spacetime around the ship. Some of the tech in those alien pods that shot through the arena roof held the key.”

“The key being…?”

“Well, they’re so fragile, how the hell would they survive slamming through reinforced concrete at that kind of speed? We wouldn’t, and it looks like humans are much tougher than those aliens were.” Bartlett consulted his own notes at this point. “The report has it that the pods contained devices which temporarily suspended the flow of time inside the field they generate.”

“And that led us to faster-than-light travel somehow.” Tremblay finished for him, and examined the report in front of him. “Something to do with space and time being the same thing, it says here.”

“Spacetime, yes. And if you can stop time, you can stretch space. And once you can stretch space then you can stretch it so that your spaceship-on-a-walkway is going faster than light.”

“How much faster?” Tremblay asked him.

“That depends on how much juice you give it, sir. More power, more speed.” Bartlett said. “I couldn’t give you exact numbers, that’s going to take a lot of experimentation.”

“I think we can take my okay for a working warp drive as read, Bartlett.”

“Thank you sir, but it isn’t quite that easy. We can’t test it down here on Earth. If we want to go ahead with this, it’s going to have to go up to the ISS.”

“Why?”

“Because if we get it only mostly right the resulting explosion would be like a nuke going off.” Bartlett wobbled his head. “Plus, you know, we’re testing an FTL drive here. You need a lot of room to work with just to measure the results.”

Tremblay sighed. “I guess it was only a matter of time before we started having to share this stuff outside of NATO. I’ll contact the Defense Minister, pass the buck to him and the PM. Any other crazy surprises come out of those pods that I should know about?”

“Not today, sir.”

“Right. Carry on, Major.”

“Sir.” Bartlett left, poring over his notes as he went. For the first time in several days, Tremblay suddenly found himself with a spare and quiet moment. Robbed of anything to distract him from it, the fatigue of the last few days hit him at full force and he sat back, rubbed his face, ran his hands back across his scalp and stretched in his seat, resolving to take ten hours to sleep tonight rather than reading base reports in bed for a few hours.

He must have dozed off anyway, because he woke with a snort when there was a sharp knock on the door. He stole a glance at the wall clock as he cleaned himself up and straightened his clothes - “Come.”

Tremblay had worked with Sergeant Ramsey, the base’s chief of perimeter security, for years, and the only thing stopping the two men from being good friends was the demands of professionalism. They still played poker with a few other senior staff every Sunday though. For the duration of those games, they were just Steve and Martin. Right now though, Ramsey ripped off a salute.

“I thought you’d want the buck passed on this one, sir.”

Tremblay stifled the urge to yawn. He trusted Ramsey’s judgement, implicitly, and so simply replied “Okay, pass it.”

“We’ve had a… I guess the best word is “convoy” show up, sir. About thirty cars, vans, all civilian. They’re staying on a field down in town, but one of them delivered this to the gate guards.”

He placed a plastic binder on the general’s desk and stood back, watching as Tremblay flipped it open. A few wide-eyed seconds later, Tremblay looked up.

“I want to talk to the man who delivered this.”

“Yes sir. He’s at the gatehouse. He said his name is Jenkins, sir.”

++

Humans don’t make good pets part 15

by guidosbestfriend

Better late than never. I thought I would be able to get this one out much sooner, but, well, here it is, a week since the last one. Regardless, special thanks to /u/Lostwingman07 for a comment on XIII, /u/ctwelve regarding punctuation (you were right), /u/Hambone3110 for the wiki which kept me from committing a discrepancy, and the multitude of authors who motivated me to stay up longer than I should have on several occasions so as to get this out “on time”.

Alien measurements are given their appropriate names with equivalent human measurements in (parentheses). Alien words with Human equivalents are put in [brackets]. Thoughts are italicized and offset by "+" symbols. Dialogue directed towards the protagonist using the gesture language are enclosed by inequality signs “< >”.

“On our [2 o’clock], their lines are fluctuating!” Gicerpt shouted excitedly, nearly losing his grip on the tank’s targeting scope. Baltvec grinned, a feral growl of excitement escaping his lips.

“Finally! What’s caused it? Is there any way we can exacerbate the situation aside from just charging in there and shooting everything to hell?”

“I think it’s those rovers again. Which squad do you think they’re from?”

“It doesn’t matter,” Blatvec cut in, “How are they still alive and what’s their current situation?”

“Honestly, I don’t know if they are still alive. There’s too many vehicles and Vulza – wait – the Vulza, they’re attacking the Celzi vehicles! They’re attacking their own team! Ha! I knew they didn’t have a firm control over those beasts; no one can control something that powerful. Now the only question is what set them off?”

“Does it really affect us right now?” shrugged Blatvec, “We can worry about how to get them to defect later. Right now we’re going to use the weakened lines on the edge of that skirmish to punch through and hopefully end this battle by outflanking them.” Relaying his orders to his sub-commanders, the Dominion horde, now containing more than 30 squads of repurposed Celzi vehicles, moved as one towards the outskirts of the swirling maelstrom where the lines were weakened due to the units called to assist with the Vulza uprising.

As Baltvec’s squad led the charge, coilguns blazing, he felt pity for any Dominion forces caught within the storm of metal and scales. Nothing could survive such bedlam unscathed.

Dear Journal,

Remember that whole military genius thing?

Yeah, more like prodigy,

Not that I’m going to go around bragging about it (I totally am).

What had started out as a friendly tussle between blood enemies had become a full-fledged war in and of itself, with an entirely new set of rules than the battle raging around it. Those I had previously thought were enemies were now fighting with my squad, or rather, for my squad. Their hover-hummers had been shredded, flipped, and pummeled from every side. I was surprised they were still large enough for my friends to use as cover.

Crouching beneath the remnants of their rides, my squad fired at any dragon that got too close. They seemed to have accepted the enemy’s assistance, and thankfully refrained from informing our new friends of our true allegiance by not attacking them. I still couldn’t believe that the enemy still thought we were on the same team – what else could be keeping them from attacking us - but I wasn’t going to complain.

I on the other hand, had no hover-hummer wreckage to hide under, not that I would have been content to do so if I had. My friends were basically helpless without the death ray cannons of their hummers, and I wasn’t about to let a stray dragon pick them off. Circling the smoking vehicles, I attacked any drake that got too close, and there were many. I was becoming genuinely exhausted, helped in no way by the ridiculously thin air, and my jumps were a mere fraction of their original length, my reflexes slow.

I was fortunate the dragons seemed to be faring even worse than I. They probably needed more air, so it made sense, but it was the only reason I was able to keep fighting so many when I had before so often struggled to kill only one. Now I waded through their attacks, dodging their drunken attempts to stop me with my lagging, yet still greater, strength. I wouldn’t be able to keep it up forever though. My squad’s vehicles, though in the same general area, were still too far apart for me to guard completely at the same time. Our fight seemed to be drawing every dragon from the battlefield, and despite the monumental effort on part of our new frienemies, the drake count continued to increase.

My fears were realized when two dragons attacked from either side, one going for Manthlel’s rover and the other attacking Rekt’s, one of the squad’s heavies. I was closer to Rekt, so sprinted – more like jogged at this point – to intercept his reptile. So intent was it upon its prey it failed to notice me until I stabbed it through the wing and in the side. That got its attention, and it bucked, throwing me with its wing, roaring with pain. I jumped back up, renewing my attack. Infuriated, it leapt at me, which meant the fight was over.

Dodging to the side in the now familiar maneuver I racked its neck and chest with my lava scimitars, cutting its windpipe and damaging its cardiac area. I wasn’t exactly sure where the heart was, but I assumed if I hacked around the general area where I assumed it to be I would achieve the same effect. Despite my quick disposal of the beast, I’d been too slow. The other dragon had reached Manthlel’s downed hummer, and I could already here shouts of alarm and panic through the monsters roars.

“NO!”

I had worked too hard, protected them for too long, to fail now! Raising my ragged, smoke-torn voice, I bellowed in rage and denial as I pulled upon my final reserves of strength, sprint-jumping towards the unfolding carnage.

Refusing to think on what I would find, I jumped over the flipped hummer, bringing the dragon’s back into view. I took advantage of my position to land on top of it, driving my blades as far into its back as I could, hoping one of my friends was still alive. It didn’t even react. The drake didn’t even move despite my burning weapons sticking out of its hide.

+What the -+

It was already dead. Shocked by this unexpected turn of events I slid down its back and into the do-it-yourself bunker underneath the hover craft. It was easy to scramble into since the dragon’s head was shoved into it, propping the hover-hummer with a foreleg, where it would have been able to bite and grind my squad mates into dust.

The inside of the fox-hole was a mess. Two squad mates lay on the ground, bleeding from wounds that had been instantly fatal, and a third lay unconscious against a wall, bleeding from the stumps of what had been two of his legs. Manthlel, however, was the focus of my attention. Orange skin the pale shade of Tang powder, he stood trembling, his arm attached by a thread, the other end clamped within the dragons mouth which was mere centimeters from his face. It had died in that position, but I still couldn’t tell you how or why. Then I saw it’s glazed, open eyes.

Every blood vessel within its slit irises appeared to have burst simultaneously, flooding its green eyes with blood as deep a red as mine. I looked at Manthlel in askance. Still shaking, he held up the pin to one of those grenades that were so effective against me. It took me a moment to comprehend what he was trying to say. When the light-bulb flickered to life my eyes went wide, and I immediately pried the beast’s jaws apart. There, cradled upon its tongue as its final trophy was Manthlel’s disembodied arm, its hand still clutching the brain-frying grenade that had ended the creature’s life.

I stared at Manthlel again. Raising his three remaining arms, he gave me a shaky thumbs-up.

Manthlel was trembling, but he didn’t care if anyone saw it. If anyone had asked he would have told them the truth in an instant: he was scared shittless. The only difference now was that he wasn’t even considering running away. Even if he had wanted to, he wouldn’t have been able to make it far in the confused disarray outside the cover he and the other squad mates had dug underneath their overturned rover.

They weren’t really doing anything from their position. The only weapons that were having any affect in this battle were coilguns or turrets, and without their rover, the only thing his group had now were anti-tank and heavy pulse guns, a few pistols, and one nervejam grenade each. With such paltry weaponry they wouldn’t be able to do a thing if anyone decided to attack them. Thankfully, Human did have a say in the matter, and he had Fusion Scythes, which were far more effective in his hands than any coilgun.

Manthlel had never seen him fight like in the way he did now. A blur across the battlefield, he shot from Vulza to Vulza, slaying each and every one that approached their impromptu entrenchment. Manthlel had seen him move fast before, but he seemed to be drawing upon an inner power source he had never before used. He was killing Vulza as though they were just as weak as any other being. The exertion was obviously taking its toll on him, however, and Manthlel could tell he was getting tired as his movements began to slow. Despite his growing fatigue, he still managed to stop every Vulza which threatened their position.

That was why Manthlel wasn’t worried when one started charging their position. At any moment Human would come charging in, slicing the monster’s head off with a single swipe or snap its neck with is bare hands. He had never actually see Human do that before, but Manthlel didn’t doubt he could.

When it had closed half the distance unimpeded Manthlel started to feel the first flutters of panic within his gut. Judging by the nervous shuffling of his companions by his side, they were as well. When it had closed two thirds of the distance and Human still had yet to make an appearance the group of four opened fire against the approaching beast, hoping to slow it while Human took his sweet time. An anti-tank pulse hit it square in the nose - which only served to enrage it - causing it to double its speed and traverse the remaining distance in two enormous leaps.

It was upon them before they could react. Lifting the rover off the hole the Vulza shoved its head into their improvised cover, instantly transforming their place of refuge into a deathtrap. One of their numbers died instantly, his upper body parting ways from the lower. Manthlel couldn’t understand.

+Where is Human? Why has he suddenly abandoned us?+

Panic threatened to overwhelm him completely as another squadmate met a similar fate as the first.

+I’m going to die I’m going to die I’m going to die . . . +

The same voice of paralyzing terror that had resounded within his head the same day he ran from the Vulza that massacred his first squad pounded once again within his mind until it echoed in his ears as well, his voice giving flesh to the most basic of instincts: self-preservation.

A roar shattered the air around him, but it wasn’t from the Vulza. It was an echo from the past, the brother of the challenge Human had thrown that first battle. It wasn’t the same, however. This was no herald of extinction. This was a scream of loss. A cry of failure and pain, but even more than that, it was the rejection of defeat, a disavowal of failure. It pulsed with an oath of vengeance and a pledge of retribution. It drove away the shackles of fear that had rooted his feet to the ground and replaced his trembling with the stiffened limbs of rebellion. As before, Manthlel found himself repeating Human’s shout, but for a different reason. He would not let this be his end, he would not die without a struggle. He would have his revenge upon this beast, not only for the lives of those it and its kind had already taken from him, but for making him forget that he was more than just its frightened prey.

He would be its downfall.

It struck again. Whether by some preternatural insight or because he had tripped a few moments before it struck, Manthlel’s only other living squad mate managed to keep anything vital out of the beast’s mouth. It was still quick though, and managed to catch several of the unfortunate soldier’s legs, reducing them to stumps. Distracted with its newest victim, it didn’t notice as Manthlel yanked the nervejam grenade off his belt and pulled the pin. It did notice him when he shot it in the head with his anti-tank gun. Blinded by the light, it roared in anger, changing targets with a speed that defied plausibility. Manthlel was ready though, and as it stuck, he stepped towards it, shoving this hand deep within its gullet.

Seemingly surprised to find such willing prey, the beast closed its jaws around his arm, removing it with the snick of teeth slicing through flesh. Manthlel’s bellow turned into a roar of pain. The grenade detonated. The Vulza’s skull acted like a resonance chamber, rebounding, containing, and increasing the deadly emission from the grenade. Every vessel, neuron, and membrane within the monster’s head exploded. Only because of its bones and scaled hide did its head itself not explode. It died with the same expression of victory upon its face.

A sound came from outside. Human had finally showed up. There was a moment of silence, then the biped slipped into the hole, pausing to take in the mess. He looked at the dead beast, did a double-take, then looked at Manthlel with a question in his eyes. Wordlessly, Manthlel held up the pin still clutched in his hand. It wasn’t until he saw the little ring and rod rattling up and down that he realized he was shaking uncontrollably.

Human seemed confused for a moment, until he pried the creature’s jaws open. Seeing his arm and the grenade still within its mouth, Human looked at Manthlel, for the first time in his memory, a look of shocked incredulity upon his features. Manthlel didn’t know what to say, so he just flashed that strange hand gesture, hoping it would suffice. Human took one look at it, then burst into a barking hiccup which Manthlel realized moments later was raucous laughter.

It had worked. Blatvec couldn’t believe it. The 74th, finding strength in the abandonment of the code, had demonstrated once again why they were considered an elite force. The Celzi forces had been routed, and the cyclone of traitorous Vulza and Celzi which had allowed such a feat had finally run its course, leaving only severely damaged Celzi and crippled Vulza in its wake.

The battle wasn’t over though. Even though the Celzi line had been destroyed, the sensor outpost which was the purpose for this fight still required attention. The only problem was its defenses. While the 74th may have managed to vanquish the mobile guarding force, the Celzi had controlled this station since the beginning of the war, giving them ample time to make its defenses nigh impregnable.

Artillery pulse turrets, coilguns, even a few plasma cannons dotted the landscape surrounding the compound. As large as their force was, too many from the 74th had died before they could commandeer a vehicle of their own. Blatvec doubted his forces would be able to punch through the Celzi defenses and survive with a force large enough to combat the token guarding squadron inside the station.

The battle plan he had been briefed on had told him orbital forces would destroy the compound’s defenses from a safe distance, making it so that all Blatvec had to do was stroll in and claim a victory. He had been told that, while the fighting on the ground would be difficult, the fighting above the planet would be a walk in the park, with friendly forces outnumbering hostiles four to one. The battle on the ground had taken even longer than expected. Admiral Licik, the commander of the armada that had acted as escort to the 74th, should have long ago finished his work above.

+What’s keeping him+ mused Blatvec. They couldn’t afford to wait long. Every moment they waited gave the Celzi more time to regroup and mount a counteroffensive. They were scattered for now, but if they managed to reformed they would pose a significant threat.

+I’ll give him two rics (one hour), then we’ll have no choice but to charge and hope for the best.+

I take back that whole military prodigy part.

These Xenos are just military idiots.

Manthlel had fainted while I was still laughing at the thumbs up he had given me. Really, it wasn’t all that funny. The absurdity of the situation had just struck me at an odd moment and I couldn’t help it. I guess all the blood loss did a spell on him, and I ended carrying him and the other guy who was missing his legs out of the hole for the squad medic to take a look at. Leaving Manthlel and Kecce – that was the other guy’s name – in Hectal’s capable medical hands, I sought out Turkey.

Trxcl was still in shock. He stood, transfixed, outside of the hastily excavated hole he and his other squad mates had created underneath their overturned rover.

+I’m still alive, right? Things got a little crazy at the end there. Maybe I got hit, but didn’t die right away, and the blood-loss has me hallucinating. Maybe I’ll be dead soon and this will all be over+ Then human walked around the side of the disabled rover. Trxcl groaned. It wasn't over. If it was, and Human was in his hallucinations, then he hoped he would die quickly. But if it wasn’t a hallucination, then that meant it really was possible for a species like Human to exist, although after seeing him fight today, Trxcl would have sworn it to be a fever dream or the result of a soldier’s story gone too far, if such a thing were possible.

Human began to move his hands.

<What’s next?>

+Not what I want, unfortunately+ Thought Trxcl, but his hands flashed the orders he himself had only just received, <Nothing. We wait.>

<Why?> Shit. This would be hard. Human hadn’t been able to be briefed on the existence of the sensor station. They didn’t have a word for it, so how could they? Really, his only task had been to fight, and he’d gone well above and beyond the call of duty on that one. Trxcl decided to use the words available to him rather than try to teach Human new gestures.

<The enemies ahead are too strong. We are waiting for an orbital strike to weaken them. It is taking longer than expected.> At least, that’s what Trcxl hoped he had said. Really, their language was just a conglomeration of nouns and verbs and a few vital adjectives that they arranged in chronological order, with the verb coming after the noun. Trxcl didn’t know why such a strange sentence structure was used, but he guessed it made sense to Human. It seemed he had understood, because his next response made contextual sense.

<We can’t use the tanks?> Human gesticulated.

<We could, but with many casualties.>

<Why not use the drop ships?> Trxcl was surprised by the question. Such a thought hadn’t occurred to him at all, yet he wasn’t a strategist. After he thought about it for a moment though, he could see why the plan was flawed.

<The drop ships themselves *would* survive the charge, but when we got out of them we’d be torn apart.> Still, it was an interesting concept.

+Maybe if we used the vehicular drop ships from the 13th and 32nd to drop the tanks behind enemy lines?+

No, that wouldn’t work either. The vehicular drop ships were basically just a cockpit connected to a pair of clamps in the back. The clamps would lock onto the outside of the vehicle in question and then carry it, crew inside, to the necessary location. That meant, aside from a structural force field to protect the vehicle form the vacuum of space, its outer hull was exposed to energy based attacks, and the power from a plasma or coil shot would easily overwhelm the force field. Even if the stations defenses would have difficulties damaging the heavily plated hulls of the drop ships, they would still be able to shoot the vehicles right out from under their charges, resulting in an airborne massacre.

Trxcl had allowed his mind to wander. A whirlwind of action erupted directly in front of him, and he jumped back in surprise, startled as human almost hit him in the face trying to regain his attention.

An exasperated look upon his face, Human signed <That’s not what I meant. Why don’t we use the drop ships, not as drop ships, but as weapons.>

Confused, Trxcl guessed at Human’s meaning, <The drop ship turrets aren’t effective again->

With an abrupt motion of his arm Human cut him off, then started gesturing with short, frustrated signs, <Not the turrets, the drop ships themselves.>

Trxcl must have misunderstood. What his mind had translated hadn’t made any sense. The drop ships only had the one turret. How else could they be used offensively? <I’m sorry, I don’t understand.> Human gave him a flat stare, grabbed his hand, then, with a force Trxcl was scared would tear his arm off, started dragging him towards the nearest operational tank.

Really, why was this so difficult for Turkey to understand? Sure, he wasn’t the sharpest knife in the cutlery drawer, more like a spoon. Our gesture language was comprehensive to the point that I had assumed conveying my point would be elementary. Really, was my idea that unconventional that no one had thought of it before? Never mind Turkey, someone had to. Now that I thought about it, I couldn’t remember any indirect artillery fire during the battle. In fact, the tactics I had seen throughout the battle were essentially the same as seen in feudal Europe, just with ray guns. And tanks. And dragons. Yeah, just like feudal Europe.

Were the professional militaries of the galaxy really centuries behind the tactics of humanity? I’m not one for thinking about implications – in case you hadn’t noticed – so I decided to reign my thoughts back to the matter at hand. Maybe my idea was somewhat unconventional. After all, I was proposing we use a spaceship as a glorified guided missile. It had an autopilot, and I had even seen it used enough times over the last 6 months that I was confident I would be able to do what I had in mind without assistance. As far as being wasteful, I had seen the troopship use a massive alien 3D printer to spit a drop ship out every hour. They would be able to make up the loss. I had a feeling our division had lost a lot of men in the battle, so they wouldn’t need their drop ships to return to the troopships. Heartless, but practical.

It would have taken far too long to traverse the length of the battlefield on foot, so I dragged Turkey behind me as I walked to the nearest operational tank. Ignoring the soldier relaxing on its top, I jumped up the hatch motioning for Turkey to follow. As the soldier looked on in curiosity, Turkey, a familiar look of confusion upon his blue-giraffe face – really, I don’t think I’ve ever seen a blue-giraffe without that look – climbed into the tank after me. The inside was a mass of buttons and consoles I had no idea how to use, but the navigational array looked nearly identical to that of the drop ship’s. In fact, I think it was more simplistic, as it wasn’t equipped to move in three dimensions.

Thankfully it was already on and idling. Too bad turning one on wasn’t as simple as pushing a button. I think a lever was involved in there somewhere. Keying up the power – a touch-slide on a console is so much less satisfying than flooring a petal – the tank lurched into action. I may have overestimated the force of acceleration, because the shout of surprise from the top of tank seemed to fade in the distance after the initial lurch. That and I had difficulty maneuvering my sweet ride through the maze of rumbling vehicles despite my many years of navigating Chicago traffic. Actually, Chicago’s usually backed up, so those years were probably counterproductive.

Still, I had made my decision, and I wasn’t slowing down. Handling the tank like a 16-year-old male driving through the red-light district, Turkey was thrown about the cabin. Thankfully it seemed to have been built with the fragility of aliens in mind, and instead of the cramped labyrinth of sharp metal corners that are the cabins of modern tanks, it was far more spacious with padding over every surface. He’d be fine. Not only was my mad rush across the battlefield extremely satisfying to the testosterone driven beast within me, we made it back to the drop ships in record time.

Cursing the fact that the tank floated above the ground, making it impossible for me to skid to a stop in a shower of dirt and gravel, I slid the iPhone accelerator back to idle with a feeling of disgust. Aliens had no respect for the simple pleasures in life. Hopping out, I moved to the nearest drop ship, urging Turkey to speed up. By the time he joined me in the cockpit I was impacitantly tapping my foot as I stood by the navigation consol. Gesturing to an orbital rendering of a 20 kilometers radius around the drop ship, I moved my hands.

<Where is the enemy holding?>

Looking even more confused, Turkey pointed to a general are about 18 kilometers from where we stood on the map. I quickly started hitting buttons, racing to finish before he realized what I was doing. It took him a moment, but when I moved my hand to the red-button-of-engaging, he started spitting-clicking in his alarm at what I had done. Trying to undo all my hard work he struggled to cancel my commands, but I stopped him, dragging him from the console. I wouldn't want him to miss seeing my idea in action. Depositing him outside the drop ships bay doors; I walked back to the console and hit the red button. I didn’t need a translator to know Turkey was enraged as I jumped from the slowly closing shuttle bay door to land by his side.

Trxcl hadn’t wanted to go with Human on his adventure of miscommunication. He had had one great idea, but that didn’t mean he would be able to think up another miracle strategy to make an orbital strike appear out of thin air. There was little he could have done, however, as human had all but forced him into a tank, driving with such reckless abandon Trcxl thought he may have survived the battle only to die at the hands of his squad’s most valiant hero. He hoped that 74th man was okay after being thrown from the roof of his charge. Trcxl felt bad for having told the soldier not to bother himself and that they were only going for a look. He had sincerely though it to be the truth when he had said it.

Now he stood, watching helplessly as the drop ship, doomed by Human’s commands, flew into the air on the last trip it would ever make. He knew he shouldn’t have been surprised that Human even knew how to enter the meanest of commands into the navigational array. He had shown that he was intelligent in both senses of the word. Well, in some ways. Lessons such as how to recklessly drive a tank and make a drop ship commit an elaborate form of self-destruct he learned with ease, but try to tell him it scarred the new recruits when he shout-growled in the showers – or whatever it was that he had been doing in the communal bathroom after his first battle – well, he still did that sometimes.

So it shouldn’t have surprised him that Human had been able to drive the tank or set coordinates for the drop ship; he had seen Trxcl himself do it for a standard cycle (6 months) now, but he seemed to have missed one crucial point. He had told the ship to go to a particular place as though it were floating in the vacuum of space. It would travel to that location then merely shut off the engines. He hadn’t specified that it was to travel to that location then land. Why he wanted to send the enemy a drop ship Trxcl couldn’t fathom. Did he really think they would just get in it and fly away? Was he really that oblivious? The Celzi never surrendered. Until Human had come they had rarely had any need to even considered it unless facing the 74th.

Whatever Human had thought the drop ship would accomplish, Trxcl knew what would really happen. It would fly a perfect arc to the location Human had specified – at drop speeds too boot, unless Trxcl had only imagined Human hitting that particular green button – then cut its thrusters mere borts (half meters) above the ground, impacting with a terrible destructive force.

Trxcl gasped as this though occurred to him, just as the bright light of the drop ships afterburners could be seen falling from the sky. Turret coil shot, artillery-pulses, and plasma bolts rushed up from the forest to stop it, but it was moving far faster than any pilot wishing to avoid crashing would have dared, making it almost impossible to hit. That was the point, Trxcl realized. The impact could even be faintly heard from where they stood, albeit long after the fact. The debris thrown from the impact was visible much sooner.

Blatvec was nearing panic. Too many men had died! Where was the orbital strike?! What was taking them so long? Were they going to waste this entire day, after all their sacrifice? And a sacrifice it had been. A Major had handed him a casualty report a ri (minute) ago, and it was just as bad as he had feared. Nearly half of the 74th was either dead or unaccounted for, which probably just meant death by Vulza. So intent was he upon the report that he failed to notice the small silhouette fall from the sky towards the enemy defenses.

“Sir! Is that it?”

Looking up excitedly Blatvec glanced up just in time to see a geyser of dirt and debris erupted from the forest canopy in the general area of the Celzi entrenchments.

“It’s about time.” Growled Blatvec, relieved that the 74th had not bled in vain. He looked to the sky, expecting to see a shower of plasma bolts and coil shots falling as rain. He was dissapointed.

“What? Was that all?” he said in disbelief.

“That’s what I asked, sir.”

“Shut it, Gicerpt.”

“I don’t think it was a plasma bolt or coil shot,” piped up Cliip. “In fact, if I had to guess and I removed all sense of logic, I would say it looked like a drop ship, but that’s ridiculous.” Blatvec agreed. Who would have taken a drop ship only to crash it into the ground? They weren’t difficult to fly. You literally told it where to go then pushed a button, and their systems were the opposite of complex, making mechanical failure almost unheard of. His thoughts were interrupted when Doarobihthla, the commander of Doa squad, caught his attention as he rushed to the side of his tank, blue with anger.

“You know those morons who were just transferred from the 109th?” he nearly screamed, spittle flying form his open mouth. “Their commander and that little freak just threw me off of my own tank! They tore off like maniacs and last I saw they were high-tailing it back to the drop ships. We need to stop them before they get there and steal a drop ship and run like the cowards they are! We need t-” Blatvec stopped him by holding one of his paws to the screaming squad commander’s mouth, more to stop the spit bath than the assault on his ears.

“I don’t need to do anything until you start speaking coherently. Now, where did you say they were heading?” Removing his paw, Doa continued as though he’d never stopped. “The drop ships, and if we don’t catch th-” Blatvec replaced the paw so he could be heard as he spoke to Cliip. "Take your squad and see if they were responsible for what we just saw. I can’t imagine why, but for some reason . . . a . . . uh . . .” his words trailed off as another shadow crossed the sky, hurtling towards to the enemy location, followed by the second a single re (5 seconds) later. Both fell with similar clouds of destruction. When the sound of the second impact reached their ears it brought screams with it.

The cries of despair from the enemy focused his mind as no technical lecture ever could. He made the connection. A grin splitting his face, Blatvec turned to Cliip again. “Forget what I just said. Get your squad and two others and follow me to the drop field.”

“What are we going to do when we get there?” Cliip asked. Blatvec sighed. A great mind, Cliip was not.

Bringing his tank to a life with the hum of an anti-grav drive, Blatvec popped out of the hatch once more to answer him, “To do exactly whatever the geniuses who are already there tell us.”

Previous fourteen

Next sixteen

All chapters

The problem with armors is that these are kinetic pulses, which means that while armor would allow an alien to remain in one piece once struck, they would still experience the throw from the kinetic energy part of the pulse. It's the exact same way with bullet proof vests of today. While your standard police jacket will stop a 9mm round, you'll still get a sizable bruise. It just spreads the kinetic energy over a greater area so you don't have as much force concentrated on one area which is what would cause your skin to split. This would mean that even though they could make armors, they would still receive the force from the hit, just spread over a greater area. Even if they shaped their armors so that the force was spread as far as possible, they wouldn't be able to make it so that it would redirect the force completely; organic bodies just aren't shaped correctly to be able to manage that without some truly bizarre and impractical armor shapes. This means that even if they made armor that would keep their guys intact, they'd still be thrown back from the force of the absorbed hit, bearing them to the ground and making it impossible to move while they were being hit. If you can immobilize your opponent so long as your shooting them, and since kinetic pulse weapons have an unlimited magazine, you could literally just shoot your opponent, incapacitate him, and then keep shooting him as you walked up to his trapped body and shove a fusion weapon through his armor. Instead of doing that, they made sure their soldiers could shoot back, even if being shot. A motionless soldier is as good as dead 9 times out of 10. Also, if they had elongated appendages, like the blue-giraffes with the long necks, you could just shoot their head and the whiplash would probably snap their neck. Correct me if this is poorly reasoned.

Quod erat demonstrandum pars: I

By devourerkwi

Dramatis personæ

Lucius Bellator Maximus, a Roman legionary from Legio V Alaudæ, based at the camp Castra Vetera in Xanten, Germania Inferior, serving Emperor Vespasian of the Flavian dynasty

Dieter, a barbarian from the Batavi tribe that was revolting against Rome

Berenice, an Egyptian woman, and her son, Isidorus, from the slums of Alexandria

Yan, a Chinese concubine from the court of and consort to Emperor Ming of Han in the Eastern Han dynasty

Glossarium

Ante mortem: Before death

Centurion: A mid–level officer in the Roman army who commanded 80 men

Pugio: A dagger used by Roman soldiers as a sidearm and auxiliary weapon

Quod erat demonstrandum: Which had to be demonstrated

The arrow rent the left side of his neck, a silver–brown bolt that fell from a cloudless sky as he drove his pugio into the Batavian barbarian’s enormous lower back. The pain in his neck was instant; so was the flood of sticky, metallic–tasting liquid in his throat and mouth. The blood flowed back through the wound and unleashed a torrent of crimson on his dusty golden armor and the black leather of the Batavian, who was still writhing in agony and likely to be alive longer than he would. The last sound he heard before falling unconscious was his own panicked gurgling as he choked on his own blood.

Lucius Bellator Maximus awoke to a damp, metallic floor in a dimly lit space. It wasn’t Elysium—at least, not the Elysium he had been promised—and it hummed, though he couldn’t see why or from where. He looked around and saw two women, a child, and the Batavian he had waylaid, but no walls or ceiling. One woman, clutching the child, had a long neck and mottled, thinning hair; her son was bald and fat with midnight skin, and scared, alert eyes that fervently scanned the dark of their surroundings. The other woman had tan–colored, smooth skin and long, perfectly straight black hair that dropped to the small of her back. It flowed as she turned her head to and fro, her narrow black eyes frantically looking about; her body was wrapped in fine silk nearly the color of her skin that plumed with each sudden movement.

The Batavian was sitting up and furiously investigating the hole in his hardened leather armor, pushing his fingers through the slit Lucius’s pugio made to find no wound. He stood up and stretched, testing his inexplicably healthy body, and slowly scanned around to get a sense of his surroundings. Lucius tentatively raised his right hand to the spot the arrow had sundered him, fingers probing, finding nothing but the rough skin of a scar. It couldn’t be Elysium; he would have no scar and the Batavian would not be with him.

The Batavian finished surveying the area away from Lucius and turned to meet his gaze. Lucius stood up, palms open and facing his former prey, indicating his will but distaste for fighting. The boy whimpered, scared, clutching his mother more tightly, and the woman in silk crouched at the ready. The Batavian leaned forward in an aggressive stance, his steely stare flittering across Lucius’s body, resting momentarily at his open hands. Their concentration was broken as a short whir revealed a portal with shimmering light behind it—and a silhouette.

The silhouette grew larger as it approached, splitting in two as it crossed the portal. The portal closed, cutting off the blinding white light. It took Lucius a few moments to readjust his vision before he noticed that each ... thing ... was as tall as a cavalryman standing atop his horse and had four pale, beige arms, each as thick as a battering ram. They lacked ears and their eyes were set at unusual angles, their necks featuring bulbous goiters. Each brandished a pointy metal stick that looked like it could be a sword but neither wore armor, choosing instead to dress in cloth that came down to the knees, the same light, billowing kind Lucius enjoyed wearing when home with his wife and children.

Lucius instantly noticed the confidence with which these strange things carried themselves. He snuck a look at the Batavian and found that his former enemy had concluded what he had: They were captives, and these enormous, ugly beings were his captors. Surely he and the Batavian were to be tortured, the women raped, the child murdered. He could not allow their innocent blood to be spilled, nor could he allow himself to be forced to fight against the Empire. He had to escape, but he didn’t even have his pugio, much less his sword. He would need the Batavian’s help.

His attention had been locked to his four–armed captors and he hadn’t noticed the mother slide backward until she hit a wall they never knew was there, quickly hiding her son behind her. He also hadn’t noticed the silk–clad woman slip behind their captors and brace herself against the portal. She let out a shriek and, as they turned to confront her, dove with alarming grace to the side. Lucius instinctively acted at their distractedness and charged the monstrosity closer to him, hoping to knock it over before it could react. He impacted it at full force, running faster than he ever had—he had no idea where his newfound speed came from—and slammed into the wall on the other side, covered in blood for the second time in recent memory. The Batavian did the same, but had somehow run headlong into the portal and sundered it in two, flooding the blinding white light back into their enclave.

Lucius tended his impact–bruised shoulder gingerly and surveyed his handiwork. His target had exploded—literally exploded—as he sandwiched it between himself and the wall. Entrails dripped from the walls and ceiling around him and covered him with a stench he was sure would last the rest of his life. He turned to find the silk–clad woman helping the boy and his mother, wiping blood from their faces and picking them up. She was clearly scared, but she was still quite useful, and she obviously understood their predicament. The Batavian, for his part, had launched his new trophy through the portal and it had skidded to a halt somewhere outside.

The Batavian bellowed a hearty laugh and shouted something in his barbarian language, pointing down what turned out to be a long hallway with many portals on each side. There were other captives, possibly other Romans; if he could find two or three more legionaries, they would recognize his uniform as that of a Centurion and he would be able to form a cohesive fighting unit that could defend the women and children. He was sure that the Batavian, large and strong as he was, knew nothing of tactics; at any rate, they spoke different tongues.

Lucius knew what he had to do. He picked up one of the metal sticks the four–armed things had carried but instantly felt a burning, tingling sensation inside his arm that made him drop it. He tried again, more carefully looking for the hilt and handle before grasping, and managed to keep it. He winced as he tested it on his forearm and understood that the part of the stick where the end of a blade would be on a short sword would burn one’s innards if it contacted someone too long. He sheathed it in the scabbard that previously held his sword as the Batavian watched and copied him.

The two nodded at each other and stepped into the hallway. They had nowhere to go but forward.

Rat in Sheep's Clothing

By hume_reddit

What was it with aliens and pancakes?

When Xiù had volunteered to help in the kitchen she’d only thought about helping the Gaoians in some way. She was a stranger – not even of their own species – and yet they’d given her shelter, a bed, food, and even clothing. They were amazingly good people, and she didn’t feel right lazing about and leaching on their hospitality.

After a few weeks – when Myun’s lessons got her to the point where she thought she could express herself coherently – she offered to clean. But there wasn’t much she could clean… that was a chore left to the cubs, who each day after the evening meal would descend on a different room as a pack – nearly fifty strong! – and have it spotless within minutes. It was hilarious and awe–inspiring, and the lone human barely had time to lift a cloth before the job was done.

Her next try was helping the Sisters with the gardens, but winter was coming, and again there was little to do. Her strength helped a little, carrying ceramic pots and bags of earth, but it wasn’t necessary, because the Gaoians had amazing floating sleds that defied gravity which the Sisters used to carry around anything heavy. It was a subtle reminder that the people who had taken her in were a spacefaring race, possessing technologies hundreds, maybe thousands of years ahead of humanity.

Eventually, it was an “incident” that gave her an idea.

The commune often had what she’d call “game nights”, where the Mothers would gather together and play what appeared to be cards. The “cards” were discs, but had the same general idea: one side was blank, while the other had a picture and a value. The game involved assembling a collection of the cards, and cards could be bartered between players as well as randomly drawn. Each player’s “pool” could be viewed, but not their final collection… so it was like someone had crossed assembling a puzzle with poker.

Ayma had invited her to one of these games, and after some brief explanation of the rules she’d joined in. They snacked on little finger foods that looked and tasted like naan chips and passed around numerous jugs of a tart juice they called talamay which reminded Xiù of Fanta. They played and chittered and talked, and while Xiù had a rather limited Gaoian vocabulary and didn’t get most of the jokes, she listened carefully, sipping on her talamay.

She lost the first six games, which really wasn’t a surprise. She won the seventh, which was. Soon, she was winning almost every game, but the Mothers took it in good stride and cheered her wins with amusing little fist pumps. She drank her talamay and toasted them for their good sport, though she’d had to explain the gesture. By the twentieth game she was losing again… though that might have had something to do with the fact that the cards had traitorously turned into blurred splotches of colour.

As it turned out, talamay contained rather a lot of alcohol. And Xiù – who never drank – didn’t realize it until it was too late.

She was so glad her mother wasn’t there to see her.

It didn’t affect Gaoians the way it did humans, so the Mothers looked on with curiosity and concern as Xiù excused herself, climbing to shaky feet. She made it five steps before she fell over, and she had to assure the suddenly worried Mothers that she was fine – she was better than fine, everything was amazing! Xiù was a happy drunk, and her giggles sounded a lot like Gaoian chittering. She wasn’t really sure whether she was speaking English or Gaori or Mandarin, mind you… and would anyone mind if she just slept right here? Xiè xiè!

They ended up calling the commune doctor, a serious but pleasant Mother by the name of Trivai, but there was nothing she could do. She didn’t know what was happening, much less what to do about it, so in the end they just left her where she was (she was too heavy to lift) and kept an eye on her to make sure she didn’t vomit or stop breathing. Not difficult, because apparently she snored when sleeping the sleep of the sloshed.

When she woke up the next morning it was to a quietly keening Myun sitting nearby, worrying about her friend. Xiù managed to assure the little cub she was fine… or she would be. At that particular moment her head wanted water, a dark room, and silence. Please, please, Myun: silence.

Eventually she was coherent enough to explain what had happened to the Mothers, as difficult as it was considering she didn’t know their word for alcohol. They listened with relief and humour… and though they’d been worried at the time the entire incident eventually became a source of comedy. Xiù didn’t mind… seeing the “mighty human” laid low by juice of all things did a lot to humanize (Gaoianize?) her in the eyes of those Mothers and Sisters who were still nervous in her presence. She suffered the teasing with their version of a sheepish shrug – a ducking of the head and rolling eyes.

But it was a good lesson: she’d been blindly eating what they gave her, without really thinking about it. She was living on an alien world, eating alien food, and it was surprising she hadn’t had a reaction to anything. She wasn’t a biologist or even a nutritionist, but she should probably be paying attention to what she put in her mouth. The easiest way to do that was to see her food being made… and maybe help out a little bit while doing so!

An idea!

She’d worked at a Chinese restaurant though most of her highschool years and sometimes during summer vacation from university, so she knew her way around a kitchen. Her mother had also taught her how to cook (so that she could be a “proper wife”). At first she’d resented it, but she soon learned that it was a handy skill. Bringing a tray of xiā jiǎo or lo mai gai always made her immensely popular at a party: her Cantonese friends always appreciated the taste of home, and her caucasian friends didn’t know the difference between Mandarin and Cantonese food but thought it was delicious all the same.

With Ayma’s blessing she learned how to cook Gaoian food. It wasn’t particularly hard. Most of the dishes were fairly simple: breads, and steamed vegetables, and roasted meats. She did not ask where the meats came from: she’d learned that lesson the hard way. She was no stranger to exotic foodstuffs… she was Chinese, after all, with a very traditionalist mother. Chicken feet, beef tripe, even xiě dòufǔ or “blood tofu” – she’d eaten it all, with varying levels of enthusiasm (she’d rather french fries or a turkey sub).

Still, learning that nava paste – an ingredient in a lot of Gaoian foodstuffs – was made from pureeing the innards of a roasted grub the size of her forearm really tested her limits.

Once she’d grasped the basic dishes, she began… experimenting. The Gaoians didn’t have rice, but they did have something like flour. Rather than sugar, they used something like sweet bay leaves. They had salt, of course, and a variety of interesting spices. Xiù played with them, mixing and matching, until she managed to cook up a reasonable facsimile of dòu shā bāo, or sweet paste buns. She wolfed down half the batch out of pure homesickness… then began “testing” her creations on the others at the commune.

Myun liked them, but the little Gaoian thought her human friend could walk on water. Xiù suspected she could lay around all day in her bra and panties, drinking beer and belching like a frat boy during exams, and Myun would think it was the Best Thing Ever… the little girl wasn’t exactly unbiased. So instead she brought her experiments to Yulna, because if she’d learned anything during her time with the community, it was that you could rely on Yulna to tell you exactly what she thought.

The bāo went over well. Noodles were a huge hit; soups and thin sauces not so much (it tended to drip through chin fur). She learned that Gaoians tended to like their food sweet, and didn’t care at all for hot spices. That was unfortunate… Xiù loved spicy food.

But she really hit the jackpot when she made pancakes, and she didn’t know why… it wasn’t like the Gaoians were strangers to sweetbreads. Maybe it was the presentation, or the syrup she made to go along with it, or the idea of topping it with fruit. In any event it was hugely popular, and it became something of a new tradition for a Mother or Sister who had agreed to a mating contract to march into the meal hall and demand some.

Aliens, mating, and pancakes. So weird.

Xiù’s best friend growing up had been a girl named Allison Chan. The two had drifted apart a little bit as they entered university, but Allison would always be one of her favourite people. Xiù had been interested in acting, while Allison was more practical–minded, choosing sociology as her degree.

Allison would have loved Gao. There was enough material on the alien world to author a million papers.

Xiù knew that the Gaoians separated themselves into clans. The males tended to form many clans, while the females all belonged to one. The females were like a nation within nations… the male clans would take and hold territory, compete and fight, while the females drifted as they wished, not caring one whit about lines on a map. They generally kept themselves out of the bickering and politicking of the males, so long as no cubs or females were harmed… but when they did act, it was as a whole, and no clan on Gao could resist them.

When she learned that the Gaoian genders tended to keep to themselves, Xiù had wondered if the females were kept like pets in gilded cages. Not so: the females could go anywhere they wanted, learn anything they wanted, seek any job they wanted. In a curious contrast to Earth’s own outdated stereotypes, it was males who had to fight the assumption that they were flighty and emotional, though they were also seen as bold and adventurous, almost reckless. Females were seen as steadfast, practical, and resolute.

Marriage didn’t exist on Gao, but they did have their own form of dating. Females were entirely in charge of the reproductive process, and the males essentially spent their lives trying to attract the interest of a female (so overall it wasn’t that different from Earth, Xiù thought with amusement). The means to attract a female was as widely varied as it was for humans… some Gaoian females liked physically strong males, others liked those who were intelligent. Some preferred the wealthy or politically powerful, while others simply favoured those males who were kind.

If a male caught a female’s attention, he could offer a mating contract. If she agreed, they would meet, “do the deed”... and then most likely never see each other again. Cubs were raised by the community – the mating contract was a record and safety against inbreeding, but a Gaoian almost never knew their true parents beyond what clan they were in. All males tithed a portion of their earnings to the Clan of Females to support the raising of the cubs. A male could tithe as much as he wanted to, and some were quite generous in an attempt to gain favour with the females (although a male who tithed so much he hurt himself was considered an idiot and actually lowered his chances).

This made Xiù feel guilty, because she knew her upkeep must be fairly expensive. She ate a lot compared to the other females, and though the nutrient spheres she used as supplements were fairly cheap, she also needed to take mineral supplements… particularly calcium. The Gaoians were very advanced, but surely her special needs weren’t free. Were there two or three males out there forced to sponsor a female they had absolutely no chance of scoring with? She hoped not; she didn’t even like it when a guy would tip too much at her waitressing job in the hopes of getting her phone number.

Then there was the search for Earth, which apparently involved up to three Gaoian cruisers at this point. Xiù tried to picture any government on her homeworld devoting three ships to searching for the homeland of one stranger. Ayma assured her that it wasn’t a hardship – in fact, the males got a thrill out of that sort of thing. Still, Xiù’s gratitude couldn’t be measured.

She hoped she’d have an opportunity to return the favour someday.

She wasn’t sure how long she’d spent on her adoptive world. It had been about three–quarters of a Gaoian year, but she didn’t know how long that was in Earth years. She wasn’t even sure how long a local day was… she didn’t have a watch, and her iPhone had run out of battery within three days of her kidnapping and had been left behind at Trig’s facility. But she had to have been on Gao for nearly an Earth year. The Gaoians were wonderful people, but somewhere on Earth her parents and brother must think she was dead, and it made her sick to think of how they must feel.

There was nothing she could do to help, though… nothing she could say without sounding demanding or ungrateful. So she helped with the small chores she was capable of, and waited.

It was a fairly early morning and the commune was enjoying its breakfast. It wasn’t a “pancake” day, though one Sister, Eama, was heavily pregnant and due almost any day. Most of the commune was enjoying their typical breakfast of cereal or the Gaoian equivalent of oatmeal. The one sign of Xiù’s influence was the “whipped cream” that some of the Mothers and Sisters were piling on top of of their nuts and berries… the human had figured out how to sweeten and whip the liquid from a foodstuff that was remarkably like soy. It was a big hit, both in the commune and beyond.

Xiù sat at the table along with the other Sisters, a bowl of cereal in front of her, most of it already gone. It was hard not to compare the meal hall of the commune with the Great Hall from the Harry Potter movies. Closest to the main doors were the long tables where the cubs would sit, chattering and chittering and generally being noisy like children should be. In the middle were the tables where the thirty or so Sisters – including the lone human – would sit, more dignified than the cubs but sometimes not by much. At the front of the room was the single long table, arranged perpendicular to the others, where the twenty Mothers who remained at the commune sat and watched the rest.

Comparing the commune to Hogwarts often cheered Xiù up. Even the personalities matched in some cases. Mother Garmin, the “headmaster”, was cheerful and happy and always knew what was going on, though she sometimes pretended otherwise. Serious, watchful Ayma was definitely McGonagall. Yulna could be Snape… not because she was malicious or petty, but because she had no time or interest in anyone else’s crap and wasn’t shy about saying it.

Xiù rolled one of her nutrition spheres around in the remains of the nuts in the bottom of her bowl. The spheres didn’t taste bad, but they didn’t taste good either, and the texture was awful… the crunch of the nuts helped a lot. The Sisters at the table paid no mind; her appetite had long since ceased to be worthy of comment, much to her relief. She knew she needed the nutrients – it was a struggle just to keep her weight up – but she still felt like a gluttonous pig every time she had to eat one of the spheres, a single one of which was an entire meal to a Gaoian.

She had finished the sphere and was swallowing her calcium supplement when the room quieted slightly. She looked up to see a lone male Gaoian marching through the meal hall, catching the interest of some of the cubs and Sisters. The male – obviously not a member of the commune – marched up to Garmin and spoke quietly, ducking his head in respect. The nearby Mothers could hear what was being said, and as their eyes flickered over to Xiù, she knew what – or who – was being discussed.

Garmin caught her gaze and gestured, calling her over. Xiù left her empty bowl (one of the cubs would grab it later, cleaning the tables was part of their chores...) and walked up to the head table.

“Shoo,” Garmin greeted. None of the Gaoians could pronounce her given name, but honestly a lot of her friends in Canada had struggled, too. The Head Mother nodded toward the male. “This is Officer Regaari, who is part of the security and executive staff for Mother–Supreme Giymuy, and her liaison to the Whitecrest clan.”

Regaari was taller than Xiù but he still ducked his head respectfully. “Sister Shoo. I’ve been sent by the Mother–Supreme to ask you to come to the capital city. I don’t know the details, but I believe she needs you for a meeting.” He had evidently noticed the slow, careful way Garmin spoke to her and emulated it. Xiù appreciated the gesture… she was still nowhere near fluent in Gaori, the principal language of the world she was on, and when someone spoke too fast she would get lost.

“Okay. Um… what reason?”

She knew her question was clumsy, but to his credit Regaari knew what she was asking. “I’m afraid I don’t know the subject, but I believe it has to do with the negotiations with the Dominion.”

“Okay. When leave? Pardon, when do we leave?”

“I have a shuttle here now, and I’ll bring you back in time for the evening meal.”

Garmin held up a paw. “Sister Shoo will need someone to come along with her.”

Ayma stood up. “I can help. Yulna can teach my class this morning.”

“Oh joy,” the Mother in question responded, but she bobbed her head in a Gaoian nod. Xiù hid a grin.

Realizing something, she turned and raised an arm to wave toward the back of the room where Myun sat eating breakfast with her brothers and sisters – cubs of different mothers but who were near the same age. She’d been watching Xiù the moment she’d been called to the front table, and she darted to her feet and practically ran over.

“Myun, I must go to meeting in capital,” Xiù explained. “So probably no taiji today, okay? Or,” the furry little girl perked up from the crestfallen look that had been crossing her features, “maybe if I not back, you lead practice. Okay?”

“Me?” she squeaked.

“Sure! Go through to zhuǎn shēn piě shēn chuí, twice maybe, but don’t make others stay if not want, okay?”

“Yes! I will!” Myun made the little fist–pumping gesture that was an eager cheer with both paws, then scurried back to her table to share the news. The corners of Xiù’s mouth rose in a close–lipped grin: Gaoian cubs were so ridiculously cute. Myun was a hard worker, too – more dedicated to her martial arts than Xiù had ever been – and she had no worries that the cub could handle the practice group, which had ballooned to nearly a dozen curious and eager cubs of both genders.

With that, Ayma gestured to Regaari and he lead the pair of them out of the meal hall. Xiù noticed a couple of the Mothers and a number of the Sisters following the tall male with their eyes as they left. Gaoian males spent so much time and energy trying to gain the notice of females that those who played aloof or hard–to–get actually got a lot of attention. Xiù just assumed he was being professional.

The “landing pad” wasn’t far from the meal hall, and a small shuttle sat waiting for them, looking for all the world like a futuristic, gull–doored minivan. The two females sat themselves in the back while Regaari took the pilot’s seat, and soon the vehicle was in the air, humming quietly with whatever strange technologies let it float through the air.

Xiù watched the landscape of Gao zip past below them. After being brought to the commune, she’d only left once – again, to meet with the Mother–Supreme in the capital city – and the alien world was still new and amazing to her. They passed over what was likely farmland, and then what seemed to be suburbs, and what looked to be a different commune of females, judging from the layout; they were too high for Xiù to make out details, and she resolved to ask Ayma when they returned.

Ayma was quiet, letting their alien visitor marvel at the sights to be seen out the shuttle’s windows. After what Xiù guessed to be close to an hour, the capital city of Gao rose into view. The city – named Lavmuy, apparently, but everyone just called it “the City” – was a huge arrangement of towering spires that wouldn’t have looked out of place in a Star Wars movie, glittering with lightweight but strong crystal and futuristic metals. Near the center was the spaceport, and ships could be seen rising or falling slowly toward it, ranging from darting Gaoian personal craft barely larger than their shuttle to enormous, lumbering beasts ten times the size of the American aircraft carrier which had once visited Victoria.

The Clan Hall, or center of government for the planet, was located not far from the spaceport. The building was relatively squat compared to those around it, in part due to its age. A few landing pads were arranged like leaves here and there along its length, and their shuttle descended towards one near the very top. A few Gaoians waited patiently along the walkway leading into the building. Judging from the blue–green colours one of them wore – the colour of the Gao sky – Mother–Supreme Giymuy was present, which meant the others were her attendants.

Xiù smoothed out her own red overalls nervously. All Gaoians wore overalls as their daily clothing, though personal tastes would add patterns, or extra pockets, or other customizations. Xiù had been provided a number of her own, tailored for her longer legs, and because she didn’t have fur the Mothers had put their heads together and effectively invented the shirt. A number had been made and given to her, in varying colours. They were loose and comfortable, almost like robes. She liked them, though she had to be careful about matching her colours in order to not feel like she was cosplaying the Mario Brothers.

The shuttle bumped slightly as Regaari set it down and the safeties on the doors released. Ayma and Xiù hopped out, standing together as Giymuy and her assistants approached them. Regaari took up a spot next to Ayma, and both ducked their heads toward the Mother–Supreme, while Xiù bowed to the elder Gaoian.

“Mother Ayma, Sister Shoo, it is good to see you,” Giymuy said. She turned to Regaari. “You were very prompt, Officer Regaari. Thank you.”

“Of course, Mother–Supreme. If I may be excused?”

“Of course. I will send a message when I need you again.”

The male ducked his head again, turning to repeat the gesture to Ayma and Xiù. Then he turned, entering the building via the walkway. The eyes of the majority of Giymuy’s assistants followed him.

The Mother–Supreme turned to Xiù, noting the way the human observed the other females. Her muzzle was set in the way that indicated amusement. “You are wondering if he is a particularly handsome Gaoian male. The answer is very much yes.”

Xiù almost burst into laughter, especially as the younger females – including Ayma – looked embarrassed. “That explains much,” she replied.

“Indeed. Too bad I am too old,” Giymuy remarked, drawing a shocked widening of the eyes from her retinue. “Come, walk with me.”

Xiù obediently fell in beside the elder as she lead the way into the building. Inside the Clan Hall was broad, rose–coloured hallways with dark, wooden rounded ceilings, dotted here and there with flowers and grasses set in long planters along the walls. Xiù would almost think she was inside a hobbit hole, except for the occasional “painting” mounted on the walls, which were actually digital three–dimensional representations of various places around Gao, including from high in the sky and from space. The Gaoians seemed to like a more “natural” decor… their buildings actually seemed less futuristic than Trig’s prison, but Xiù knew the miracles were there, hidden underneath.

Ayma and the assistants – Xiù still didn’t know what the half–dozen females actually did – had fallen in behind them as Giymuy lead them through the halls. The lone human glanced sideways at Giymuy. “You need me for meeting?” she asked.

“Yes,” the elder replied. “Though not with me. A representative from the Interspecies Dominion is here, and he has asked to speak with you.”

“The Dominion?” They were the interstellar group that Gao was thinking of joining, weren’t they? The organization that knew where Earth was? Xiù felt hope flare inside her.

They had moved into a very wide, tall hallway that looked to stretch the entire length of the building. More Gaoians, most male, were walking past, and they all ducked their heads in respect to the Mother–Supreme. Wide doors made of wood or some similar alien material, nearly six metres tall, were set here and there along the hallway. Giymuy came to a stop in front of one pair of doors, turning to Xiù.

“Yes. His name is Furfeg, and he is Guvnuragnaguvendrugun. He has asked to speak to you alone. They are a large species, but they are plant–eaters, and friendly… you need not be afraid of him.” The elder Gaoian laid a paw on Xiù’s arm. “I do not know what he wants to speak to you about, but I have hopes that he intends to help you. Do not agree to anything that makes you uncomfortable. If you are unsure, call for me.”

“We’ll wait here,” Ayma promised.

Xiù wanted to hug the Mother–Supreme, but resisted. “I will. Thank you.” At Giymuy’s nod, she turned to the door and touched the sensor bar that stretched from the level of her waist to a scant metre from the top of the door. The door swung inward obediently without even the creak of hinges, and sensing her movement, closed immediately after she stepped through.

The room was huge and open, and the light from Gao’s sun shone through the crystal windows that lined the upper part of the ceiling. A circle in the floor showed where a table could rise up out of the floor, surrounded by smaller circles that showed the locations of chairs that could do the same, adjusting their heights and shapes based on the species trying to use them. Xiù had marvelled at them the last time she was in the capital… after she’d been “confirmed” as part of the Clan of Females, but politely asked to come meet the other Clan leaders simply to smooth over any tension because of it.

On the opposite side of the room was… Furfeg. Giymuy hadn’t been kidding when she’d described him as large. Xiù had thought the Locayl were big (Ayma had explained that Gaoians were relatively tiny compared to most sapient species, and by extension so were humans) but this species topped them by nearly a metre. He was a four–legged mountain of brown fur, straddling a chair which had smoothed itself out into a bench that held his mass without apparent strain. A pair of arms with three–fingered hands rested comfortably across his torso, as wide across as a queen–sized bed. He reminded Xiù of Snuffleupagus for some reason… though he lacked the elephant–like trunk, he had long, floppy ears and shaggy fur. His eyes were huge and blue, located closer to the sides of his head than a human’s or Gaoian’s, and Xiù remembered what Giymuy had said about his species being herbivores.

He stood as she entered, but didn’t approach her as she stared, wide–eyed. She noticed that he lacked fur along a strip on each of his sides, and the skin beneath glowed colours, turning a light blue as he looked at her.

The large creature bobbed his head toward her. “Greetings, Miss Chang,” he said in a deep, masculine voice, startling her. “I am Furfeg. Pleased to meet you.”

She stared at it – him – for long seconds, her jaw hanging open. “You speak English!” she finally blurted.

He looked back at her, and the softly glowing lines along his sides pulsed. “No, you hear English,” he said, and she heard the amusement in his voice. “That is the name of the principal language on your world, yes? The… `language of business’, I believe you term it?”

“Y–yes… but how?”

He tapped the side of his overlarge head, and she realized she could see small tracings there under his fur… cybernetics of some sort. “High–end language translation implant… it doesn’t require pairing with an implant in the sapient you’d like to converse with. Very handy in my line of work.”

“What work is that?”

“Fundamentally? I’m a diplomat. Assigned here as part of the Interspecies Dominion’s efforts to entice Gao into joining… not just provisionally, but as a full standing member. Efforts that were very much on the cusp of success. Until, as it happens, this world gained a new member, one who is very much not Gaoian.” At her confused look, his eyes flickered toward the closed doors. “I take it the Mother–Supreme did not explain my reasons for wishing to meet you?”

Xiù laced her fingers together to keep them from fidgeting. “N–no, she just said it was important.”

“Ah.” That great shaggy head bobbed back and forth, and she assumed it was his equivalent of a nod. “Then, Miss Chang – `miss’ is the appropriate honorific, is it not? – I’ll explain it plainly: the government of Gao and its single colony have agreed to join the Dominion as a full, voting member.” He waved one arm, including the entire world in the gesture. “This agreement has been a long time in coming, and the negotiations have been some of the most challenging of my career. The Gaoians are very clever, and aren’t to be tricked. That cunning is why we seek them, and in return they’ll gain a number of trade advantages as well as mutual defense agreements.”

“That sounds good,” she said. “But… where do I come in?”

“Ah… the Gaoians have added one small, last–minute proviso to the agreement. Namely, that as part of the deal the Dominion is either to supply Gao with the location of your homeworld and the right to deliver you there, or we are to transport you there ourselves. They’ve made it very clear that they aren’t willing to negotiate on that point.”

Her heart flew. “Can you? Bring me home?”

He hesitated. “No.”

Her hopes crashed back into the ground. “W–what? But you just said the Gaoians won’t negotiate on that!”

“Yes. And likewise, I cannot negotiate, either. Bringing you home is not within my power. So we are at an impasse… one only you can resolve.”

Her eyes began to burn. “But why? Why can’t you take me home? You know where it is… the Corti know where it is! If they can steal me on a lark then why can’t you bring me back?”

“There has been an… incident. Are you familiar with the species we call Hunters?”

Xiù hesitated, fighting back tears. “Y–yes… there’s been some mention of them. They sound like… interstellar boogeymen? They attack without warning and kidnap people?”

“They harvest people,” he corrected grimly. “Though if the translator is processing `boogeymen’ correctly then yes, that’s a good descriptor. They consume other sapient beings. We are all herd animals to them, and though we know little about them, we know that their entire society – from their social status to perhaps even their procreation – is dependent on their hunts. They strike without warning, and the more audacious the target the more they seem to like it.”

Xiù shuddered, thinking of a James Cameron movie. Then she realized: “They attacked Earth?”

His head bobbed again. “Yes. Near the same area where you were taken. In fact, we believe the Hunters may have simply followed the energy traces of the ship that took you, but instead found the more tempting target of a well–populated, undefended world.”

“What happened?”

“It was a slaughter.” As her face paled, he held up a limb. “Of the Hunters.”

“What?” she said disbelievingly.

“Oh, yes, I’ve seen the footage myself. In fact, it seems to have somehow leaked out onto the interplanetary data–network,” he grumbled, and the strips along his sides tinted a pale red which then turned a soft blue. “A cluster of Hunters – the most feared species current extant in the galaxy – attacked a human sporting event… hockey, I believe you call it. They assaulted with their heavy pulse guns, your people replied with wooden sticks. When it was all done there was not a single human fatality and the Hunters were smeared everywhere. Then the audience complained that the ice surface was ruined and they couldn’t continue the game.”

She could only stare. “Well… my people take hockey pretty seriously.”

“I’ll keep that in mind.” His flanks rippled blue, and the translator filled his tone with humour. “But now I hope you see the problem: the humans now have irrefutable proof not just of alien life, but of the existence of a practical means of travelling the stars. And they know that some of the life among those stars is malicious. The eyes of your world are aimed upward now, and your people are likely fingering their weapons as they watch.”

“Then.... then you need me!” She held her hands toward him. “I can talk to them for you! I can explain to them that the Hunters aren’t part of your society, that you don’t mean any harm! Let me help!”

Her hopes were dashed again as his flanks rippled black and grey, and he shook his head. “I’m afraid it’s too late for that.” The translator had made his voice solemn.

“What? What does that mean?” Her stomach had dropped to her feet and was currently congealing into lead in the vicinity of her toes. “What have you done?” she rasped.

He held up a limb. “No one has been harmed, nor will they be,” he explained. “But your world has been placed under quarantine. An interdiction field has been installed… a force field, surrounding your star system, preventing anything from entering or exiting.”

“What! Why?”

The translator made the sound of a sigh. “Because the galaxy is not ready for you.”

“Not ready for us? Or do you mean we’re not ready for it?” she hissed between her teeth, sounding like Myun when she was angry.

“Either. Both. Look at your hands.” Xiù blinked at the non–sequitor, but glanced down – her hands had clenched into fists in her shock and anger. “The ignorant would look at us and assume that I am physically superior. Yet, if I tried to strike you, I’d only end up hurting myself. In comparison you could shatter my bones with little effort, and it would take weapons normally used against armored vehicles to harm you. Your people move faster, hit harder, and can take more damage than any species the galaxy has seen, including the `boogeymen’ known as the Hunters. In some ways you even think faster, your neural pathways optimized for defense… and attack.

“Then there’s those organisms living inside you. If not for the Corti suppressor in your neck, Gao might very well be a plague–world already.” He gestured helplessly. “You – your people – are deadly in a way we’ve never seen before, and you come from a world where that deadliness was needed.”

The big alien leaned back in his seat, releasing another sigh. “When this subject came up at the Galactic Council, I made a point of researching your species. I have seen much of your culture, your artistic and technological output, and it is amazing. You may be technologically inferior, but the competitiveness your world has forced into you has let you reach amazing highs… and terrifying lows. It is those lows that ignite fear across the galaxy.”

“But we haven’t done anything yet! You can’t accuse us of being evil while you have the Corti snatching people away and experimenting on them, others killing for a paycheque, and Hunters eating people! Why are we worse than them?”

“You’re not. But you could be.” His voice was sorrowful. “I’m very sorry. Had the Corti left well enough alone, had the Hunters not been so arrogant… the situation might have been very different by the time your people had developed faster–than–light travel naturally. But that isn’t the situation we have.”

She looked at him, too shocked to even form words. It wasn’t until she realized that her flat stare was making him afraid that she looked down. “So we’re tried, convicted, and imprisoned forever… for having potential!” She was suddenly furious. “Gao was right to think twice about joining you! Nǐmen quándōu shì dǎnxiǎoguǐ!”

She didn’t know if his translator understood the Mandarin, but he flinched from her tone alone. She ignored him, the anger rushing out of her as quickly as it had came; she moved over to sit on a chair that rose out of the floor and sized itself for a Gaoian, its best guess at what she would need. She rested her elbows on her knees and hid her face in her hands.

Furfeg’s mouth opened, but whatever he was going to say was interrupted by the door bursting open and Ayma storming in, the Mother–Supreme following at a more measured pace behind her. “Xiù! You were shouting! What happened?” The Gaoian Mother glared at the big alien.

Xiù startled, surprised to hear perfect English coming from Ayma… apparently Furfeg’s translator worked for everyone in the vicinity. I could have been speaking properly to the people who’d taken me in… but they wouldn’t even let me have that!

“Furfeg, when you had me invite Xiù here, you lead me to believe that it would be to tell her something positive,” Giymuy said. She never raised her voice, but her disapproval was like a physical force, and even an alien three times her size quailed in the face of it.

“Unfortunately not. But she deserved to hear it from me.”

“What? What did you tell her?” Ayma growled.

“They’ve… walled off Earth. My homeworld,” Xiù answered for him.

Ayma seemed surprised to hear Xiù sound perfectly intelligible, but wasn’t to be distracted. “What? How?”

“An experimental device, essentially a system–encompassing energy barrier,” Furfeg clarified. “It was installed several cycles ago.”

Even Giymuy seemed taken aback. “That is far more than a quarantine, Furfeg! Such measures are ridiculous… when did the Council decide on this?”

He shook his head. “There was no debate. The action was taken unilaterally by the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun Confederacy. The other members… simply did not oppose.”

“Abomination,” Giymuy spit. The Mother–Supreme was Xiù’s own mother dialed up to eleven, she decided. “Is this what you would have Gao participate in, Furfeg? Would you have us nod our heads as you create more prison worlds? I told you the treaty would depend on helping Xiù!”

“Actually, I believe your exact words were that it would ‘depend on Xiù’, Mother–Supreme. I reviewed the translator several times. I interpreted that to mean that the treaty was subject to her approval, regardless of anything else.”

Xiù growled. “You’re not a diplomat, you’re a lawyer.”

“Perhaps. The two only differ in scale.”

“You really expect me to advise them to agree to join you? After what you’ve done?”

“Yes,” he stated, and his colours turned black, implacable. He took a step toward her, his need to convince her overcoming his natural fear of her as an unstoppable predator. “Neither one of us can do anything to help your homeworld for the moment. But you can help Gao. The predatory species of the galaxy see them as prey because they are unaligned. Once they join, attacking the Gaoians will be tantamount to attacking the Dominion, and even the Corti will hesitate.”

“Pardon me if I don’t see a whole lot of potential bravery in the Dominion!”

He bobbed his head, accepting the rebuke. “Perhaps. But anything is more than nothing, which is more than they have now.”

“You’re trying to blackmail her,” Ayma snapped. “Let’s go, the air in here is bad–”

“Mother Ayma,” Giymuy said. Her voice was calm, without a hint of censure, but Ayma’s muzzle snapped shut. The elder Gaoian turned to Xiù. “Xiù, what do you think we should do?”

She stared back, wide–eyed. “M–me? What does it matter what I think? You’re the Mother–Supreme!”

“Yes,” Giymuy replied calmly, “and you’re one of my Sisters. We stand together, Xiù, like the Clan of Females always has.”

Xiù glanced, near panic, at the three aliens who were all staring at her expectantly. Had they really just told her to decide the fate of an entire planet?

“The choice is in your hands, Miss Chang,” Furfeg said. Damn him!

She wanted to tell him “cào nǐ mā”... not that he’d understand it. He might not even have a mother. Ayma was right… he was emotionally blackmailing her. She didn’t owe him a damned thing.

But she did owe the Gaoians. The only reason to say no would be to spite him. Spite him… and prove him right.

“You should join them,” she said, nearly a whisper.

Ayma squeezed her shoulder and made a quiet keening noise. “Xiù…”

Xiù looked up toward Giymuy. “You’re still growing. Because you’re not aligned with anyone, you’re alone, and the Corti feel brave enough to snatch your ships travelling between your own worlds because of it.” She cast a hostile look over at Furfeg. “I don’t know how much they can help. I don’t think you can count on them at all! But if joining them makes the Corti, or the Locayl, or anyone think twice about hurting Myun or any other cub… it’s what you should do.”

“This is not right for you,” Giymuy said.

“No,” she replied. “But it’s right for Gao.”

Giymuy looked back at her, and she saw the grim resignation there. The Mother–Supreme nodded. “Very well,” she said. She turned to the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun. “The Clan of Females of Gao will no longer oppose the acceptance of the treaty with the Interspecies Dominion, Furfeg. We’ll skip the normal diplomatic flowery prose and acknowledge that for all intents and purposes the deal is done.”

Furfeg nodded, his flanks glowing a soft purple, but Giymuy wasn’t finished. “Be aware, however: we will be using our newfound clout within the Dominion to address this miscarriage of justice. Be certain of that.”

The glow of his flanks did not fade one bit. “Mother–Supreme, I hope for it.” His head turned to Xiù, who sat on the nearby bench, her arms wrapped around her. “Thank you, Miss Chang. It is actions like what you have demonstrated here that will convince my brethren of the foolishness of their actions.” He turned to gather up his data tablet.

“Mister Furfeg?” He looked back, meeting Xiù’s gaze. Her eyes were red, but she didn’t cry… that would happen later, once she was alone. “Is it possible to send a signal to Earth?”

He hesitated, his colours turning a dark blue spotted with white. “The quarantine extends to communications.”

She stared back at him. “My family… they have no idea what happened to me. They don’t even have the privilege of thinking I’m dead.”

He looked at her for a long moment, and she had no idea what the rainbow of colours running across his sides could mean. “I will make no promises,” he finally said. “But… I’ll see what I can do.” She nodded, knowing it was the best she could get.

The big alien left, heading to the spaceport and the ship that would take him to his superiors, the good news stored on his tablet. With him gone Xiù was back to needing to speak Gaori… as she expected she’d have to for a very long time. But for the moment she didn’t want to speak at all. Ayma seemed to sense her need, her paw gently stroking her hair, petting her the way she would a distraught cub.

The Mother–Supreme was staring into space, looking thoughtful. “There are layers to this, I’m certain,” she said after a moment. She shook her head. “For the moment you should both go home and rest. Find peace among the cubs. I will summon Officer Regaari to take you home.”

She turned to leave, but hesitated at the door, turning back to look at Xiù. “I wish you had fur, Shoo. Because you’d make an excellent Mother.” Then she was gone, her attendants scurrying along behind her.

Xiù followed Ayma to the landing pad as if sleepwalking, and during the shuttle ride back to the commune she didn’t bother asking about the patterns in the landscape. When they arrived it was just before the midday meal, and the cubs were getting out their morning lessons. Myun had obviously seen the shuttle approaching, so she’d dashed straight from her lessons to the landing pad, waiting at the edge as they touched down. She began to dart forward as Xiù stepped out, but hesitated at the look on human’s face.

“Myun?” The furry little alien girl blinked at her. “I think I could use a hug.”

“What you’re asking for is difficult.”

“Oh, really? Don’t tell me you’re so easily defeated by planetbound primitives.”

“There’s no reason to be insulting. Unlike most of my brethren, I am capable of respect, and these `primitives’ you mention are worthy of it… their networks are well–built and defended. Most likely due to their adversarial nature… it’s like they launch network attacks against each other for the fun of it.”

“I’m not asking you to cause damage or exfiltrate any data. I just need you to deliver a message.”

“And you want that message to be targeted rather than widecast… which is the problem. I need to isolate the appropriate node, and that requires persistent intrusion and reconnaissance.”

“So you can’t do it?”

“What did I just say about insulting me? I swear it’s like talking to a wall, except the wall sounds more intelligent.”

“There’s the Corti I came to see.”

Wei Chang, “YesWei” online, sat staring at his computer screen. Beside him a warm summer breeze blew in through his open window, carrying with it the noise and smells of the nighttime Vancouver suburbs.

It was late… he was supposed to be in bed. Summer vacation was almost over, and school would be starting soon. Grade twelve: his last year of high school. His mother made noises about getting to bed at the proper time, but the fire was lacking in it. A year before she would have marched into his room and ripped the power bar from the wall – whether he was in a match or not – and refused to return it until the next morning, cursing at him in Mandarin the whole time. Now all she would do is poke her head in through his door, remind him it was time for bed in a flat voice, and then go sit in the living room, where she would watch the news without really seeing it.

Xiù had been missing for nine months. She’d gone to a late class and never returned, and none of her friends had heard a word from her. They’d filed the missing person report almost immediately, but it was difficult to get the police to take it seriously: Yes, we’re sure she left the class. No, she doesn’t have a boyfriend. Yes, we’ve called all her friends. Wei had scoured the university campus for her while his frantic father drove around in their car and his mother fretted by the telephone at home.

No one in the family slept that night, and the next day the police took the matter more seriously. He remembered the cops talking quietly where they thought he couldn’t hear... speculating on what could have happened to an attractive young woman walking home at night, and his stomach tied itself into knots at the possibilities offered.

By the second day, Xiù’s face was on the news, and the Chang family could do nothing but wait… but his father was always out, always searching. Days turned to weeks turned to months, and hope died bit by bit… but his father was always out, always searching.

Dad eventually had to return to work, because like it or not the bills had to get paid, and he couldn’t neglect what remained of his family. Every night, however, he would drive around Vancouver for an hour, searching against hope. Wei’s mother never yelled anymore… not even when he’d deliberately do things to piss her off, wanting her to snap and rage at him. She never did; deep inside her the idea that Xiù had run away to escape her nagging and control was taking root and festering.

Wei had no comforting words to offer. He knew his sister wasn’t the type to run away, but he really, really wished she had, because the other explanations were so much worse.

Then came the day the Rogers Arena was attacked by aliens, and Xiù Chang was completely forgotten, no matter how much his mother shrieked at the RCMP officers. And as much as Wei wanted to get angry, he couldn’t blame them. The Earth being attacked by aliens was big thing.

If it could be called an attack, and not a joke. Wei didn’t know what to make of it – aliens were supposed to be strong and tough and take an army lead by Will Smith or Sigourney Weaver to take down… not get their heads caved in by a bunch of guys with hockey sticks lead by Henrik Sedin. If there hadn’t been so many witnesses who’d personally seen – and often gotten hit by – the energy weapons, it could have been passed off as a lame publicity stunt.

He was as interested as anyone else, but not just because he fought digital aliens three hours a day or because – hey – energy guns are awesome, but because he was sure those aliens were connected somehow to Xiù’s disappearance. He felt it in his gut.

The first thing he’d done after seeing the news was hop on the internet. It was rough going… any website that even mentioned aliens was getting bombed by the curious and the panicked. But eventually he managed to find what he was looking for… a site that listed UFO sightings across the world. Fringe sites. Not the kind of sites the RCMP would even think of when investigating missing persons.

From those sites, he learned that there had been UFO sightings in Vancouver the night Xiù had gone missing. Multiple sightings.

Wei realized that up until that moment, even he had given up hope. An alien attack had given him hope. Now he had to figure out what to do with it.

Had the aliens kidnapped some humans to try and figure out how tough they were before attacking? (If so they needed to fire their scientist–guy, because he really dropped the ball...) The aliens had landed in some kind of pods, which didn’t seem suited for interstellar use, no matter how fast they might travel. So had they been launched from some kind of mothership? If so, was Xiù trapped on that ship right now?

Wei was terrified that his sister was locked in a cage, being experimented on… or worse. The one thing that helped keep some of the nightmares at bay was the pathetic performance of the aliens during the attack. Xiù was a shrimp but she was in good shape and took her gung–fu pretty seriously… she could hit pretty hard, not that he’d ever admit that to her face.

But if she was on an alien ship, what could he do? NATO had taken everything associated with the aliens and everyone knew it… the media were making as much of a nuisance of themselves that they could, and one Canadian teenager couldn’t add much. Wei haunted online forums as much as he could, trying to contact people who claimed to have been abducted before… people who suddenly had a lot more credibility. But even they – assuming he was talking to the real deal and not more kooks – had little they could offer him.

Now the new focus of the world was the “darkening”... astronomers everywhere had noticed that every object in the sky beyond Uranus – every object – had dimmed, just a little bit. Every object, all at once. Wars and rivalries across the entire planet had come to a screeching halt as humanity realized that, somewhere up above them, alien assholes were doing something… and humans probably weren’t going to like whatever it was.

Wei followed the discussions on the forums with interest. Even the people who seemed to be the Real Deal when it came to knowing about aliens had no idea what was going on.

His screen was sitting on one of those forums when it happened: a window popped open on his computer. He growled, thinking an ad had somehow dodged his popup–blocker… fringe websites had to use some pretty shady ad networks. He’d almost closed it before the content of the grey box sunk in, and his jaw dropped as he read the words:

Your sister is safe. She was taken, but not by the creatures that attacked your city. She was taken, but she escaped, and is among friends.

Xiù is safe.

Below was a picture of his sister, wearing some kind of weird red clothing, like overalls crossed with robes. The picture was from an upward angle, and her head was turned to the side, and she was speaking and gesturing angrily. But she was unhurt and gloriously alive.

Wei stared at the screen for long seconds. Then he jumped to his feet, not giving a damn that his legs hit the desk and sent his mouse flying. “Mom! Mom! Kuài lái!”

I guess they didn’t need to evolve the ability to keep learning; by the time they’re adults, they’ve learned all they’ll need to survive.

I don’t know if I’d go that far. I was aiming more toward subconscious action... “muscle memory”.

I don’t think any creature that is unable learn would survive long in any circumstance. But humans are capable of learning surprisingly complex behaviours and executing them on automatic.

Most likely any intelligent species that didn’t need that ability to evolve would be shocked and possibly frightened by it. Consider: it would raise into question just how “in control” a human is at any given moment. We struggle with it ourselves... the simple act of safely waking a soldier who’s seen too much combat is a classic example.

My thoughts are that in the Jenkinsverse, humans were of the few/only species to evolve on a world where taking even just a few milliseconds to think about a threat could get you killed. Get back up the tree, then figure out whether or not it was a tiger or just your buddy being a jerk.

Deliverance

by Hambone3110

Chapter 5 of The Kevin Jenkins Experience

Part of the Jenkinsverse

++Four years previously.++

Everybody loved a home side win, except for the tourists. Amir didn’t feel like a tourist, but Pakistani people supported the Pakistani cricket team, even if - like him - they had been born in Birmingham, had never left England, spoke English more fluently than their supposed “native” language, with an accent that was as British as tea and wet weather.

“Amir!”

His best friend Muhammad and the rest of his friends had started heading in a different direction while Amir was zoned out. “You coming?” he asked.

Amir knew what the answer would be, but he had to ask anyway. It was how things worked. “Where?”

“For a drink! Come on bruv, we may as well have SOME fun tonight.”

Amir shook his head. “You know that’s haram.” he said. It was their one constant conflict that Muhammad was only a Muslim when it was convenient. The rest of the time, he was just another nineteen-year-old, high on life and not interested in the consequences.

“We’re all sinners, bruv.” Muhammad told him, amicably.

Amir turned away “I’ll see you tomorrow.” he called over his shoulder.

At least there were no catcalls or anything. They respected his faith that much, even if they didn’t respect it enough to practice it properly themselves. He just wished that his best friend wouldn’t use “we’re all sinners” as an excuse. It may have been true, but that didn’t mean he had to exploit it. That just didn’t feel like Islam.

He didn’t preach though. He was no Imam, he didn’t know how to be. All he had was his job delivering takeaway food, a council flat, and his religion. It was enough, most days.

He knew from experience that the bus stops near the Edgbaston cricket ground would always be heaving after a one-day game. He didn’t mind the walk: it was mid-July, and even the famously inclement British weather had decided to produce a warm night. So, anonymous and alone with his thoughts, he weaved through streets of Friday-night partiers, just another brown face in a crowd that ran the full gamut of human shades, hunched and with his fingers fidgeting with the edge of his pockets.

He was so shrouded in melancholy that he didn’t even see the person he walked into, but they felt solid as a rock. Knowing full well that a Pakistani face in this day and age could get into serious trouble with a surly drunk, he stepped back a pace, and got halfway through his “sorry mate” when he realised that the other man wasn’t moving. In fact, he still had his back turned.

Nobody else was moving either. Nothing else was moving. Traffic stood as still as scenery in the street. The pavement was solid-packed with warm, clothed, human statues, penning him in - he couldn’t even shove them aside to weave through the crowd. He stared at a young woman - she was in the middle of flicking her hair aside to answer her phone, and it stood out impossibly parallel to the ground. Even the light had a strange quality - he swore it took his shadow a brief instant to react when he moved.

And then that shadow became much better-defined as the night-time street orange was flooded out by whiteness. He looked up, and it filled his vision.

One man looked around in confusion, rubbed his back, and returned to his conversation. The streets didn’t even notice that Amir Bahmani was gone.

++

Kirk was a rich being - a Councillor of the Domain earned a handy sum of money from their position, not to mention the royalties from his biographical accounts, political sponsorships and some shrewd investments. Nevertheless, between buying his ultra-fast ship and then having it fast-tracked through a refit drydock at a corporate freeport where the owners were happy to sign an anonymity contract for an appropriate fee… well. His accounts were looking rather less healthy than they had done in some time.

They would, however, bounce back. He was a client of one of the best investment brokers in the business, after all. And the refits had been worth it. The little life-support blister with its bed, ablutions cubicle and control console had been dismounted from the hull, and behind it had been installed a somewhat larger and more luxurious living suite. Below that, a workshop loaded with the latest in nanofactories and CAD/CAM tools, a dense and comprehensive automated laboratory that could double as a sickbay.

And behind that, the enormous generator and the sealed unit that was the Corti blackbox drive. Mass made no difference to a Corti drive - any ship, any size, any tonnage, the only thing that mattered was how much energy you could force down that little box’s throat, and the behemothic bulk of the fusion reactor that made up by far the largest part of the ship’s size and mass was rated to power city districts.

There was one last addition: an excursion chamber, equipped with all the gear he could need to remain safe on practically any planet up to and including a Class 12. And it was necessary - the first destination on his list was a Class 10, an unclaimed world (after all, who in their right minds would want to claim a death world?) with the uninspiring designation “Main Yellow 2.55467-1.00209-0.1413-57.88811-3 Terrestrial Temperate 10” - literally nothing more than the type and location of the planet and of the star it orbited.

He slept most of the journey out. The downside he was discovering to his ship was that, having as it did a stupefying turn of speed, the trip times were barely long enough for him to complete the in-flight checklist and get some rest. By the time his alarm woke him he was already within the last hundred or so interstellar units of final approach. There had barely been time for his neural implants to convert the slow-access digital data on his destination into working organic memory.

But, they had. He knew everything that it was practical and useful for him to know about that world, barring any gaps in the data, which was how he handled its unique upper-atmospheric turbulence with practiced ease despite having never previously landed without guidance from the ground.

It helped that his target co-ordinates were experiencing a clear day, and as hoped he found a thermal contact within only a short distance of the information that had been in Vakno’s file. Best to land a little way from it, he thought.

He did so. Landing a ship that was effectively a couple of small rooms tacked onto a highly oblate spheroid was a challenge in its own right under MY210573TT10’s gravity, which was nearly 20% higher than the galactic standard norm. Not as high as Earth’s, but enough to be uncomfortable once he stepped outside of the ship’s generated gravity field. Once landed, he performed those few post-flight checks that any good pilot concerned themselves with, and then retreated to the excursion room.

It took only moments to select the appropriate harness and don it. The device had its own onboard gravity generator that would mitigate the local field, and the rest was a biofiltration force field that should keep anything nasty from coming into contact with him.

Time to meet the first human he had seen in the flesh for three years.

++

++

Amir had expected a ramp. Instead, the whole room slung under the ship’s equatorial ring descended to ground level, and a pair of large and very solid doors opened, gracefully and silently. He hefted his spear. If it was another of those grey-skinned devils, it wouldn’t know what hit it.

Instead, what stepped out and blinked in the sunlight was a six-legged being fully twice his height, upright atop a complicated pelvis. It raised both its pairs of hands in a gesture of peace and surrender and, with exaggerated care, produced a piece of technology which it set on the ground. The alien clicked at it, producing a sound not dissimilar to a strip of cardboard in a bike’s spokes. This was, apparently, some kind of a language, because once it had finished clicking, the little device on the ground spoke in flawless, though unaccented, English.

“Please, I couldn’t harm you even if I wanted to. You don’t need the spear, Mr. Bahmani.”

Amir practically fell over. It had been years since he had last heard any human language at all, let alone his name.

“H…” the words wouldn’t come at first. He could barely remember speaking aloud other than to recite the Adhān to call himself to Ṣalāt five times a day, and the Rakaʿāt. He had not spoken anything else in… years, probably.

They had been important. Only his faith had kept him going throughout those years. He didn’t have the first idea which way Mecca was, and so had simply settled for facing toward this planet’s east.

He cleared his throat and tried again. “You know English?”

This generated a chattering sound from the being’s lower abdomen, which he decided was probably laughter, followed by another barrage of clicking and crackling noises. “I couldn’t begin to pronounce English, I’m afraid. But my translator here can. You are Amir Bahmani though, yes?”

“I… yes. How do you know?”

The being made a gesture that he couldn’t identify - its body language was unreadable.

“I paid good money to get my hands on a copy of your abductor’s records.” It told him. “My name is…” <an unintelligible sound like plastic beads in a blender> “...but other humans have nicknamed me “Kirk”.”

“Kirk… like, Star Trek?”

“That’s the joke I think, yes. Though it’s also a fair approximation of the first syllable of my name.”

“My abductors… You’re not with them are you?” Amir hefted his spear again, and “Kirk” retreated a step or two, holding up four placating hands.

“No, no. I draw the line at abduction, vivisection and experimentation upon sentient beings. No, I’m here to offer you the chance to leave, if you wish.”

“You’ll take me home?!” Hope swelled in Amir for the first time in a long while. Earth! people! He mentally corrected himself at that one - Human people!

“If only I could.” Kirk told him. “But Earth is… well. The focus of much attention right now.” He looked around at Amir’s camp. “Actually, I'll just be blunt about it. The rest of the galaxy found out about your species and collectively shit themselves in fear. Earth has been quarantined - they put up a force field around the whole solar system, nothing gets in or out. I… disagree with that decision. I have a plan, and it starts with finding every abductee I can and offering them the hope of a way home.”

He extended a hand, and Amir noticed for the first time that it was made of sleek plastic and metal rather than pale flesh. “Are you in?” Kirk asked. “Shake carefully please, it doesn’t matter so much if you break the prosthetic rather than my actual hand, but they’re a pain to repair.”

“Bismillah! You have to ask? I want to go home.”

They shook hands.

“I promise, I’ll try.” Kirk told him.

++

Having a uniformed chauffeur waiting at the airport holding up a sign with “Terri Boone” on it was a novel experience. The chauffeur was efficiency itself as she took Terri’s bags and politely delivered her into the back seat of a sleek black Audi. Next to the expensive car with its buff leather upholstery and general air of wealth, her travel-stained jeans, battered leather jacket and the faded hoody from Chamonix she had owned since a teenage skiing vacation that she wore under the jacket all looked not just dishevelled, but downright squalid.

She entertained herself on her phone as the chauffeur weaved in the comfortable silence of money through freeway and midtown traffic to her apartment, and was surprised when the chauffeur not only brought in the bags, but insisted that no tip was necessary. After quickly discussing what time the car would arrive to take her to Mr. Johnson’s office, she was left alone to re-acquaint herself with her neglected home.

She threw open the windows and lit some scented candles to drive out the scent of emptiness that had built up in the months she had been gone and then, in a move that would have surprised anyone who did not know her extremely well, she emptied all the drawers out of the chest next to her bed and lifted it up, revealing a small, slim box stashed underneath.

From this she withdrew a device of some kind and a USB stick, which she plugged into her PC and launched some programs from, before spending nearly two hours carefully inspecting every nook and cranny of her apartment with the device. Eventually, and apparently satisfied, she returned both to their box and rebuilt the hiding place.

Only then did she boot up some more programs. She spent half an hour alternately typing and watching the screen intently. That done, she took a spin through the shower, combed her hair, threw on some fresh clothing and the same old leather jacket, grabbed her handbag, and departed.

She would have been thoroughly disappointed to learn that her sweep for bugs stood no hope whatsoever of detecting the ones that had been installed a month previously. Among other things, finding them would have required a microscope.

++

++

“Nope, not organised at all.”

Kevin Jenkins was patiently explaining things and going through the notebook as some of the biology and medical teams examined the peculiar scar on his temple. They had made it as far as the political situation.

“I mean, before a few years ago, legally speaking we were all “non-sentient indigenous fauna". It’s a bureaucratic mess out there, believe me.”

Tremblay examined the notes again. Mostly it was full of observations about the governmental structures of dozens of different species. the Dominion especially was troubling him. “Left hand doesn’t know what the right hand’s doing?”

Jenkins shrugged, ignoring a lab-coat’s protest to keep his head still. “Left hand could fill in a couple forms in triplicate requesting a third-party committee add a debate to their agenda on whether there’s grounds to start the process of commissioning an independent review on what part of the right hand’s up to.” he sneered.

“You make it sound... inefficient.” one of the junior officers commented.

“The Dominion couldn’t find whatever passes for their ass with whatever passes for their hands without three policy meetings and a vote.” Jenkins replied, tersely. It wasn’t quite a snap, and certainly not aimed at the officer, but there was definitely bitterness in the way he said it. “It’s all there in the manual.”

“And what’s in the manual is disturbing.” Tremblay said. He turned a page, and arched an eyebrow. “Roswell Greys? Really?”

“That was pretty much my reaction.” Jenkins said. He had a resigned expression as one of the scientists laid a ruler against his scalp and took a picture.

“According to this they call themselves the Corti Directorate and are the ones primarily responsible for alien abductions on Earth.”

“Hence how they became the Roswell Greys, I guess.” Jenkins sniffed. “But they’re not as bad as some of the motherfuckers out there. At least you know where you stand with the Greys, even if that is under a microscope.”

“Under a microscope still sounds pretty bad.”

“Eh, they’re just self-serving, cowardly, apathetic and practical to a fault. At least we can understand how they think. There’s things out there that think in ways I don’t even know the words for.”

“Like those things that attacked Vancouver, I’m guessing.” Tremblay turned to that page. The sketches were remarkably detailed. The biologists had gone into ecstatic paroxysms over them - the high-definition TV footage from the hockey game had been useful, but the panicked and shell-shocked cameramen hadn’t done the world’s best job of focusing on them and what had been delivered for necropsy had been thoroughly pulverised. A sketch was no substitute for having the real thing under the knife of course, but the detailed drawings of the cybernetic interface between creature and gun had answered some unresolved questions.

“Yeah. They scare me, but not for the right reasons.” Jenkins said.

“The right reasons?” That was Doctor Sung, the base’s counsellor and psychologist. He had, hitherto, been silent, content to just sit in the corner and watch the man who claimed to have spent years wandering the galaxy.

“Look, those bastard things… you know how some people see morality in terms of black, white and shades of grey? Well the Hunters see it in purple, orange and shades of fucking tartan. They’re notorious across the whole galaxy for not only eating the meat of sentient beings, but apparently preferring it to, like, farming a cow or something. That sounds like the right reason to be afraid of them, to me. They’re actual honest-to-shit space monsters. But that’s not what scares me about them.”

“What does?” Sung asked.

“You saw what happened in Vancouver.” Jenkins replied. “Well, that was no fluke: I’m telling you, I personally beat the crap out of three of those fuckers with their own limbs, right after I tore said limbs clean off. It wasn’t even difficult, man.”

He shrugged helplessly. “The worst nightmares in the galaxy and some random barkeep from Fuck-Nowhere USA can literally dismember them bare-handed. Worst I had to show for it was a black eye. That scares me.”

Sung cocked his head to one side, curiously. “Being powerful scares you?”

“I didn’t do shit to deserve it, you know? It’s not like you can just say “Hey, I EARNED that”, we’re, like, Kryptonians. We’re Superman, and the worst part is we - the human race, right? - we never had Ma and Pa Kent to teach us to be all about protecting people and all that shit. Before Vancouver, every day the news was full of the latest trending fucking atrocity.”

He stood up, raised his arms and adopted a goofy parody of a TV presenter. “it’s time for Wheel of Paedophile, where we reveal which TV icon of yesteryear was fiddling little girls! And after that, which journalist got beheaded for God today, kids? Tune in and find out on The Humanity Show!”

The moment of sarcastic enthusiasm died, and he sagged back down. ”Hell, it’d still be full if that shit right now if we didn’t have bigger things on our minds. And pretty soon we’re going to go back to being fucked up to each other when it turns out that whatever we do we’re still, like, probably years from even heading out to the barrier and knocking.”

He sighed. “That’s why the Hunters scare me: because despite that they scare the shit out of everything else, The Hunters never got a reaction like this. Which means that somebody up there thinks we’re WORSE than the Hunters, and I’m scared they might just turn out to be right.”

“You don’t think very highly of people, do you.” Tremblay commented.

“You’re damn right!” Jenkins exclaimed. “But, y’know, individuals can be kind of cool, so we’ve got that going for us.” he sniffed. “Which is nice.”

++

++

“Miss Boone. A pleasure to meet in the flesh at last.”

Terri didn’t know what she had expected from Mr. Johnson exactly, and really, he lived up to that lack of expectation. He was a dapper, handsome man of about fifty years, with a grey-flecked beard, grey-flecked hair and grey-flecked eyes, wearing a tailored charcoal suit and grey socks. The kind of guy she’d have happily picked up in a hotel bar if she was in the mood for a couple of nights with an older, wealthier man, but no long-term entanglements. He had that curiously accentless voice too, that gave nothing away about where in the world he had been born.

Still, she shook his hand, prepared for - and duly receiving - the circulation-halting firm grip of a man who shook hands for a living.

She was immediately convinced that, whoever he really was, Mr. Johnson was not actually her client. If he turned out not to be a proxy for the real deal, then she would have happily eaten her treasured Chamonix sweatshirt.

Not that this suspicion bothered her much. The amount of money on show meant that frankly the client could have contacted her via strippergram for all Terri cared.

“It’s been a pleasure getting paid.” she said, deciding that playing along with the politeness game could go shove it. “What’s the new job?”

Johnson didn’t seem fazed in the least by this blunt approach, and simply handed her a folder. She flicked through it, seeing names and faces but not bothering to really examine them. One stood out, however.

“Hey, I recognize her. She was that film student who went missing from Vancouver a few days before the attack, right?”

Mr. Johnson smiled the thin-lipped professional smile of somebody who was being paid far more to smile thin-lipped professional smiles at her than she was being paid to receive them. “Xiù Chang, yes. Based on the information you recovered from the abductees, it seems likely that she was abducted herself. The others in that dossier are similar cases, most from this country, a few others from elsewhere in the world.”

“You want me to look around, try and find some more?” Terri asked.

“You have it exactly. That dossier should provide a template for the sort of thing we’re after. Circumstances, factors common to all abductees, and so on.”

“And for this you’re offering me…?”

“A million dollars, Miss Boone. The dramatic turn that events have taken recently means that we’re keen for this to be done with the utmost expediency.”

We, Terri noted. Her sweatshirt was definitely safe.

“I don’t usually say this to the man with the cash.” she said, carefully. “But… why? Everyone knows that the best working theory for the Darkening so far is that there’s some kind of barrier up around the whole solar system. If these people are outside it, then what’s the rush in finding them? What good is that information?”

“And if they’re wrong, Miss Boone?”

“Are they?”

“That’s hardly relevant.”

“True, it’s not, really. After all even without a giant force field imprisoning us, it’s not like we’ve got hyperspace or whatever, so while I’m grateful for clients who pay so well, I do wonder why you want to spend so much on getting this done “with expediency”.”

“And you will continue to do so, I fear. You understand the assignment?”

Terri sighed. “Chase up on missing persons cases that match the profile of these apparent abductions, report them back to you as I find them, for which I will receive a million dollars.” she said.

“Precisely. It is always a pleasure to do business with a professional, Miss Boone.”

“Sure.” Terri replied. “A pleasure.”

Johnson waited a minute or so after she was gone and then stood, unlocked the side door to his office, and stepped through.

There was a coffin-sized metal-and-glass object along one wall of that room, and the being within - small, naked, grey-skinned, large-eyed and bulbous-headed, stared out at him lazily from where it floated in a gel bath inside.

“She agreed.” he said.

“Good. She is just the right mix of clever and mercenary. An excellent find.”

“Thank you, sir. She does, however, raise a very good point. Exactly what good will this information do us?”

“The more we know about who’s out there, the more I can assist the being who’s tracking them down. I didn’t come here to live out the rest of my life on a pre-warp deathtrap of a planet, Johnson. I want to go home.”

The Corti approximated a grim smile. “I want that barrier down.”

++

Maria Nazwisko didn’t know what to make of anything. She had got used to the idea of alien life, got used to scavenging whatever scraps they could be bothered to deign to kick her way. Her ribs and bones were visible everywhere, her gums bled constantly, and the sores just wouldn’t heal.

And then just like that, the attitude had changed. One minute, she was ignored by aloof creatures who barely deigned to acknowledge her at all, now they saw her and walked across the other side of the transitway. If she went into an eating-house to beg, before she had been lucky to get scraps - now she got as much as she could stuff into herself while around her tables vacated and the owner carried itself in a way that suggested that, if its species could sweat and if that sweat meant what it meant in humans, it would have been sweating.

She hadn’t had enough time to figure out why when she heard the first recognizable word to fall on her ears in months.

“Maria?”

It was an alien. one of the tall white ones with too many legs, though those were usually friendly. Behind it - him? - stood a human an honest-to-god human. She didn’t care that he looked like he didn’t speak a word of Polish, she didn’t care if his skin tone was practically the opposite of hers, right now it was enough just to see somebody the right size, with the right number of limbs, eyes, fingers…

Weeping, she slammed into him at a dead run and hugged tight, oblivious to the way nearby beings stepped back in alarm at the solid sound their compact little bodies made. He made awkward comforting noises and rubbed her back.

“I think this one might be a bit fragile, Kirk.”

“She’ll get better. She’s going home.”

++

++

“Extraordinary guy.” Dr. Sung commented, once Jenkins had agreed to go under an fMRI scanner and departed with the medical technicians and biologists.

Tremblay made a strained noise. “Seems like a bad case of PTSD to me. Not that I’m an expert.”

Sung had the trademark dry humour of psychologists everywhere. “Well, speaking as an expert, I agree with that diagnosis.” He said. “But he’s coping well, and he actually makes a valid point.”

“Don’t tell me he’s turned you into a misanthrope too?”

“Confidentially? I think he’s the opposite of a misanthrope. The impression I got is that he’s the kind of man who’s a bit too driven by his compassion. But step back and think about it for a second. Personally, I believe his account, which means that he’s more or less the only man on Earth to have the chance of really getting to know what it’s like out there - apparently only a handful of the rest ever got that translation implant, and none of them were out there for as long.”

Tremblay leaned against a table and folded his arms. “Meaning?”

“Meaning he knows how ET thinks. He’s got a bit more of an outsider’s perspective than the rest of us. Maybe the reason he’s so bitter on the species is because he can see what they see in us.” He smiled uncomfortably. “It’s notoriously difficult for people to acknowledge stuff like that.”

“True. Self-deception’s a powerful thing.” Tremblay said, helping himself to a mug of the coffee that had been percolating in the corner of the lab since they arrived. Sung flipped through the document the pilgrimage had assembled.

“Which means by extension that self-awareness is a powerful thing too.” he said. “The whole world has been going over the question of why an alien civilization would bottle us up, and really the answer’s so obvious when you look at it from Jenkins’ perspective. We’ve been quarantined and the only reason to quarantine something is because it’s dangerous.”

Tremblay sipped his coffee, and poked around the lab, pausing at a sample of alien bone that was attached to a detailed report on its composition, strength, density and toughness - all depressingly inferior to the human norm, to judge by a summary of percentages that ran down one side of the page. “I suppose it’s hard to argue with that.” he mused. “Hmm.. hand me that notepad a second, would you?”

Sung did so, and availed himself of the coffee as well while the general flipped through the contents of the Abductee handbook, logged on to the lab’s computer and watched the footage from Rogers Arena, referring back to the notepad several times.

“Something up, sir?” he asked.

“Just… looking at things from a military perspective.”

Tremblay picked up a pen and tapped the screen with the reverse end. “See here? The way they exit those pods.”

“What about it?”

“It’s not aggressive enough.” Tremblay said. when Sung raised an eyebrow and gestured a need for more information, he stood up and put down his coffee. “Okay, so when a soldier enters a hostile area full of known threats, they move like this...”

Miming holding a gun, he barged forward, pretend weapon tucked tight into his shoulder and pointed almost along his sightline, weight forward, posture loose but coiled, ready to spring in any direction as danger demanded. Sung blinked and the general was half-way through dropping some virtual targets with a volley of precise shots. The burst of simulated violence lasted no more than a second or two before he relaxed again.

“Bear in mind that I’ve not done that for real in about ten years, and I’m fifty-one years old. I’ve slowed down a lot. But you get the idea - aggression. You throw yourself into the fight economically and efficiently - little movements, big effect, make the best possible use of the moment of surprise.” Tremblay told him. “Now the aliens moved like this…”

Despite being deficient two pairs of legs, Tremblay’s imitation of the beasts on the screen was uncanny. This time, the posture was upright and proud, the invisible gun held awkwardly level with his solar plexus and out away from his body. His progress across the room was notably slower, more like arrogant strutting than a hostile rush, and his “weapon” was much slower to aim. Everything looked more sluggish, less precise, less deadly compared to the study in focused violence that had preceded it.

“I follow.” Sung nodded.

“Yep. But then we get to… here...” Tremblay clicked forward in the footage to the point where one of the players swept in and smashed one of the aliens to the ice with his hockey stick. Obviously panicked though they were, as the remaining Hunters drew together in a defensive circle, their posture changed as well, into a stance much more like the one the general had first demonstrated - compact, focused, precise.

“That did them no good of course, but it shows that they at least know how to do things properly, so the question is, why weren’t they moving like that in the first place?”

“You have a theory there?” Sung asked him.

“I do. And it’s one that bears out Jenkins’ account of these things being the boogeymen of interstellar space. They practically swaggered out of those pods as if it didn’t matter if they did things the right way or not, like they seriously believed they were invulnerable.” Tremblay picked up his coffee again. “They got cocky.”

“Does that scare you?”

Tremblay shrugged, shaking his head very slightly with a wide-eyed expression. “I don’t know what to feel, yet. I’ve not had first-hand experience or years to get my head around the idea. It just doesn’t seem real, somehow.”

They sat in silence for a while, Sung sensing that the general was in the mood for a little peace and quiet, and content to give it to him. Eventually, both their meandering trains of thought were brought back to the here-and-now when Jenkins returned with the scientists.

“Well, you’ll be pleased to know the fMRI corroborated my account.” Jenkins said.

Tremblay accepted the summary and afforded it a quick reading.

“Fine. I think I’m convinced” he said. “But interesting as all of this is, the information’s a bit academic, isn’t it?”

“Yep.” Jenkins agreed. “But I wanted to make sure you’d got your heads around a few things before I dropped the real surprise on you.”

“Which is?”

Jenkins grinned, and retrieved the battered hiking pack he’d been carrying when he first arrived at the base. Buried at the bottom under his spare shirts and underwear was a padded manila envelope, which he presented to the general.

Tremblay opened it and tipped its contents out onto his hand - a small, featureless silver box, about the size of a hard drive. The only feature of note on its surface was what appeared to be a power socket on one end, though not of a make that Tremblay recognised.

They all leaned closer, jaws dropping. Sung broke the silence, though only barely. “Is this…?”

Jenkins’ grin would have put the Cheshire Cat to shame. “Alien, yep. I managed to get my hands on it while working in a ship salvage yard on Freeport Fifty-Two. Smuggled it back to Earth when the observation team finally agreed to strip out my implants and bring me home.”

“What is it?”

The spacefarer’s smile broadened even further.

“This, gentlemen… is an FTL engine.”

__

End chapter 5

you're right about the magic "humans are the best at everything" thing. I might have gotten a bit too excited.

Just a bit. It's important to remember that humans in the Jenkinsverse have innate physiological advantages over other species. The other species have some huge advantages of their own, not least of which being that the Corti invented FTL long before the first human-like apes figured out that putting rocks around a fire contains the fire and makes it useful.

An advantage is like a good starting position in the race - you've still got a lot of work to do if you're going to turn it into a medal.

Quod erat demonstrandum pars: II

By devourerkwi

Dramatis personæ

Lucius Bellator Maximus, a Roman legionary from Legio V Alaudæ, based at the camp Castra Vetera in Xanten, Germania Inferior, serving Emperor Vespasian of the Flavian dynasty

Dieter, a barbarian from the Batavi tribe that was revolting against Rome

Berenice, an Egyptian woman, and her son, Isidorus, from the slums of Alexandria

Yan, a Chinese concubine from the court of and consort to Emperor Ming of Han in the Eastern Han dynasty

Glossarium

Bellum se ipsum alet: War feeds itself

Braccae: Trousers worn by legionaries in cooler climates

Caliage: Military boots worn by legionaries that were made from layers of heavy leather and resembled sandals

Centurion: A mid–level officer in the Roman army who commanded 80 men

Montefortino helmet: A helmet worn by Roman infantry that had a knob on the top and neck and cheek protection

Paludamentum: A cape fastened at one shoulder, worn by Roman commanders

Quod erat demonstrandum: Which had to be demonstrated

Lucius’s first, careful step into the hallway made too much noise, his caligae stained with bodily fluids that started to crack as they dried. Their fight had been brief but the portal’s destruction had caused a ruckus he was sure other sentries would have heard. He approached the first portal on the left and spied a window about 10 feet off the ground, roughly where the heads of the four–armed things were, just below the top of the portal. The portal itself protruded a bit from the sleek, silvery wall and he thought he might be able to jump and grab the edge, holding himself aloft for a few seconds so he could see inside.

He beckoned to the Batavian and pointed at the window, silently gesturing his intent to try to see through it. The Batavian nodded and moved to stand guard as Lucius bent into a quarter–squat and exhaled slowly, readying himself. His legs impelled his body upward and he sailed straight past the window and into the ceiling.

He cried out in pain despite the protection of his Montefortino helmet and started falling back to the ground, albeit far more slowly than he expected. He found he had time to reorient himself and land on his feet, his caligae’s worn leather cushioning his impact. Something was gravely wrong; he shouldn’t be able to jump so high and he should have fallen much faster. He looked up and noticed that his helmet had left a puncture and dent where it had hit the ceiling; Lucius didn’t know why this happened, but he jumped with less power and felt as if he was floating up to the window. He grasped the protruding top of the portal and held himself up, finding it surprisingly easy. Lucius was quite strong, but he felt as if he were lifting his youngest son, not himself.

But he had found more Romans. He saw two soldiers, easily recognizable by their braccae. He also saw a senior officer, his paludamentum curiously flapping in what must be a great wind he could neither feel nor hear. He saw them start to slide across the floor as if being pulled by an invisible rope, their hands clawing at the floor, looking for something to grab ahold of. He felt the entire corridor shudder and heard the creaking of bending, failing metal. He saw the far walls behind the window visibly give way and reveal an inky black speckled with white dots. The Romans inside hurtled toward it and disappeared into the darkness.

Lucius let go of the portal–top in a daze and fell slowly to the ground, sagging to his knees in defeat. The Batavian strode to the next portal on the right and jumped up, unleashing a feral roar as he peered through. He pushed himself off the ceiling and to the floor, rebelliously punching the first thing he saw: A glowing light at his eye level on the side of the portal. It opened obligingly and Lucius felt an unnaturally strong wind pushing him toward it, sucking the air from his lungs.

His body slammed into the right–hand wall and it abated the mysterious wind’s force just enough for him to see the Batavian’s bulk splayed across the portal–hole, arms and legs spread apart, straining. Lucius carefully braced his caligae against the protruding part of the portal and slowly bent toward the Batavian, wrapping his arms around one of the man’s massive, rippling legs. He pulled.

The Batavian felt Lucius’s help and did his best to hurl himself toward Lucius, rolling out of the portal–hole and impacting the glowing light at the portal’s side with the whole of his torso. The portal obligingly closed, stopping the wind. Lucius and the Batavian fell to the floor, sucking in great gasps of air. The Batavian started laughing. Lucius stood up and plodded back to their holding room, certain that the other rooms had met the same fate these two had. He couldn’t fathom why his room’s walls were still intact.

As he entered their room he looked around to try and find the women and boy. The boy was crying—understandably so, Lucius mused—into his mother’s arms as her terror–stricken gaze went straight through Lucius and into a place far, far away. The silk–clad woman sat with her legs crossed and head bowed, her long hair a tousled, tangled mess.

“We cannot stay here,” said Lucius. He was met with no response. “We cannot stay here!” he repeated, raising his voice. They remained silent, seemingly ignoring him. “We must leave!” he shouted. The boy’s crying stopped; his mother refocused on Lucius’s frantic visage. The silk–clad woman peered at him through her hair. “We must leave,” he pleaded, “or we will surely die.”

Lucius felt a rough, calloused hand on his shoulder and turned to find the Batavian looking down at him with sad, icy blue eyes behind thick blonde hair that spilled over his forehead and touched his nose. Lucius’s shoulders sagged for a moment before he remembered himself. “I am the Third Alaudæn Centurion,” he thought, “and I must lead these people from this place.”

He thought for a moment and realized that the others did not speak Latin. He steeled his posture and gestured to himself, saying, “Lucius,” then pointing at the Batavian and asking, “And you?”

The Batavian smiled ferociously, sensing Lucius’s newfound resolve. “Ha! Dieter!” he said, jamming a thumb into his chest. “Dieter! Lucius!” he bellowed, clapping Lucius on the arms and raising his fists in triumph, laughing as if he had just won a war.

“Dieter and Lucius,” agreed Lucius. He turned to the mother and son and held his hand out with his palm open and facing up. “And you?” he asked.

The boy sniffled and spoke slowly and quietly. “My name is Isidorus,” he said in heavily accented, broken Latin. “My mother, Berenice. From Alexandria,” he finished, receding into his mother’s arms. She remained quiet, keeping at Lucius with her piercing, ghastly stare. She might not speak a word of Latin, and Lucius didn’t know Egyptian. He turned to the silk–clad woman.

“Yan,” she said, preempting his question. She flew into a rapid monologue in a harsh–sounding language Lucius didn’t recognize, abruptly stopping, probably because she realized that he had no idea what she was saying. She bowed her head and glanced up at him expectantly, unwilling to make eye contact.

“Lucius. Dieter. Isidorus. Berenice. Yan,” said Lucius, gesturing to each person in succession. He nodded to himself and turned to the portal. “Come,” he said.

Quod erat demonstrandum pars: III

by devourerkwi

A complete listing of all parts of Quod Erat Demonstrandum is available here.

Special thanks are due to /u/iamcptplanet for many of the ideas used in this series and in this chapter in particular, as well as invaluable discussion, editing, and enthusiasm.

According to the official timeline on the Jenkinsverse Wiki, the Corti abducted the first humans around 2,000 years before the Vancouver incident. This is the story of those abductees, set in the year 70 AD.

Dramatis personæ

Lucius Bellator Maximus, a Roman legionary from Legio V Alaudæ, based at the camp Castra Vetera in Xanten, Germania Inferior, serving Emperor Vespasian of the Flavian dynasty

Dieter, a barbarian from the Batavi tribe that was revolting against Rome

Berenice, an Egyptian woman, and her son, Isidorus, from the slums of Alexandria

Yan, a Chinese concubine from the court of and consort to Emperor Ming of Han in the Eastern Han dynasty

Glossarium

Et lux in tenebris lucet: And light shines in the darkness

Paludamentum: A cape fastened at one shoulder, worn by Roman commanders

Pilum: A heavy javelin used by Roman soldiers, somewhat longer than a large man, that could be thrown 50-100 feet

Quod erat demonstrandum: Which had to be demonstrated

“At least nobody can come from behind us,” thought Lucius as he crept through the metal hallway. It wasn’t particularly long; a good soldier would be able to throw his pilum down its length. The next two portals hid the same white-speckled black and each protected them from another powerful gale. He had stopped checking them after the third nearly claimed frail Berenice. Now, he and Dieter led the party as their footsteps echoed up and down the hallway, Isidorus swinging between Berenice and Yan, holding their hands.

They soon reached a dead end. Another portal blocked their path and they had nowhere to hide from the gales, so Lucius had the others retreat to their original room while he wedged himself into the corner between the portal and the wall. He slapped at the curious light that controlled the portal and it opened with an abrupt whir and hiss, but no gale came. He peeked in and saw a new room filled with glowing tables but immediately slapped at the light again to close the portal, hoping he hadn’t been seen. He backed away it, reaching the original holding room without ever taking his eyes off the portal.

“Dieter,” he said, and the man perked. “Come.”

“Battle?” asked Dieter, using one of the few Latin words he knew outside of Lucius’s name. Lucius shrugged and drew his metal stick, walking back toward the end of the hallway. Dieter followed him, also having drawn his metal stick, and they took up positions on either side of the portal. Lucius used hand signals to tell Dieter which sides of the room they would each check and clear and Dieter nodded, grinning. He was excited; Lucius was solemn. Dieter lived to fight; Lucius got the job done. It was the difference between warriors and soldiers, uncivilized and civilized.

Lucius exhaled and hardened himself, then nodded at Dieter to punch the portal-light. He did and they scanned the sides of the new room opposite themselves, neither seeing anything moving. Lucius nodded again and they crossed each other as they entered the new room, stealthily moving through it. As they reached the other side they found a trio of new ... things ... huddled up against the far wall. They were as tall as the four-armed things but their skin was patterned into a white-and-blue zebra stripe and they had two arms and four legs. Their long necks made them look like giraffes and despite how much bigger they were than even Dieter, they were trembling.

“Surrender!” demanded Lucius, brandishing his metal stick menacingly. They made a series of clicking sounds and tried to back up farther. One lost its nerve and tried to run past Dieter, but with a gleeful roar he set off after it. One enormous stride covered more distance than Lucius thought natural and one enormous hand grabbed at the thing’s left hind leg. There was a sickening crunch that Lucius recognized as shattering bone and a whump signaled the beast falling to the ground. Dieter yanked the thing’s leg and it tore straight off, spraying him in a geyser of blood. He stood in shock, holding the dismembered leg as the thing bled along the floor as it tried to crawl away, wailing in slow, pained clicks.

Dieter’s mirth evaporated and he slowly circled around the blue giraffe, stooping in front of its face and solemnly whispering something to it. He placed his hand on its head and the beast’s clicking intensified, rising in pitch and volume until it hurt Lucius’s ears. Dieter suddenly jammed his metal stick into its neck, clearly hoping to mercifully end its suffering, and the beast convulsed with astounding seizures, a single line of blood dripping from the puncture wound as its clicks grew erratic. Dieter stood and backed away from the beast, mortified, and Lucius ran over—it took a mere four strides to cover such distance—and yanked the metal stick from the beast’s neck, careful to grasp the handle and not where its blade should be. The blue giraffe lay crumpled in a smoking heap, the smell of burnt flesh and crisp meat adding to the bloody stench that already permeated the room.

Lucius deigned to throw the metal stick at Dieter’s feet and walked back to the other two blue giraffes. They cowered before him, swinging their necks down low, unwilling to look at him. Lucius sheathed his metal stick as he stood over them, unsure of what to do.

“Don’t hurt them,” squeaked a small voice from behind him. Lucius whirled around to find Isidorus hiding behind one of the glowing tables. He turned and knelt, beckoning the boy to come over.

“I won’t,” he said, “unless they try to hurt us.”

“Then why did Dieter kill one?” asked Isidorus.

“He didn’t mean to,” said Lucius. “Look at him: He is a proud warrior but his face is full of shock.” Isidorus turned to face Dieter and found the Batavian staring through him the way his mother had stared through Lucius. “A warrior does not mourn a kill like this, Isidorus.”

Yan tiptoed into the room, Berenice on her heels, and pulled the boy from the scene and back to his mother, guiding them both to the far side of the room behind a large glowing table that obscured the grisly scene. Lucius walked to Dieter and studied his old enemy’s face with a hardened glare. Then he punched him square in the jaw.

Dieter took the blow and hardly flinched. His eyes turned to meet Lucius’s and they were glazed and wet, his mouth hanging open slightly, letting a trickle of blood out of the corner of his lip. His shoulders sagged and he tried to say something but all Lucius heard was the soft gibberish of a remorseful barbarian.

Lucius looked around the room, really looked around, for the first time, and noticed the small windows spaced every few feet. He walked to one and pressed his face to it, gasping as he looked outside. The same speckled blackness he had seen behind the hallway portals took up the entire field of view. He went from window to window, each one showing a black palette pocked with bright white dots. He went to the other side of the room to check those windows but the first one showed him a figure cloaked in a paludamentum, floating as if on the sea’s surface after drowning.

Dieter kept babbling and Lucius turned to head back to his new prisoners, unable to figure out what had happened to his compatriot. Behind him, Isidorus spoke to the still-silent Berenice in hushed Egyptian while Yan tended to both of them. The blue giraffes stayed quiet, clearly terrified. A portal whirred and hissed and a gray figure about Isidorus’s height strode into the room. Its eyes took up most of its face and its ears came to a sharp point at the sides of a swollen head that pulsed with each breath. It approached Lucius and stared up at him coldly.

“Are you done killing my employees?” it asked in perfect Latin.

Salvage01. Salvage

by Rantarian

This work is an addition to the Jenkinsverse universe created by /u/Hambone3110.

Where relevant, measurements and explanation is given in brackets following their alien names.

Bekmer stood waiting in the cavernous flight deck of the Zhadersil, an ancient and automatically maintained carrier ship that had managed to survive the destruction of the V'strak war machine that had spawned it a fifth of a galactic cycle ago [~50 million years] in the last Age. That it still existed in one piece was astounding, that it had still been somewhat functional when Bekmer and his team moved in had been nothing short of a miracle. Nobody would have normally thought to investigate a chunk of space rock orbiting an unremarkable Class 10 Deathworld - the latter was more worthy of attention by any measure - and yet a routine scan had uncovered something astounding. The outer hull had been pock marked and covered with enough space dust to credibly disguise the ship as a natural piece of space debris, it had been a simple case of being in the right place at the right time.

Bekmer, and the few members of his salvage crew, had stumbled upon the find of a lifetime - the Corti Directorate would be particularly pleased, once they found out about it - and it was certain to make the entire crew wealthy, and Bekmer himself fabulously so. The ship was in no condition for movement, however, and as a result Bekmer had kept the discovery quiet for the past few cycles while the many necessary repairs were made to restore the ship to even a mere vestige of a threatening military vessel. This deathworld was uninterestingly known only by its coordinate set, cursorily scanned by exploration drones and was well beyond the borders of any recognized government, and Bekmer was damned if he was going to try and fly a barely space-worthy fortune through uncontrolled space.

"Remind me why we are doing this again?" Bekmer asked, his gaze set disapprovingly on the Micro-Freighter that had just put down. Even the smallest freighter ships were large vessels, dwarfing the smaller salvage vessel that had borne the salvage crew to the Zhadersil, but against the vastness of the ancient ship's flight deck it seemed ridiculously toy-like. "Restorations are proceeding as scheduled, and the weapons will soon be active. This is a distraction we cannot afford."

Treoffa, his immediate subordinate and sometimes mate exhaled sharply through her nostrils in a show of indignant frustration. "They're not active yet, and our sensor buoys have detected faint Hunter activity in systems nearby. Not to mention the possibility of any pirate vessels who might have chosen to make their base out here."

"Still..." Bekmer said, although more hesitantly after the mention of the vicious creatures who ate the flesh of fellow sentient beings, "we're practically invisible here. We barely found the ship by accident, we weren't even looking for V'strak relics since you'll recall that none were supposed to exist. Besides, we've even got the cloaking field up, now."

"We are acutely vulnerable!" hissed Treoffa. "We both know the extent of the Hunters' expertise with cloaking technology! Do you wish to underestimate their expertise at detecting the cloaking fields of others? This is a microscopic expense compared to what we stand to lose if this vessel is taken from us!"

Bekmer opened his mouth to make some retort, but was interrupted by the hiss of machinery as the Micro-Freighter opened its containment bay for inspection, lowering the cargo lift on powerful pneumatics to reveal four white and gleaming cylindrical pods that hinted at containing something more interesting than everyday weapons. These were stasis pods, and from the way the indicators blinked on them they were all occupied with the internal temporal suppression fields fully active. The devices used a variant of the FTL drive to store whatever was inside of them in total suspended animation for as long as they had power.

Azhiz, the Robalin the two Corti entrepreneurs had entrusted with the task of returning with such cargo, crawled forth from his pilots hatch with an eager grin on his face, as if barely able to contain his excitement. He was an uncivilized sort, even for a Robalin, wearing clothing with highly contrasting colours and with many of his soft green scales stained into a vibrant yellow. No doubt some preposterous attempt to declare his individuality to the galaxy. He was, however, refreshingly mercenary and had thus far served the salvage crew well, although Treoffa and Bekmer had both ensured that the Robalin had had nothing to do with his species' ambition to uncover the ultimate bio-warfare weapon.

His lack of involvement did not mean that they had to like him.

"Azhiz," Bekmer greeted the Robalin coldly, "you have been asked to bring us soldiers. I trust you have not wasted your time or our funds?"

Azhiz was used to such a reception, and if he was still bothered by it he didn't show it. "Master Bekmer," he softly hissed as he bowed subserviently, "I have done entirely as you wished. All are combat-capable individuals and each has been... enthusiastically encouraged to follow any orders given to them."

"Cerebral Detonators?" Bekmer asked. It was what he had asked for, but it never hurt to confirm - especially when dealing with a Robalin. Cerebral detonators were cheap, inobvious, and exceptionally effective at ensuring that the implantee followed orders. They would eventually degrade, but only long after the ship had been salvaged and as such long after the implantees services were required.

"Indeed," Azhiz asked, maintaining his subservient posture. "However I regret to inform you that one of the subjects was... damaged."

"Damaged?" Treoffa interjected sharply. "The pods appear to be functional and undamaged. What have you done, Azhiz?"

Azhiz grew outwardly uncomfortable, his posture more submissive. "The fourth subject awoke during surgery," he said, with slow deliberation. "The fault was with the surgeon."

"Brain damage?!" Treoffa asked. "We can't have a brain-damaged soldier running around! That'd be more dangerous than the Hunters!"

"N-no," Azhiz replied, "he had not yet been operated on. He was damaged as necessary to capture him, and it proved necessary to employ a Strike-Drone's main cannon."

The two Corti paused, exchanging worried glances. Strike-Drones were a new war technology the Corti Directorate had intended to sell to both sides of the Celzi-Dominion conflict, ensuring impartiality in their enterprises while reaping a considerable profit. They were a hover platform carrying a heavy kinetic cannon, and had been intended for use on tanks, Vulza, and unfortunate infantrymen. Bekmer wasn't sure why a science vessel would have one, since there were so few reasons why they'd ever need one, and they almost never met with unfortunate... his thoughts trailed off as the pieces began falling into place.

"You said 'damaged'," Treoffa mused, "but I take it you are not suggesting that one of those pods is filled with mopped up remains."

"It can't be..." Bekmer breathed, horror finding its way to his face and contorting it. "They're under containment! There's no way in!"

"What?!" Treoffa asked, the truth of it dawning on her at the same time. They'd been all over the news, in every important conversation, and they were exactly the sort of thing an idiot Robalin like Azhiz would have thought perfect for a soldier.

"It's a human," Bekmer spat, "isn't it, Azhiz?! You've brought a human aboard our ship!" Azhiz recoiled at he vehemence of Bekmer's reaction. "I- I had just thought... the one on the news was fighting Vulza!"

"Where did you even get it?!" Bekmer demanded as Treoffa stood by in clear shock. "Their homeworld is under containment!"

"A Corti science vessel had one they'd not yet returned," Azhiz explained quickly. "They were going to destroy it, or try to destroy it anyway. I convinced them of a more lucrative alternative."

"And then?" Treoffa asked, finding her voice. "Was it they who did the surgery?"

"They tried to," Azhiz continued, "but the dose they used to put the human to sleep was based on records from another human recorded on a hospital ship. This one was more resistant."

"Did it kill everyone on the ship?" Bekmer asked coldly. He'd lost old companions to accidents in human containment breaches.

"It would have if they had not had a strike-drone aboard," Azhiz replied. "It still got twelve out of thirty before it was hit, and would have been more if it wasn't for the fact that they were ready for something like that. Once it was down, they prepped him like they originally intended and set him up with a cerebral detonator, basic translator, and a big dose of the new frontline protection serum."

"Thank goodness for that," Treoffa said. "We haven't got any of that on hand."

"They left it injured, however?" Bekmer asked.

Azhiz nodded quickly. "I think they were angry at him. Understandable."

"Unprofessional," Bekmer replied. "We will review the damage to it, and see if it can be put to use before we need to destroy it."

Treoffa nodded in agreement. It seemed that neither Corti wished to have a human running around on the ship.

"Now," Bekmer continued, "What else did you bring?"

"It's conscious," a voice said, and bright white light seared the eyes of Adrian Saunders, blinding him even as he opened them.

He felt as though he was drifting, a strange sensation compounded by the fact that there were two clearly alien beings standing by consoles around him, although at this point the strangeness of little gray men being real had somewhat lost its edge.

Not Heaven then, he thought dreamily. Not that he had ever believed in that, or had ever expected to end up there even if he had. This state was not entirely unfamiliar to him - he recognized the effects of too many pain-killers when he felt them, although he'd hoped never to be shot again after leaving the military six months ago. Much like the rest of Adrian's hopes, however, that one had also turned to shit.

"Does it understand me?" one of them asked, turning to the other. It's voice was clearly male, but there was a strange dissonance in Adrian's head where alien sounds were twisted into his native English. It also sounded like a total arsehole.

"It should," said the other, this one with a female, but not feminine, voice. She looked at Adrian with all the empathy of a five year old boy pulling the wings off of flies. "At least the translator isn't showing any errors."

The male turned to him again. "Can you understand me?"

"Get fucked..." Adrian replied. "Don't need none've that..."

"It seems he hears you," the female noted wryly.

"What you need," the male continued, more intently now, his tone ice cold, "is for your ribs to be re-assembled and for emergency action to be taken to stop your organs from dying. Do you understand?"

"You fuckers shot me," Adrian said, or mumbled. "Flying thing with a big gun on it..."

The male leaned in, scowling - or at least what Adrian thought was a scowl. "Two things: That wasn't us, and those 'big guns' are meant to assault armoured vehicles. You are lucky someone cared enough to keep you alive so that I could put you back together. We are salvage hunters, and today you are our salvage."

"We brought you out of your stasis to run our demands past you," the female interjected.

Adrian processed this for a moment, trying to figure it out through the fog that covered his thinking. "Demands?"

"If we save you, we will feed you, we will arm you, and we will help you get home," the male said. "In return you work for us. You protect us."

"Protect you?" Adrian asked, confused. "What about the flying thing? The... drone thing..."

The two aliens shared a brief glance before turning back to him. "We prefer you for the job. But if you don't want it, then our medical resources are better spent elsewhere. Do we have a deal?"

Adrian was silent for a while, long enough that the two aliens shared what might have been a worried glance.

"Yeah," he said, albeit unhappily. "I guess we have a deal."

+++++++++++++++++++++++++

The human was returned to a medical coma with the addition of more drugs. Treoffa decried the sheer amount of medication required to achieve this as a waste of resources better used elsewhere, but Bekmer had ordered her to continue - Treoffa was only second-in-command.

"Ensure his survival," Bekmer had told her as he'd left the human in her care. "Ensure he is returned to a combat ready state as soon as possible. Do whatever you have to do, and remember... the soldiers were your idea."

Bekmer had other things to attend to, such as three somewhat disgruntled soldiers currently awaiting an explanation for their abduction and temporary enslavement.

They awaited him in the Zhadersil's brig - the small hold of his salvage craft was not enough to cope with all three - and none of them looked happy.

They rose as he entered the room, separated not only by thick metal bars but a kinetic shield similar to what had encapsulated the human's home star system. The latter was pointless, the bars were heavy enough to contain an enraged Vulza - a curious thing to consider, Bekmer thought - but this was as much about making a statement as it was about containment.

"I am Bekmer," he told them, behaving as much like a commander as he was capable of achieving. "All you need to know is that you have been brought here to protect the salvage opportunity of a thousand lifetimes, and of course the crew carrying it out. Of that crew you have now met the Robalin and myself. There is another Corti, as well as two Rrrrtktktkp'ch, currently involved in this operation."

He stepped closer to them, ignoring their glares of animosity. "Your compliance has been ensured by the addition of cerebral detonators."

They were so shocked that he almost revealed amusement, but that would have been unprofessional. It was more common for slave-soldiers to be unaware of the modification, to be tempted with a prize until they threatened disobedience, but with these three that chance had come and gone well before they'd woken up from suspended animation.

"You," he said, pointing at the Chehnasho, a gaunt amphibious creature with bulging eyes and slick brown-green skin. Chehnasho were frequently employed as mercenaries in conflicts for their cunning and rapid movement in combat. They were an androgynous species, with each individual able to adapt its gender as desired, and this had ensured their spread throughout a multitude of worlds. "Your name?"

"Zripob," Zripob replied with a harsh, croaking voice. "We are slaves, then?"

"For the time being," Bekmer told him. "Work well and you will be released when our work here is done."

Bekmer didn't wait for the Chehnasho's answer, instead turning to the bone, fur and leather arrangement that was a Rauwryhr. They were often employed as scouts for military forces, where they decided to involve themselves, and were able to see well at night as well as take flight to provide an aerial advantage. "And your name?"

The creature gazed at him hatefully before answering. "Trycrur," she replied, her voice so surprisingly feminine that Bekmer nearly revealed his shock. It didn't matter, of course, which gender the creature was so long as it could fight, but Rauwryhr bred with difficulty and rarely allowed their females to risk themselves in combat roles.

Bekmer nodded, pretending that this was what he had been expecting all along and moved to the next caged alien - this one a powerfully built Gaoian male who'd thus far been standing in silence and giving him a black look from beneath fur very nearly as black. "And you, Gaoian?"

"I am Chir," the Gaoian said forcefully. "You'll pay for what you're doing to us!"

"I doubt it very much, Chir," Bekmer replied, tapping the side of his head. "Cerebral detonator, remember?" Chir grunted and threw himself at the bars, grunting with surprise as he was thrown back by the kinetic shield.

"You will be released shortly," Bekmer told them. "Ponder your circumstances until then. Consider how good work and obedience may be rewarded, and how defiance-" he turned his eyes to look at Chir, "meets with destruction. No more warnings."

Bekmer turned on his heel and strode from the brig, leaving sight of the soldiers before exhaling a trembling breath. It was obvious that they hated him, that they may well risk detonation to get at him, and that if that did occur that Bekmer would be in a very poor position to respond in any way that not result in brains splattered everywhere. The human, as far as he could tell, was the only one who didn't have any reason to completely despise him, and was the only one to who Bekmer could offer something beyond the simple prospect of freedom following the work - even if that prospect was a false one. He had to hope that that would be enough.

His communicator beeped, and by reflex he allowed the link to connect before quickly checking the name on it to sound like he had everything under control. "Treoffa? What do you want? Don't tell me the human has-"

"Died?" Treoffa asked, finishing Bekmer's question for him. "No. Although that would have been better, perhaps."

Death would have been better? Bekmer could not hide his surprise this time. "What are you talking about?" he asked irately.

"Come and see," she replied. "Now."

The link disconnected before Bekmer could respond, and he hissed in irate fury while he remained unseen in the empty corridor before hurrying to do as instructed.

Treoffa was not given to fancy, and aside from her enjoyment in taunting Bekmer she was entirely professional - that, after all, was what he found so welcome in her as an occasional mate.

"This had better be important," Bekmer snapped as he entered the room where Treoffa was busily running scans on the comatose human.

"It is," she assured him.

Undisguised concern was now so evident in her voice that it gave Bekmer pause. "Tell me."

"The damage was severe on a cellular level," she began to explain. "Organ tissue was dying, as was muscle, and that is not even taking into account all of the bone fragments."

"Azhiz told us that much," Bekmer replied impatiently. "A cellular regenerative should have alleviated the former problem."

She nodded. "That was my first step, but there is no information on how to reassemble a human this badly damaged, and so I initiated localised trials for the various possible drugs."

"At least one should have worked," Bekmer said. "We're not entirely unfamiliar with human physiology."

"They all worked," Treoffa replied. "The problem is that the Cruezzir formula had an unexpected result when introduced into the human's gut bacteria."

"Ah yes," mused Bekmer, "the unfathomable infestation of competing microbes living inside an even more unfathomable host. What was unexpected?"

"There was a rapid mutation," continued Treoffa. "One I did not notice until it was too late. The bacteria in question have started producing the same regenerative proteins that the Cruezzir was intended to elicit only whilst it was in the subject's system. He is now effectively self-producing the protein."

Bekmer was silent, looking down at the still body of the human. To his unaided eyes nothing seemed to be changing - it wasn't as if every injury the human had obviously endured was sealing up in front of him. "What is the outcome?" he asked.

"The protein has started to flood his body," Treoffa said, "and all damaged cells are regenerating. There are signs of new growth on the bones already." Bekmer produced a strangled noise, and it was a moment before he could talk again. "Are you telling me you've just taken the most dangerous species in the recorded history of this galaxy and made it stronger?"

She nodded slowly. "What do you want me to do?"

The answer to that took a long time for Bekmer to consider. He stared at the motionless human without thought, numb shock filling the space where logic and cunning usually resided, and a cold knot of fear resting in his gut.

"Follow my original orders," he said at last. "May the Directorate be merciful on me if I am wrong."

+++++++++++++++++++++++++

Time had passed. Chir wasn't sure how much, since the ship did not simulate day/night cycles and the Corti slave-masters had not seen fit to provide their slave-soldiers with any means of telling the time. The 'soldiers' had worked out a haphazard roster on their own, based on their varied needs for sleep, and had done their best to work as required. Even Chir had been quiet and obedient, although he considered the chances of ever seeing his beloved homeworld again to be slim.

He was at least not the only soldier in the group; Zripob had served in two major engagements on behalf of the Celzi before the Dominion had paid his company more to serve them for a third. Mercenaries were a rarely advertised part of modern war, and usually took on roles for ship-to-ship action rather than getting blasted into shreds of meat in the planet-bound infantry, and Zripob's experience in this would prove invaluable.

Trycrur, on the other hand, was no soldier at all, but was apparently considered a highly competent weapons designer and had worked in a Dominion military department before she had been snatched. She had been dressed in military colours at the time, however, and it was unsurprising that anyone simply searching for a lone individual in soldier dress would have identified her as anything other than a soldier. She knew, at least, which way to point a gun, but from what Chir could tell this was about the entirety of her soldier skills. If they were attacked by anything other than an immobile target, he doubted she would be of any help.

The three of them rarely moved from their patrol lines around the salvage crew's own ship, although Chir had every indication that there was a lot of ship he did not see. The flight-deck alone was big enough to fit two full Gaoian cruisers, and he wondered at the use its previous owners had put it to. From what he had overheard they had been named the V'strak, and although he was entirely unfamiliar with anything by that name it was clear that the ship was truly ancient and that they valued a great ruggedness in all of their structures. Judging by the lack of cushions, they also valued discomfort - truly alien beings.

"What do you think they're talking about?" Zripob asked him as they met to change over patrol shifts. "The Corti, I mean?"

Chir displayed surprise, and turned his attention to the Corti who had emerged from some other part of the great ship and were proceeding towards their salvage vessel. They were speaking quietly, but the conversation was clearly quite heated. They'd been getting more like that lately, and Chir did not like it - angry slave-masters did not make for happy and free slaves.

"I've heard the word 'Human' being said a few times when they thought I couldn't hear," Zripob confided with him quietly. "The way I hear it, Corti haven't exactly got the best relationship with those monsters. Do you think they've pissed one off?"

"They're not so bad," Chir replied. "There is one on my homeworld who has been adopted by the females as one of their own. An excellent protector, and one not aligned with any of the male clans. She is even well respected by our leaders."

"That doesn't help us if these fools have managed to get ones attention," Zripob said. "Who do you think gets sent to fight it first if it turns up looking to turn Corti into gwalish [cold meat stew]?"

Chir clicked his acceptance of the fact. "Hopefully it won't come to that."

+++++++++++++++++++++++++

"Hopefully it won't come to that," Treoffa said. "I don't think we have enough medicine left to kill him."

"We could eject him into space," Bekmer suggested, "or we could just start stabbing and see where that takes us!"

"He's not unconscious anymore," Treoffa chided. "I think he may object if you try any of that, and then he'll tear your limbs off and beat us all to death with them."

"But he's mutating!" Bekmer replied angrily, glancing about to make sure the slave-soldiers couldn't hear him. He could see two of them, the Gaoian and the Chehnasho staring in their direction. "Let's get into the ship and talk in private!"

He opened the hatch and allowed Treoffa to enter first, then he closed it behind him before continuing. "He's mutating!"

"He's not!" Treoffa replied sharply. "The gut bacteria have continued to flood him with the formula, and it is affecting his body in unforeseen ways."

"You said his organs have grown!" Bekmer said, almost accusing in his tone. "That doesn't normally happen with Cruezzir! I should know, I've used it myself!"

"Scans do indicate growth in the lungs, most likely compensating for the thin air," Treoffa said. "Although that has ceased since his ribs have regrown. Other organs which appear to be responsible for toxin filtration have also grown somewhat, most likely in response to the drugs we've been feeding him. It now takes thirty percent higher doses to achieve the same effect."

"He's bigger!" Bekmer said, flustered for claims to throw at his second-in-command.

"Yes," Treoffa said, "his muscles grew slightly when I exposed them to mild electrical stimulus. I increased the stimulus, with proportional effects, although it seems to have plateaued for now. It took seventy percent of our remaining food supplies to achieve this, and we'll have to get Azhiz to go and get us more before long."

"Seventy percent..." Bekmer repeated, dumbfounded by the number. That was an incredible amount of food, enough to have lasted them until the end of their work here. "And yet you say he hasn't mutated!"

"He has grown," Treoffa said, "but he is now simply a prime version of a human, and probably biologically immortal if my cell scans are accurate."

"This is too much for my judgement, Treoffa," Bekmer said weakly as he flopped down into his command chair. "He's too dangerous to let survive, and we certainly can't send him back to Earth even if the shield fails. Can you imagine a planet full of biologically-immortal super-beings? We couldn't find a decent attack vector with regular humans, how are we supposed to deal with this?"

"Well whatever you do, don't go threatening him with his cerebral detonator," Treoffa warned him.

Bekmer got to his feet at the mention of the device, suddenly rather more pleased with himself. "I nearly forgot about that! Those idiotic researchers put on in his head as well, didn't they? We can just activate that, and-"

"It's been effectively destroyed," Treoffa interrupted. "His immune system recognised it as a foreign object and has ruined it. I can't say that it'd explode even if you reached into his skull and pressed the button yourself."

"Then there is no helping it, Treoffa," Bekmer said with enormous disappointment. "We have to inform the Directorate."

Effectively the biological components, yes. It was mentioned that Treoffa expended most of the food supplies in feeding Adrian. While humans normally eat a lot by comparison, this was truly an absurd amount.

It isn't really super healing, so much as it is superior healing, and some level of regrowth ability that is enabling fast muscle and organ growth. This is basically just the effects of the medicine, after all. It isn't doing anything that the human body is incapable of doing on its own, given the impetus. Larger lungs are natural for those who live at high altitudes for example.

Quod erat demonstrandum pars: IV

By devourerkwi

Dramatis personæ

Lucius Bellator Maximus, a Roman legionary from Legio V Alaudæ, based at the camp Castra Vetera in Xanten, Germania Inferior, serving Emperor Vespasian of the Flavian dynasty

Dieter, a barbarian from the Batavi tribe that was revolting against Rome

Berenice, an Egyptian woman, and her son, Isidorus, from the slums of Alexandria

Yan, a Chinese concubine from the court of and consort to Emperor Ming of Han in the Eastern Han dynasty

Clepta, a corti abductor, scientist, and trader

Glossarium

Legatus: A general in the Roman officer drawn from the senatorial class

Montefortino helmet: A helmet worn by Roman infantry that had a knob on the top and neck and cheek protection

Per aspera ad astra: Through hardships to the stars

Quod erat demonstrandum: Which had to be demonstrated

“There were only six of us,” said the gray thing mournfully, holding up all six fingers on its right hand. It folded in the thumb and two ... pinkies? “And now are there are three. I understand the guards—that’s just pragmatic,” it continued, waving a hand dismissively, “but it was rather impolite to dismember and electrocute my helmsman.”

Lucius had never heard the word “electrocute” before but that was a question best left for later. “How do you know Latin?” he asked.

“He knows Egyptian too,” added Isidorus.

“How do you all know Chinese?” asked Yan. Lucius turned to her, mouth agape. The last time she had spoken she was unintelligible and now she, too, could speak Latin.

“You’ve known Latin this entire time?” he asked angrily, approaching her in a few quick bounds.

“You’ve known Chinese this entire time! You hid it from me like a coward,” she spat. Lucius struck her across the cheek with the back of his hand and she recoiled with the loud smack of bone against skin, falling to the floor and crawling under a glowing table. Lucius moved to drag her out from it but a great pair of hands threw him halfway across the room and he crashed into another table and cracked it in two as if it were paper.

“Lucius!” bellowed Dieter. The commotion had broken his trance and his eyes bulged with rage. “Do not hit the woman!”

Lucius sat up from the rubble and held his throbbing head in his hands, the headfirst blow not softened very well by his montefortino. “You too, barbarian? Well,” he sniffled, “I suppose I can’t call you a barbarian if you speak Latin.”

“It is you who speak German,” said Dieter. “The gray thing speaks German, too.”

The gray thing sighed and walked to the nearest glowing table, tapping on it rhythmically. The room was filled with lilting, high–pitched noises that reminded Lucius of the wind chimes his wife had bought at the market. She had overpaid and he had struck her just as he had struck Yan, bringing cries of fear from their children. She wouldn’t lay with him for weeks after that and his eldest daughter refused her regular tutor, requiring a female teacher because, as she put it, men were too violent for learning.

The chimes ended and the center of the room was filled with a great light that somehow showed images of Lucius, Dieter, Berenice and Isidorus, and Yan in quick succession. The gray thing gestured at them. “I’m not speaking any of your languages, nor are you speaking each other’s. My computer has listened to you speak and has figured out how to translate you. As long as you are near this,” he said, holding up a matte black device shaped like a small ram’s horn, “we will all understand each other.”

Lucius didn’t know what “computer” meant either but, once again, there were more pressing matters. “Who are you?” he asked. “What are you?”

“I am a corti and I hail from the Corti Directorate. Neither are of your world, mind you; actually, you are no longer of your world, for that matter. Just take a look through the windows.”

The party moved to the windows and just as little Isidorus set to jump up to one Lucius realized he had chosen the same window through which he had seen the floating, dead Roman. He caught the boy and brought him to the other side, whispering that the view was better from here. Yan’s panicked whimpering proved that he had done the right thing.

“All I see is black,” said Dieter. “I see black and dots of white. This means nothing!”

“Those ‘dots of white’ are stars,” said the corti.

“Then why do they not wink and play as stars are wont to do?” asked Lucius.

“Because without an atmosphere to—you know what, forget it. You wouldn’t understand.”

“Tell me, corti!” yelled Dieter, advancing step by step. “Tell me, tell me, tell me!” He grabbed the corti by each arm—tentatively and gently, Lucius noted—and hoisted it up in the air, holding it aloft. The corti, somehow, was calm.

“No. You’re too primitive and I literally can’t afford to spend the next two thousand years teaching your feeble minds the basic science the rest of the galaxy figured out when you were still hanging from tree branches.”

Dieter furrowed his brow in confusion and dropped the corti, who fell to the floor with an ungraceful crash and struggled to set upright. Dieter muttered something about it “not being worth it anyway” as he returned to his chosen window.

“Explain it to me,” commanded Lucius.

The corti sighed again and thought for a moment before speaking to them as if they were children. “Usually you would look up at the sky and the stars would twinkle because of the, uh ... ‘air’ ... surrounding you, changing how you see them. Up here, above the ‘air’, that doesn’t happen. We are in a ship moving between the stars, from one planet to another.”

“There are more worlds like ours?” asked Lucius.

“Innumerably many.”

“Good,” he said. “More lands for the Emperor to conquer.” He heard Dieter’s scoff but the corti’s only rebuke was to shake its head, but then its thin lips curled into something resembling a terse grin.

“I think it’s time I introduced myself. My name is Clepta, but,” it said pithily, “you may call me Legatus.”

“You’re not my commander,” said Lucius sharply.

“Oh, but I am. You’re my captives and you must do as I say.”

“You saw what we did to your guards. You are no longer in charge.”

“And then what? You’ll be stranded here with limited food.” Clepta puffed up its chest and strutted purposefully to a window. “This is your ocean,” it said as it gestured to the inky blackness, “and you have no way of navigating. You’ll never get to a port before you starve.”

“You abducted us,” said Yan. “Why should we trust you?”

“Doesn’t matter, we’re the key, he needs us to save himself.” Berenice was suddenly lucid and walked to Clepta, putting her palm against its oversized head. She cackled. “You thought I couldn’t hear you but I could! I was so tricky and you didn’t know.” She receded back to the window and her own internal cataonia.

“What does she mean?” asked Lucius.

“I don’t know,” mused Clepta. “The, uh, process sometimes leaves your kind a bit addled. Look, I’ll cut you a deal. You and Dieter work for me as bodyguards and I won’t vent you and your friends to space.”

“What?” Clepta said so many things Lucius didn’t understand that he was starting to get agitated.

Clepta sighed once more. “Work for me and I won’t kill you the way I killed your countrymen. I assume you remember the caped man floating outside the window?”

Lucius nodded. He didn’t understand how, but clearly the corti had the power to summon the great gales. “We will work for you, at least for now,” he said.

“Good,” said Clepta. “Now go back to your old room.”

The five humans crept back out to the hallway in silence and Clepta closed the door behind them, turning to address the two remaining vzk’tk crewmen. “You guys are such cowards. Clean this up.”

“Yes, Boss,” said one, still struggling to talk. The poor dumb things were so terrified during the encounter that they couldn’t even speak, and Clepta opined that they might have to be replaced at the next port. For now, however, there was business to be done. Entering the captain’s modest quarters, Clepta sat in a hard, cold chair in front of a communications device and opened a secure link.

“I want hazard pay,” said Clepta. “In advance.”

“No,” came the garbled voice on the other end of the line. “Results first.”

“I need money to fund the research, idiot,” snapped Clepta.

“You are corti. Figure it out,” said the voice. The line cut.

Clepta leaned back in thought before tapping a series of commands into the desk, waiting for the confirmation chimes before opening a line to the bridge. “Hey, cowards? When you finish cleaning up Rtkalrrk, set a course for the nearest gray market trading post.”

Salvage02. Food

by Rantarian

This work is an addition to the Jenkinsverse universe created by /u/Hambone3110.

Where relevant, measurements and explanation is given in brackets following their alien names.

Previous Chapters:
Chapter 1: Salvage

Ever since he had woken up, Adrian Saunders had been hungry. The gray alien woman - she had introduced herself as Treoffa and her race as 'Corti' - had provided him with an ample supply of meal tablets that were commonly used for space travellers.
They were bland and offered little in the way of gastronomic satisfaction, but he'd spent enough time in the Middle East eating all sorts of things that made 'bland' seem like a real treat.

After a week of eating several hundred of the things, he would have just about killed for a battered sav or a good pub parma. Maybe with a beer.
"You can't tell me you like these fucking things," he once complained to Treoffa when she brought his first dozen for he morning. "The first couple aren't bad, but you have to admit the rest could use a bit of flavour. Maybe a bit of tomato sauce."

"The rest of us only require a single tablet per meal," Treoffa said disapprovingly. "You are merely a gluttonous species."

Adrian couldn't really argue with that, although he'd never felt like he'd ever simply eating for eatings own sake. If good food had ever defined his life it was in its absence, and aside from too much horse meat while deployed, or too many burnt sausages in his youth, he'd never really had much cause to miss it. Food was just a way to quieten his belly after a long and hard day - he really did miss the tomato sauce, though.

"So how am I, anyway?" he asked Treoffa. "You've kept taking tests, but I'm feeling shitloads better than I ever have. Might be just my imagination, but I reckon I might have put on a bit of muscle as well."

"You have," Treoffa told him. "The medicine has worked better than we had imagined, and your body has been busy optimising itself. Hence the extra muscle, and your brand new rib cage. Normally I would have had to fabricate a replacement, but you managed to create your own."

The things she was saying were good news, Adrian was sure, but her tone was terse and displeased. That was the sort of tone that someone took before they started telling you the bad news, like the good was supposed to mitigate the bad by being said first. Adrian had always been a 'tell me the bad news first' kind of guy; in his opinion it was the only way to stay sane when the good news was bad, and the bad news was truly fucked up. At least then you could end on a note of 'it could have been worse.'

"What are you telling me, Doc?" he asked. "This stuff going to end up giving me cancer?"

Treoffa appeared to consider the possibility for a moment. "No," she said, "it is unlikely. But your body is inuring you to other chemicals, beneficial or otherwise. If you are hurt again we do not have enough painkillers in stock to deaden the sensation. Your caloric requirements have also risen, and we may soon need to ration you heavily so that the rest of us do not starve to death."

"So I get to starve instead?" he asked. He was somewhere between bitter and alarmed - bitter that he may soon be forced to go very hungry, and alarmed that his own eating habits were threatening the crew in general. "Is there something I can do?"

Again, Treoffa appeared to consider his question. "Perhaps, but I will need to run it past Bekmer. I know he was intending to ship in more food, but Azhiz has already been sent to collect more medical supplies. With more crew we might have undertaking a crop growth plan, but with your demanding diet I doubt the standard plans would have supplied us in any case."

"What about my imprisonment in this luxury?" he asked sardonically, gesturing to the sparse medical bay. "Don't mind telling you that if I have to sit around here much longer I'm going to end up going berko."

Treoffa looked puzzled as the translator tried to find a matching translation and then gave up.

"Berserk. Mad. Bloody crazy," Adrian supplied helpfully. He'd already discovered that his typical idioms generally translated bizarrely, and had tried to avoid them when he wanted to make himself understood. It hadn't mattered during his deployment since he usually didn't need to speak the language of wherever he happened to be in bumfuck nowhere, and the density of his Australian slang usually ensured that even if the other folks did happen to speak English they remained completely ignorant as to what he'd just said. That had often been for the best.

A look of worry flashed over her face and she nodded. "I will see what Bekmer says."

"Continue investigating," Bekmer told his two technicians. "I don't like being denied access to anywhere in our new ship, and we need to ensure everything has been catalogued before we sell it. You never know if there's another fortune just laying around somewhere."

Criq and Mrrgha gestured their compliance, ready to go about their business after delivering their report. They were rarely seen outside of mealtimes, and spent most of their time working on hardware while Bekmer worked on software. Normally he would have Treoffa for help on that, and to act as a go-between to ensure everything was working properly, but while she was busy attending the human that was impossible.

"You still need to prioritise repair," Bekmer called after them as Treoffa joined him. "I don't want anything falling back into pieces because you were trying to get through a door."

"Problem with a door?" asked Treoffa as they left.

"Exploratory efforts continue," Bekmer replied, taking to his command seat once again. "Where possible, anyway."

"Perhaps we could get the human to lend assistance?" Treoffa suggested. "He has told me that if he doesn't get work he intends to wilfully turn psychotic."

Bekmer blinked. "Can they do that?!" he asked, then shook his head in a surprisingly human gesture. "Of course they can! They can do anything! They're the new super-beings, aren't they?! That would certainly explain why they keep killing whole crews of researchers."

"Bitterness does not become you, Bekmer," Treoffa chided. "It is unprofessional - our son will not return, and this human was not responsible. Have the Directorate made a determination yet?"

"They are still conferring," Bekmer said, his bitterness clearly unmitigated. "You can imagine the stir that this has made. Some are calling for extermination while others are calling for further experimentation. All of them want to know where we are."

"And have you told them?" Treoffa asked.

"Of course not," Bekmer replied sharply. "If they send an inspection team before this salvage operation is complete, we may lose all rights over it! You say the human wants to help? Register his physiology with the weaponry and assign him a weapon. The planet below us is rich with fauna and quite frankly he'll be one of the most dangerous things on it. He can hunt for his food."

"That is considerably barbaric," Treoffa said. "I suppose it fits. Who will you have take him down there? Unlike Earth, it has not been subjected to development. It's all jungles, forests and fields."

Bekmer paused. He did not want to go, and he didn't want to send any of his crew down to a Deathworld. "Send the Gaoian," he finally said. "I don't like the look of him, and if they both die I'll sleep better."

+++++++++++++++++++

Chir piloted the landing capsule with care, trying to aim for a relatively flat piece of land that was unlikely to immediately destroy them. Beside him sat the human they'd all been surprised to discover was a fellow member of their soldiering group, although Chir hadn't yet had much to say to him. Their initial introductions had started with the human asking him 'if he was some kind of raccoon', and it hadn't exactly improved. At least the human hadn't decided to pick a fight with him - unlike 'Shoo' who resided on his homeworld, this one did look dangerous.

Right now the human was busy peering down at the world below, quietly singing something about 'building a city on rock and roll' - conscientious advice on proper foundations put into song, perhaps? - and not paying too much attention to Chir. Being ignored by the human was something that made Chir feel something between annoyance and relief.

"So you eat meat, yeah?" the human finally said. He was still looking out of the viewing window, but unless he was talking to himself - and Chir wouldn't have been all that surprised - he was talking to Chir.

"I do, yes," Chir confirmed. He wasn't sure where the human was going with this. "I also eat vegetation. I am an omnivore, if that translates?"

The human barked something that Chir guessed was a laugh. "Yeah, mate. That translates. Treoffa says you don't eat much, though. I guess that's why you all do a decent impression of stick figures."

"Is that... an insult?" Chir asked, genuinely confused. It certainly hadn't sounded very flattering, but the human had said it in a tone that seemed good-natured.

The human grinned at him, baring his teeth in a way that Chir had been educated to perceive as friendly rather than incredibly hostile. "Nah, mate. Just talking shit."

Chir wasn't completely up to speed on human physiology, but he was fairly certain that they did not eject fecal matter from their mouths. "I do not think your kind excretes from its mouth," he said dubiously.

The human looked at him a moment before breaking out into more laughter. "Mate," he said, catching a breath. "You've obviously never had to deal with some of our glorious leaders."

Chir motioned that he understood, even though he wasn't anywhere near sure that he actually did. "I take it that you were not one of these glorious leaders?"

The human shook his head. "Not me, mate. I just go where they tell me and fuck shit up. Speaking of which, what the hell does this thing fire? I don't see any ammunition..."

"Ammunition?" Chir asked, looking at the kinetic gun that had been shaped to fit the human's physical configuration. "It runs on energy, this is the primary weapon distributed to soldiers under any government. It fires a powerful blast of kinetic force."

The human looked at the weapon he was holding. "No shit?"

"No shit," Chir repeated, starting to get the feel for the human's way of talking. The bigger versions can really 'fuck shit up'."

"I think I was shot by one before," the human said. "It was fuckloads bigger though. Hurt like hell."

"Your kind is unusually resilient to such weaponry," Chir said. "I have heard news of a human who is the terror of the battlefield. There were stories of this human battling several Vulza at once!"

"What the fuck's a Vulza?" the human asked.

Chir described the great winged lizards with some poetic license. He'd never actually seen one in person - he had been that lucky in life at least - but he'd seen video feeds and static images of the beasts.

"So some kind of space dragon?" the human asked. "You're pulling my fucking leg!"

"I haven't touched you!" Chir replied sharply, before realising that this was yet another of the human's turns of phrase. "I am being truthful!"

The human's face took on a look of contemplative enthusiasm. "Are there any of these things down there?"

Chir shook with shock. "I should hope not! These weapons will be of no use against a Vulza! You might as well resort to bare-handed combat for all these will do you."

"Right," said the human, going quiet. It seemed to Chir that he had come to some kind of decision.

Adrian had come to a decision. These guns sucked and he needed something better. Just about anything would do, and he thought that if he had a bit of time with a lathe and one or two of these weapons he could come up with something really special. He had been an saboteur and, by necessity, an engineer during his time in the Defense Force and now that he was getting a feel for the technology he was seeing a lot of disappointing shortcomings. Shortcomings that made him as giddy as a schoolboy to solve.

He also wanted to kill one of these dragons. He was fairly sure he could engineer a weapon to shoot a spear at extremely high velocities. He might even be able to make a semi-automatic version, given time. Maybe with high-explosive armor piercing heads.

He giggled. The possibilities seemed endless.

He was getting ahead of himself, however. The raccoon-guy, 'Chir', was his pilot to the surface of the world below, but he had been instructed to stay with the landing ship as much as possible, and to return if any danger threatened it. It was up to Adrian to get his own food for the next two weeks, and Treoffa had gone so far as to give him some kind of alien Esky that, from what he could understand, stored food without needing to freeze it by stopping time when the lid was closed. Good enough for food, he supposed, but rubbish at getting your beers nice and cold.

The landing ship made an almost imperceptible touch-down in what Adrian would have described as an idyllic meadow. Perfect picnic weather in a flat field amidst rolling hills of blue-tinged grass, broken only by the occasional stand of purple-leaved trees. A crystalline blue lake would have added greatly to the effect, but the best it had to offer was a winding, half-full river with muddy shores.

"We need to be careful out there," Chir said, plainly worried.

Adrian looked out of the view window and back at Chir. "Are you fucking kidding me?"

Chir shook his head, having quickly learned to perform the gesture.

"Right then," Adrian said, duly warned. He waited for the door to open and they stepped out into the deathworld. "Time to go gun down some delightful bunny rabbits."

Salvage03. Hunting

By Rantarian

Chir followed the human into the alien grasslands. The winds blew with powerful gusts that sent wave–like ripples through the bluish grass that covered the local terrain and nearly knocked Chir off his feet. The human, for his part, seemed entirely unaffected by the inclemency.

“Bit windy,” the human remarked. “Nice to feel the sun for a change, though. Guess it’s a different one, but same difference, hey?”

“Same difference,” Chir repeated, aware that the phrase made absolutely no sense but he was beginning to detect that as a trend with this human. He fingered the trigger of his kinetic gun warily as his feet left the short ramp and stepped onto the land of the deathworld. A chill of fear ran up his body; this was the most dangerous thing he’d ever done.

He looked around him, hardly willing to go any further. He could feel the beat of his heart, his senses grown more alert with fear, and it almost seemed to deafen him. The human was carefree, ignorant and possibly fatally stupid, and it was up to Chir to make sure that Chir survived if nothing else.

In the blue–purple sky he could see distant shadows weaving through the low clouds. Birds of some kind, but moving so fast! There were thirty of them, maybe, flying in perfect formation in the even more powerful air currents above. It was amazing that they could survive them, but this was a Deathworld and what could you expect?

“We should go down to the river,” the human suggested. “Animals usually gather there, and if nothing else there might be some fish. Those trees might have some birds, and maybe they have fruit or nuts, too.”

“Sound advice,” Chir agreed. He was glad that the human at least seemed to know what he was doing when it came to hunting and gathering. He noticed that now that they were on task the human seemed a lot more focused, intensely surveying his surroundings for any sign of... anything. “Perhaps one of us should stand guard by the shore?”

“If I feel the need to get wet I’ll know who to have at my back,” the human replied. “I’ve watched enough movies to know that jumping into water on an alien planet is just asking for trouble, though.”

“I was not aware your people had made contact prior to the recent incident!” Chir said in surprise.

“We hadn’t,” the human admitted, “but we do like our stories. My old man had a whole collection of these black–and–white movies, real old things. Most of them total crap, mind you. The Monster from the Black Lagoon, Forbidden Planet, the whole Lost in Space series. Ironic that I never liked them much.”

“And they were about dangerous waterways on other planets?” Chir asked. It seemed an oddly specific thing to write so much about, especially given that the human had just admitted that the human species had not even made contact until just recently.

“No, that was just the occasional thing you’d see... other times it would be mutant monsters, invading aliens, or rampaging robots. Crap like that”

“I see,” Chir said, hoping to sound like he did. He was familiar with theatrical productions, of course, but the concept of using it to portray imaginary monsters from space was beyond him. Gaoian theatre tended to focus on moral lessons, as did drama in most cultures. Some few used it for comedic value, and he knew the Chehnasho were unique in dramatising their historical records with so much poetic license that it became pure fancy. The idea of stories with so much horror and violence was simply alien to him, as indeed the human was.

“Wait here,” the human said as they reached the muddy flat that ran down into the river. There was debris laying here and there, muddy logs and driftwood resting on the riverbank, only partially submerged. The river itself was brown with mud, far from refreshing and likely containing contaminants that would kill a whole clan of Gaoians.

“What are you doing?” Chir asked, as the human took aim at one of the logs. “That–”

The human fired with deadly accuracy, and the log snarled with life. Chir recoiled from the vicious reptilian creature that hissed and growled as the human shot it again with equally unimpressive results. It had looked like a log! Exactly like a decaying log, and yet it had all been a disguise. The reality had been a savage beast laying in wait for the next meal to present itself, and the human had seen straight through it!

“What the fuck is wrong with this piece of shit?!” the human yelled as he shot the beast a third time. “Is yours working or did baldy give me a lemon?”

Chir shot the creature as well, with about as much effect. The creature was clearly predatory, and increasingly pissed off. Others of its kind were also starting to move, albeit lethargically.

“It seems to be in perfect working order,” he told the human, his voice wavering. “Perhaps a retreat is in order?”

“This thing is about as useful as shit on a stick,” the human declared, and hurled the gun at the creature with all of his might. The gun struck the monster in the head with a loud crack, toppling it with the force of the blow.

Chir and the human both stood in shock as the dazed creature writhed on the ground, struggling to get to its feet.

“You’ve got to be fucking joking,” the human said, staring at the open palm of the hand he had thrown the weapon with.

“Your gun is gone,” Chir reminded him. “We can always get another, but there are another... four of them! They’re converging on us!”

“Mate,” the human said, looking up with the most predatory grin Chir had ever seen on a sentient being. “Have you ever heard of the Crocodile Hunter?”

Adrian ran towards the next of the monsters, feeling more alive than he’d done in years. Adrenaline surged through his body and he could feel everything. But this wasn’t an adrenaline surge borne of fear – oh no – this was borne of the ecstasy of the fight.

The monsters were reptilian creatures with long legs, some way between dogs and crocodiles, but heavily favouring the latter. He’d considered calling them ’dogodiles’, but decided that that was fucking stupid and ’Wolfigators’ was much better.

The Wolfigator he’d approached leapt at him with a sudden ferocity and speed their normal movement belied. Adrian was no stranger to ambush predators, however – how many months had he spent training in the outback? – and old infighter reflexes took over. He dodged to the side and delivered a slamming blow to the side of its head.

The Wolfigator went down in a sprawling mess, and Adrian could have sworn he’d felt the skull fracture under his blow, but it was still getting up again. They were tougher than he’d thought, but not quite as tough as he’d hoped. He leapt onto its back, wrapping his newly–muscle–bound arms around its neck, his legs around its legs, and squeezed.

“Die you motherfucker!” the human screamed at the troubled alien monster. He slammed its head down onto the ground repeatedly as its body spasmed in an attempt to get free.

Chir watched on in horrified excitement. The monsters had all been attracted to the current threat, the human, and he was putting on quite the show. When he’d determined that strangulation wasn’t going to do the job, he’d simply resumed punching it in the head until it stopped moving, and then rolling off the corpse before the remaining three could lunge at him.

“Punching them takes too much effort,” he shouted, presumably to Chir. “I need something a bit harder. Find me a good sized rock while I keep them distracted.”

Chir looked around, glad at finally having something to do. He was, after all, an armed Gaoian warrior, and it was shameful for him to sit by and allow an unarmed man to do all the fighting. The human seemed to have gained some humility now, since he’d restrained himself to just punching the ones that made a lunge at him.

Finally Chir found one! It was a good sized rock, although Chir doubted it would be much use against creatures from a Deathworld. But as the human was also from a Deathworld, maybe he could make it work! He threw it to the human with all his might. “Catch!”

Adrian caught the large pebble by reflex, and found the ridiculous uselessness of it so ludicrous that for a moment he forgot what he was doing and almost earned a mouthful of sharp teeth for the privilege.

“What the fuck is this supposed to be, fuck knuckle?!” he shouted. “I asked you for a rock!”

“That’s the biggest one that could find!” Chir protested.

“What about all those fucking things sticking out of the mud?” Adrian demanded. He could clearly see a dozen fist–sized rocks jutting out of the mud, up near where the grass grew and where Chir was standing, all there for the taking.

“Those are far too heavy to lift!” Chir replied, as if the very concept of pulling them out was entirely absurd.

“Give me strength!” Adrian snarled as he punched the next Wofligator in the side of the head. This time he grabbed its upper jaw and put his boot into the lower. With a moment of effort there was a sick, wet rending sound and the lower jaw was torn away revealing bone and gore. The Wolfigator shuddered in his arms and fell still.

Adrian picked up the jawbone.

Chir could not believe what he had just seen. The human had ripped apart the monster’s skull and killed it in one horrific move. It had been far more violent than anything he had done so far, even the punching, and he felt sick from having watched it.

But only two of the monsters now remained, and they seemed to have at least the awareness to try to encircle their prey. If they decided to strike at the same time, Chir wondered if the human would get out unscathed.

The rock, the largest that Chir had been able to lift, had been derided by the human as being so inadequate that he had merely tossed it aside. The human was now reduced to using the jaw as a primitive weapon, swinging it so as to ward the monsters off. He was backing off, though... the human seemed like he was in trouble!

If nothing else I can distract one, Chir thought. It might give the human a chance to get away, or to gain better ground.

He took aim at the nearest of the monsters, and then fired.

A kinetic blast hit the Wolfigator to his left in the head, stunning it long enough for Adrian to belt it in the other side of its head with its old friend’s jawbone. The jawbone broke when it struck the skull, but the skull itself exploded in gore.

He leapt the corpse before it could fall, putting it between himself and the other Wolfigator, and giving him time to come up with another plan.

Right now he knew three things. First, his hands hurt like hell from all the punching he was doing, and he suspected he’d got at least some hairline fractures in his bones; second, he had no weapons other than his aching hands; and third, there was probably only this one Wolfigator left to hunt on this particular river bank.

Unlike a crocodile, it was not a completely unintelligent beast. It had clearly been trying to work with the others in some sort of pack, and that meant some form of intellect no matter how rudimentary. It also meant that there was something bigger out there that they’d have to work together to take down. Adrian wondered what that was, and if it would taste any good. He reckoned Wolfigator at least would taste kind of like Croc.

His eyes fell on a pair of rocks – proper rocks – nearby. One stone, the other a mud–smeared piece of quartz. “Hey, Chir,” he shouted, “think you could distract this bastard for me?”

Chir responded by taking aim and pulling the trigger on his kinetic gun repeatedly, knocking the beast around a greatly infuriating it in the process. It looked as though the weapon hurt the creature, at least somewhat, but that the most it could cause would be severe bruising. That didn’t matter, though, because a proper weapon would soon be in hand.

Chir watched the human move while keeping the monster under sustained fire. He tried to hit it in such a way that would deter it from following the human, who was clearly trying to escape at this point, but all it seemed to be doing was enraging the creature into greater savagery. He hoped the human would make it to the grass in time, and that together they could escape this bloody nightmare and flee back to their shared enslavement.

Stars above, he thought to himself, did I really just think of enslavement as the better option?

After the seventh shot, the monster was no longer responding to the kinetic blasts, having achieved the point of total rage, and was now chasing after the human who had a mercifully good head start.

Chir’s sigh of relief was cut short as the human fell to the ground, heaving an enormous rock from the ground and bringing it down against another. It shattered on impact, and the human cried out in equal parts jubilation and pain.

“What are you doing?!” Chir cried out. “Run for it you psychopath!”

The human just looked at him, caked with mud and blood and gore, with the same predatory grin from before. In his hand was a sharp and clean white stone with a wicked edge.

“Take this motherfucker!” Adrian cried as he drove the makeshift axe–blade into the Wolfigator’s neck. The flesh there tore apart like tissue paper under the keen edge, and blood gouted out in a brief torrent as the important arteries were slashed open.

Blood was everywhere, and the blade was slick with it in his hand as he brought it down again, jamming it in behind the creature’s neck where its spine was supposed to go. It stopped moving after that, and Adrian allowed himself to sit back and rest as the adrenaline drained from his body.

He looked over to Chir. “Now that,” he said, “was a rock.”

Chir sat quietly in the ship as the human – Adrian, as he preferred to be called – carried in packaged meat and stowed them in the food preservers. He had taken his time about it, cutting off the thick skin with the declared intention of turning it into clothing.

Chir growled to himself. Wearing the flesh of animals? The human was a true savage.
And yet, Chir was forced to consider, that same savagery had been enough to annihilate five extremely dangerous predators with marginal help from the Gaoian warrior who should have been at the forefront of any battle. Chir burned with shame at that fact, and he almost resented the human for making him feel that way.

“Remind me to get a metal spear made for my next trip down here,” Adrian said to him as he stowed the last of the meat that would fit in the preservers. The skins he had lain out tidily on the floor next to them, and it had taken Chir all his willpower to avoid retching at the stink and sight of them.

“You intend to come down again?” Chir asked, incredulous that anyone might want to repeat this experience. “Why would you possibly need to do that? You’ve got enough meat here for... I don’t even know how long!”

“Maybe two weeks,” Adrian replied. “We eat more than you, remember?”

Chir stared at the preservers. He had heard of ’Shoo’s’ extreme dietary requirements, but next to this colossal quantity of food she seemed entirely reserved.

“I haven’t been able to fit it all in, though,” Adrian continued. “There’s a fair bit I couldn’t get together for it, I think two entire legs, and then some.”

“A pity that your bloodbath will not have all the results you desired,” Chir replied sarcastically. Then he sniffed the air – something was burning!

“I smell fire!” he said sharply. “If there’s a grassfire here, we’re likely to be caught in the conflagration if we do not depart immediately.”

“Easy there, big fella!” Adrian said, starting to smile again. “Since you eat meat, I figured I might put together a little something we have on Earth.”

“You’re cooking?” Chir asked, surprised more than anything that the savage would actually cook its meat. He knew from the reports that ’Shoo’ would eat many meats entirely raw, and she was far from the savage that this human represented.

“Yeah, mate,” Adrian continued. “We call it ’barbecue’.”

Salvage04. Turning Point

by Rantarian

This work is an addition to the Jenkinsverse universe created by /u/Hambone3110.

Where relevant, measurements and explanation is given in brackets following their alien names.

Previous Chapters:
Chapter 1: Salvage
Chapter 2: Food
Chapter 3: Hunting

The first chance that Trycrur had to see the human, he and Chir were returning from the surface of the Deathworld. She had been asleep at the time of the mission, and had awoken in horrible shock to Zripob shaking her awake and telling her the bad news - that a human had been on the ship all along and that Chir was being made to take him down to the surface of the planet.

It had only been natural for the three slaves to have bonded in their shared captivity, and Trycrur was already thinking the worst of the human before the landing craft had even set down on the flight deck. She had ground her teeth together in agitation as the door opened, had hissed in relief as Chir was the first to disembark, and then inhaled so sharply she entered a coughing fit as the human emerged, covered in dried mud and blood. He had clearly made some attempt to clean himself up, as the mess had been washed from his face at least, but his clothing was effectively destroyed.

"Chir!" she said, moving over to him quickly, giving the human a wide berth as she did so. "It is good to see you're alright! Zripob told me you took the human down to the Deathworld! What happened?!"

Chir stared at her a moment with a blank, haunted expression. "We... had barbecue."

The human joined them at the mention of the word - his ears must have been incredibly sharp - and bared his teeth at her. "G'day."

Trycrur recoiled so abruptly that even Chir was prompted to follow suit, before looking at the confused expression on the human's face - his teeth still bared but somewhat more uncertainly - and sighing. "This is a human, Trycrur. And that is what they look like when they smile. It is supposedly a friendly gesture."

"Most of the time, anyway," Adrian qualified. "Trycrur, is it? Reckon Trixy suits you better, what do you think, Chir?"

"I think that it would be terrible to call anyone that," Chir replied directly, and Trycrur marvelled that he could be so blunt with a creature that looked like it'd just rolled around in a lake of blood.

"Well, what do her friends call her then?" Adrian asked.

"Trycrur," replied Trycrur.

"Fuck them, then," Adrian replied cheerfully, although Trycrur couldn't understand why he felt himself entitled to suggest she copulate with anyone.

"Excuse me?" she asked, offended at his forwardness.

"It's a thing he says," Chir said wearily. "It doesn't actually mean what it means..."

"Exactly," Adrian agreed, and Trycrur felt even less informed than she had been a moment ago.

"Trix, then," Adrian continued. "As a compromise."

That didn't seem like much of a compromise, but Chir seemed as defeated as he was deflated, and he didn't give any further protest to the sudden renaming of Trycrur. She couldn't help but feel a little bit betrayed.

"Hey Chir, where should I put the Eskies?" Adrian asked as Chir started to walk towards the internal doors that led out of the flight deck. "Is there anything that I can use to move all of them at once?"

Chir looked to Trycrur. "Trix... I mean Trycrur, please get Adrian a hover platform to help him move all of the preservation containers. I am well past my sleep cycle."

"Yeah mate," Adrian said, "I was going to say you looked totally bushed. Go get some shut-eye while Trix helps me get everything sorted out."

Chir paused, no doubt waiting for his translator to make a best-effort - Trycrur's own translator was trying several possible translations, all relating to forests or shrubs - before giving up and heading to where they'd made their quarters.

Adrian turned to her as Chir strode purposefully away, once again baring his teeth in what seemed so unlikely as a to be a friendly gesture. "Well then," he said, so good humoured that Trycrur wondered if he was somehow unaware of what he was covered in, "looks like I'm in your hands."

"Food supplies for the human have been secured, and nobody ended up dying down there - with the exception of several of the local animals," Bekmer informed Treoffa. "Normally I would like to know why it has stretched their skins out on frames in the far section of the flight deck, but I doubt I'd like the answer."

"He's already visited me in the medical bay, and told me all about it," Treoffa replied. As usual Bekmer thought he was more informed than he actually was, and it secretly pleased Treoffa to disabuse him of this notion. "He intends to turn them into clothing."

"Wearing the skins of other creatures?" Bekmer asked, genuine disgust in his voice. "It is exactly as savage as I had thought, Treoffa! Did you ask it what was wrong with his polymeric clothing?"

"I did, and it seems he prefers what he calls 'leather' because it looks 'hardy' and has unlikely thermal reductive properties," Treoffa told him. The exact words had been 'tough' and 'heaps cool', but Treoffa saw no reason to make Bekmer fight his own way through the near-unintelligible jargon. Relieving Bekmer of that responsibility was simply part of her job as far as she was concerned.

Bekmer sighed. "I admit to have given up trying to figure out what the human means. It baffles me, but I am beginning to suspect that this is simply because I have credited it with more intelligence than it is actually due."

"What of our food, then?" Treoffa asked. "Azhiz is overdue on his medical supply run, is he not?"

"He is," Bekmer confirmed. He looked troubled, and actually disturbed. Not over the possibility that something had happened to Azhiz - neither of them cared one whit whether the Robalin was alive or dead - but the loss of any supplies, and the micro-freighter, would have far reaching consequences for the Salvage crew. Without that vessel, the only way to obtain more supplies would be to take the main ship. That would mean either leaving the Zhadersil unattended or attended with a minimal crew and no power - the salvage ship was currently the Zhadersil's life support until its own power could be properly restored, and there was no telling when that may be.

"By how long now?" Treoffa pushed. She knew the answer, but she knew that Bekmer needed to play out the conversation if he was going to do what she wanted.

"Far too long," Bekmer replied. "We need to act as though the micro-freighter, and Azhiz, are lost. He may have defected - he is Robalin after all - or he may have met with some... misfortune. Either way, we need to consider the worst case scenario."

"That our location and the details of our work have been revealed to others," Treoffa said. It wasn't a question, and it wasn't a guess, but she had left something unsaid. If it had been pirates that had caught Azhiz, they'd be coming here to kill them all and claim the Zhadersil as a prize. If it had been the Hunters... well, the prospects were similarly terminal but with bonus torture and culinary elements.

"We can't yet move the Zhadersil," Bekmer told her, "but I have Mrrgha and Criq working on its reactor as we speak. Even a small amount of power would be enough to get us out of the system, or at least into a debris field that cannot easily be scanned. We can augment the FTL drive from our own ship if necessary."

"At least if we are boarded, we have a particularly psychotic human to resolve the issue," Treoffa said, offering some comfort to Bekmer.

Bekmer frowned in dismay. "On that note I have somewhat unfortunate news. It seems that the Directorate want us to send him - alive - to their studies division as soon as possible. The penalties for lack of compliance..."

He trailed off, but Treoffa had some inkling of what would await a Corti who defied direct orders from the Directorate. Not death, but isolation and irrelevance. If Bekmer ignored this order, he would discard any chance of future reward or acclaim. A win for Treoffa, who would take over the leadership of the Salvage team, but she wanted to take that from Bekmer fairly, not because some bureaucrats thought they knew better.

"Then we had better hope that the technicians get us a functional reactor."

+++++++++++++++++++

"What in the murk are you two making?" Zripob demanded of Trycrur and Adrian. He had gone in search of Trycrur out of concern when he had not found her asleep in their quarters, and had found them working together in what appeared to be a machining workshop.

"Hey there, Kermit," Adrian said, waving a gloved hand. He was wearing a poorly cut vest made of reptilian skin, the only garment he had actually managed to fashion from the disgusting materials. The rest had been wasted in failed attempts, and even this - abhorrent as it was - was completely rubbish from even the standpoint of simple workmanship.

"Once again," Zripob grated, "that is not my name. Now answer my question!"

Trycrur looked up from her console, her face lit with something that Zripob could only describe as fiendish delight. "We found a fabrication unit. Adrian had some ideas, and when I mentioned that I'd worked in developing weapons for the Dominion..."

She shared a glance with Adrian. "Well, I'm helping him put some ideas into practice."

"What kind of ideas?" Zripob asked, now curious. He had been aware that Trycrur was a weapons developer, but the idea of a Deathworlder coming up with weapons intrigued him. He was not unaware of the tactics being developed by certain division in the Dominion-Celzi conflict.

Adrian produced a kinetic rifle, heavily modified and with a long cylinder connected to the kinetic aperture. A strange attachment was connected to the cylinder with a mechanism presumably intended to be used to operate it. "This," he said, "is the prototype."

"It's like a coilgun!" Trycrur said excitedly. "Except not! We made the kinetic aperture smaller to concentrate the force, and that lets it fire a projectile! Using the force that would normally go into recoil, we've created an automated mechanism to load the next projectile into the... chamber?"

Zripob blinked. Most of that had gone right by him, which wasn't surprising since he was just an infantryman at heart, but it was clear that Trycrur was looking to the human for advice and ideas. He wondered what the human was getting out of this partnership.

"I don't see how it could be any more useful than the regular kinetic weapons," he said dubiously. "Worse, if you think about it, since your ammunition is a lot more limited."

"Nice to have an audience for the test run, then," Adrian said. He put a hand on the mechanism and drew it back - Zripob could see that it was intended to slide back and forth - and made an audible ker-chank as something physical moved inside of it, and for some reason the sound made Zripob's blood run even colder than it already did.

"We made a combat harness as well," Trycrur said, pointing out a dummy wearing the armour. "That was Adrian's idea as well."

Zripob frowned, not liking what he was seeing here much. He took a step back as the human raised the weapon and looked down the long cylinder - after all, a prototype might explode - and went still as the trigger was pulled.

A loud thunk terminated in a deafening crack as the projectile punched through the armour, passed through the dummy, and put major cracks in the rear plate. The sound echoed down the abandoned hallways of the ancient ship, and with the exception of the human they were stunned and silent. The human put down the weapon and went and investigated the armour with apparent disappointment.

"Would it be easier," he asked, turning back to Trycrur, "to give the gun more power, or to make the rounds explode?"

Trycrur absorbed this information for a moment, then wilfully broke into the most predatory grin she could manage as a herbivore. "Why not both?"

"You should be working on the reactor," Mrrgha admonished her husband as she came upon him fiddling at the door. "The door is not important. You heard what Bekmer said!"

Criq clicked in irritation. "We don't know it isn't important, Mrrgha! We don't know what is on the other side! What if it's the command room? What if there's a giant 'on' button for everything?"

"What if Hunters come and eat us because you were too busy trying to get into a janitorial cupboard?" Mrrgha asked testily. She had put off her sleep cycle for some time to continue working on the reactor, and did not enjoy finding her husband shirking his duties to indulge himself in idle fancy.

"I think I almost have it, though," Criq replied. "I've got the right algorithm this time, I'm sure of it! These systems are extremely hardened, so it's unsurprising that we've had so much trouble."

"How long will it take?" Mrrgha asked, irritated but resigned to the attempt being carried out.

"Not long," Criq answered, "but long enough to show my wife how much I adore her."

Mrrgha snorted - Criq had always been laughably incapable at romance, but his inept attempts were persistent and that made him charming. "I'll be the judge of that."

+++++++++++++++++++

"He was asking me about all sorts of things," Chir told Bekmer. The Corti leader had taken a sudden and inordinate interest in what the human had been doing whilst not on duty, and what his conversations with the other slave-soldiers had been. "Mainly about how the ships worked. He wanted to know how they moved, 'where the rockets were', and how the flight deck maintained atmosphere when one side is exposed to space."

"What about weapons?" Bekmer demanded. "Did he take an interest in those?"

"He said ours were as dangerous as a wet kiss," Chir replied with a frown. "Although I'm not sure how dangerous he rates those."

"That would explain what he's been doing with the Rauwyrhr female," Bekmer mused. "We've detected power anomalies in a fabrication chamber, and it appears to have been used recently to fabricate new types of weaponry."

Chir was surprised - Adrian hadn't told him anything about that, and nor had Trix... Trycrur for that matter! Further on that, he'd never have imagined that those two would have found anything in common, one was a genius after all, and the other was a savage Deathworlder who'd beaten a monster to death with a piece of another monster. Not exactly Scientific Award winning material. "I was not aware," he said, his curiosity piqued. "Do you know what they've made?"

"They have not seen fit to inform me yet!" Bekmer snapped. "A problem I wish you to remedy for me! And once that problem is resolved, please inform our resident human that we have need to place him into stasis once again."

"Stasis again?" Chir asked. This meeting had been filled with surprises - the meeting itself had been a considerable surprise - and of all things he'd never expected Bekmer to be putting the human into a box again. Of them all, he was the only one who didn't seem to mind working for the Corti - claimed he owed them his life in fact! Chir wasn't sure whether that made him a friend or an enemy, but as he didn't fancy having the human as an enemy he hoped it was the former.

"We need to send him on a short trip," Bekmer said. "Let him know that he won't need to pack anything."

+++++++++++++++++++

The door opened, interrupting the married couple's frenzied neck-wrangling. They panted as they regained their composure, returning as quickly as they could to their professional duties.

"You did it!" Mrrgha breathed. "I hardly believe it!"

"My lovely wife needs to put more faith in her husband's cleverness," Criq replied teasingly. "Now, let's see what's in-"

They were interrupted by the whir of machinery and the clank of pneumatics. A blue line of pulsing light flashed over them, and they recoiled as one from its intensity. They could feel it burn slightly here it touched on their skin, and they shielded their eyes to prevent themselves from being blinded by it.

"No match found," spoke a cold mechanical voice from the darkness. "Purging alien material."

Red irises lit in the darkness, joined by the glowing energy of an unknown weapon. Red-orange light reflected off of polished chrome, revealing reptilian features with sharp, pointed teeth. Criq threw himself in front of his wife in a desperate act to protect her from whatever it was, but his feeble attempt was the very essence of ineffectiveness. An arc of white-hot light punched straight through him and and Mrrgha both, scorching the wall behind the with a black circle where the metal burned.

The light had burned straight through both of them, but it was not mortal and they both screamed in agony and terror. Neither could move and at least one of them had lost control of their bowels, but any concerns of impropriety were far beyond them now.

Mrrgha watched a second pulse destroy her husband's head, silencing him forever. The remains of his face were ash collapsing around a hole that somehow seemed to turn to face her as the corpse spasmed. She gibbered in fear and horror until the third pulse came for her.

+++++++++++++++++++

"There you are," Chir said as he entered the quarters the four soldiers had been assigned for sleeping - even if Adrian spent more of his nights in the medical bay being monitored by Treoffa for... Chir realised he didn't really know what.

"Here I am," Adrian said, stowing a long something that had a very weapon-esque appearance to it. "What's up, mate?"

"I've just had a chat with Bekmer," Chir said seriously.

Adrian snorted humourlessly. "And what did our bald friend have to say for himself?"

"About that," Chir continued, "he wanted us to have a chat of our own. I think some things are about to change."

Salvage05. Dead Mans Switch

By Rantarian

“What kind of ’little trip’?” Adrian asked suspiciously. There wasn’t any reason for the little bald dictator to get Chir to put questions to him, or to let him know about travel plans. Not unless you considered that Adrian had some kind of friendly relationship with Chir that he didn’t share with Bekmer, and that this was expected to provide some kind of leverage over him. It was almost like the Corti knew about friendship and trust without understanding how they actually work.

“He didn’t say,” Chir answered, “but I’d be hesitant to trust anything he says.”

Adrian nodded tersely, although he was glad that Chir shared his mistrust of the unpleasant little alien; ever since coming amongst aliens he’d never been entirely certain that he was picking up on things that were actually there. “Mate, back on Earth there’s a saying about something looking and smelling like bullshit.”

“Oh?” Chir asked. “What’s the saying?”

Adrian faltered at that, normally people knew the implications of something looking and smelling like bullshit. “It means it’s bullshit. All lies, total crap.”

“That is a terrible saying,” Chir said with some disappointment. “What do you intend to do?”

“I’ll ask Treoffa what’s going on,” Adrian decided. “She’s usually a bit more up front about what’s actually going on.”

“She is as duplicitous as Bekmer,” Chir stated in annoyance. “If not more–so! You should take it as a rule to never trust a Corti!”

“Well she did keep me alive,” Adrian reminded him. “That counts in her favour.”

Chir shook his head vigorously, trying to mimic the human movement of emphatic denial and succeeding brilliantly. “No, that’s just more ’bullshit’. You’re a human! You’re the most dangerous thing on two legs, and they wanted you to help defend this ship. The rest of us they had to enslave, but–”

“Wait, come again?” Adrian interrupted. “Enslaved?!”

There was a heavy pause as Chir hesitated, clearly shocked. “Nobody told you? We’ve all got cerebral detonators – bombs – in our heads! One wrong move and blam! It’s all over!”

Hot anger rose in Adrian’s gut, he could feel it bringing on the edge of his temper and clouding his judgement. He liked Chir well enough, and he didn’t like Bekmer at all, but he hated slavery, and right now the image of pounding the little grey alien’s head into mush was all too tempting. “How long has this been going on?” he asked, nearly growling the question. “How long has that little motherfucker had his claws in you?”

“We were abducted to be brought here as slave–soldiers not long before you emerged from the medical bay,” Chir explained. “We were told our situation, and that we’d be released if we behaved ourselves and did our work.”

“And you trusted him?” Adrian asked with some surprise.

“Not at all,” Chir scoffed, “but so long as there’s a chance...”

“So long as there’s a chance, you won’t fight back,” Adrian finished for him, understanding completely. Hope could really fuck a man over when it was used against him, and it looked like the Corti was clever enough to know that much. “How about I go over and rip his fucking arms off, then slap him to death with them?”

“Maybe that would work,” Chir said, “if the entire Salvage crew didn’t have access to the kill switch. Do you think that you can contain them all before they blow our brains out? Are you so sure that you also don’t have a detonator they simply neglected to tell you about? If you attack Bekmer he’ll either threaten to kill you with a detonator, or the rest of us.”

“You’re saying he’ll use your lives to protect his own from me,” Adrian said, his body tense with restrained anger. “It makes sense for a bastard like him.”

“And as a result,” Chir continued, “we are, as you might say, ’proper fucked.’”

Adrian pondered the matter for a brief moment, then broke into his predatory grin. “Not necessarily. Go get the others, I’ve got a plan.”

“No,” Treoffa snapped, “I’ve already told you four times, Bekmer! I haven’t seen them! I will let you know if they contact me at all, but if you really want to talk to them why don’t you talk the walk down to the reactor room and check in on them yourself?!”

She disconnected the call in anger, then forced herself to return to calm professionalism. Lately there had been too little of that, and although much of it could be blamed on the human as a catalyst, Treoffa considered the rest of it to be solely the result of Bekmer’s poor decision making.

Wherever the two technicians were hiding, she thought, they’d better be working on the reactor. Nothing would save them from her fury if they’d spent this time slacking off when Hunters could be closing on their location for all they knew.

“Could this day get any worse?!” she said to herself, and then jumped in her seat as she was startled by the opening door.

It was just the Rauwryhr female. Treoffa relaxed; after Bekmer’s most recent rant she didn’t think she had the mental strength left to deal with the human, but the Rauwryhr were a straightforward species. Not especially bright for the most part, but acceptably logical in spite of their attachment to emotion and empathy.

“Can I help you?” Treoffa asked as the slave–soldier stepped into the room. The girl had a kinetic gun, but it was slung at her side and she seemed nervous rather than aggressive. “Is something the matter?”

“There are two things I really need to know,” the Rauwyrhr female said, coming closer. “Two things that could be very important to both of us...”

Treoffa frowned. “What are you talking about? If this is some kind of trick, do not forget my power over you!”

“Ah,” said the Rauwyrhr, flinching back. “I had not forgotten! In fact that is part of why I came to see you. The human has found out about our cerebral detonators... he wasn’t pleased, and is on his way to see Bekmer!”

“What?!” Treoffa exclaimed. “Why didn’t you say something sooner!?”

“Bekmer will undoubtedly threaten him with our deaths... unless you’ve got one in the human’s head as well, of course, but I don’t want to die and I thought maybe you could help!” the Rauwyrhr rambled. “Maybe I can help you! I’m a friendly voice, after all! I could calm him down!”

“Y–yes,” Treoffa said, still shaken from the revelation. “That’s an excellent suggestion! If you can manage it, I’ll be certain to put in a good word for you with Bekmer!”

The Rauwyrhr female’s attitude shifted immediately from defeat into anticipation. “By that I take it that he doesn’t have a cerebral detonator as well.”

“What?” Treoffa asked, off–balance at the sudden shift in behaviour. “No, he– How dare you?!”

“My second question, Treoffa,” the Rauwyrhr said confidently, taking an unmarked canister from her pocket with her thumb held down on the mechanism on top. “Have you ever heard of a ’Dead Man’s Switch’?”

This was a terrible plan, Trycrur thought to herself as she held the entirely inert canister in front of her as though it might do something. Adrian had said that normally people would use explosives for this purpose, but for today that role would be served by something that just happened to look the part, so long as Trycrur could manage the required deception.

Zripob and Chir had been sent down to the reactor to take care of the two technicians, Adrian had gone after Bekmer personally, and Trycrur had been tasked with deceiving the female Corti.

This was a terrible plan, but it seemed to be working.

Treoffa was eyeing the canister warily. She hadn’t moved. It seemed like she did know what a Dead Man’s Switch was, and suspected the worst, just like Adrian had said she would.

“Looks like you have some idea what this is,” Trycrur continued, reciting the lines she had been given with a bit of her own improvisation thrown in. “We built it out of parts from a kinetic gun, so that it will fire a single, powerful, kinetic pulse in all directions if the mechanism is released. The force will turn us both into a fine paste on the walls.”

“You would threaten to kill us both?” Treoffa asked, apparently trying to force some scepticism into her voice and failing miserably. She hadn’t once taken her eyes off the canister, and her fear was palpable. “It’s Trycrur, isn’t it? Surely we can work something out?”

“Whether I kill us both depends on whether you try killing us first,” Trycrur replied. “You could start killing the others, but then you’d still be stuck in here with me and an armed kinetic grenade. Not ideal for you, especially when you have to consider whether Bekmer has the same interest in preserving your life that you do.”

“I assume you are going somewhere with this?” Treoffa asked peevishly, dropping the pretence of professionalism at last. “You can’t just be here to stand around threatening me?”

Trycrur had to give her credit for skipping ahead to the better offer, it made this flow a little more easily for her. “I’m glad you asked. You and I will be taking a short walk out to the Salvage ship where we and the rest of your crew are going to have an interesting talk.”

“You think you can walk in here and threaten me?” Bekmer hissed, seething at the sheer audaciousness with which the human had kicked in his door and presented him with the ultimatum.

“Yeah,” Adrian replied coolly, nodding towards the deadly device in his hand. “I do. Let’s not forget that this grenade will smear you across your office, but the worst it will give me is a bloody nose.”

Bekmer practically shook with rage. He couldn’t remember the last time he’d been so angry, or the last time he’d been so completely outsmarted. The threat of explosive death had been intended to be used with the slave–soldiers alone; he couldn’t have imagined that they would have turned the threat of it so neatly on its head without the human’s help. Once again a human was ruining Bekmer’s life, and he was forced to admit that with this he had come to thoroughly despise them as a species.

“I’m going to tell you what’s going to happen now,” Adrian continued, entirely in calm control of the situation. “We’re going to go to your ship, and there’s going to be a group discussion.”

“Oh?” sneered Bekmer. “Just what will we be discussing there? Freedom perhaps? Revenge? Do you intend to torture me?”

“I considered torturing you,” Adrian told him with such bluntness that Bekmer didn’t doubt it. “The others talked me out of it, so you already owe them that much. Turns out they’d much rather freedom over revenge. But this is the conversation we need to be having as a group, get moving!”

Chir and Zripob were running, not having wasted any particular time to inspect the charred corpses of the Rrrrtktktkp’ch once the pulsing blue searing light had swept across them, and a mechanical voice had said “No match found”. Both of them were smart enough to know a messed up situation when they found themselves in one, and they’d proceeded to extricate themselves out of it just as a hot pulse of concentrated energy blasted into the metal of the walls.

“What was that?!” Zripob croaked as they rounded the first corner into cover. He was breathing heavily from sudden exertion.

“How should I know?!” Chir asked, his own breathing less heavy thanks to a body more suited to a flat run. “That thing would have killed us, though. I’m willing bet it was what turned those Rrrrtktktkp’ch into barbecue.”

“Into what?” Zripob asked, and Chir realised that again this was probably something that he alone had discovered from a human.

“It’s a human thing,” Chir answered weakly. “It’s where you cook meat until it is charred.”

“Sounds wasteful,” Zripob replied disdainfully. “With their dietary demands you wouldn’t think they’d want to waste anything.”

Rapid metal clanking in the hallway behind them brought them back to the situation at hand. It seemed the thing that had killed the technicians, the thing that had tried to kill them, was in pursuit.

“Perhaps now is not the time for such discussions,” Zripob judged.

Trycrur and Treoffa had arrived first in the small meeting room, followed soon after by Adrian and Bekmer, and Trycrur could see that, like her, Adrian still had the fake grenade held out to look dangerous.

The room itself was small and functional, with little besides a table and six padded chairs. Every surface was clean, gleaming metal, and the walls were covered in metal tiles whose logical arrangement made you think ’science’. It was to its very core a Corti meeting room.

“All of the important people are here, then,” Adrian said in obviously fake cheer once the two Corti had been seated. “We may as well get started.”

“What about the others?” Trycrur asked. “Shouldn’t we wait for them?”

“These are the guys in charge, Trix,” Adrian replied. “It doesn’t matter what giraffe guys think once we’ve convinced these this fuckstick and his second–in–command.”

“We can hear you, you know,” Bekmer interjected. “And we know what your demands are.”

“Freedom, yes?” Treoffa guessed. “I can remove the–”

“If we give them that they’ll just kill us,” Bekmer interrupted, turning his hard gaze towards Adrian, and Trycrur had to admit that the Corti was brave to do so. She doubted she’d have been able to so much as meet Adrian’s gaze had she been in his position. “Isn’t that right, human?”

“Maybe,” Adrian replied. “We could do that, but these people just want to go back to their lives. They’re willing to forget about the whole fucking thing if they can live through this little school trip you’ve got going on here.”

“And what about you?” Bekmer asked. “Will you forget?”

“Oh, you know me, baldy,” Adrian said with a grin, “I’m like a fucking elephant.”

“You know we have no idea what that is!” Bekmer accused. “You are taking advantage of our ignorance!”

“That’s right, baldy,” Adrian said, leering over the small, grey alien who was still trying to look in charge. “I’m taking advantage of your ignorance, much helped by the fact that you’re dumber than a box of rocks. But if you just want to fuck around, maybe your second–in–command would enjoy a field promotion!?”

Bekmer hesitated as he glanced towards Treoffa, whom he found looking directly at the table in front of her. Trycrur could see he looked desperate, and he wasn’t getting any support from his second–in–command when he needed it most. The situation was completely abnormal, so far beyond anything they or Trycrur had any experience with that unless you knew what you were doing there didn’t seem to be any way out. Trycrur remained confident because Adrian was confident, although he was probably confident because he was most likely insane.

“If you guarantee our safety,” Bekmer said levelly, but with black hatred in his expression, “I will have Treoffa remove the detonators, and we will release you all at the earliest possible opportunity.”

Trycrur suppressed her excitement, forcing herself to remain cool and detached – a completely professional detachment intended to give off the air of dangerousness. Adrian had said that she’d be the cool voice of reason to his violent psychopath, which she had to admit was a lot easier than the other way around.

“That sounds satisfactory, Adrian,” she said. “It will need to be done immediately, of course. We can’t trust them to leave our sight before then.”

“You heard the lady,” Adrian said. “Treoffa will need to remove the detonators as soon as your technicians join us.”

The hissing sound of the pneumatics working the door alerted them all to the new arrivals, and Trycrur and Adrian turned expectantly as Chir and Zripob fought to burst through the door at the same time. Both of them were heaving great gulps of air as they leaned on the walls for support.

“What happened?” Trycrur asked immediately, wincing as she broke character.

“Hah!” Bekmer said. “It seems that everything did not go as you had planned, human!”

“The technicians...” gasped Chir. “Dead.”

“What the fuck did you do?” Adrian asked. “They weren’t the sort of guys who put up a fucking fight.”

“We did not kill them,” Zripob grunted. “They were dead when we found them... we barely escaped the same awful fate.”

“They were barbecued!” Chir declared. “By a robotic killing machine!”

There was a tense silence that hung over the room, and Trycrur realised that everyone, even the Corti, were looking at Adrian.

“You have got,” he said, “to be fucking kidding me.”

Salvage06. Robotic Death Machine

by Rantarian

This work is an addition to the Jenkinsverse universe created by /u/Hambone3110.

Where relevant, measurements and explanation is given in brackets following their alien names.

Previous Chapters:
Chapter 1: Salvage
Chapter 2: Food
Chapter 3: Hunting
Chapter 4: Turning Point
Chapter 5: Dead Man's Switch

"Right then," Adrian said, having taken a moment to gather his thoughts after the most recent of events turned his plan into shit. "Trix, you stay here and treat these two like they're the enemy. I don't want them using the distraction to fuck us over."

Trycrur nodded, making sure the two Corti could both see the canister in her hand. "Don't worry, I'll make sure they don't go anywhere."

Adrian nodded. "Good. Chir and Kermit are with me. I need to go and get the prototype, do you think you two can hold it off?"

"No," grumbled Zripob, "but we'll manage it somehow if you're quick. I haven't survived a dozen boardings to go down fighting a glorified maintenance drone."

"Use this ship's hull for cover if you have to," Adrian told him. "The flight deck is a fucking nightmare for infantry shit, so don't go running out into the open."

"Anything else?" asked Chir.

Adrian pause for a moment. "Anything else you can tell me about it?" he asked.

"Not much," Chir said, "just that it fired a hot, intense beam that seems as hot as plasma."

"It scanned us too," Zripob volunteered. "Then it said 'no match found', but we were already withdrawing."

"What the fuck does that mean?" Adrian asked, then shrugged. "Doesn't matter I guess. We'll have to deal with it either way. Everyone knows what they're doing?"

Everyone, including the Corti, nodded mutely.

"Right then, let's get this show on the fucking road."

+++++++

"This is insane," muttered Zripob as they peeked out over the barrier they'd put in place. It was really just a small cargo container that had been out on the deck. A hover lifter had been conveniently on hand for pushing it into a position of greater tactical use, and now they both cowered behind it to the sound of heavy mechanical footsteps growing ever closer.

"Unknown spacecraft configuration," the machine said, "marked for destruction."

"Can it do that?" Chir asked, concerned.

"How should I know?!" Zripob demanded. "Let's see what we've got to fight it with."

"Two kinetic guns, and two fake grenades," Chir replied immediately.

Zripob frowned. "We're going to die, aren't we?

++++++++++

Adrian raced down the corridors towards the soldier's quarters. He'd never had cause to move this fast aboard the Zhadersil before, and he discovered that the reduced gravity made it much harder than it had to be. At walking pace he could compensate for the bounciness of movement, but running made that impossible and he found himself kicking forward off of the walls as often as the floor.

"How are they so short with such low gravity?" he grated. "Fuckers need to eat their wheatbix."

The soldiers quarters were not the closest rooms to the flight deck, those were reserved for the workshops and the workrooms of the Salvage crew. They'd all preferred having the Soldiers quartered some distance away, apparently feeling that this made them safer rather than the reverse. If time wasn't of the essence, or if he thought he could beat an alien death robot with his bare fists, he might have sent Chir or Zripob to get the weapon for him - if they could lift it - but death robots might be a stretch for even a human.

"Finally," he said with a grunt as he flew into the quarters and kicked his leg out against the opposing wall to stop himself.

He opened the door to his storage unit with so much force that he tore it off its hinges, and he tossed the broken pieces aside with disgust he reached in and took out both parts of the prototype.

Large holes had been punched through the container, and pools of steaming polymer were hardening on the floor as they filled the air with a gag-inducing stench.

"It's still advancing," Chir said needlessly. "At least it hasn't managed to hit us yet."

"Our weapons do about as much to it as they do to the human!" Zripob complained. "We're 'up shit creek' as the human has said. How do you suggest we keep this thing distracted?"

"Maybe you could run out there waving your arms about to distract it," Chir suggested.

"Are you serious?!" Zripob asked, completely aghast.

"Of course I'm not serious!" Chir hissed. "I have no doubt that if Adrian does not get back soon that we're going to die."

"Then if I'm going to die, I'm at least going to try to get a good look at this thing!" Zripob replied. "I won't have it said that Zripob died cowering like a Pondling."

"I'll look too!" Chir decided. "From the other side. Maybe it will have to think about who to shoot and give us both enough time to live through it."

"Right then," said Zripob. "On three."

"One," said Chir.

"Two," said Zripob.

"Three!" they said together, and rounded opposite sides of the container with weapons firing. They each got enough time to get a good look at it before fleeing back into cover.

"I see we both survived," Chir said, although he could have been happier about the situation.

"I've never seen anything like that," Zripob said, shaken. "I think it was mostly steel... and I think its eyes were glowing."

"It was made to look like something dangerous," mused Chir. After his experience with the reptiles on the planet the mere appearance of such things seemed less unnerving. "A reptilian predator of some kind. Long neck, like a Rrrrtktktkp'ch, but I could see its teeth even from here."

"Sharp, but I doubt it needs them for eating," Zripob replied. "Bipedal, but with a tail. Maybe for balance? Could be a weak point."

"Now if only we had the means to exploit it," Chir said grimly. "But I guess that's what we keep a human here for."

+++++++++

Adrian glanced at the charge bar on the weapon he'd affectionately named the 'speartosser' and grimaced. Not even half charged, with six full power packs feeding it from a backpack he and Trixy had cobbled together from leftover Wolfigator leather.

He'd been surprised to discover that the kinetic guns simply pushed their regular power production into the shot, rather than storing it in a capacitor for a more powerful discharge, and when he'd suggested it she'd taken the concept and run with it. As a result the lone weapon that had all the lethality of a wet fart had become a powerful kinetic cannon capable of punching explosive spearheads through half an inch of steel, and hitting with the power of an angry horse when no rounds were loaded.

But it needed time to charge when it had been turned off for a while, and right now he'd have just about given his left nut for the charge bar to fill, because from the distance he was covering he'd be well and truly back onto the flight deck before that happened.

"Come on you little bastard," he grunted as he kicked open the door to the flight deck to reveal a situation growing from bad to worse for his squad mates. There was a lot of distance to cover, and not much time before the metal man finally reached them. Hot raybeams shot through the increasingly porous container, often missing the two of them by a whisker. From the looks of it Chir and Kermit were shitting their collective pants, but when they saw him they gave a relieved wave.

"Lasers is it?" Adrian said to himself. "That's not a good sign."

The metal man was approaching them, its laser firing three times before what seemed to be a ten second cool-off period. If it had lasers, at least it had shit lasers. He leapt atop a hover lifter and kicked the floor repeatedly, gathering speed as he pushed the hover lifter beyond all safe speeds towards the robot. The charger bar was almost full, and with the hover lifter moving with inertia he knelt down on the platform and took careful aim.

Then the robot turned towards him and he was hit by a bright blue pulsing light.

Chir had watched in incredulity alongside Zripob as Adrian had sped across the flight deck on a hover platform with the inertial brakes turned off. He was wearing some sort of harness with a cable attached to the long weapon in his hands, and seemed to be taking careful aim with the intent to end the battle in a single shot.

Then the scan beam had hit him, and Adrian had shouted 'What the actual fuck?' before shouting an obscenity about something called a 'dinosaur' and another thing called a 'terminator'. Chir thought that both of these things sounded pretty dangerous, and if the robot was both of these things rolled into one it was worse for all of them.

"The human is unnerved," Zripob noted, likewise worried.

Chir didn't respond; he was intently focused on what Adrian was doing. Watching as the human jumped from the hover lifter's platform as the robot powered up its laser. Listening as the robot announced that genetic matches were detected. Staring as the robot did not immediately fire.

Chir blinked. "What did it just say?"

"It said genetic matches were detected..." repeated Zripob, and both of them stared at Adrian.

++++++

Adrian watched the hover lifter slam uselessly into the dinosaur terminator. Dinonator? Termisaur? He'd figure out a decent name for it later, but it bore a freakish resemblance to the velociraptors of Jurassic Park, although rendered in chrome. It hadn't shot at him yet, so that was a good sign, but right now it seemed to be struggling with some kind of mystery of its own.

"Percent chance native lifeform: 89%. Mammalian suborder." it said.

Adrian looked at the charging bar on his gun. Almost...

"Possible explanations: 46% Bio-engineered fauna..."

He kept looking. Almost......

"... 33% Evolved pet..."

He took careful aim. Almost...

"... 18% Livestock..."

"Fucking livestock?!" he spat angrily, and pulled the trigger as the charge bar finally completed.

++++++

A blast like rolling thunder echoed through the flight deck as the robot's metal head wrapped around an explosion before blowing apart in pieces of shrapnel. Another clang sounded from a distant wall as a shower of metal fragments hit it. Chir covered his ears until the painful experience was over, and even then a high-pitched ringing still remained.

"3% Other, Motherfucker!" Adrian shouted, walking over to the metal husk that still whirred and tried to figure out how to move. He had the cylinder that formed most of the length of the gun resting over one shoulder, and must have been even more rocked by the explosion than Chir because he swaggered as he walked.

Zripob, seeing that the danger had passed, or had at least reached a point of tolerable dangerousness, indicated to Chir to follow him over to join Adrian at the robot. What they found when they reached there was an unimpressed looking human examining a long power cable, radiating an expression that conveyed disgusted contempt.

"Am I seriously looking at a fucking extension lead?" he asked, looking up at Chir and Zripob. "I was really hoping to use that gun, but if it needs a power point then that's just fucking woeful, don't you reckon?"

"It looks like the power actually goes into the robot," Chir said. "Then it feeds into the gun."

Adrian sighed, looking down with shoulders sagging. "That's really just the most disappointing thing I've heard all day, Chir. Can't even begin to tell you..."

"What did it mean by native life form?" Zripob asked. "When it scanned the rest of us it said no match found."

"I couldn't really tell you," Adrian said with a shrug. "Did look a lot like a dinosaur, though."

"Perhaps I may suggest an explanation," said Bekmer, and they whirled to see him now standing behind them. He was holding a Kinetic gun on Trycrur with one hand, and the fake grenade with the other. "And then perhaps we could re-evaluate our earlier agreement? No need to disagree, as Treoffa has the ship's weapons trained on all of you."

Salvage07. Incompetence In Command

by Rantarian

This work is an addition to the Jenkinsverse universe created by /u/Hambone3110.

Where relevant, measurements and explanation is given in brackets following their alien names.

Previous Chapters:
Chapter 1: Salvage
Chapter 2: Food
Chapter 3: Hunting
Chapter 4: Turning Point
Chapter 5: Dead Man's Switch
Chapter 6: Robotic Death Machine

65 Million Years Ago

The Zhadersil drifted in high orbit above the outpost world of Affrag, its engines inert and few remaining hands standing by as the emergency meeting was convened in the war room adjoining the command deck.

Shiplord Xagh waited for the last of his senior officers to seat themselves before him. Their faces were all sombre, these meetings were only for critical situations and they knew what was coming would not be good news.

"My fellow V'Straki," he said, greeting them as fellow beings rather than subordinates - a fact that was not lost on them - "I have received some truly devastating news."

He paused, letting them prepare themselves, although the tension in the air was palpable. "Five teyrak [five days] ago, our beautiful homeworld was directly targeted by the Igraen Alliance in a successful attack of a scale we have never before witnessed. The planet we called home is no longer habitable, and all those we loved are gone."

There were shocked murmurings around the table, disbelief that the Igraen Alliance could be so bold, or so competent. The V'Straki had found the galaxy a surprisingly easy target, given their flimsiness compared to other creatures on their homeworld, and each V'Straki warrior was worth a hundred or more of any Igraen species.

"Shiplord," Varr called out from his seat, the seat reserved for the second-in-command. "How is this even possible? The last reports I saw showed the Igraen military in tatters and their worlds in ruin."

"A simple act of desperation, Varr," Xagh replied. "A cloaked asteroid of significant size. It was not detected until the debris field it carried with it was already crashing through the orbital defense network. It is clear that they hoped this action to cripple the Empire, and I am sorry to say they were correct."

The officers were aghast. The homeworld effectively destroyed - and with it almost all of the females the V'Strak Empire had - was a devastating blow, but the orbital defenses had included manufacturing yards, colonial stations, and more. With that all gone, V'Strak Empire had lost its core world and more than 90% of the population.

"The Zhadersil is one of the few warships not currently engaged in battle," Xagh continued, "and you all know that this was because we were awaiting a refit. Our crew are few, our weapons outdated and our complement of Exterminator Drones is down to just one unit with a dead battery."

"We should still strike back," hissed Varr. "We cannot allow this to go unpunished."

"The Zhadersil is not prepared for combat duty," Xagh spat back. "If we were to direct it into battle, it would be overwhelmed by Igraen drones. We would die, and the ship would become theirs. I will not allow this to transpire!"

Varr looked like he was about to say something, but a glare from Xagh and he remained silent. They were all under immense stress, and the only way they would get through it would be to stick to the warriors code.

"We have lost contact with several major colonies more recently," Xagh continued. "No inspection has yet been made on those systems, but the Igraen are not particularly cunning, and it is likely that they have repeated their plan on the colonies they are aware of."

"What about Affrag, Shiplord?" asked Tachot, the senior medical officer to the Zhadersil and Xagh's good friend. "Are they likely to strike here?"

"Affrag is a new colony and would not be known to them yet," Xagh replied. "They are under instructions to disable all communications and other detectable systems until further notice is given."

"What is the plan for us, Shiplord?" Varr asked.

Xagh sighed. "It cannot be helped that we cannot enter the battle, but our forces are deploying fission-drones against all known enemy strongholds. It is against the Galactic Charter, yes, but they broke it first, and this is now a matter of our survival. Do not doubt that the enemy has embarked upon a campaign of total genocide."

Two cadra (two months) had passed, and the Zhadersil had not moved from its orbit above Affrag. The colony was still running silent - as was the Zhadersil - and nerves were frayed. Xagh had had an argument with Varr in full view of all the crew, and had then been forced to dispense final justice to subdue any further resistance to his continued command.

"Five ships, three colonies," Dorn reported in their first private meeting with him as second-in-command. "That's is how many V'Strak holdings remain, including the Zhadersil and Affrag."

"Then our enemy came very close to victory," Xagh said. He felt sick, with those numbers there may be too few for the V'Strak race to recover; very few females had been allowed to leave the homeworld, and as a result almost all of their eggs had been in that one basket.

"Our enemy is dead," Dorn stated. "There have been no further encounters since the fission drones were deployed and their remaining fleet was annihilated."

"I cannot believe they are all gone," Xagh said. "I doubt we have been quite so thorough. What is the report on the homeworld?"

"Dust chokes its atmosphere," Dorn reported, "scientific projections show that the climate has been irrevocably altered, and the temperature has dropped sharply. It is unlikely that it will ever be habitable again."

"Then the war is over and now we must attempt to rebuild," Xagh decided. He had been considering the next course of action for some time, and had finally come to the only conclusion available. "We're going to have to abandon the Zhadersil."

Dorn stared at him. "Shiplord?!"

"There are no more refit stations, Dorn," Xagh told him. "This ship is a relic, in dire need of repairs that we cannot give it, and we no longer have an Empire to serve."

"That is treason..." Dorn said in horror.

"It is truth," Xagh replied fiercely. You said it yourself: five ships, three colonies. How many females in those colonies, Dorn? Have you read that? I have, and that's why I know that our greater duty is to our species."

Dorn frowned, and looked through the details on his datapad. Then he frowned more. "That's not..."

"I know," Xagh said. "Affrag has five, and that's as many as at Colvu and Grikt combined. The other ships are full of males, Dorn, but they are far from Affrag and are likely to converge on the other two colonies."

"You're suggesting we become colonists?" Dorn asked dubiously. "I am no farmer."

"Then be a hunter," Xagh said. "Be whatever you want, but you will be amongst fifty males vying for the attentions of five females, rather than three hundred males vying for the attentions of two or three!"

Dorn was silent, thoughtful. He nodded after some time. "As you say, Shiplord, it seems to be the wisest option available to us."

"Good," Xagh said, pleased while also regretting the necessary abandonment of his ship. "We will announce it to the crew together, and then we will begin to strip the vessel of anything that may be useful in our new home."

+++++++++++++

Present Day

Trycrur was still, not wanting to give the Corti a reason to shoot her. He was smart - he'd already talked her into giving away the fact that the bombs were fakes, and she no longer doubted that he could foresee any action she might take. She couldn't even look at Adrian, she was so ashamed of her ineptitude and cowardliness. She had obeyed the Corti's orders once the truth had come out and although she felt completely guilty over this she didn't want to die. Now she just waited for the others to give themselves up to whatever the Corti had in mind, and hope they felt merciful.

"Yeah, nah," said Adrian, and Trycrur finally looked at him in shock.

"Good," said Bekmer smugly, clearly pleased with his own deviousness. "Now, if you will just-"

"That means no," Chir interrupted. "A positive followed by a negative is a negative. The reverse is also true."

Bekmer paused, confused. "Is that true?"

Adrian lowered the barrel of his gun to point it at Bekmer. "Nah, yeah."

"I told you-" Bekmer began.

"I told you that you were dumber than a box of rocks," Adrian said. "Mate."

"You will comply or die," Bekmer seethed. "The cerebral detonators-"

"Fuck you," Adrian said again, interrupting. "If you could kill us all that way, you wouldn't need Treoffa to point the ship's guns at us. Maybe you will kill these guys, but will Treoffa be fast enough to save you from me?"

Bekmer was silent, and even his light grey skin seemed a little paler than it had a moment ago.

Adrian had bared his teeth into a grin again, but Trycrur saw no friendliness there now. She'd learned that the nature of a human grin could be read in their eyes, and all she saw there now was the black savagery of a Deathworlder.

"You're going to do exactly what I fucking tell you, you bald little shit," Adrian told the Corti vehemently. "That is your way out of this. If you fight me, I will fucking kill you. If you use your little detonator, I will kill you as slowly and agonisingly as possible."

Adrian leaned in towards the quickly wilting Corti. "DO YOU FUCKING UNDERSTAND ME YOU ARSEHOLE?!" he screamed with so much fury that the little alien actually fell over backwards in terror. Trycrur nearly fled as well, such was the force of the violent intent surrounding the human.

"A fucking 'yes' will do," Adrian spat at the fallen Corti.

"Y-yes," Bekmer whispered.

"Good," Adrian grunted, still staring down the Corti leader. "Treoffa, do you hear me?"

"I can," her voice rang out from the ship. It was as shaky as Trycrur felt.

"The deal is still on the table," he said. "If you're interested in taking charge of this arsehole and getting these detonators out, we'll help you out until we can get home."

Everyone waited, and the silence seemed to go on forever. The cold knot of terror tightened in Trycrur's belly as she tried to guess what would happen next.

"Bekmer," Treoffa's voice rang out again. "Your detonator code has been disabled. In accordance with the charter relating to Incompetence in Command I am replacing you as commander of the Salvage team and am placing you in confinement in the Zhadersil's brig."

I did not, as the V'Strak are so distantly removed from the current galaxy that their existence is all but forgotten and almost no details are known about the time. Hell, 65 million years is such a long time that even the nuclear option being deployed against their enemies would likely no longer be detectable, and it is so long that the habitability ratings of many worlds would have changed.

Right now the Zhadersil is the only significant relic ever found, and there is no reason to assume that the V'Strak have survived, since if they had they'd probably be a big player in the galaxy by now, and the Deathworld below would be highly industrialised.

In summary, it is an element that can be used or ignored by the other authors. A piece of history from the Galaxy's unenlightened past, and possibly the reason that so many modern species have arisen in a similar time frame.

Salvage08. Check

By Rantarian

“And what we have here,” said Adrian, “is sweet, sweet justice.”

He slid the knight into position, knocking over the opposing Queen. “Check!”

“Excellent move,” Treoffa said as she moved her remaining castle across the board. “I believe this is ’Checkmate’, however?”

Adrian stared at the bored and frowned. “Shit. You’re good.”

Treoffa nodded her head in gracious victory. “I am considered to be a genius even amongst Corti, and you are providing me a significant challenge despite not being all that intelligent by your own species standards.”

“Fuck off!” Adrian said with a laugh. It had been, by his judgement, about two weeks since Bekmer had been relegated to the brig and the others had had their cerebral detonators removed. Treoffa had taken over the salvage mission, but her pace was slow considering that she was doing all of the work on her own. But, as she had admitted, now there was only one share of the reward, and it was all hers.

“Have you spoken with Bekmer,” Treoffa asked him, although he knew she knew he hadn’t. “Asked him about his theory about the V’Strak?”

“You know that I’ve been avoiding him,” Adrian replied. “Not seeing him helps me resist the urge to kill him.”

“I appreciate that,” Treoffa replied. “And your team is surprisingly compliant without the threat of death hanging over their head.”

“They’re happy to have their freedom,” Adrian said. “I know they want off this ship, but they also know where we are and don’t want to risk it. Unclaimed space, yeah?”

“Yes,” Treoffa replied, resetting the board for another game. She had learned it surprisingly quickly, and had become eager for more matches, although she tried to hide such desire. “It may be full of Hunters, or pirates, or both. We are closest to the Celzi borders, so I wouldn’t doubt there are at least some refugees fleeing the war altogether in the hope of finding somewhere uncontested.”

“Trycrur has been busy inspecting the reactors,” Adrian said. “With Kermit and Chir for protection, in case more Robosaurs come visiting. She says they should be functional.”

“The actual hardware is not the issue,” Treoffa replied. “Or at least that is what my technicians also told me. The issue was that we still have no access to the command deck, and the operation of the Zhadersil requires some biometric access that we obviously lack.”

“So the steering wheel lock is on, and you’re trying to jimmy it off,” Adrian interpreted.

“A woefully inadequate analogy,” Treoffa replied, “but essentially yes.”

Adrian frowned. “What can I do to help?”

“I doubt you’re technically proficient enough with our technology to bypass even our systems, let alone those of a long extinct civilisation,” Treoffa said, “but on that note, shall I relate Bekmer’s theory in his pleasant absence?”

Adrian nodded his permission. “Go ahead.”

“Bekmer believes, and I support him in this, that the V’Strak were Deathworlders like you,” she said. “You only need to see how the rugged, uncomfortable design of everything is similar to what is endured by you humans.”

“That’s pretty thin,” Adrian replied.

“There’s more of course,” Treoffa continued. “The date of the end of the V’Strak Empire appears to match a major extinction event on your own planet and several others. I believe that this indicates an aggressive genocide of the V’Straki race across several worlds, although it wasn’t until I looked into date comparisons for well–documented death worlds that I began to see the pattern.”

“Somebody killed the Dino–guys with asteroids?” Adrian asked. “Couldn’t have that just been a natural event? I’ve seen Discovery channel enough to know that there’s lots of big fucking rocks out there.”

“I have found eight of them all occurring at the same point in time,” Treoffa said. “The data is clear, this race was murdered.”

“That begs the question, then,” Adrian said after a moment. “Why?”

“It is difficult to say,” Treoffa replied. “Death worlds are not usually well documented, it is enough to know to avoid them, but if we consider the political impact that you humans have had on the Galaxy–”

“What impact is that?” Adrian interrupted. “We’re not even able to get out into the galaxy with our shitty little tin cans.”

Treoffa paused, and to Adrian it was clear that she was considering her words carefully. “I am going to tell you something,” she said deliberately, “and I would very much like it if you wouldn’t kill anyone afterwards.”

“I’m surprised you’re not...” Chir trailed off, waving his hand vaguely.

“Going on a murderous rampage,” Adrian asked. He looked thoughtful. “I am pissed off, I suppose. It’s not fair that they’ve made this decision for us, that they’ve sealed humanity into a little bubble to try and keep them from getting out.”

Chir grunted his agreement, although he seemed far from convinced. “You’re a dangerous species, you only need look in a mirror to see that, Adrian. It is not surprising that they would fear you.”

“It would have been smarter to kill us,” Adrian replied, much to Chir’s surprise. “Because once that bubble pops, the human race will be out and they will be totally pissed off.”

“They say it will last for millions of your years,” Chir told him, repeating what he’d heard on the news.

“Do you really believe that?” Adrian asked dubiously.

Chir frowned. “No, but that is what they say. I may be wrong, Adrian, but you do not seem all that bothered by being unable to return.”

“Yeah,” said Adrian, “well... some shit happened right before I was abducted. Let’s just say that I wouldn’t have much to look forward to by going back there.”

“I won’t pry further,” Chir told him, “but I cannot wait to get back to my homeworld.”

“Wife and kids?” Adrian asked him.

Chir snorted his amusement. “We do not have such family arrangements. Before my time out amongst the stars I would have thought any such thing absurd, but Zripob’s people spawn anonymously and the females raise their children as a group, while Trycrur’s are like your own with formalised relationships. One female may have as many as ten males serving her.”

“Not entirely like my own, then,” Adrian said.

“No,” Chir agreed, “but nobody is like a human.”

Treoffa was entirely pleased with herself. Not only had she assumed command of the salvage mission, and not only had she ended up in a position where the entire reward would go to her, but she would also be able to blame the lack of response to the Directorate’s orders on Bekmer.

Bekmer would need to die for the plan to be complete, of course, but he had sealed his fate there when he had gone up against a human with only his wits and had come off second best. Bekmer was a fool, and soon he would be a convenient scapegoat.

“I cannot believe I allowed him to intermingle his genes with my own,” she said to herself as she considered all of the years she had played good subordinate. Years she had once thought wasted that had now borne unexpected fruit. Life could be strange sometimes.

Now Adrian’s genes had provided a potential way to access systems previously locked out. His genetic markers were substantially different to the ones belonging to the V’Strak, but they were a close approximation to their pets and livestock. The system was a broad template meant to cover everything from military vessels to freighters, and as a result there was plenty of exploitable code to provide for the animals they must have transported.

It had allowed her access to only the least secure systems, but any access was better than no access, and it was the biggest single step they’d made in gaining control since getting here. She had access to the official ship logs, now, and although they were themselves intrinsically valuable from an archaeological point of view, she hoped they’d provide even more value in uncovering further systems access.

Soon she would be in full control, soon she would be rich, and soon she would be rid of the troublesome slave–soldiers. If she could somehow convince Adrian to get into a stasis pod, well... that would make her success all the sweeter.

Ten long shadows moved smoothly against the black of space, invisible to anything save each other, making their careful approach to the ancient ship in high orbit around a Deathworld; exactly where the Robalin had said it would be before he had died. It looked like a piece of space debris, but now they knew better, and they had come knowing their enemy.

They had brought ten ships to seize a prize, and one thousand soldiers to fight a single human. The flight deck was open to their landing, protected only by the thin kinetic shield intended to hold the atmosphere in, and they moved into position to make their simultaneous landing.

This time they would have the advantage in numbers.

This time there would be no humiliating defeat.

This time the Hunters couldn’t lose.

Salvage09. Positions of Power

By Rantarian

The doors to the flight deck were sealed, but Treoffa knew that they would hold out only for so long. It had been just a few moments since the Hunters had made aggressive contact with the flight deck, and in that time she’d found her prospects of a bountiful future diminishing with each ship that landed.

“Ten,” she said to the soldiers she’d summoned to her office. “There are ten Hunter troop ships that have just landed on the Zhadersil. I estimate one hundred troops per ship.”

“Oh fuck,” said Chir, mimicking the human’s manner. It was unhealthy the way they regarded him, had begun to imitate him, but that was a matter for safer time, assuming one ever arrived. If it didn’t, then it would no longer be a matter at all.

“Sorry,” Adrian said, clearly confused by the heavy air of horror that surrounded the rest of the group. “What the fuck is a Hunter?”

“They’re monsters,” Trycrur explained. “They raid poorly defended outposts and ships, seize the contents and eat the crew.”

“Eat the crew?!” Adrian asked in clear disgust. At least humans seemed to take issue with eating other sentient beings, which made them a damn sight better in Treoffa’s book, no matter their other failings.

“They do not eat livestock unless they are forced to do so,” Treoffa expanded. “They prefer the meat of intelligent beings, for whatever insane reason.”

“And we’ve got a thousand of these arseholes out on the flight deck right now?” Adrian asked, pointing in the general direction. “Don’t they think the portions will be a little small?”

Zripob grunted. “Now is not the time for jokes, human!”

Treoffa frowned. “I’ve sealed the doors, but they’ll only stand up to so much damage, and the salvage ship is out there with them, but they’ve never attacked anywhere in such numbers before.”

“They’re after the ship?” Chir asked.

“Yes,” Treoffa said, “but if the source of their information was who I think he was, they’ve come in such numbers because we’ve got a human on board. After the humiliating defeat they suffered on Earth I think it’s fair to say that they want to make an example of a human, and one with no access to outside intervention.”

Everybody now turned to look at an increasingly uncomfortable Adrian.

Everybody was looking at Adrian, like he was somehow going to figure out a way to single–handedly defeat a thousand heavily armed soldiers who’d come ready to face a human.

“You’ve got to be fucking kidding me,” he said. “What am I supposed to do against all of that?”

“If we don’t do something,” Treoffa said, “they’re going to eat us and get their hands on advanced technology the rest of the galaxy does not have access to. Nobody wants to see that happen.”

“Right,” replied Adrian rubbing his temples with his thumbs. Just when he thought the bullshit had come to an end, something happened to remind him that there wasn’t one. “What do we know about these guys? They’re here for the ship, they’re here for me, and there’s a thousand of them. Anything else?”

“They eat people,” volunteered Trycrur.

“Thank you Trix,” Adrian said tersely, “is there anything else?”

“Physically they have seven eyes, astounding depth perception, six legs and cybernetic weapons fused to their arms,” detailed Treoffa. “Does that help?”

“No, but keep going,” Adrian said.

“They’re highly militarised and know their tactics,” Chir said. “It isn’t easy to get the drop on them, and impossible to get the drop on a thousand of them.”

“Great,” Adrian said without enthusiasm. “Are there any weaknesses we could exploit? You said they have cybernetics, are they hardened against electro–magnetic pulses?”

Treoffa considered the question for a moment. “I don’t think that’s ever been tried.”

“That’s a maybe then,” Adrian said, starting to feel better about his chances against a thousand space–cannibals. “What about explosions? Kinetic weapons? Fire? Electricity?”

Trycrur and Zripub slowly moved the gut–turning quantity of meat from the preserving containers into the stasis pod. If nothing else, the Hunters’ scans would detect the presence of a human–sized quantity of organic material, but the effect of the stasis field would prevent any further information, such as the fact it was just a pile of wet meat rather than a human male.

“Is it just me or do all of his plans seem completely insane?” Zripub asked, grimacing as he laid yet another gargantuan slice of meat into the pod.

Trycrur sighed. “It isn’t just you,” she said, “but they’ve mostly worked so far so I think we should keep trusting him.”

“What does that say about us?” Zripob wondered. “We’re packing meat into a stasis pod to work to a plan created by a Deathworlder savage to trick a thousand psychopathic cannibals into accepting a token of our good will which we know they won’t honour. When does the plan get to the part where we survive?”

“You know we don’t have any weapons to fight that many Hunters,” Trycrur reminded him. “Adrian was after weapons for hunting on the Deathworld, or for shooting Bekmer. We didn’t expect an army.”

“He’s hardly taking any weapons to speak of out there with him, anyway,” Zripob grumbled. “Just those other things you helped him make. How the hell is he supposed to win with that?”

The Alphas stood together on the flight deck, coordinating their infiltration strategy. This was the first time they had ever had to deal with this particular alien technology, and as such there was the unwelcome delay to have to deal with. There was also the fact that this was the single largest hunt that their kind had ever embarked upon, and they were still sorting out the particulars of appropriate command chains.

They were making progress, however, on the forward doors. Heavy plasma cutters had finally been deployed, and although they were making slow progress in cutting through, it was still progress and when they were done nothing would stop the great brood from seething throughout the ship.
They had left some of their members aboard the ships, wise enough to have them employ the ship weapons if everything should go poorly. Surely even a human could not stand up against that!

Alpha Primus clicked. +<excitement; hunger; statement> Soon we shall feast on human flesh, kindred. The first of many.+

More clicking from the others in agreement. They were all shamed by the failure on Earth, and this overpowering response against a single human was their best hope of regaining the fear the galaxy rightfully held of them.

Alpha Secundus clicked above the rest. +<fervour, demand> I shall claim his skull and place it on my wall!+

The argument that followed regarding the various claims on the human’s body parts was interrupted as the speaker system flared into life.

*“Attention arseholes, this is your human speaking, I wish to inform you that you can suck my left nut–”

The speaker system cut off, unexpectedly terminating whatever further abuse the human was going to hurl at them.

Alpha Tertius clicked furiously. +<Rage; statement> Insolence! It dares to challenge all of us! It will die horribly!+

There was vehement agreement from the others, and Alpha Secundus made its intention known to eat the eyes of the human while it still lived.

The speaker broke into life again, immediately gaining the attention of every Hunter on the Flight Deck. “Excuse me, Hunter army,” said a well spoken female voice. “We have captured the human and wish to trade him for our own lives. Please cease cutting into our doors if you agree, and we will send him out to you in a stasis pod.”

The Alphas looked at each other in ecstasy. The human delivered to them so easily, by its own side no less!

Alpha Primus clicked with glee. +<Happiness; deceit; suggestion> *We shall pretend to accept their terms! Then, once we have the human, we shall recommence our attack!“+

Alpha Secundus clicked its own appreciation of the plan. <Agreement; statement> They will be without defence. The brood will feed!+

The others agreed in similar fashion, and started issuing their orders to pull back from the doors and wait. Soon the real show would begin.

”This is a terrible plan, you know,“ Trycrur told Adrian as she helped him with his gear. “There’s got to be another way!”

“We haven’t got a lot of time, Trix,” Adrian said with some resignation. “Believe me when I say I’d prefer I didn’t have to do this, but from what you’ve all told me I’m the only one who’s going to be able to survive out there.”

“Sorry,” she said, “but if we don’t get access to the Salvage ship...”

“We’re all fucked,” he said. “I know, we only have one shot at this. Just remember to carry a torch with you.”

“I can echo–locate,” she said.

He sighed. “Of course you can. Looks like a bat–girl, echo–locates like a bat–girl...”

“Are you ready to do this?” she asked him, ignoring his rambling.

“Nobody’s ready to do this,” he replied with a half–hearted grin. “But I’m still going to give it a red hot go.”

The hunters leered in as one as the airlock door of the flight deck opened to reveal a stasis pod on an automated hover lifter. It drifted slowly amongst them, and those closest watched with intense caution under the general suspicion that this was some kind of trap.

Alpha Primus clicked in delight as the scan reports came in positive to the presence of organic material and negative to any unexpected surprises. +<Disbelief; statement> It appears they really are so foolish!+ Alphas Secondus and Tertius chorused their mirth at the fact, and gave orders to initiate the plan. Finally they would feast on the flesh of a human, even if it wouldn’t be claimed in the traditional manner.

Adrian watched the bug–like aliens skitter around the pod, drawing back as a ship weapon turned and fired on the container. The entire container was destroyed immediately, and its contents blasted out in a spray of gore.

Their attention was focused entirely on the red flesh that oozed from the wreckage of the stasis pod as they competed over sampling it in a swarming activity. None of them paid any attention to the small form high above them, not when their interest– and their jubilation – was so focused.

It was ironically easy to forget to think in three dimensions when faced with such a large room, but the access corridors around all sides of the flight deck had never been locked away but simply uninteresting. One of them led to the ceiling structures, the massive mechanisms designed for moving ships, and served yet another way into the flight deck for the enterprising defender. It also had a magnificent view of the action below.

“Come on out you fuckers,” Adrian mumbled to himself as those who had been left to crew the ships finally emerged, flooding from the hatches without restraint, leaving access to their ships wide open. They had feared him, had been cautious a moment ago when they had faced their greatest enemy, but now they thought themselves victorious. They thought themselves invincible. They would soon learn they were wrong on both counts.

He gritted his teeth and tied the leather cord to the structure at his feet, and then stuck the rubbery tube in his mouth. This was about to get unpleasant.

There was something wrong with the taste of the meat, Alpha Primus realised. It didn’t taste entirely fresh, and nor did it have that certain something that belonged to sentient beings.

It looked to the other Alphas. +<Confusion; dissatisfaction; question> Is this how a human is supposed to taste?+

They were equally disappointed, and made no effort to disguise the fact. They had come so far for this, with such an army, and this was their reward? If it wasn’t for the ship, it would have been the greatest single waste of effort in their history.

That was when all the gravity went away.

Adrian grabbed the rope tight as the gravity disappeared, holding it firmly with his right hand while his left gripped a small hover–drone normally used for taking pictures and other surveillance. It couldn’t carry anything but itself in anything approaching standard gravity, but in zero gee it could move him.

The angry commotion was snatched away by the wind as power shut down. Treoffa had maintained remote control over the power distribution system in the Salvage ship. Without power being fed to the Zhadersil there were no lights. Without power being fed to the Zhadersil, there was no forcefield holding in the atmosphere on the flight deck.

That was unfortunate for the thousand–odd Hunters being sucked out into the blackness of space without protection, their many limbs flailing as they tried to remain on the flight deck, arms being torn off as they found grips on the floor in the face of cyclonic wind speeds. A thousand Hunters, and associated limbs, personally entered high–orbit of the Deathworld.

Adrian waited for the wind to subside, holding his breath for long enough that the scant few more he had in the hastily assembled air–bag would last him a minute more. He released his white–knuckled grip on the rope and kicked himself down into the airless void. It was Treoffa’s turn to work now.

Treoffa still had video feed from the drone in Adrian’s hand, and along with the others had borne witness to the terrible tragedy unfolding upon those who couldn’t deserve it more.

Right now she could, if she wished, leave the human to die, but that would invite violent rebuke from the others in the room, and would doom herself as well. As much as she hated admitting it, she was entirely reliant upon Adrian for her own survival, and unlike Bekmer she had the intelligence to see it and to accept it.

Under her guidance the drone dragged Adrian towards the Salvage ship with solid acceleration. There were enough Vacuum–Suits in there to provide for all of them, except for Adrian for whom the physiology had not yet been registered.

The plan was working so far though, she had to admit she had thought it would fail, but now she was willing to wait and–

She twisted the view of the camera suddenly as something attracted her attention.

“Is that what I think it is?” asked Chir, pointing out the Hunter ship that had just switched its engines back on.

Treoffa stared at it. One ship had still had its pilot. One hunter ship was still active. “Fuck.”

Salvage10. Air Time

By Rantarian

Adrian Saunders had not known what to expect from the vacuum of space. He had thought that maybe it would be cold, or maybe that is body would swell up a little like Arnold Schwarzenegger in that movie of his about Mars. He had not expected it to be so dry that his eyes kept watering – the void of space robbed the moisture from them so quickly that he had to blink furiously to clear the tears away.

He was so focused on this process that he did not immediately notice the Hunter ship starting to lift from the deck. Not, at least, until the hover camera diverted him from his planned destination of the Salvage ship and turned him towards the Hunter vessel.

Fuckin’ A, he thought angrily. I have about ten breaths worth of air and she wants me to go fight some more guys.

The ship was taking its time at least, needing to work its way up and around the other Hunter vessels before it could move freely. The invading ships had come in hard and fast, clearly not anticipating any situation where they’d actually have to escape in a hurry, and the lack of gravity was allowing them to drift slightly in the gravitationless flight deck. Adrian was touching down on the Hunter vessel as it was finally turning to make a speedy withdrawal.

He exhaled his held breath through his nose and took another gulp through the tube. He drew the combat knife he’d had Trix fashion for him from its sheathe, and slipped into the open hatch.

Lesser Navigator supposed that it was technically now the Alpha of the brood, alone to have encountered the human and survived. It was simply regrettable that it was now a brood of one, but some time in the breeding chambers would remedy that.

It had already sent notice ahead of it as to what had happened, during the brief moments the engines needed to power back up, and did not look forward to the situation it would find when it finally reached home.

That was when it heard the clang. Something had landed on the hull. It gripped its fusion sword worriedly, although it told himself it must have been a piece of debris. There was nothing alive in the airless void, but just to be safe it scanned the hull.

The results came back immediately. The human was alive, it was on the hull, and Lesser Navigator had left the hatch open!

Adrian was pleased to discover that although the hatch had been left open, the Hunters made similar use of force fields to contain their air. He breathed long, deep breaths as he wiped the water from his eyes onto his sleeve, and when he was satisfied that he was capable of continuing he slipped the hover camera into his pocket and pulled out the communicator.

“Operation Ripley’s a success so far,” he said into the communicator. “Maybe you could tell me why I’m on this fucking ship instead of yours?”

“We can’t let any get away,” Treoffa replied. “Not when we are so close to total victory. Kill the last of them! Quickly!”

Adrian turned off the communicator and snarled his lack of appreciation at being ordered about like that, but he set about to do as she’d said. He had his combat knife ready, knowing it was all he’d need in an enclosed space. “You call that a knife?” he joked to himself, examining the large blade.

The door slid open, revealing a single Hunter carrying a much longer blade, clearly enhanced with the addition of technology, and actual flames seemed to rise from its edge.

“Technically,” Adrian said, “that’s a sword.”

Normally Lesser Navigator would have scoffed at the tiny blade the human held out. It would have done so now, had it not been for the fact that a human was holding it. The same human, presumably, who had vented nearly a thousand of its brethren into space.

This was not a scoffing matter. Humans were strong, they were fast, and from the lack of protection this one was wearing they were at least highly resistant to being exposed to the vacuum of space.

Lesser Navigator had been gifted with a kinetic pulse gun implant in its right forearm as a broodling, but it was useless here. An anti–tank kinetic pulse gun would be similarly useless. It had chosen a fusion sword for the fight against the human for this reason, although it was not a weapon that Lesser Navigator was proficient with.

It held it out before itself, and then swung!

Adrian stepped in by reflex as the Hunter swung the deadly blade at him, getting inside the swing in two quick steps and stabbing the Hunter up through whatever passed for its ribcage. All seven of its eyes went wide at that, and he tore the blade out violently only to slam the butt of it against the creature’s skull repeatedly until had entirely collapsed into gore.

He paused to steady himself, and looked down at the dropped sword, raising an eyebrow when he saw that its blade had cut deep into the metal floor. He looked at the empty void of space beyond the hatch that had replaced the comforting flight deck of the Zhadersil.

“Fuck,” he drawled out. “That is not good.”

“Status report, Adrian?” Treoffa demanded after a few minutes had passed. The hover cam had gone dark for some reason, but had transmitted sounds of violence.

“Yeah,” Adrian replied shortly, much to everyone’s relief. “So it seems like I’ve left the Zhadersil.”

“What?!” interjected Chir. “They surely did not capture you!”

“Yeah, nah,” Adrian reassured him. “These guys are all dead, but now I’m stuck in a ship I don’t know how to fly, going I don’t know where. Not the best outcome to the situation I’ll admit, but it wasn’t me who didn’t follow the plan.”

Treoffa found herself subject to three uncomfortably narrow stares. “I did what I believe was needed. Do you have access to the command deck?”

“Lots of consoles and comfy–as–fuck seats?” Adrian asked. “Yeah, I’m on it right now.”

“Good,” she said with relief. “Now listen closely, I’m going to teach you how to fly a starship.”

Treoffa had powered up the gravity field on the flight deck long before Adrian had managed to re–orient the ship to face it. The ship had almost drifted from the Zhadersil, and he wasn’t so far from it that he had begun to panic, but he had been far from familiar with piloting the starship and was forced to do so with incremental, often jerking movements.

At least the landing had been an automated process, but once that part of his excursion had been complete he was still faced with another jog through hard vacuum.

The hits just kept coming.

“Alright,” he said, checking over his gear to make sure he had everything, and adding the future–sword to his collection. “Back to the plan.”

He took a final breath and held it as he leapt from the hatch, racing down the gangway and onto the open floor of the flight deck. From here the Salvage ship seemed a long way away, and he wished he’d known how to park the ship closer, but he was out of choices now.

His lungs burned as he ran, his eyes watering almost enough to blind him. He held each breath for as long as he could – and then forced himself to hold it for longer – before exhaling sharply through his nose and sucking hard on the tube.

Five breaths left.

Four.

Three.

He reached the door to the Salvage ship. It was closed and locked, as it normally was, but Treoffa had told him the code before he’d left on his mad mission and he kept his burning eyes open so that he could match the alien symbols against the ones he had memorised.

He miskeyed.

Two breaths.

Let me in you motherfucking thing, he raged internally, putting the long sequence in again.

The red light flashed. The code was rejected.

One breath.

Salvage11. Victory for Some

By Rantarian

“Adrian,” Treoffa repeated. “Adrian, are you there?”

The four of them had been standing together, listening to Treoffa chanting the human’s name for what seemed far too long. Their expressions grew dimmer with every repetition – they knew that he had only so much air in that bag.

“Adrian,” Treoffa began again. “Adrian, are you–”

“For fucks sake, can’t a man suffocate in peace?” came the reply at last, although the speaker seemed far weaker than the human that had left them. “Doc, I don’t mind telling you that I’m buggered.”

The relief in the room was palpable. “We were getting worried,” Chir said. “You took longer than expected.”

“I forgot the door code,” Adrian explained. “God, it was getting harder and harder to breathe.”

“If you forgot the door code, you would not have been able to get into the Salvage ship,” said Treoffa, a question in her statement.

“About that,” Adrian said, “I’m afraid I’ve cut a big hole in your door with a future–sword I picked up.”

“You damaged my starship?!” Treoffa exploded angrily. “How do you intend for me to fix that? And where is my video feed?”

“Oh right,” Adrian said, and after a moment the video feed was restored to show the ruined features of the human’s face. Trickles of blood ran from bloodshot eyes, and cheeks showed swelling and bruising. He looked like he’d been on the receiving end of brutal violence, but he still managed a weak grin.

“Your face!” Trycrur exclaimed. “What happened to you?”

“It seems that a walk in hard vacuum doesn’t come cheaply,” Treoffa said curtly. “Even for a human.”

“I do feel like two pounds of shit in a one pound bag,” Adrian agreed. “Listen, I don’t think I’m up for another walk outside. Do we have any other options?”

“Are you feeling up to some computer work?” Treoffa asked.

Adrian grimaced. “It doesn’t sound like I’ll have a choice.”

Over the next three hours, while his condition worsened, Treoffa had stepped Adrian through the keystrokes and commands required to enable remote access. From then it was another hour of waiting and feeling sorry for himself before she had informed him that a Vacuum Suit had been configured for his own use, and another few minutes of trying to figure out her instructions to put it on.

He wasn’t feeling good at all, his body ached, his skin itched and his senses and mind were failing him with increasing severity. None of this pointed to a condition that was going to go away any time soon.

Hard vacuum. Zero pressure. Little wonder that he felt as though he had the Bends. His body now was stronger than it had ever been, and it still felt like several kinds of shit–house. Good thing he wasn’t still sporting the old model, or he’d almost certainly be dead – a fact that was good for his sense of humility if nothing else.

“Treoffa,” he said as he steadied himself by the broken airlock. He was ready as he could be to venture out there again, this time with air and suits for everyone. “Do you know how to treat decompression sickness?”

“Such a thing is not uncommon on planets,” she replied, “but we do not have the facilities to do so here.”

He paused, staring at the open flight deck. “Treoffa...” he began.

“I will have the others prepare a stasis pod for you until we can get you treated properly,” she said. “I can’t tell you how long that might be.”

He nodded to the camera, and then set out across the flight deck one more time.

On Treoffa’s orders, Trycrur and Zripob had rushed to ready one of the remaining three stasis pods, running through the brief systems checks as they pushed it on a hover lifter towards the airlock Adrian would return by.

They knew it was bad; the Corti had explained to them that there was no way she could know how dire his condition was, and that in any case all instances of Corti researchers exposing human test subjects to hard vacuum had never been experimental in nature. But Adrian had seemed to think his condition was bad, and that was all the information she needed to ready the only medical aid she could offer.

All together, the had waited outside of the airlock, counting down the moments before the pressure equalised, and rushing to help the forlorn human as best they could manage, easing him from his Vacuum suit and into the stasis pod.

Trycrur had been horrified to see he looked even worse in person than he had on the video feed. After his victory against a thousand or so Hunters, it had been difficult to imagine the human was even capable of dying. It wasn’t hard to imagine it anymore.

“Don’t worry,” she told him as he laid back into the pod. “We won’t let you die.”

“I know you won’t,” he said, smiling wanly as the pod closed.

Once she was alone, Treoffa breathed a sigh of relief, and allowed herself a moment to experience satisfaction. A thousand Hunters repelled, all of their equipment seized – and being inventoried by the others as she worked – and the human was in the stasis pod where he belonged.

Added to the fact that Bekmer was imprisoned, and the key to the Zhadersil and the resulting reward was nearly in her grasp alone, and it was hard to imagine a greater success.

The air for the flight deck would need to be recaptured, but with ten full troop ships at her disposal it would be easy to harvest the atmosphere of the planet below.

Besides the three remaining slave–soldiers, only one thing remained to be taken care of before her victory to be complete.

Something needed to happen to Bekmer.

65 Million Years Ago

“This is my last entry as Shiplord of the Zhadersil,” Xagh spoke into the recorder, watching the computer translate his voice into text record. “We have taken what we could of her and now leave her in high orbit of Affrag, under the care of our last Exterminator drone.”

He paused for effect, but the delay was not recorded by the software. He frowned at it, irritated that its transcription held none of his emphasis or pauses. It would all be transformed into dry words on a screen, devoid of any of the emotion he felt. It was a notable event for a Shiplord to abandon his vessel, and he couldn’t help but feel he was betraying some part of himself in doing so.

“The Zhadersil has served us well,” he continued, “but the time as come to make a new start. Time will tell whether we are successful or not, but one thing is certain – we will not be returning to the Zhadersil while I still live.”

He took a steadying breath. “To this end I am updating the biometric command profiles to use the entire homeworld genetic listing. Anyone with a recognised sequence will simply need to sit the command chair. I hope it may still serve you in your own time of need.”

There was a final pause, as he examined the ship from its interior senses, knowing that he had walked every corridor, understood every part of every system. The Zhadersil had been his to know – that was what it meant to be Shiplord.

“Xagh out.”

Salvage12. The Backup Plan

By Rantarian

ULTIMATUM FROM HUNTERS: DEMAND ALL HUMANS BE TURNED OVER ELSE QUOTE SWARM OF SWARMS ENDQUOTE WILL RAID KNOWN HUMAN LOCATIONS. ALL SHIPS, STATIONS CARRYING HUMAN PASSENGERS ADVISED: JETTISON IMMEDIATELY. NOTIFICATION ENDS.

The message was succinct; its timing was undeniable – the human, Adrian Saunders, had managed to enrage the Hunters beyond any point they had ever been angered before, and now there was every chance that they would make another attack on the Zhadersil, and soon.

Treoffa’s chances of success were looking a little bit dimmer than they had a few moments ago. The only thing she had in her favour was that there was no way the slave–soldiers could have learned about this yet.

“What to do?” she asked herself, although she felt rather more out of her depth than she was letting herself admit. As far as she could work out, she had a few options.

First, she could run away. That would be ideal for survival, but it would also be giving up on the Zhadersil entirely, and may lead to the ancient starship falling into the hands of the Hunters.

Second, she could maintain operations here, but drop Adrian Saunders off with a Directorate patrol. Then she’d be rid of the human, but the Hunters would have no reason to give up on the Zhadersil and she would be completely without any real protection.

Thirdly, she could defy the Directorate – risking her own future at this point – and heal Adrian Saunders, knowing that he was still the biggest target for Hunters in the entire galaxy, and knowing that he had limited capacity to defend them in the short term.

Three options, all terrible. “Is this what it’s like to be him? she wondered aloud. “Every option is terrible. Every possibility is completely... ’fucked’.”

She reclined back into her chair, her eyes closed in thought. This was exactly the sort of situation that needed some sort of mad plan to get out of with all her victories intact, but she was a creature of logic, and what she needed was a deranged savage.

“What do I know?” she asked herself, opening her eyes. “I know that the Directorate have ordered Bekmer’s crew, and therefore me, to hand over the human. I know that that human has single–handedly defeated a Hunter invasion. I know that if he’s not here, I’m likely to find myself the target of another without anyone here to do the fighting.”

And there it was. The idea.

The completely, wonderfully insane idea.

“Let me be blunt with you,” Treoffa said to the assembled soldiers. “I have been ordered to turn Adrian Saunders over to the Directorate.”

They stared at her, glancing at one another as though waiting to see who would speak first. Treoffa didn’t give them the opportunity to interrupt. “I have been delaying, but I can no longer do this.”

“The fact that such an action would be reprehensible notwithstanding,” Chir said, “as well as the fact that I at least would prevent such a thing, how would you intend to reach Directorate space? We know there are Hunters out there, and possibly pirates as well.”

“There would be that risk involved,” Treoffa replied. “Especially in light of the fact that the entire Hunter swarm have declared war on the Human race. Any world or ship harbouring a human has been threatened with annihilation.”

The stunned silence was as she had expected, fear on all their features but also determination. None of them was willing to simply give up on the human, be it from a sentimental or practical standpoint. They’d seen enough to have good reason to prefer having a human on board, regardless of the danger.

“If we can expect another Hunter attack,” Trycrur said, “it would be better to have him with us, then for them to find us undefended.”

Zripob croaked agreement. “There’s no way we can allow him to leave us undefended.”

“And yet,” Treoffa said, “if we don’t hand him over, the Directorate will undoubtedly come to fetch him. They would take the Zhadersil from me, and who knows what they would do to Adrian Saunders?”

“They might allow us to return home,” Zripob pointed out.

“You have been aboard the Zhadersil,” Treoffa replied, ready for this point. “They would not allow word of the discovery to spread.”

“You seem so sure,” Zripob said suspiciously. “Could it be that this was also your plan?”

“Originally, yes,” Treoffa admitted. “But circumstances have changed. I believe that action would be ultimately pointless.”

“So presumably you have some sort of plan?” Chir asked. “I cannot imagine why you would have called this meeting otherwise.”

“Very astute, Gaoian,” Treoffa said. “I do indeed have a plan, but I will require all of your support to pull it off.”

When Adrian Saunders awoke he was surprised to find himself in the familiar surrounds of the Zhadersil medical bay. Treoffa was hovering nearby, working at one of the monitoring consoles.

“I thought I needed to go some place else?” he asked as he assessed his condition. At the very least his eyes didn’t hurt, his skin didn’t itch, and his body didn’t ache like it was being slowly pulled apart. “I feel better, at least.”

“You are better,” Treoffa replied, coming over to him and running a hand–held scanner over his exposed skin. “Or at least better than you were. My machines kept you alive long enough for your superior healing capabilities to do their work, but you deteriorated significantly before you improved while you were unconscious. You are not fully recovered yet, but you won’t need to be stuck in here for the remainder.”

“I thought you said you didn’t have the facilities,” he said. “Did something change?”

“You could say that,” Treoffa said. “I wasn’t sure if you’d survive a natural healing process, but necessity forced my hand.”

Adrian paused, his eyes narrowing on Treoffa. “What’s happened this time?”

“Two things you need to know about,” Treoffa said. “First of all, your victory against the Hunters has seen the entire Hunter Swarm declare war against your species. They have threatened all those who harbour them.”

“You don’t seem that concerned about having me here,” Adrian noted.

“We are already their target, whether you are here or not,” Treoffa explained with characteristic bluntness. “You are a factor in our favour, and I do not wish to give you up. Which brings me to my second topic.”

“What’s this one?” Adrian asked bemusedly. “Some sort of new disaster or hope–crushing event?”

“I’ve been ordered to give you over to the Corti Directorate,” Treoffa told him. “They’ll be wanting to dissect you.”

“Think of it like a game,” Trycrur suggested. “Except if you lose you kill everyone.”

“That’s real fucking reassuring,” Adrian replied tersely, going over the controls again in his head before pressing the next button. A symbol appeared that he guessed meant ’good job’ or ’correct’, or something along those lines.

“Good! Now the engines would be turned on!” Trycrur told him. “You won’t get any forward momentum until...?”

Adrian thought, then pointed at the virtual control grid on the left of the simulator’s centre console. “Until I drag the dot in this direction?”

“Correct!” Trycrur said, making her best attempt at a smile. “Not too far though, because you’ll slam the ship into the bulkhead and kill everyone.”

“Fucksake,” Adrian hissed out between his teeth. “This is a lot to remember all at once.”

“Don’t you have spacecraft on your world?” Trycrur asked. “I seem to recall that your species had at least managed to get into space.”

“We do,” Adrian said, a little more defensively than he would have liked. “But we have joysticks, not stupid touch–screens with dots.”

Trycrur looked perplexed. “What’s a ’joystick’?”

Adrian did his best to explain it to her. Then he found himself giving her a basic run–down on what he could recall of Earth’s aviation history. It was bland stuff, or it was when he told it, but she had the decency to at least look interested, although she certainly perked up when he got to the part about jetpacks.

He wondered if those would be possible in this futurists wet dream. Probably. Had anyone made them yet? It certainly didn’t look like it.

“Why am I learning all of the details, anyway?” he asked when she finally returned his attention to the simulator. “You said I could just tell the auto–pilot where to go and what to do.”

“You can do that,” she agreed, “but an auto–pilot can’t get you out of a bad situation, and it can’t react very well to unexpected events.”

He sighed. “Right, I guess we’ll keep at it then.”

“Thank you all for your assistance in this plan,” Treoffa said to the gathered soldiers. “Today we’ll be doing something really stupid, but I believe that with Adrian’s help we have a chance of pulling it off.”

Adrian shrugged. “It’s no more insane than anything I’ve done recently,” he said, “and I think it’s got a better shot of working from what you’ve told me.”

“And this time we have a contingency plan,” Chir added, gesturing towards Adrian. “Although I feel that ’Adrian is the plan’ maybe getting a bit stale.”

“No shit?” Adrian muttered. “But I’m just the contingency plan. I don’t see why the main plan wouldn’t work. From what you’ve said everyone is shit scared of the Hunters.”

“Quite,” agreed Treoffa. “If anybody cares, we’ll be leaving Bekmer in his little cell here while we’re gone. He’ll have enough sustenance, but I’m sure you won’t be concerned if he starves a little.”

“I don’t care if he starves a lot,” Adrian said unkindly, but not undeservedly. “How long have we got before the collectors arrive at the meeting zone?”

“Five sleep cycles,” Treoffa said. “But we’ll be leaving tomorrow. Get your rest, everyone – we’ve got quite the show to set up.”

Adrian exited stasis on another Corti ship, and that was not a good sign. It meant that the handover had happened, and that the main plan had either failed, or had failed to succeed before he awakened.

No matter the case, it was time to engage he contingency plan – that being to kill everyone on board and take control of the ship.

With a gentle push he opened the pod and slipped over the side to drop onto the floor of the small room, taking what he had come to discover was called a ’fusion sword’ with him. There was no–one around the pod, but there was a sense of tension in the air. The sense of something very important happening.

He left the room quickly to avoid an unplanned jettisoning at an inopportune time, just in case the main plan finally worked. Somewhere out there were three Hunter ships piloted by his friends, all making the demand of the Corti vessel to eject its human cargo.

That plan, had it succeeded, would have seen the Corti write Adrian off as a loss. It would have seen them all go home safely none–the–wiser.

Now it had to be Plan B.

“Those Hunters have clearly never dealt with a Sealed FTL before,” said Ship Master Crfti, gazing out into the warp corridor. “A pity about Salvage Officer Treoffa, however.”

He turned to Ship Second Tlkitz. “Make a note of that matter, Tlkitz. Treoffa did her duty to the Directorate well. Far better than that fool, Bekmer.”

“As you say, Ship Master,” replied Tlkitz immediately, and set about to do just that. “What do you think she was attempting to warn us about before her ship was overtaken by the Hunters?”

“Probably the Hunters,” Crfti said. “What else would she have to be so desperate about? I must say, however, that she was surprisingly unprofessional at the last.”

“Death by Hunter is... unsettling, Ship Master,” Tlkitz replied. Personally he couldn’t think of a worse fate to experience. To be at the mercy of an unstoppable monster who did not know the meaning of the word. Such was the source of nightmares for any intelligent young Corti with dreams of the stars.

“We will be back home soon enough, Tlkitz,” the Ship Master reassured him. “Despite their threats, there is no way that the Hunter swarm will descend upon our homeworld.”

“I am sure it is as you say, Ship Master,” Tlkitz replied, although he remained far from reassured. There had been three Hunter ships. Three! Normally nobody saw more than a single vessel at a time, and that was more than enough! Tlkitz found himself continually glancing at the warp corridor as well, but not with the smug glory that his Ship Master did. He looked at it with dread.

At least nothing had managed to get on board.

Now that he was on board the Corti vessel, Adrian took the time to be stealthy. It looked as though the crew were on high alert, but their attention was focused outward, not inward, and when he observed them from his hiding places they seemed jumpy.

Not jumpy enough to react in time when he descended upon them, his sword often cleaving through more than three at a time. He hadn’t really had the chance to use a sword on Earth, but he didn’t imagine that those varieties would cut quite so easily, nor that they would cauterize the wounds and leave the corridors bloodless.

He hid the bodies as soon as they had fallen, dragging them into adjacent storage rooms and piling them into macabre little mounds. They had little besides their Kinetic guns on them, however, and after the first few he refrained from any further strip searches.

He’d learned more about Corti anatomy than anybody ever wanted to know.

“Thirteen,” he counted, checking off the heads rather than fragmented body parts. “I wonder when they’ll start to miss them.”

The Endless Sequence was a Corti heavy scout, capable of extended exploratory or reconnaissance missions and was furnished with its own botanical facility to feed its crew of 60.
Physically it was almost as big as a light cruiser, but was twice as fast and half as deadly. It was the perfect vessel for transportation missions that valued speed over quantity.

Yet it was only because the Endless Sequence had been nearby that the Directorate had commanded them to collect the human. And it was only because the threat of punishment outweighed the threats from the Hunters that the Ship Master had complied.

“This was not,” he had explained, “an order he could afford to overlook.”

And given the speed of the vessel it was natural that they feel confident in the decision. Or at least they had until they had encountered the Hunters at the rendezvous. They had barely managed to load the human before they had appeared, and had fired their ultimatum out across all channels.

Rather than comply with the requests of such loathsome creatures, the Endless Sequence had fled with all haste, abandoning the small salvage ship to its grisly fate.

Tlkitz was fine with that much, however, if it meant not sharing that fate. He had waited some time before relaying the order for all hands to return to their usual stations, wanting to be sure of no surprises.

It was only then that he discovered the surprise: thirteen crewmen had not returned to their regular stations.

He did a quick scan, understanding why some might try and shirk their duties after such tension, and was puzzled to find all missing members hiding inside a storage room.

“What,” he asked aloud to the command deck, “is so interesting about storage compartment thirty–seven?”

Salvage13. Plan C from Outer Space

By Rantarian

Adrian Saunders was holding eleven armed Corti soldiers hostage on their own ship. They didn’t seem happy about it, but when the alternative had been slaughtering them with impunity they were at least understanding, and were informed enough about human capabilities to be very cooperative.

He had decided that Plan B wasn’t working for him.

It had sounded straightforward when Treoffa had explained it. The Zhadersil would be raided by Corti and eventually more Hunters if he was believed to still be on board. That was why Plan A had been to have the Corti transportation ship eject the stasis pod into space for the Hunters, thus writing him off as an unfortunate loss, while in actual fact the Hunter ships would have been piloted by his comrades who would then pick him up and return him to the Zhadersil.

Plan B was for when that plan failed, and he had to pilot the entire Corti vessel back after exterminating its crew. In this case the official Corti records would indicate that the human they were after had taken control of the vessel and was taking it who–knew–where. Not ideal, but so long as Treoffa could shut down the locator beacon the Directorate wouldn’t have any reason to go looking for it in the vicinity of the Zhadersil.

But unlike the Hunters, the Corti weren’t being actively aggressive, and mostly seemed terrified when he leapt out of hiding to kill them.

It was beginning to bother him, and that’s where Plan C had come from.

“So,” he said to them, waving his sword back and forward between them and causing them to shrink back in fear. “This is real fucking cliche, but I need you to take me to your leader.”

“That is most unusual,” Ship Second Tlkitz mused, running through another scan. “The two teams I sent down to storage room thirty–seven are leaving as a group, but the thirteen who were in that room are still there.”

“Maybe there is something going on down at the storage room?” Ship Master Crfti suggested. “Get in contact with them, see what they have to say for themselves.”

“As you say, Ship Master,” Tlkitz said obediently, and turned to the communication console to his right. “Investigative teams, report.”

There was a delay. Longer than he would have expected. He activated the communicator again. “Investigative teams–”

“We’re fine,” came the response at last. “Everything’s fine here. We’re all just coming up to the command deck.”

“To the command deck?” Tlkitz queried. “If all is well, return to your stations.”

“Negative, Ship Second,” the investigative team responded again, almost plaintively. “We will be coming to the command deck. We have something to deliver.”

Tlkitz hesitated. That was puzzling, there was nothing he was aware of on the ship that would ever need to be delivered to the command deck, save for the occasional protein tablet for the hard working Ship Master and his trusted Second.

“Ship Master,” he said uncertainly, “the investigative teams are on their way here. They have something to deliver.”

“What have they got?” Ship Master Crfti asked. “I’m not hungry enough for a protein tablet.”

“I’ll check,” Tlkitz replied, and turned back to the communicator console. “Investigative team, what are you delivering?”

At that moment the door to the command deck literally burst apart to reveal a human with a fusion sword.

The human bared its teeth at them. “A surprise, motherfucker!”

Adrian had done his best James Doakes impression and there had been nobody else around to appreciate it. That had been disappointing, but he was getting used to nobody knowing what the hell he was talking about and he didn’t let it slow him down.

He pointed the fusion sword at the Corti sitting in the most commanding chair.

“You’re the dickhead in charge here?” he demanded.

The Corti leader shrank back in plain horror at the current situation. “All hands, defend me!” he cried out desperately. “Fire on the human!”

There was hesitation from all corners, all members of the command deck crew glanced at their kinetic sidearms with the kind of forlorn looks that told him they knew exactly how useless they’d be.

“Respectfully, Ship Master,” said one of the Command crew, “but with what?”

“Look, mate,” Adrian said, addressing the Ship Master, “I’m about to offer you a way to stay alive, but if you don’t want it then someone else can always get promoted.”

He let the words sink in, and the Corti leader regained his composure. “The Directorate will not allow this to pass lightly,” he warned Adrian, “but I will listen to your demands.”

The situation aboard the Zhadersil had been tense. Plan A had not worked – in fact it had failed spectacularly when they had discovered that the Corti ship had been a heavy scout with a Sealed FTL drive – and now they were waiting to see if Adrian would manage to return.

“This is not an ideal situation,” Treoffa had said, “but we have little choice to hope everything goes as–”

“It’s here!” Trycrur excitedly interrupted. “The Corti ship just appeared in a lower orbit!”

“We’ll have to go out and board it,” Chir said. “Treoffa still needs to disable the beacon, and we need to guide it onto the flight deck.”

“Adrian only managed fifty–six percent of his simulated landings with any success,” Trycrur reminded them. “We don’t want him ramming a heavy scout through the Zhadersil by accident.”

“We need to make sure it’s actually him, first,” Treoffa told them. “I’ll contact the ship, just in case the plan has failed spectacularly.”

Two hours later, Adrian was back on the flight deck of the Zhadersil, its massive space now substantially filled by ten Hunter ships, the Corti Salvage runner, and most substantially by the Heavy Scout, the Endless Sequence.

“You know, Chir,” he said to the Gaoian as they strode across the deck, “I know the power is back on, and all this new air is sealed in, but I don’t think I’ll ever be comfortable walking around here again.”

“I know what you mean,” Chir replied, glancing nervously at the end of the flight deck where metal turned into the black void of space. “But you know, I find it a little hard to believe you didn’t end up killing all of the Corti on the scoutship.”

“I’m a soldier, mate,” Adrian replied, “not a murderer. They didn’t put up any resistance, and they were all too happy to get into their escape pods when told to.”

“You don’t think that was a mistake?” Chir asked. “What if they tell the Directorate?”

“They will tell the Directorate,” Adrian said. “They’ll tell them what I said I was going to do.”

Chir responded with his approximation of a confused frown. “Which was?”

“I had them enter the coordinates for the Hunter homeworld,” Adrian told him. “I told them I was going to war.”

“And they believed you?!” Chir asked, clearly aghast at the idea of anyone going to the Hunter homeworld.

“Mate,” said Adrian with a broad smile, “I can be very persuasive when I need to be.”

“We’re amassing quite the fleet,” Zripob observed as Adrian and Chir reached the airlock. “Pity we don’t have enough people to fly all of these.”

“I thought you wanted to go home,” Adrian asked. “Or at least get back into that war you were fighting in.”

“The Dominion–Celzi war,” Zripob replied. “Yes, I was just considering that a mercenary company with a fleet of this size would be quite the substantial force. The Dominion, or alternatively the Celzi, would shit their collective pants if they came against this kind of force.”

Zripob gave an undulating croak of laughter. Stealing a ship from the Corti Directorate had brightened his day, and the more vessels he saw housed in the enormous flight deck the more he found himself wondering what the future could hold if he managed to take control of such an assembly of vessels.

Could it be possible for him, a low born pond–raker, to ascend to the lofty heights of Fleetlord? It didn’t seem so far–fetched right now.

“What’s that war even about?” Adrian asked. “From what I’ve heard it has been quite drawn out. Who are the good guys?”

“It’s a political thing,” Chir inserted, “there are no good guys. That war is a significant reason for my people being reluctant to join the Dominion at this time, in spite of other benefits. It has proven itself to be a meat–grinder.”

“I don’t really pay attention to such things myself,” Zripob admitted. “As long as there’s someone willing to pay for mercenary work I’m happy.”

“And when the war inevitably ends?” Chir asked. “What will you do then?”

Zripob croaked his laugh again. “Then there’s easy guard duty for freighters or work as bodyguards. Just because there’s peace doesn’t mean there’s no danger.”

“Especially not with that message the Hunters put out, I imagine,” Adrian mused.

The laughter died in Zripob’s throat, the amusement left his eyes. “That is true,” he said. “So maybe I’ll have to find work far away from any humans. No offence intended.”

“My main worry,” Adrian said, “is that there are more humans out there, and that maybe they’re not capable of fucking up a small army.”

“More to the point,” Chir said, “how will those around them react to the news? We know you’ve outclassed a thousand Hunters – taken ten of their ships in the process – but that’s not common knowledge.”

Zripob gestured his agreement with a bobbing motion. “Their friends will become their enemies,” he said. “It will come down to a matter of pure survival.”

“It’s a matter of survival for us as well,” Chir reminded him. “Except the Hunters will come for us either way, so we actually want our human here.”

“I think that maybe,” Adrian said, rubbing his chin, “I really will need to declare war on them.”

They stared at him in combined horror. Zripob had never heard of anyone who was willing to throw their military at the Hunter brood – he’d have called anyone who suggested such a plan insane – but this man had already given the Hunters a bloody nose without much preparation and had even walked through a dissipating trace atmosphere and survived.

“I won’t say they don’t have it coming,” Zripob said, “but how do you expect to win such a war?”

“I don’t know if I can,” Adrian admitted with a frown, “but it seems to me that we’ve got a few aces up our sleeve. First thing’s first, though: we’re going to need some much better weapons.”

With all that had been going on, it had taken Treoffa days to trawl through the enormous number of logs, reports, and manifests in the Zhadersil’s memory banks. She was not accessing it through the ship’s own operating system, and as a result the file tables were not being read. Each file she had opened had been a complete mystery until she had started reading.

But she was finally done, or at least she was done reading everything that seemed important. The complete picture was much as Bekmer had posited, and matched what she had come to suspect herself.

Earth had produced a sentient race once before, and they had built the Zhadersil. From the records of those final days, almost all V’Straki had been exterminated by a final genocidal campaign by their enemies, and had been destroyed with such completeness that it was little wonder that almost nothing remained.

And now the final record; the last words of Shiplord Xagh. Any creature of their homeworld may be recognised by the ship as a commander.

The human could command the ship.

Treoffa leaned forward with both hands on her desk, her breathing and movement both under her strictest control, her body and temper both feeling taut enough to snap. She knew that it must be possible –somehow – to use this to take control of the ship for herself, but she couldn’t see how.

For the life of her, she simply couldn’t see how.

Quod erat demonstrandum pars: V

By devourerkwi

Dramatis personæ

Lucius Bellator Maximus, a Roman legionary from Legio V Alaudæ, based at the camp Castra Vetera in Xanten, Germania Inferior, serving Emperor Vespasian of the Flavian dynasty

Dieter, a barbarian from the Batavi tribe that was revolting against Rome

Berenice, an Egyptian woman, and her son, Isidorus, from the slums of Alexandria

Yan, a Chinese concubine from the court of and consort to Emperor Ming of Han in the Eastern Han dynasty

Clepta, a corti abductor, scientist, and trader

Glossarium

Scientia potentia est: Knowledge is power

Simplex: Naïve

Quod erat demonstrandum: Which had to be demonstrated

They had shuffled back down to their room in silence and picked their way around the two four–armed things’ pulps—“corpses” was a mite generous—to get through the door and back inside. Each of the five had sat down where they originally woke up, taking comfort in familiarity. They had stayed quiet for a while and Lucius took the time to look around the room.

The room, which was shaped like a quarter–circle, had been fully lit in their absence but there were no visible lanterns and the amount light should have required hundreds of them. The ceiling was about three men tall and made of a smooth–finished, utilitarian alloy that reflected some of the newfound light. The far wall opposite the door was finally visible and it had tall, man–sized windows arranged in wide panes separated every so often by dark gray rods. Beyond them was the same black palette with the white dots that Clepta had claimed were stars.

Isidorus caught Lucius staring at the windows and leapt up to go closer. Lucius saw Isidorus’s reflection in the glass as the boy approached it, clouding the view outside. The windows hid the great gales that nearly claimed Dieter, but these seemed safe. The boy pressed his nose against the glass, staring out into the black.

Dieter said something, though it was in his barbarian language, not Latin. It took Yan’s aggressive–sounding tongue for Lucius to figure out. “We don’t have the black ram’s horn,” said Lucius, “so I don’t understand you.” Dieter grunted in frustration and repeated himself, slapping his leg.

There was another set of chimes and one of the metal rods near the windows ejected a small gray ball that rolled right up to Dieter’s leg and stopped there. Dieter stared at Lucius with alarm. Lucius shrugged, and Dieter picked it up carefully. He held it to his ear, hearing nothing; he sniffed it, smelling nothing; he poked it, finding it mushy; and finally he took a bite of it, eliciting frightened gasps from the other four. Dieter made a face but kept chewing, eventually swallowing with an audible gulp that moved his Adam’s apple up and down the length of his stubby neck. Importantly, he didn’t die; in fact, he took a second bite, and then a third.

Dieter finished the gray ball and looked around impatiently, as if he wanted more. He yelled up at the ceiling. Again, a gray rod rolled a ball of what was apparently food to Dieter, but another rod also rolled a small, cylindrical container of what was very obviously water. Dieter wrenched off the top of it and downed it in one giant gulp, laughing loudly and speaking more of his barbarian language. More food and more water rolled to him.

Soon, Yan, Isidorus, and Lucius had all followed Dieter’s lead. Isidorus was thoughtful enough to say his mother wanted food, and Berenice was soon nibbling at one of her own gray balls of food. In just a few minutes, the five had downed a few dozen food balls and nearly as many cylinders of water. Lucius had to admit that though the food was tasteless, he felt far better.

Clepta strode into their room moments after they finished eating, arms folded against its chest, its eyes narrower slits, left hand clutching the black ram’s horn that let them talk to each other. “Clepta!” shouted Dieter as he chewed on his eighth food ball. “Your food is terrible! You need a new cook.”

“You killed him,” said Clepta, pointing at the bloody pulp at the broken portal.

“Oh,” said Dieter. “Whoops.” He grinned, clearly pleased with his handiwork.

“More importantly, you just consumed eighty percent of this ship’s food and water reserves in one meal and I don’t yet know when we’ll be at the next port. So thanks for that.”

“How do you have so little food?” asked Lucius.

“Apparently, each of you eats more than five times as much as any other being on the ship, so the food should have lasted far longer than it has. Even with bulk discounts, you ... humans ... are going to cost me a small fortune just to feed.”

“But this is gross,” said Isidorus, still curled up in his mother’s lap, finishing his third cylinder of water. “I don’t want this anymore.”

Clepta walked to Isidorus and Berenice and kneeled down beside them. “Child,” he said softly, “I don’t care.”

“I can cook,” said Yan. “When we get more food I will prepare meals for the crew.”

“Great,” said Clepta sarcastically. “We have a housewife onboard. Did you know that I left my mate because she would rather stay on the ship and cook than help me haggle for supplies? You better have something else up your sleeve. I don’t want more dead weight.”

“Wait,” said Dieter. “You’re ... male?”

Clepta stared at Dieter coldly. “Yes, obviously.”

“You don’t look male,” said Dieter.

“We’re different species!” said Clepta, raising his voice.

“Don’t yell,” said Lucius.

“I won’t cook if you yell,” said Yan.

Clepta closed his eyes and left the room in a huff, noting that Berenice had stolen the black ram’s horn from him as he trudged down the hallway. Good; now the computer would translate for them without him there and they might start revealing things he could use. Developing translation implants would take a lot of time and Clepta couldn’t afford to wait.

Even so, once the humans went to sleep—his tranquilizer supply was running low—the one–size–fits–all implant primers he injected upon abducting them would activate. Each primer contained an adaptive protein that would force their brains to form new neural connections; it was a delicate process, but it had worked on every species the Directorate had encountered thus far and was a critical first step to developing a translation implant. After all, humans were strange, but they couldn’t be that different from every other species, and the implants were important.

“Why aren’t we moving yet?” demanded Clepta as he strode onto the bridge, his eyes flicking between Trkn’kr and Qil’kr. The brothers had finished cleaning up Rtkalrrk’s body and were standing awkwardly around the helm control, fingers occasionally jabbing at some inputs that returned only an annoyed beep from the ship’s computer.

“We don’t know how to fly the ship,” said Qil’kr. “That was Rtkalrrk’s job.”

“You have got to be kidding me,” said Clepta. “You big blue buffoons don’t even know how to activate the autopilot on a trade ship?” He smirked as they shrunk from him. “You do realize, of course, that it takes vocal commands, right? So let’s try this again: Set a course for the nearest gray market trading post.”

Trkn’kr was the brave one today. “Uh, Ship?” His voice was a whimper but the computer would have registered it; still, nothing happened. Clepta stood incredulous, hands on his hips.

“ ‘Ship’? ‘Ship’. You called it ‘Ship’. It responds to its actual name. You ... do know the ship’s name, right?” he asked, mockingly.

“Y—yes,” said Trkn’kr. He took a deep breath, his neck rippling as he shuddered under the newfound pressure. “Simplex,” he said quietly, “go to the nearest gray market trade station.”

The Simplex’s computer chimed in accession and its engines hummed to life. Clepta glanced out the side window and saw the caped abductee start floating in the opposite from his previous direction as the Simplex accelerated. The figure retreated into the black of space until the gentle gleam of his golden helmet and the billowing crimson cape were invisible against the background.

“Oh, and we’re low on food,” said the corti. “You’re going hungry until we reach the station.”

Salvage14. Knight takes Queen. Checkmate.

By Rantarian

Iraq, Earth: Three Years Prior

“What’s crackin’, fuckhead?” Jezza shouted as he strolled back into camp and saw his old mate Adrian Saunders standing there. “I thought you were off brassing up Towel–heads?”

He gave Adrian a friendly punch on the arm and grinned at him. “Or is it about that time?”

Adrian grinned back. “It’s about that time. Where’d you fuck off to, then? Clearing IEDs?”

“Yeah,” Jezza replied grimly. “Fuckin’ arseholes planted a bunch of them outside the city. Killed a bunch of kids last week. Pipe–bombs can really fuck a lot of people up.”

“That’s fucked, that is,” Adrian said. “How long you got left before you get some time back home?”

Jezza grunted. “Who can fucking say?”

“Too bad, mate,” Adrian said sympathetically. “I’ll tell Sandy you said hi.”

“Thanks, mate,” Jezza said. “When I get back we’ll all have to have a barbie. Get our drink on.”

“Goon of fortune?” asked Adrian with a grin.

“Fuck me,” Jezza asked with a laugh, “how bogan do you think I am?”

“Depends on the weather, mate,” Adrian asserted.

“Fuck off,” Jezza said, laughing more. “I get no fuckin’ respect!”

“What’s all this shit?” Adrian asked suddenly, spotting long cuts on Jezza’s forearms in various states of healing. “Lose a fight with a cutlery drawer?”

“Yeah, right,” Jezza said, looking the wounds over. “I was trying out that knife juggling trick you’re always showing off with.”

“Mate you’re meant to catch the knives,” Adrian said.

“Fuck me,” Jezza said, slapping his forehead melodramatically. “Here was me thinking I should just hold my hands out and let the fucking things stab me!”

“Nah, mate,” Adrian replied. “That’s where you were going wrong. It’s all in the wrist, you see.”

Jezza broke into more laughter as Adrian broke into a wide grin. “Fuck me you’re an arsehole sometimes, Ades! I’ll tell you something else that’s all in the wrist...”

“If that’s an invitation to a hand–job,” Adrian replied quickly, “I’m afraid I’m going to have to decline.”

“Such a fucking arsehole,” Jezza repeated deliberately, although he never stopped grinning.

Present day, Zhadersil Machining Room

“So basically it shoots pipe–bombs,” Adrian said in summary. “Although instead of explosive charges, it all uses your kinetic technology.”

“That seems extremely dangerous,” Chir said dubiously. “How many projectiles does it expel?”

“Every pipe–bomb has around five hundred ball–bearings,” Adrian explained. “The launcher is automatic, but due to limitations on our resources it can only shoot about fifty every minute.”

“Fifty per minute?!” Zripob asked, staring at the deadly looking device. “That could annihilate... a small army.”

“I’ve already constructed two hundred of the ’pipe–bombs’,” Trycrur advised them. “More are on their way, but I think that should dissuade all but the biggest attacks.”

The four soldiers looked at each other, each of them bearing an expression of barely repressed excitement and joy. Trycrur and Adrian had spent the last two weeks together in the machining room, with Adrian describing what was required and her turning it into reality. The end result was a basic robot that could move around and shoot bombs.

“I’m going to suggest that you don’t want to be in the area when we let this thing loose,” Adrian said. “Hell, I don’t want to be in the area when we let this thing loose.”

“Adrian,” Zripob said, still staring at the machine in a sort of giddy anticipation, “this battle robot will change the face of warfare!”

“This thing?” Adrian asked, looking at it. “I don’t know about that, but we have got some ideas for those big fucking industrial cutters that the Hunters left behind.”

“They shoot a controlled burst of focused plasma,” Chir said uncertainly. “That’s how they can cut through thick hulls.”

“And if you widen the focus aperture?” asked Trycrur, clearly attempting to suppress her own excitement with unparalleled failure.

Zripob looked at her as though she’d lost her mind. “If you did that you’d just get an uncontrolled cloud of plasma just bursting out the end...”

“Yeah, mate,” Adrian said, “we’re gonna make ourselves some big fucking flamethrower tanks.”

Treoffa had not interfered with the soldiers or their activities. She knew that whatever the human was building would be deadly to his standards, and therefore most likely to break all sorts of warfare agreements between civilisations over what they were allowed to do to each other.

She allowed it because if it ever came time to turn weapons against humans themselves, it’d be extremely helpful for them to have built the weapons required to do it.

With that said, the concept of tanks bathing the flight deck in searing plasma was still unsettling to her. What kind of savage, brutal world was Earth that this sort of thing came naturally to its inhabitants? She had resolved to look into that as soon as she was back in Directorate space.

It hadn’t ended with the tanks, either. He and the Rauwryhr female had assembled a robot that crawled around and rapidly fired explosives at the enemy. Following that, in the time between building what the human had called ’Flame–Tanks’ they had co–opted the Endless Sequence’s supply of hover devices and had turned them into guided explosives.

Treoffa could only imagine the kind of devastation this would cause against any enemy coming armed with the standard galactic arsenal. Good.

While they were doing that, however, she had been sending out the hover cameras she had taken from the Endless Sequence prior to the rest of the hover equipment being harvested, and exploring the entirety of the Zhadersil. Or at least she had been exploring everything that wasn’t behind locked doors, and ever since the robot had scanned Adrian she had discovered many routes that had been sealed no longer were.

She just needed to find the command deck – she realised it was probably behind one of those doors still locked – and then she could see about taking her place as the new commander of the Zhadersil.

’Shiplady Treoffa’. She liked the sound of that.

Corti Directorate Space: Cankkr Operations Station

Overseer Jkra held his breath before exhaling a long, controlled breath that carried away some level of his tension with it.

“The Hunter homeworld?” he asked again. He knew he had heard correctly the first time, but the whole thing sounded so completely mad that he felt the need to ask again. “He went to the Hunter homeworld? Are you entirely sure of that, Ship Master Crfti?”

“I entered the coordinates myself,” Crfti told him. “He said he was going to go there and kill them all. Are all humans that crazy?”

Jkra paused, thinking about what he had learned of humans since the Hunters sent out their message. A considerable amount, but little of it pointed to that level of foolhardy ambition being the average.

“No,” he said sardonically, “it seems it was just your lucky day, ’Ship Master’. And there is still no sign of your ship?”

“None at all,” Crfti said unhappily. “It seems most likely it was destroyed by the Hunters. I can’t see how it could ever have had a chance on their homeworld.”

“Nor do I,” Jkra said, looking out of his window towards the distant stars. “But it begs the question as to why the human thought it was a good idea. Surely it must have seemed suicidal, even to him?”

He focused his gaze back on Crfti. “Now, it seems to me that you may be worthy of a replacement ship.”

Crfti looked up in surprise; that sort of thing wasn’t expected for a Ship Master who had had his vessel stolen out from under him. “I am?”

“Yes,” Jkra said, leaning back in his seat. “A single man scout ship. I think your ship is still out there somewhere, and if you ever want to command something bigger you’ll need to find it.

Adrian Saunders had taken one look at the harness Trycrur had designed for him and had known exactly what it was. The functionality was unmistakable, especially when you took the joystick into account.

”It’s a jetpack!“ Trycrur announced gleefully. Then a little more awkwardly, “Sort of, anyway. It actually hovers under standard kinetic technology. No flames anywhere!”

“This is still fuckin’ A, Trix,” Adrian said, eagerly inspecting it. “Feels like Christmas!”

“What’s that?” she asked. “Some sort of material?”

“Mater–” he started, then laughed. “No, it’s not a material. It’s a yearly religious thing. People give gifts.”

“Oh!” she said, pleased. “Good Christmas to you, then!”

He chuckled. “Good Christmas to you as well, Trix. Not that I have any idea what time of year it is actually is anymore.”

Trycrur sighed. “On Rau, my homeworld, it is the time of the great song. Music is very important to my people, it is how we remember the feeling in our history.”

“It’s been a while since I’ve heard any music,” Adrian remembered. “With everything going on, I’d almost forgotten about it, but music is real important to humans as well. Akka–Dakka, Gun N’ Roses, Johnny Farnham... good times.”

“I’m singing all the time!” Trycrur admonished him. “Well... humming.”

“What?” Adrian asked. “Bullshit, I’ve never heard you!”

“Ah,” Trycrur said, “in ultrasound...”

Adrian snorted. “Of course in ultrasound.”

They were interrupted by the arrival of Treoffa, who seemed to be on some sort of mission. “Adrian,” she said, then looked askance at the hover suit.

“Hover suit,” he said. “What’s wrong?”

Treoffa promptly returned her attention to the matter at hand. “I have some doors I need you to open.”

Five doors had needed opening before they had finally found the command deck, and with the promise of something interesting going on the entire group had been in attendance.

Treoffa had explained that since she hadn’t been able to locate any maps of the structure of the vessel in the databases she had access to, she had resorted to using the hover cams to create an internal map of the Zhadersil’s layout. When this process had been completed, she had focused on identifying substantial sections of the map that the hover cams hadn’t had access to, reasoning that any command deck must be of a substantial size on such a ship, and therefore should be easily found by such a method.

It had left her with a dozen possibilities.

The doors that Treoffa had claimed were locked did indeed resist attempts to simply open them. At least until Adrian pressed his hand against the flat metal plate that marked the side of each door. After that the door locks would audibly disengage, and were opened as easily as any other.

The first had been the Zhadersil’s medical bay, a large section separated from the rest of the ship by a clean room. It was large enough to serve a few dozen patients at the same time, and undoubtedly had facilities far beyond those of the small room Treoffa had set up for the same purpose. She and Adrian had, however, seen the clean room for what it was, and had understood the implications.

“We won’t go in there until we are sure it’s safe,” Treoffa had determined. “Your germs have a way of enduring.”

The second room had clearly been intended for the storage of weapons, although it was unfortunately empty now, and the third was full of racks that were empty of munitions. At the very least Adrian was pleased to see the suggestion of what he called ’missiles’, a type of explosive delivered by primitive rocketry.

The fourth room had been a large set of sleeping quarters, so large that Treoffa guessed that this must be the residence of the Shiplord. The others guessed as much too, although they knew comparatively little of the vessel’s history, thanks to the uncharacteristic design and elegance of the room when compared to the rest of the ship. In no culture did a common ship hand get such a large room, or the allowance to decorate it as they saw fit.

That had brought them to the fifth room, and this had been the command deck. It was grand, at least twice the size of any Treoffa had ever been on before, and polished metal surfaces gleamed under the lights. There were eleven seats, positioned variously around the two–tiered deck, most of them facing the wall–sized display on the most significant wall, although there currently seemed to be neither power to it, nor to the consoles that any of the seats faced.

One seat was set apart from the others, a seat covered in faded emblems, with interfaces built into the arms.

That seat, Treoffa did not doubt, had belonged to the Shiplord.

“This place looks like a chromed up Star Trek set,” Adrian had said once they’d gotten over the shock of actually finding it. “Look, there’s even a chair for Kirk to sit in.”

“I have no idea what you’re talking about,” Chir said, although he was clearly finding the place as wondrous as the rest of them.

“It’s an old TV show,” Adrian replied, and then when they all turned to him in confusion. “You know what? Never mind.”

“We’ve finally found it,” Treoffa said. “What I originally came to find. What Bekmer wasted his future to try and secure. My treasure, and your freedom.”

She turned to Adrian. “And it couldn’t have happened without your help. Do not think me ungrateful.”

“No worries,” Adrian said, “Just so long as you keep your part of the bargain, we’ll be alright.”

“Of course,” she said, walking over to the main chair. “But this is now the moment of truth. Adrian, I need you to sit in this chair. The rest of you should wait outside, I cannot promise that this will be entirely safe. Don’t worry, this will just take a moment.”

Adrian waited awkwardly while the Corti shoo’ed the rest of the soldiers from the room, closing the door behind them. He was a little nervous, wondering just how dangerous a sixty–five million year old process could be, but was at least reassured by the fact that Treoffa was still in the room with him.

“What’s next, then?” he asked. “Do I get to sit in the big chair?”

“Not quite,” Treoffa said, pulling out the needle–gun from her small tool–kit and pointing it at Adrian. “I’m afraid I don’t need you alive for the next part.”

Adrian paused, his eyes focused on the gun in her hand. “So it’s betrayal then?” he asked, his gaze hardening. “I always had you pegged as a cold one, but I didn’t think you’d try and pull a Bekmer here.”

“It’s not personal,” Treoffa explained. “I actually quite enjoyed the games of chess. I don’t dislike you, Adrian Saunders, merely the threat that you pose to me and what I want. Before you were at least useful as a weapon against the Hunters, but now you’ve built me machines to take over that role.”

“So, I’m guessing it’s not painkillers in that thing?” he asked. “What with my huge organs. Heh.”

“Indeed not,” she replied. “This will unfortunately be extremely painful. My condolences that your superior qualities have brought it to this.”

There were no more delays. Treoffa fired.

Adrian tried to dodge the first dart, but the space between them was small and he couldn’t get far. It hit him in the side.

Whatever the shit in those syringes was, it must be really fucked up for Treoffa to be using it so confidently on him, and he’d been humbled enough by his walk through space without needing further reminding that he wasn’t invincible.

It took a moment before they both realised that the shot had not penetrated his Wolfigator leather vest, and he used the delay to throw himself back behind the command chair, gaining what cover he could and giving himself enough time to consider his next option.

He’d been lucky once, and he wasn’t dumb enough to believe he’d be lucky twice. He had to assume the next shot would kill him, just like he always had back on Earth, and act accordingly.

“I should’ve made some proper armour,” he muttered to himself as the next shot went wide. It was clear at least that Treoffa wasn’t a soldier, she didn’t have the aim for it, and despite her technical gifts she hadn’t done anything smart like turning hover cams into toxin delivery platforms, or brought a gas mask and an aerosol poison.

“What is it with you people and your fucking pea shooters?!” he demanded as he rose from cover, his adrenaline starting to kick in. He put a foot on top of the command chair and launched himself at her, hoping to take her by surprise, or at least to shock her enough that she screwed up the next shot.

Treoffa fired again, her eyes wide with fear as she expended the last syringe.

She held her breath.

The aim was good, and if the projectile had moved any faster, it would have hit.

Instead, Adrian twisted his body violently to narrowly avoid the syringe, his hand reaching out instinctively to grab it from the air.

In normal Earth gravity he would never have had the time to complete his mid–air spin. With normal reactions he doubted he would have been able to launch the syringe back at Treoffa.

But nothing about this was normal, and he felt as surprised as Treoffa looked when the needle hit her dead centre, piercing her through her sternum and sending her toppling.

He wasn’t sure if it was the needle, the force, or the toxin that killed her, but by the time he had regained his footing she was already dead at his feet.

He looked at his hand. “I guess it really was all in the wrist.”

The computers finally awoke from their long slumber, initiating the long list of system checks required when a starship was activated after an extended shutdown period.

System Start >> Military configuration (Zhadersil)
Checking Hull Integrity >> Damage detected in: flight deck ship support system; flight deck airlocks 5, 6; secondary engine module; FTL Drive; habitation section 4; Quantum Reactor.
Checking Life Support Subsystem >> OK
Checking Reactor >> 2% Power remaining *INSUFFICIENT POWER FOR FTL*
Checking Weapons Systems >> Missile Array Zero Munitions; Mass Driver Zero Munitions; Devastator Cannon charging.
Checking Shield Systems >> OK. Activating... OK.
Checking Navigational Systems >> OK. ERROR: CANNOT FIND POSITION.
Checking Genetic Sequence >> Unrecognised configuration... Known Genetic Markers detected! Sequence has been registered as User 0.
Initiating Shiplord setup...
Request ’Great Name’... Received Response: ’Adrian Saunders’.
Request ’Given Name’... Received Response: ’Oh fuck’
Send Greeting ’Shiplord [Given Name] [Great Name] >> Announcement: “Welcome to the Zhadersil, Shiplord Oh fuck Adrian Saunders.”
Request ’Command Code’... system error, could not connect to homeworld database. Bypassing...
Interrupt! Send Emergency Notification: “Power Low – All non–vital systems shutting down. Contact V’Strak Command Technical Division for further assistance.”
Could not parse input ’You have got to be fucking kidding me.’

Salvage15. Solitude

By Rantarian

Jennifer Delaney. Early twenties, reasonably attractive, and with good prospects for a career in IT. Had a house in south Belfast, a cat and a dog as well, and some fish – intermittently anyway.

Naturally she’d followed all the news about the thing that happened in Vancouver where a bunch of aliens got themselves all beat up by a crowd of sports thugs. It had been the kind of thing that it was difficult to get away from, unless, ironically, you actually did get abducted which was actually rather scary but at least it got your mind off the weather and you didn’t have to look at those terrible News Limited front pages anymore. So there’s a silver lining right there.

Jennifer Delaney was also afraid of heights, but it was funny how you didn’t think ’Oh I’m very high up what if I fall?’ when you’re looking down from orbit.

She just wished that this particular planet looked anything like Earth. Unlike the lush blues and greens of her beautiful homeworld, this one had a more ’barren desert’ appearance. That would certainly be preferable if you suffered from allergies, but Jennifer Delaney rather liked flowers and didn’t like dust. This much would probably clog the vacuum cleaner.

Then you’d either need to either pay someone to repair it or shop around for a new one, but it’d never be quite the same as just having the old one back.

“Oh yes,” she said to herself, now speaking aloud. “One last thing. Jennifer Delaney has probably gone a bit mental.”

Nobody answered her. There wasn’t anybody left aboard the Blue Encounter.

“Well,” she corrected herself, “I suppose there are bodies, just not necessarily living ones, which is really what you’re after when you’ve starved for conversation for a while.”

The Blue Encounter had been manned, and she used the term loosely, but some extremely kind and understanding blue giraffe aliens. They had been a lot better than the one little grey alien who had kept her locked up in a cage.

He certainly hadn’t been worth saving, she told herself. She had accidentally beaten him to death while trying to convince him to simply take her home. That had been an ’oops’ moment if there had ever been one.

The next oops moment had come when all of the Giraffes had got sick and died before a week had passed. Jennifer had worried then, that she would catch whatever the Giraffes had caught, and she had been extremely careful about heaping all of the bodies in a single room to prevent the germs from spreading.

In the end she just had some mild flu symptoms and that was all. She had felt a bit silly afterwards, but had made no attempt to go anywhere near the bodies.

“I suppose that makes me the captain of this ship,” she said to the small floating camera she had following her around. One of the Giraffes had set it to track her, before they’d all died, and she hadn’t yet figured out a way to stop it.

She didn’t even want to stop it anymore, it had become so much like another companion. Like a little bird in a Disney film. Or a little bug in a Disney film.

Or– she stopped that line of thinking. “No need to go crazier faster than you have to, Jen.” she admonished herself. “You need to keep it together, keep studying. You’re not a Disney princess and no Prince is going to come and rescue you!”

She wished one would, though. Being rescued by a Prince would be really great instead of trying to learn an alien language in order to learn to fly an alien spaceship so that she could go find some more food before it all ran out.

“I wonder if they have Princes out in space?” she said, distracted again. “I can’t imagine any of those grey guys being very Royal, but those Giraffes were big at least.”

She sighed. Back to figuring out the alien language. Back to staring out the window when any understanding failed to present itself.

Back to watching the barren world below do absolutely nothing. Back to tracing the path of the object that just appeared–

Wait. That was a new thing!

“New things are good!” she told herself, getting up from her extremely comfortable seat and pressing her face to the window. “Unless it’s being abducted by aliens I suppose. Although can I still be abducted if I’m technically in the middle of an abduction?”

She shook her head. “Focus, Jen! Alien spacecraft, getting closer! Might be scary! Might be a prince!”

This possibility seemed increasingly dubious as the vessel grew closer. It was fierce looking with sharp angles and a paint–job that said ’be afraid’.

Not literally, of course, unless it said it somewhere in alien and Jennifer was fairly sure there weren’t any letters written anywhere.

That had been one thing she’d noticed early on: spaceships did not have names written on the outside, and for some reason that felt wrong.

“It’s going to dock...” she said, suddenly so afraid that she thought it might be a good idea to hide. That seemed, in fact, such a very good idea that that is exactly what she did.

She was hiding in a cupboard when the ships clanged together and interlocked. She barely allowed herself to breathe, closed her eyes, and put all her effort into listening.

She could hear something moving on the ship, its weight indicating something big, and probably something dangerous. Jennifer Delaney gripped the broom handle as tightly as she could, enough to whiten her knuckles.

She could hear it moving towards her, and she wondered if its weird alien senses could tell it exactly where she was. Maybe it could smell her, she hadn’t exactly had a good wash in months, or perhaps it could feel the vibrations of her trembling...

I’ll give you some vibrations to feel! she thought fiercely. She was ready now, for whatever might come, but she still hoped these aliens were as ridiculously fragile as all the rest had been.

She stepped from the closet as she brought up the broom handle in a blind swing. “YAAAAAHHH!”

Something firm and rough grabbed her wrist and flipped her in a single fluid movement. She exhaled sharply as she hit the decking, her eyes flying open and seeing the face of the human man who had subdued her.

His eyes were as wide in shock as hers must have been, and he released her as he seemed to suddenly realise where exactly he had been holding her.

“Bloody hell,” he said, clearly flustered but obviously Australian, “you’re a human woman!”

“Bloody hell,” she repeated, too stunned to do anything else, in her own heavily Irish accent, “so are you.”

Three months ago

“What makes you think I care?” Bekmer demanded. “Why in all of the stars would I give any kind of damn about your poor choices, human? In fact, I should be laughing! Ha ha ha... HA!” Adrian leaned back against the brig’s door, with nowhere better to be than right here. It had been two months now since Chir, Kermit and Trix had collectively decided to give up on the Zhadersil, and with rather more sorrow had given up on Adrian as well.

He couldn’t blame them, he could now see that his behaviour had become increasingly erratic after the Zhadersil’s reactors failed to power the ship. It hadn’t been made any better by gaining access to the news feeds about humans being dumped into space, or set upon by Hunter patrols who were coming properly armed.

That was the situation that Adrian had created. Not a future of hope by any means, just one of worse fear and greater tragedy.

Story of his life, really.

“I thought maybe you’d like a visitor,” Adrian replied. “It must have been a while since your last one.”

“Treoffa came at times to gloat,” Bekmer said. “But I don’t think that counts. And if you are my only option for conversation, well... please vent me now!”

“You’re all talk,” Adrian told him. “If you wanted to die you’d stop eating. I don’t care enough about you to start force feeding your sorry arse.”

Bekmer winced. “I would not be able to process nutrients inserted in that manner.”

Adrian laughed. “If only I thought you were actually making a joke, Bekmer, I might have planned a second visit.”

“Don’t worry about me, human,” Bekmer replied irritably. “I will somehow manage to survive without being graced by your company. Just remember to keep feeding me and make sure we don’t get invaded by any more Hunters.”

Blue Encounter: Present Day

“Uh,” Adrian said, looking at the pretty, blue–eyed redhead he’d just slammed into the floor. “Human man. And you’re Irish!”

She blinked, confused for a moment before realising what she said. “Oh, right... sorry.”

He helped her back to her feet. “You’re alone here,” he said. “I saw the bodies.”

She froze, wide–eyed like a deer in the headlights. That had clearly been the wrong thing to say, but it seemed that the time he’d spent with no human contact had not improved his ability to speak to women. “That may have come out wrong,” he admitted. “Obviously you’ve been through some rough times.”

“They just died,” she said, her voice wavering. “They all got sick a while after I got here.”

“What about you?” he asked, glancing in the direction of the room with the corpses in it. They’d been similar to the technicians that Bekmer had had on his crew, but their bodies were swollen and covered with bulbous growths. It hadn’t looked like a good way to go.

“I had a bit of a fever,” she said. “But I got better! I’m fine now!”

“Yeah,” he said, “yeah of course.” That was clearly important to her; Adrian had seen enough people in fucked up situations to know when they weren’t dealing with it. Being the lone survivor of a plague, stuck in space for who knew how long... well, that’d mess with anyone’s head.

“So,” she said, “are you here to rescue me?”

Three months ago

If there was anything good to be said for hard vacuum, it was that it was quiet, and the view was amazing. He had to admit that as far as planets went, Affrag had an extremely Earth–like appearance.

Adrian had spent about ten minutes admiring that view, drifting next to the Zhadersil’s outer hull. He’d come out here to inspect the damage that had been covered over by space debris until it had all been ejected by the Zhadersil’s shields turning on. Now the whole ship was clean and visible, and he could see the long gash torn in its starboard side.

“Not sure I’m going to be able to fix that,” he’d determined pretty early on, but he’d set about investigating the damaged areas anyway – it had seemed like the thing to do, and he wasn’t ready to give up on the old ship just yet.

There was every sign of something big having hit the ship, and since there had been nothing in the ship logs about having been damaged before Xagh had abandoned it, he guessed it had been an unfortunate collision with space rocks.

“Zhadersil,” he said, speaking directly to the ship computer. It was still active, along with basic life support, but that was about it. “What was this section?”

“Shiplord Adrian Saunders,” the ship responded, “external damage is detected in secondary engine module and habitation section 4.”

“So the primary engine module is undamaged?” he asked.

“Shiplord Adrian Saunders,” the ship responded, “primary engine module is undamaged and unpowered. There is insufficient power to activate the primary engine module. There is insufficient power to activate the secondary engine module. Warning: Damage detected in secondary engine module.”

“Fucking reactor again,” he muttered. It all came down to power, it had always come down to power. They had spent two months trying to fix that problem – the Quantum Reactor was a total fucking mess – and in the end the others had decided that it was hopeless, and they had left.

Adrian wasn’t ready to give up on it quite yet, though, and every news report he heard of humans being killed or exiled just furthered his resolve. He couldn’t give up, not when he alone had command of such a powerful vessel. Not when the Hunters had declared war on humanity, and on him. Not as long as there was hope.

They’d originally intended to try re–routing power from the Hunter ships through the secondary conduits. That had ended with an electrical fire on the flight deck and half the flight–deck relays burning out, a situation which Adrian had personally assessed as ’not particularly ideal’.

Trix had determined that the only real way to channel enough power into the ancient ship would have been to inject the power across a wide distribution of nodes. Good in theory, she’d said, but impossible in practice.

Seeing all that empty space in the damaged section, though... Adrian couldn’t help but wonder if she’d been too quick to give up on that plan. Maybe if he parked a couple of the Hunter ships in there, he’d be able to hook up enough relays...

Maybe. It was a big maybe.

Blue Encounter: Present Day

“There’s not much worth taking,” the man said as he busily rifled through the cargo bay. “This all the food you got left?”

“Y–yes,” Jen answered, worried suddenly that this was a raid and not a rescue. “They don’t taste very good.”

“Just needs some tomato sauce,” the man said. “But they’re alright for a quick snack, and I know a guy who can’t get enough. I’d say you had about a week left before you started going hungry.”

“I figured out how to put out a message,” she said. “But I didn’t know their language. I was hoping someone would come...”

“Nobody was going to come, at least nobody you’ll ever want to meet,” he said flatly, looking at her with his cool eyes. “Nobody out there’s going to help a human.”

“Why?” she asked. The way he said the word ’human’ clearly carried some deep meaning. The blue giraffes hadn’t seemed to have any particular issue with her, unless they simply didn’t know what she was.

“Because the guys they’re all scared of are scared of us,” he explained. “They’re called ’Hunters’, and I’m running around in one of their ships.”

Two months ago

“You’re very optimistic, human,” Bekmer said. “Another visitation so soon? People will begin to talk!”

“Fuck you, baldy,” Adrian replied wearily. “I’ve got questions.”

“Oh dear,” Bekmer said, pacing his cell. “What’s the matter? Nobody else to answer them? Oh that’s right... you said you killed Treoffa, and everyone else abandoned you. How unfortunate.”

“You’ll answer,” Adrian said, his eyes narrowing.

Bekmer scoffed. “And what? You’ll torture me if I don’t? Kill me? Savage!”

“Let’s say you don’t answer,” Adrian posited, his eyes narrowing. “I’ll deduct one meal for every answer you don’t give. You like being hungry, fuckface?”

Bekmer stared daggers at him, but finally relented. “Fine. Ask your questions.”

“There’s a big fucking hole in the hull,” he said. “I thought I could use the exposed relays to supply the Zhadersil with enough power, but they’re shut down. I can’t get the ship to activate them.”

“Hm,” Bekmer said, considering the matter. “Still haven’t got the reactor working I see?”

“The reactor is close to dead,” Adrian told him. “Totally fucking useless except for keeping the lights on.”

“And your plan is to inject power across multiple sections by parking other ships in the hole in the hull,” Bekmer said, understanding. “Intelligent. Was it your idea?”

“No,” Adrian said, “and that doesn’t matter. Tell me how to keep the relays active.”

“I don’t know,” Bekmer said with a sigh, then put his hands up defensively. “No, that isn’t unwillingness on my behalf, simply ignorance. If you want me to help on this, well... I want to stretch my legs.”

Adrian was silent. He stared at the small grey alien as if he could read the underhanded plan the creature was hatching, but the Corti’s face was only sneering arrogance. “Fine,” he grated through clenched teeth. “I’ll think about it! But if you’re fucking with me, I’ll break one of those stretchy legs.”

Liberated Hunter Ship: Present Day

“Here,” Adrian told the Irish girl, passing her a wrapped package. “I made lunch, but you look like you need it more than I do.”

She took it hesitantly, unwrapping it slowly until she saw the meat and salad ’sandwich’ he’d managed to assemble. Then she unwrapped it quickly and jammed it into her mouth unceremoniously.

He grinned, double checking the flight console to make sure everything was in order and waiting for her to finish before continuing the conversation any further.

She breathed heavily as she finished the last bite, and he wordlessly handed her the canteen of fresh water. He’d been lucky, really, to have had access to the hunting grounds of Affrag. With the weapons that Trycrur had made for him, and the hover pack to give him air superiority, he had easily managed to keep his larder stocked with plenty of meat. Recently he had begun trying various plant–life, testing at first to determine taste and toxicity, and had discovered several plants that had suited his needs.

“Thanks,” she said, burping gently into her fist. “I... never got your name?”

“Adrian Saunders,” he told her, checking off the last of the settings. “Captain in the ADF, but more recently Shiplord of the Zhadersil. You?”

“Jenny Delaney,” she replied. “I work in IT. Where did you get that food?”

“Straight from the source,” he said, “one hundred percent natural. Some kind of crocodile creature in that one, but I’ve got other sorts in the meat locker.”

“We’re not going home?” she asked, clearly disappointed.

“We can’t,” he said. “They’ve put a barrier up around the whole fucking system, pardon my French. You know, when I was a boy the shows always had space full of beautiful green women who’d throw themselves at the Captain of a starship. Turns out it’s just full of fucking arseholes. Pardon again.”

“What!?” she asked in surprise, clearly not uncomfortable by the casual swearing he was having so much difficulty in avoiding. “Why would they do that?”

“They’re afraid of us,” he told her.

“You said they were afraid of these ’Hunters’!” she replied accusingly. “What are you doing with their ship, anyway?”

“I actually have several,” he admitted a little uncomfortably. These were the kinds of details he’d hoped she wouldn’t pick up on before getting back to the Zhadersil. “I, uh... well, that is to say there was a bit of a sortie and I won.”

“Against how many?!” she asked, looking around. “This ship is easily big enough to fit a hundred!”

“Yeah...” he said, stretching out the word. “I’d say there were a thousand maybe.”

The look she gave him then was one of profound doubt. “Now Adrian, I don’t want to suggest you’re not a capable soldier, but I doubt one man could hold out against a thousand aliens! What about their technological superiority?! They must have had lasers to shoot straight through you! They could have blown you up with bombs!”

He frowned. “I didn’t fight them personally!” he said. “I’m not a total fucking idiot. I just sort of... flushed them all out the airlock.”

“What... like in Alien?” she asked, eyebrow raised.

“Finally,” he said with a laugh. “Somebody gets it!”

Jennifer Delaney. Mid–twenties, reasonably attractive, and completely lost in space. Mortgage in default, dog and cat long gone, and fish... well, the less said there the better really.

She’d been rescued by a man – he wasn’t handsome like a Disney Prince, but he was definitely a man – and hadn’t starved to death, so today was better than yesterday so far, but if she was perfectly honest with herself the Zhadersil had not been what she was expecting. Instead of a super–high tech wonder, it was more like a broken down old race horse that had been put to pasture where it had inevitably died and now somebody was living inside its corpse while it drifted in the cold depths of deep space.

Jennifer Delaney may not be the best person for analogies, they tended to get away from her somewhat.

“I see what you mean, Captain,” she said, preferring for the time being to refer to him by the title that wasn’t stupid. “It really is completely fucking huge!”

They were standing on the Zhadersil’s flight deck, and there were several more Hunter ships present, as well as a smaller ship of another design with a big hole cut in the side. Dwarfing them all was a far larger vessel of similar design to the small vessel, and that was a ship that looked high–tech. Jenny privately wondered why he didn’t just live in that one, but since they’d only just met she was concerned that maybe that was a personal question and she didn’t want to insult the only human and sapient being she’d met in God knew how long.

“There doesn’t seem to be anyone else here, though,” she said, looking about the quiet deck. “I’d have thought that with all these ships...”

She went quiet when she saw his expression harden. This was clearly a topic that bothered him. “Sorry if that was the wrong thing to say.”

“There used to be some others,” he said. “They left by various means.”

“But you stayed,” she said before she could help with herself. It was just so damned curious to find someone else who had been living alone and didn’t seem to have a problem with it.

He nodded. “I stayed. Come on, I’ll show you to one of the better rooms.”

She thanked him, and let him help her with the few belongings she’d assembled over the course of her solitude. Most of it had been assembled from things the Blue Giraffes had had in their cargo hold, but it had become hers by right of being the only one to survive. Technically she supposed that meant that the whole ship should have been hers, but the surplus of dead aliens inside of it didn’t exactly make it prime property.

Adrian hadn’t had any problem with stripping out everything of value, however. How he’d learned to do that was anybody’s guess and frankly she had been a little too worried that he was some kind of thug to think about asking any questions like that, or really any questions at all.

Now that she did have time to think about asking questions, it seemed like it would be an awkward turn of conversation and really if Jenny had any serious conversational skills she wouldn’t have gotten into IT. Or lived alone.

“This is impressive,” she said as he ushered her into the room intended for her use. It was clearly ornamented with engravings in the metal walls, decorated with faded images and pictures of dinosaurs for some strange reason. “What’s with the dinosaurs?” she asked, pointing out a Triceratops in one engraving.

“Dinosaurs built this,” he said simply, and then when she looked at him with an expression of ’that must be crap!’ he added: “Yeah, I know it’s nuts.”

“So this is home now, huh?” she asked him as she placed her belongings on one of the surfaces. “I guess that makes us neighbours?”

“If you want to stick around,” he said, “I’ll be happy to have you. I’m starting to have conversations with the computer.”

“With the computer? It’s voice activated?” she asked. “Is it intelligent?”

“I wouldn’t call it intelligent,” he said, “but it does understand basic commands.”

And then, to demonstrate his point, he spoke to the room. “Zhadersil, play some music in this room.”

The room responded with a harsh, hissing language and music began to play. It was a strange, electric–sounding instrument strummed in a manner that reminded her somewhat of the orient. There were soft lyrics of that same harsh, hissing language.

She screwed up her features at the unpleasantness of the sound. “It’s a pity about that awful singing,” she said.

“Oh, right,” he replied. “You don’t have a translator. We’re going to have to figure out what to do about that.”

Quod erat demonstrandum pars: VI

by devourerkwi

A complete listing of all parts of Quod Erat Demonstrandum is available here.

Special thanks are due to /u/iamcptplanet for many of the ideas used in this series and in this chapter in particular, as well as invaluable discussion, editing, and enthusiasm.

According to the official timeline on the Jenkinsverse Wiki, the Corti abducted the first humans around 2,000 years before the Vancouver incident. This is the story of those abductees, set in the year 70 AD.

Dramatis personæ

Lucius Bellator Maximus, a Roman legionary from Legio V Alaudæ, based at the camp Castra Vetera in Xanten, Germania Inferior, serving Emperor Vespasian of the Flavian dynasty

Dieter, a barbarian from the Batavi tribe that was revolting against Rome

Berenice, an Egyptian woman, and her son, Isidorus, from the slums of Alexandria

Yan, a Chinese concubine from the court of and consort to Emperor Ming of Han in the Eastern Han dynasty

Clepta, a corti abductor, scientist, and trader

Consua, Clepta’s former mate and staff biologist

Glossarium

Castra vetera: Old camp

Centurion: A mid-level officer in the Roman army who commanded 80 men

Simplex: Naïve

Sub rosa: Under the rose ("in secret", "covertly")

Quod erat demonstrandum: Which had to be demonstrated

Berenice’s grin was so wide Lucius thought her face might split in two. He wanted to ask her why she was so happy but the corti had left and he had taken their ability to talk to each other with him. Lucius resigned himself to quiet, figuring he might as well clear his mind.

“I was tricky again,” she whispered mischievously, in Latin.

“What did you say?” asked Yan, also in Latin.

“I was tricky again!” said Berenice triumphantly. “I was tricky and he didn’t know and now we can talk.”

“Mother stole the magic black thing,” explained Isidorus.

Berenice cackled gleefully and produced the black ram’s horn that let them talk to each other. “Let me see it,” said Lucius.

“No!” said Berenice. “It’s mine now and I will keep it safe. I couldn’t keep my son safe from the gray man but I can keep the black horn safe from you.” She spat the last word with such vitriol that Lucius winced.

“From me?” asked Lucius.

“You!” she shouted. “You Romans conquered my childhood home, destroyed the Great Temple, and have slaughtered my people for four years! Jerusalem burns, and you, Centurion, are responsible!”

“I know nothing of the Jews and their rebellion against Emperor Vespasian,” said Lucius defiantly. “I was stationed in Xanten at Castra Vetera. I’m the Third Centurion in Legio V Alaudæ; my men and I were in Germania Inferior putting down a ... different rebellion.”

“If you fight the Jews with the savagery with which you fight Batavia, it is no wonder they wish to leave Flavian rule,” said Dieter quietly.

“Don’t speak to me of savagery, barbarian,” snapped Lucius. “I fight because I need to, not because I like it. Your people shun civilization. We try to bring you order and you bite our outstretched hands.”

“You destroy everything you touch!” shrieked Berenice.

“Mother, you’re scaring me,” whimpered Isidorus, clutching at his mother’s arm. Berenice glared at Lucius and held her son close, the other arm cradling the magic black ram’s horn.

Lucius huffed. “I will not apologize for my people taking what is rightly ours.”

“We were here long before you were, Centurion,” hissed Berenice, “and we will endure long after your empire topples.”

“Perhaps. But now we have the stars to conquer and a way to reach them. Nothing can stop Rome,” said Lucius.

“I can stop you,” said Dieter.

“I already bested you in single combat, Dieter. Were it not for a stray arrow I would have finished the job.”

“I can stop you,” he repeated.

“No, Dieter, you can’t. You are brave and strong but you lack precision. You see an enemy to kill, not a battlefield to conquer. Do you even know why I chose to fight you, of all the others I could have fought?”

“Because I am the strongest,” said Dieter proudly. “No Batavian fights better.”

“No,” said Lucius. “I chose to fight you because you were guarding my true objective: Your army’s rations. Men cannot fight without food.”

“I think this Clepta understands tactics,” said Yan, arms resting on bent knees and head tilted sideways on her arms. “He gave us food so we would be strong. He expects us to fight for him.”

“You’re right,” conceded Lucius, “but it’s not just that. He needs us for something. We need to find out what.”

“I will do that,” said Yan. “I am consort to the Emperor and skilled in the ways of the court.”

“You?” laughed Lucius. “I have never seen a woman who looks or dresses as you do. Surely Emperor Vespasian would have more conventional tastes.”

“I don’t know who that is,” said Yan. “I am consort to Emperor Ming of Han, ruler of China.”

“You must be a very good cook,” said Dieter, eyeing Yan with a lascivious grin.

“Only for emperors,” said Yan, turning away from him. He frowned in consternation at the instant rebuff.

“Enough,” said Lucius, using his commander’s voice. “We need to come up with a plan.”

“Is it safe to talk? He might have spies,” said Yan.

“He can’t. There is nowhere to hide here and it’s not as if he can listen to us from the other side of the ship,” said Lucius.

“Then we must decide when to strike,” said Dieter. “He is but one and the tall blue striped things are not strong.”

“We should bide our time,” said Lucius. “We need to learn more about our enemy and our situation if we want any hope of reaching our objective.”

Clepta sat back in the uncomfortable metal chair in his quarters, the five humans fitting neatly onto his viewscreen, their conversation fed into his implant as he listened. Good, he thought. They’ll never truly trust one another. He muted them and set the computer to record them continually and alert him if they mentioned any of the standard keywords—mostly those about escaping, revolting, or violence in general. Then he queried the flight plan and noted that he had enough time to make a few calls before they arrived at the gray market trading post, so he connected to the first one and saw his former mate’s face replace the humans on his viewscreen.

“I still hate you,” she said. “Why did you call me?”

“Hello, Consua. Why did you pick up?” he replied.

“Because I could use a good laugh. How far in over your head are you this time?”

“I don’t know yet. But I need a biologist. If you’re willing to meet me at this location,” he said, relaying encrypted coordinates using their old personal cipher, “I’ll show you something you’ve never seen before.”

“The last time you said that I nearly died,” said Consua. “And then you left me because I was scared to repeat the mistake.”

“Well, it’s your choice,” said Clepta. “But I have a new species and the implant primer should start taking effect during their next sleep cycle.”

She grimaced; Clepta knew that she loved watching neural adaptations as they happened. “Fine. I’ll think about it,” she said.

“Great. See you there,” he said.

“No promises,” said Consua, reaching for her viewscreen. The line disconnected.

Clepta allowed himself a moment of self-satisfaction before calling his next contact. “Clepta!” exclaimed the guvnuragnaguvendrugun, his colors flittering through the hues of excitement and predatory opportunism. “Always a pleasure doing business with such a bad haggler. To what do I owe the pleasure?”

“Don’t berate potential customers, Jorm. I’m swinging by for a few meetings and I need more supplies while I’m there.”

“Standard stuff?” asked Jorm, his strips turning a deep, swirling brown, the color of bored resignation.

“Yes,” said Clepta, “but I want bulk discounts.”

Jorm turned yellow and pink and laughed heartily. “Clepta, your, uh, experiments never last long enough to make use of ‘bulk discounts’, at least not since you jettisoned Consua. Are you sure you’re not about to make the third-biggest financial mistake you’ve made since we met?”

“Third?”

“Getting rid of Consua was the first. Asking me for a loan was the second.”

Clepta sighed. It had taken him far too long to pay that off. “Look, Jorm, I’m sending over a shopping list,” he said, tapping some more buttons on his console. “Just have it ready for me when I get to the station, OK?”

Jorm sat and looked through the list, turning white and gray and green, his puzzlement clearly visible. “Are you sure this isn’t a typo?” he asked.

“Which part?”

“All of it,” said Jorm quizzically.

“No, it’s accurate.”

“I don’t think I have that many dizi rats, Clepta.”

“Then I’ll take what you have, and increase the nutrient balls to make up for it.”

“OK. Here’s your estimate,” said Jorm, tapping a few buttons of his own and turning the bright blue of hope. Clepta’s console chimed and he read the number.

“That’ll do,” said Clepta. “I’ll see you when I see you.”

“Thanks for your business,” said Jorm. “Just a reminder: I expect payment in full upon delivery.”

“Yes, of course,” said Clepta. He disconnected the link. He had no intention of paying old Jorm, and he had two deathworlders to make sure he got away with it.

Salvage16. Help

By Rantarian

Jennifer Delaney had to admit the defences that the crew of the Zhadersil had built were impressively dangerous, although the robot that shot pipe–bombs had a tendency to crawl around in a creepy manner, turning and refocusing its camera on anyone walking by. Its appearance was almost spiderlike and she’d never liked spiders much, or any bug for that matter. Except for ladybirds, and maybe butterflies, she liked those.

“How does it know what to shoot at?” she’d asked when Adrian had explained the basic premise of the killing machine. “It won’t start shooting at me, will it now?”

“As I understand it, it’s able to tell who the bad guys are, but just to be safe, I’ll register you. We wouldn’t want to have rescued you from starvation only to have you blown to bits, would we?”

Jennifer frowned, furrowing her brow slightly. She’d known soldiers in Ireland, but the only other people she’d known who spoke so casually of weapons and killing were gamers, and none of that was even close to real. She wondered if Adrian had some form of PTSD; it didn’t seem unlikely given his experiences, but she felt it would be a bit difficult to ask. How did you ask that sort of thing anyway? ’Hi, you seem like a bit of a psycho, but are you suffering from any post–traumatic stress disorders?’

She doubted that would be well received.

“So,” she said, more conversationally in order to change the subject, “how did you end up getting abducted? On base? On the battlefield?”

“Camping,” he said, although he seemed displeased by the question. “It was while I was camping. In the bush.”

“Oh,” she replied, a little disheartened by the limited response. “For me it was outside this pub my dad runs. It’s a family business, been in the family for generations. I think my great–grandfather got it off a man who owed him money. Anyway, I was waiting for some friends to come by and pick me up. We were going to go to one of those ’old film’ nights at the cinema. ’Stars of the Silver Screen’ was it’s name, I think that night it was supposed to be Audrey Hepburn.”

She paused for a moment, considering what she’d just said. “I wonder if they thought I ditched them?”

“Maybe at first,” he said after an uncomfortable moment. “Later... probably not. So which Audrey Hepburn movie?”

Two Months Ago

Bekmer had cooperated in the end, seeming as pleased as he could be about the time outside of his little cage. Together they’d ventured outside of the Zhadersil, working by the light of Affrag’s reflective glow.

“The ship is automatically deactivating the relays,” Bekmer had determined after repeatedly testing a range of them. “It’s the system protecting itself. You will need to terminate them correctly before you can have any expectation of functionality.”

Adrian surveyed the mess of the wreckage. “There’s got to be a million of the fucking things need doing!”

“Likely only in excess of forty thousand,” Bekmer said, more than a little smugly. “So you should be done in mere months [months] if you work at it!”

“We’ve already been here for nearly four months, fuckwit,” Adrian replied sharply. “How long before the Hunters come back? How many do you reckon will be coming next time?”

Bekmer was contemplatively silent. “If you trace back to the larger conduits, there will be maybe a tenth of number. Terminate those. It will be much quicker.”

“Four thousand then,” Adrian said, looking over the cavernous space with a heavy sense of resignation. “That’ll still be a fucktonne of work.”

Zhadersil: Present Day

It had been three days since Jen had arrived on the ship, and Adrian had spent most of the time trying to get her properly acquainted with where things were and how things were done. For the first time in a long time Adrian felt some gratitude towards the Corti for seeing fit to install a translator unit in his own head; it was damned inconvenient for Jen to interact with the Zhadersil’s computer system without one and she had to guess at every response it gave.

For the first time ever, Adrian wished that Bekmer was still around. The bald little alien had been a total fucking arsehole, but he’d have been able to install any of the devices that Adrian had ’recovered’ from the Corti corpses that had remained aboard the Endless Sequence, given the right impetus.

Add to that the fact that she had most likely taken out the entire crew of the Blue Encounter and she was in desperate need of the inoculation that had kept him from killing everyone on the Zhadersil. Until that happened he couldn’t afford to let any non–human onto the ship, not even an enemy, in case the illnesses that every human carried within them managed to escape into a major population. The galaxy didn’t need another reason to find humanity terrifying.

“This,” he explained to her, sitting in front of the console on the Endless Sequence, “is the detection array. This is a Corti scout ship, so it’s got better sensors than most. I had... a guy I knew set this up a while back so it was translating in English. Speaks in English too, if you set it to vocal interaction. It’s always pushing the information through to the Zhadersil, so we’ll be told whenever it picks up something weird.”

“So this is how we avoid nasty surprises?” Jen asked, looking over the console. “It is in English! That’s a sight for sore eyes, let me tell you that!”

He smiled at her. It must have been a long time since she’d been able to simply read anything. In a society of hyper–advanced technology, she wouldn’t even have been able to find pen and paper to write anything for herself.

“Is it possible to set up the Zhadersil computer to use English as well?” she asked. “Maybe so it doesn’t sing in that awful voice?”

He gave a short chuckle. “I asked that same guy whether it was possible, but the computer systems were too different. I guess you’d know more about that sort of thing than me, being in IT.”

“Yeah,” she said, disappointed. “You’d at least need some sort of conversion software, but I wouldn’t know where to begin...”

“Look,” he said, “I used to be a sort of engineer. In the end that didn’t help me all that much, but I knew the general rules and that helped. Some stuff... well the laws of physics don’t change just because we’re in space.”

“I’m not sure that that idea can be applied to software,” she replied. “A completely different computer system will use a completely different language. There may be some similarities, or there might not. It doesn’t help me any that I have no idea how any of this technology works.”

“Well then,” he said, passing her a tablet device. “While I scan for Corti vessels, you start reading this.”

“What is it?” she asked, taking the device and playing with the buttons.

“That,” he said, “will let you access the Help interface. I need you to learn these systems.”

One Month Ago

Bekmer was sitting on the uncomfortable bed that was bolted to the wall. The only item of furniture in his cell, unless you counted the bucket that the human had given him to relieve himself in. It was a disgusting receptacle, one the human rarely cleaned properly, when it was cleaned at all.

At first he had suspected that the human had left it there as a form of passive torture, and had displayed his feelings of the matter by hurling its contents over the wall. The human had been disgusted, and extremely displeased much to Bekmer’s own enjoyment, until he had simply returned the emptied bucket to Bekmer and left the mess as it was. It had remained that way for five miserable days until the human finally washed it down.

Bekmer no longer believed the bucket was any kind of torture, but merely a task that the human had no desire to deal with and therefore performed it in the most expedient way possible. Bekmer had not made another mess, he hadn’t seen the point.

There had also been the excursions the human had allowed him to go on. As much as he despised the human, he had come to despise his boredom more. He was a Corti, a brilliantly intelligent being of a proud people, and he did not belong in a cage. He could not endure in a cage with nothing to do, nothing to see, nothing further to think about. At first he had insulted the human as a point of defiance, but now... now it was merely a ritual they both performed before Bekmer acquiesced. They both knew it, and Bekmer hated the human even more for knowing, but he still played the game.

“The Hunter ships are connected,” the human had explained in the most recent of his infrequent business visits. “The relays are all active after being properly terminated – a thankless fucking job that was, by the way. I think we might be ready to fire them up.”

“Then fire them up,” Bekmer replied. “That was not a question.”

“Last time I tried that, I almost set fire to the fucking flight deck,” the human said. “I’d much prefer it if you were out there making sure we avoid another inferno.”

“I know this may disappoint you, human,” Bekmer replied drily, “but I am not a firefighter.”

“I wouldn’t be surprised if you burned like a twig,” the human returned. “I just need you to monitor the output and shut the fucking thing down if it looks like it’s going to burn.”

“And what will you be doing?” Bekmer asked acidly. “While I have all the fun?”

“I’ll be doing anything else,” the human replied. “Like keeping the navigation set, and firing the FTL.”

“What is wrong with the navigation system?” Bekmer asked.

The human grunted, a wonderful reminder of his savagery. “It hasn’t updated in sixty–five million years. It tries to contact the fucking database about seconds after booting up, fails and then reboots.”

“You’re entering coordinates directly?” Bekmer asked, unable to contain his concern. “Absolute or relative?”

“Relative,” the human replied. “It’s not easy to do, but I’ve spent about twelve fucking hours practicing.”

“That is exceedingly optimistic, human,” Bekmer replied. “There are two possible ways that this plan gets us killed. First, if the FTL system gets corrupt data, we could end up anywhere, in anything. Second, if the warp tunnel requires live data, it may collapse when it gets corrupt data.”

“I’m going to say that’s bad,” the human said. “How bad?”

“Depending on how it collapses we could be disintegrated, dumped out in fragments, or just dropped somewhere else,” Bekmer explained. “There’s no way you’ll be able to do this with a broken Navigational unit, and I’m not letting you kill me in the crazy attempt!”

“Then what the fuck do you suggest?” the human asked irritably. “I can’t make the system work when it keeps rebooting.”

Bekmer blinked, shaking his head. The human was so stupid, to keep trying to make the unworkable work when there was such a better option being so obviously available. “Take me aboard the Endless Sequence and I’ll patch the data through to the Zhadersil,” he said impatiently. “It won’t be seamless, but it shouldn’t kill us either.”

“Are you sure you can do it?” the human asked, clearly not understanding who it was dealing with. Of course, a primitive beast from a backwater planet could hardly be expected to comprehend the abilities of those who graduated from the Corti academies, as it would naturally have nothing with which to compare.

“It should only take me a few [hours],” Bekmer replied curtly. Although he was aware that it would take significantly less than this, he always made a habit of underpromising and overdelivering, and this habit did not fail to extend to the various trite tasks the human put to him. “Do not doubt my skill, human!”

It would be a very long time before Bekmer realised that he had just been played.

Sesavrt Research Station: Two Weeks Ago

There had been hardly any real work done in the time since Trycrur had retuned to the Dominion. Instead she had been debriefed, then debriefed a second time, and then a third. For a full week it had seemed that all anybody wanted her to do was to talk about her experiences aboard the Zhadersil. That and tell them where it was. She was not unaware of their interest in the technology that had built the ship – especially in light of revelations that it had been built by ancient sapients of the same Deathworld that now belonged to the humans – but she had thus far resisted telling them all of the details. This had been something that the three of them, being Chir, Zripob and herself, had predicted and had discussed as they made their return journey under cloak in a reclaimed Hunter vessel, and they had all agreed that their story would include a ship with functional FTL, rather than the useless husk they had abandoned.

Abandoned along with Adrian. Trycrur still felt pangs of guilt over that, as raw and fresh as the day they had left as he slept. They had left him a recording, explaining their reasoning, explaining that his erratic behaviour had been too concerning to risk angering him in a discussion over what they were planning. He had not been willing to give up, even when all evidence had pointed to a dying vessel – no, that wasn’t right... a dead vessel with delusions of survival – and that nothing could be done by a mere handful of individuals to fix it.

Still, it hadn’t been as though they’d simply doomed him to stay there, had it? They’d only taken one Hunter vessel between them, in spite of their preference to avoid them altogether where possible. They’d been guilty enough to have left him with everything, and Trycrur wondered if the others also predicted that the human would remain there until forced to leave. She knew he was stubborn enough, but she thought the main problem was hope. Every successful bit of work aboard the Zhadersil had dangled hope in front of them; hope to restore the ship, and hope to use it to take the fight to the Hunters. It had taken the flight deck fire to destroy the hope in the rest of them, but it hadn’t been enough for Adrian. Hope was his poison.

She sighed. She had never used to think this way. Before being abducted by the Corti, and before meeting Adrian, she had been a capable Weapons Designer for the Dominion, focused on finding ways to refine and advance current technology. Upon her return she had started to turn the ideas she had discussed with Adrian into living reality, only to be pulled from the Design team for psychological review. They had suspected her time spent with the human – and his beautiful, evil mind – had corrupted her way of thinking. Why else build weapons that could kill so indiscriminately?

It could be true, however; Trycrur had once been a naive worker following the status quo. The Rauwryhr that had returned had wanted to ’fuck shit up.’ She was beginning to suspect that the two were even more distinct, and that the latter lacked the home to return to. Everybody had noticed the change, and they were now past the time of tolerance and to the stage of trying to get her medical assistance. Even her two husbands had overstepped their bounds and tried to have her assessed.

And so Trycrur found herself living a life where nobody understood her. In the quiet moments she found that had even started to miss the Zhadersil, at least as it was after the Corti had been dealt with and the ship had considered Adrian to be its new master. There hadn’t been any bureaucracy getting in the way of what she enjoyed doing there, and no psychological examinations to keep her ’deteriorated mental state’ in check.

So that was why, when Chir’s call had come through, she’d hurried to connect the link.

“Chir,” she greeted him cheerily. “It is good to see you again.”

“And you,” he replied. “How is life after the Zhadersil treating you?”

She hesitated, long enough that he must have noticed. “They are treating me for a deteriorated mental state. I do not believe that there is anything wrong, however.”

“They’re doing the same to me,” Chir replied. “And it seems I was absent for longer than I had thought. My world is now part of the Dominion, and they have only just released me from questioning.”

“Have you heard anything about the situation with the Corti Directorate?” she asked. “Last I heard they had disavowed any connection to Bekmer and Treoffa’s actions.”

“The situation hasn’t changed,” Chir replied dourly. “The Dominion appear disinclined to push the matter, especially with their attention on the Celzi. There is no continuing investigation.”

Trycrur bared her teeth angrily. “Those... those ’fuckers’!” she spat. “They didn’t tell me that!”

“They didn’t tell me that, either,” Chir said, anger clearly evident in his eyes. “I got it from a friend with higher connections. I got something else as well: the Dominion is gearing up to go looking for the Zhadersil.”

Salvage17. Warp

by Rantarian

This work is an addition to the Jenkinsverse universe created by /u/Hambone3110.

Where relevant, measurements and explanation is given in brackets following their alien names.

All Chapters

Zhadersil: Two Weeks Ago

"I will need to monitor power flow from the source," Bekmer told the human. "It may not be sufficient to shut down power in the Zhadersil's internal systems if things go awry."

He was not pleased with the fact that he had been taken advantage of, and now it was time for turnabout. The human had posited the concept of using other vessels FTL drives to reinforce the main bubble. A lengthy consideration had determined that that would be in no way suitable, but that it could potentially allow the assisting vessel to carry on while all else would be subjected to the normal consequences of a collapsing warp field.

"I'm not a fucking idiot," the human said, "you just want to get into a spaceship while I'm busy somewhere else."

"What I want is to survive," Bekmer replied, injecting as much acid into his words as he could manage. "You'll need to be in the other vessel. How can I possibly escape when you'll be right there?"

"And the navigation and FTL systems?" the human asked.

Bekmer sniffed. "Those may now be accessed and activated remotely. Which era do you think we're living in?"

The human was silent for a time, no doubt trying to bump enough neurons together to formulate some kind of response. "If that's the case, then let's do it. But if you're fucking around..."

"You'll kill me, or torture me, or starve me," Bekmer interrupted. "Yes, I've got all the standard threats memorised."

The human stared at him hatefully, but Bekmer knew by now that he had already won. "Then let's do it right now."

"As you wish," Bekmer replied tersely, although he was smiling on the inside. Soon, very soon, he would be free and the human would almost certainly be dead.

The human opened the heavy door to the cell, standing nearby as it always did while Bekmer exited. The human normally followed him closely in case he tried anything suspicious, but today that would be impossible. The human would need to trust Bekmer enough to let him on to one of the Hunter ships, and once Bekmer was that far ahead he could manage the rest as the situation progressed.

"Stay in contact," the human told him, handing him a communicator, and Bekmer took it disdainfully.

"You'll need a Vacuum Suit to get to the Hunter vessels," the human explained as they reached the outer airlock closest to the damaged hull. "I didn't manage to set up any kind of protective field to hold in the atmosphere around there yet, so it's just the ships themselves with air."

"Understood," Bekmer replied, carefully putting on his own suit. He was almost there, almost free, and it wouldn't pay to go getting excited. A few more (minutes) and he'd have won his freedom and his revenge. That he would not be able to claim the Zhadersil after all was his only regret, but sacrifices had to be made.

They stepped through the airlock, and Bekmer froze as he took in the scene: the Hunter vessels were not drifting in the wreckage anymore, but appeared to have been welded to the Zhadersil. What that would mean for his plan he wasn't sure, but he was desperate and would make the gamble anyway.

"Alright," he said over the communicator once he was at the console. "Everything looks good here, human. I'm ready to activate power flow on your signal."

"Understood," came the reply. "Activate now."

"Activating," Bekmer said, switching the power lines to active. There was a hum as power transferred to the larger vessel, and the power flow readouts looked good.

"FTL system has power!" the human said triumphantly. The sound of the human's taste of victory was like a warm glow to Bekmer, who knew how quickly it would transform into horror and death.

The human continued reading out the status of the plan, and Bekmer listened intently for his cue. "Navigation locked to Dominion space. FTL... engaged!"

There was a sense of pressure as the ancient FTL fired up, a bubble of altered space-time forming around the enormous ship and everything it contained. There was the normal sense of energy that always accompanied the formation of that bubble, and then the initial tingling on the surface of Bekmer's skin as the ship began to slip through space at a faster-than-light rate.

Now!, he thought, doubling the power flow to the Zhadersil, and the conduits exploded almost immediately, burning like lines of plasma in the void.

Bekmer smiled at the human's cry of alarm, and turned the ship's power fully over to its own FTL. It was make or break time.

"Enjoy disintegration, human!" Bekmer shot across the communicator as the larger field broke apart and his ship tore itself away from the Zhadersil. It was working! It was all working!

He laughed as the human cursed him over the communicator, and then the human was gone. The Zhadersil was gone. Bekmer was free.

"Finally!" he said, relishing the sensation of victory.

Then there was an explosion inside the ship and all the lights went out.

+++++

Adrian was white-knuckling the console. The fact that the FTL drive on the ships had been booby-trapped to destroy the reactors was of little comfort when the Zhadersil was screaming through space in a disintegrating warp bubble. He didn't know the first thing about how to fix the situation. He did know that he couldn't pour any more power into the Zhadersil's FTL without burning out the power conduits like Bekmer had intentionally done, and he knew he couldn't use this ship's own FTL without detonating the reactor.

"Fuck!" he shouted at the console. "Fucking fuck!"

He brutally pounded it with his fist, almost as though that would help in some way. Then he kept hitting it when it didn't.

"Shiplord Adrian Saunders," the Zhadersil computer system said, interrupting his outburst. "Warp field integrity at 30%. Emergency Stop advised. Go ahead?"

"Emergency stop?!" Adrian repeated. "Fuck, yes, go ahead! Go ahead!"

"Insufficient power for Emergency Stop," the computer immediately replied. "Power supply at seventy percent of requirements."

"Seventy percent?!" Adrian repeated. He looked at the smashed console beneath his fist and found another one to work on. "Fuck me dead I hope this works."

He turned up the power supply to the Zhadersil. Conduits outside began to spark brightly into the airless void. "Zhadersil," he ordered, "engage Emergency Stop!"

"Emergency Stop engaged," the computer repeated. "Warp field integrity maximised. Warp field now under controlled shutdown."

The stars returned as the warp field fell away, and Adrian breathed a heavy sigh of relief. "Still fucking kicking," he said. "Still fucking kicking!"

It had been too close that time, he'd have died if it wasn't for the Zhadersil's own systems intervening at the last moment. Bekmer had almost succeeded in royally fucking him over, but wherever Bekmer was now he either had his own problems or was beyond them.

"Fuck that guy."

He ran a navigational scan to find out where he was, and hissed air out through clenched teeth. The Zhadersil wasn't in uncontrolled space around Affrag anymore. Now it was beyond any system, out in the darkness of deep space.

Out on the edge of the Dominion-Celzi conflict.

"Well that," he said grimly, "is just completely fucking wonderful."

Zhadersil: Present Day

"Food's running low," Adrian told Jennifer over breakfast. "Or at least low enough to make me concerned. I'm going to take a run to Affrag, get some meat, some eggs, some fruit and veg."

"Can I come along?" she asked. "I want to help, and I'm getting tired of reading the Help interface."

"Not this time," Adrian replied. "You're not inoculated against everything, so you might pick up some disease you won't be able to shake. Plus I only have the one hunting rifle."

She seemed deflated, and he thought quickly about what he could get her to do so she didn't get depressed. She was getting better - albeit slowly - with human contact, but he had to make sure she always had something to do.

"Tell you what," he said, and noted the way she perked up immediately. "It's been a while since I've had time to do any cleaning at all. There's a literal bucket of shit... er, poo in the brig. Can I get you to do some washing up while I go get our food?"

"You want me play housewife?" she asked. "I don't know whether I should be insulted or not. Is Australia so backward that you think that just because I'm a woman I can do the dishes? Maybe I have magical sweeping powers given to me by the fair folk?"

"It's not about you being a woman," he explained quickly. "It's work that needs doing, and I'm still dealing with a whole lot of problems from the last incident I had. That's why I was out looking for abandoned vessels to strip. I need replacement parts."

"What for?" she asked. "Everything seems to be working from what I can see. Not that I know everything about the dino-ship, you'll understand, but the lights are on and we've got air."

"The ship can't move," Adrian said flatly. "The... method I was using to give it power isn't going to work again without serious outdoor repairs. If you prefer the idea of rebuilding a power grid in hard vacuum over washing up, be my guest. You have no idea the work I put in getting it working the first time, and frankly I don't want to give much thought to how much work it's going to be this time around."

"What's the rush?" Jen asked, innocently enough but with a slight hint of worry in the voice. "From what I can tell we're fine for the time being, aren't we?

"We're in a warzone," he told her, deciding to finally fill her in on the situation since there was no helping it anymore. "Not near the main action, as far as I can tell, but close enough that I'd prefer to get out of it sooner rather than later. I may be awesome, Jen, but I don't think I can fight an actual army."

"Don't think that the Ripley plan would work again?" she asked. "Flush them all into space?"

"Not this time," he said gravely. "One of the guys we used to have here was a mercenary who did ship-to-ship boardings. They go in wearing vacuum suits, just in case. They'd probably also leave their main ship outside. The Zhadersil has a big gun that it tells me works, but again I'd need to get it powered. So yeah, the faster I get things done the better, and that means all the little tasks fall to you. I'm sorry if that makes you feel bad, but I need to be able to have you pick up the slack for all the small things I won't have the time to do. Can I trust you to do that for me, Jen?"

She was quiet for a moment, taking in the full extent of what he'd said and weighing it up. She took a breath, the deep kind you take when you've made a decision, and nodded. "You can trust me to do that."

+++++

Avtlz Command Carrier: One Week Ago

Chir looked at the report again as he waited for the multi-link to connect. A field of debris had hit the Krditl system, exploding out of a disintegrating warp field and causing quite the stir. Scanners had determined that the debris had come from a Hunter vessel, but the only genetic markers in the debris had belonged to a single Corti. A mystery, unless you happened to be aboard the Zhadersil, and knew its position was close enough to Krditl to make a coincidence very unlikely.

The link finally activated, displaying the familiar faces of Trycrur and Zripob. Both were serious, as though they'd been expecting the call.

"It's been a while, Trycrur," Zripob said, greeting her. He had maintained brief amounts of contact with Chir, but he had been busy with the mercenary group. Things had been going about as well for Zripob as they had for the other two of them.

"This is about the Hunter ship?" Trycrur asked after nodding her own greeting. "I saw it on the news. Do you think it came from the Zhadersil?"

"The debris had no Hunter genetic markers," Chir said. "A single Corti. Draw your own conclusions, but to me it sounds like Bekmer had an accident."

"That doesn't make me unhappy," Zripob said. "Although I would have liked being involved in that outcome."

"So would I," Trycrur said coldly. "I am more interested in the fate of the Zhadersil."

"That's why I've contacted you both," Chir said. "The Dominion have traced the Warp path back to Affrag. Starting yesterday, they began an intensive sweep of the system."

The other two were obviously shocked. "There's no way the Zhadersil could remain hidden," Zripob replied. "They'll already be boarding it, the poor bastards."

"That's just the thing," Chir said. "The scans have come back clean all around that position. The Zhadersil wasn't there."

He let that news sink in for a moment, watching their expressions change as they thought about how to take this news. No Zhadersil in high orbit around Affrag was either very good or very bad news.

"So what became of Adrian Saunders," Zripob wondered, voicing the thought for all of them.

"That's what I'm going to go and find out," Chir told them. "Is anybody else in?"

"I'm in," Trycrur said too quickly, then paused before continuing. "I'm getting tired of speaking with psycho-analysts, and not building any weapons."

"I'd be in too," Zripob said, "but my unit is being dispatched to some other planet and I'm expected to 'lead the charge'. If you find Adrian, say hello from me."

"Well then," Chir said, talking directly to Trycrur now. "Looks like it's just you and me."

Humans don’t make good pets part 16.1

By guidosbestfriend

Rie’uo’abuie’ayu had a headache, but that seemed a trivial annoyance compared to the feeling of profound shame he felt after the events of today. Try as he might, he couldn’t think of what he might have done differently without having first known the future.

Who in their right minds would have predicted that the Dominion forces would abandon centuries of military dogma and use his own vehicles against him? Who could have foreseen that the Vulza, which had carried the Alliance so close to victory, would ignore the training they had received since birth and turn sides in a matter of hocs (minutes)? At least the battle seemed to be going according to plan above the planet. He assumed, since he and what remained of his forces were not being vaporized by an orbital strike.

It had been difficult, feeding incorrect intelligence to the Dominion, especially since it was such a novel idea, but Rie’uo’abuie’ayu supposed that it would soon become a standard tactic in warfare. How could it not, especially when it had proven so effective? Instead of finding a force consisting of a few outdated battleships, cruisers, and an aging carrier, the Dominion fleet, prepared for an easy fight, had arrived to find an opponent more than capable of matching them blow–for–blow.

Well, not at first. The Celzi Admiral, Cciic, had waited until the Dominion force had committed their ground forces. Only after the enemy fleet had dedicated themselves to the conflict did he order the reinforcement fleet to drop the cloaking fields that had been painstakingly installed on each ship, specifically for this battle. If everything had gone according to plan, this battle would have been the end of the 74th and the only effective Dominion unit. It still might be, if Admiral Cciic would finish off the fleet above and send an orbital strike of his own against the Dominion position.

Rie’uo’abuie’ayu’s musings were rudely interrupted as a commotion reached his ears from somewhere behind him. Turning he saw the turrets surrounding the sensor station frantically firing into the air, soon followed by a concussion wave as what seemed to be a small meteorite stuck the ground with a force impossible on a planet with such weak gravity. Even though he was nearly 200 borts (100 meters) from the point of impact, his vision was obscured as dust and dirt from kicked up from the landing fell about him. Coughing, he stumbled towards the panicked yells coming from the landing zone, dreading what new surprise this day had in store for him.

Recognizing Fleezle through in the debris cloud, Rie’uo’abuie’ayu caught the dazed comm officer’s attention by slapping him a couple times. Once he had regained cognizance, Rie’uo’abuie’ayu slapped him a few more times for good measure, “Lieutenant Colonel, report!”

Pointing in the direction of the commotions source, Fleezle tried to speak, but was nearly unintelligible as he was racked with a violent coughing spree. Rie’uo’abuie’ayu thought he caught the words “madness,” and “insanity,” in his hacking speech, but Rie’uo’abuie’ayu didn’t feel like waiting until the comm officer regained his breath. Running in the direction Fleezle had indicated, Rie’uo’abuie’ayu’s trepidation grew as signs of destruction increased as he approached the source of the chaos. His jaw dropped when the crater materialized through the dust and debris filled air.

It was some debris from the battle above. It had to have been. The remnants of the “meteorite” within the crater had obviously once been a part of a space craft. The fact that ship fragments from the conflict above were raining down upon the planet didn’t bother him, however. It was the fact that it had landed in the midst of his men. Any debris that fell to the planet and was large enough to make it through the atmosphere had an entire hemisphere of land to choose from, but of all places it chose the few bortos (kilometers) occupied by his soldiers.

“It hates me,” he muttered under his breath. “The universe legitimately hates me. This entire battle it has bent the very limits of probability to ensure my easy victory ended in failure. What’s next? Will the Dominion suddenly have Vulza of their own which they will use to assault my position? Or maybe the planet itself will open up and swallow the remnants of my men!” He knew he was shouting by this point, but he was having difficulty caring. “Or maybe–”

Rie’uo’abuie’ayu’s rantings were cut short as shouts of alarm and “Incoming!” sounded several hundred borts (meters) to his right, followed by another ground shattering impact. “Another one!?” Rie’uo’abuie’ayu yelled in disbelief, but he barely had time to register his newest complaint with the universe before another shuddering concussion came from his left. Eyes popping in near apoplexy, Rie’uo’abuie’ayu looked up. His heart nearly failed him, both metaphorically and medically, at what he saw.

Drop ships were falling from the sky, but instead of landing, they continued to accelerate right up until they slammed into the ground, obliterating anything nearby and jaring anything remotely close. They fell in pairs, each only several re (seconds) apart. The turret defenses, meant to protect against ground assaults, didn’t have the complex targeting computers necessary to effectively intercept aerial attacks, and despite their operators best efforts, they made no noticeable difference as the orbital strike of insanity continued to rain from above.

“Just when I had thought this rictos (day) couldn’t get any worse.” Even as the words left his lips, the bombardment increased tenfold.

Blatvec couldn’t remember the last time he’d had so much fun. It was dulled somewhat by the fact that the 74th had just suffered more causalities than in any previous single encounter, but considering the forces against which they had been pitted, that there was anything other than casualties was a miracle in and of itself. There was also something savagely satisfying in watching a massive cylinder of reinforced armor plating fall on an enemy position in a gout of dirt and debris.

The shouts of surprise, panic, and sheer unbelief towards the beginning of the bombardment, heard even at this distance, had been also tickled Blatvec’s fancy. He had long given up the hope that he was anything other than a psychopath at this point, but he hoped he was a fair one.

Even if he was the most biased of commanders, he had to admit, the squad–leader of the new unit from the 109th was a genius, which was even more shocking considering he was a Vzk’tk. When General Ickret had personally informed him of the transfer, Blatvec had felt nothing but disgust. After all, the 109th was those who struggled even in basic training. Soldiers who were accepted only because of the current climate of desperation. Units from the 109th could hardly dream of being a part of the 74th, let alone expect to survive in it.

The results didn’t lie, however, and this Vzk’tk had not only saved the entire 74th, but now managed to conjure up an orbital strike using drop ships. An unheard of tactic, probably because such an idea was preposterous. Seeing the results, however, Blatvec couldn’t say it was ineffective.

Strangely enough, the Vzk’tk squad leader looked nearly as shocked by his own plan as Blatvec. He had none of the calm confidence Blatvec had come to associate with true masters of strategy, and if he hadn’t been the only creature of full intelligence, if such a term could be applied to a Vzk’tk, on the premises when Blatvec had arrived, he would have assumed the idea had come from anyone but him.

The other . . . thing . . . +Human, right?+ couldn’t have conceived such a ploy. Sure, it was mildly intelligent, else it wouldn’t have been put in the army, but it didn’t have a translator, and what fully sapient species didn’t have a translator? Blatvec assumed it was just the 109th squad’s personal attack dog. He thought he remembered Ickret saying something about a “Human,” being a great asset or something similar, and seeing the speed with which it ran from drop ship to drop ship Blatvec could believe it, but surely it didn’t have the capacity for strategic thought. Right?

Too many of his assumptions had proven wrong that day for Blatvec to feel like making another, so he decided to reserve final judgement until he was proven correct or otherwise. Still, he doubted he was wrong.

Dear Journal,

What makes someone Human?

Because I feel like I lost it.

Once Turkey managed to grasp what I was doing, he fell quickly into line, and we doubled our rate of bombardment, sending pairs of drop ships at a time to their doom. I guess seeing your only method of getting off of a planet fall from the sky and land in enemy territory tends to grab one’s attention, because it wasn’t long before a couple of squads from our team showed up. Had their vehicles not been floating above the ground in perhaps the greatest killjoy of the galaxy, they would have been able to angrily tear into the clearing which Turkey and myself were rapidly depleting of drop ships.

As it was, they still managed to hum like a herd of disgruntled cows, which, if you’ve ever seen such a spectacle, is no laughing matter. Cows can be mean if displeased. I knew the powers that were probably wouldn’t be too happy with us shooting off their only mode of exoatmospheric transportation, but Turkey had said they wanted an orbital strike, and if this didn’t suffice then they were just too gosh darn picky.

I knew my excuses wouldn’t mean jack as far as discipline was concerned, but it still felt good to make them in my head. Since I was sure I was about to be the first soldier to die by a firing squad composed entirely of tank, which would suck to no end, my shock was palpable when the other squads hopped out of their vehicles, took one look at what we were doing, then started to emulate us.

Drop ships were soon clogging the air in their eagerness to throw themselves against the enemy. Accordingly, the ground in the direction of the enemy boiled with impacts, and I felt a detached sense of pity for the guys stuck over there. Something about that feeling didn’t feel right, although I couldn’t tell you why.

Putting the troubling thoughts from my mind in my most basic and practiced mental maneuver, I set myself to the task of finding even more drop ships to give as gifts unto the enemy. They seemed to be enjoying it, as their shouts of overwhelming joy and jubilation reached my eager ears. They were so happy!

After nearly 30 minutes of concerted effort, we had destroyed nearly all of the three troopship’s worth of drop ships. We still had the vehicle drop ships, and I had already started towards the closest one, when I heard an unintelligible shout that rang with unmistakable authority.

Turning to look at its source, I saw the most frightening figure. It wasn’t that tall for an alien, though it was still slightly taller than me. It had six arms and two legs, was covered in a brown exoskeleton, and had two prominent pincers like those of an ant jutting from its face. Really, I thought those ant–lizards (lizard–ants? One or the other, choose whichever you prefer) had looked like insects, but this guy looked like the lovechild of a giant ant and a spider spawned from the depths of hell.

Intimidating as his visage was, it wasn’t his appearance that frightened – or perhaps fascinated – me, or even the fact that he was holding two anti–tank pulse guns at the same time, which I’d never seen any other alien accomplish, as the guns were apparently heavy by xeno standards. Rather, it was the aura of unstoppable determination that this alien seemed to exude. It didn’t seem to be directed at anyone in particular, it just seemed to be there.

It took me a moment before I realized that I had felt that feeling before. It was the same feeling you felt every single day on earth. The idea that everyone had a single goal in life they would give everything to achieve. The feeling of being alive. The aura surrounding every human who hadn’t given up completely. The essence of resilience. I hadn’t even realized that essence seemed to be missing from every alien I had seen so far, but now, shown in sharp contrast, I was able to recognize for the first time what nearly every one of them I had met seemed to lack.

They were alive, certainly, but so many seemed to merely wish to survive. I hoped humans weren’t the only ones in this galaxy with the opposite mindset, because if they were space was ultimately going to rather boring. Still, even if most of his brethren have backbones of gelatin, I knew I wouldn’t want to cross Demon Dude here lightly.

Whatever it was that he had shouted, it made everyone stop firing off drop ships like kids in charge of the fireworks on the fourth of July and start heading back to the vehicles they had arrived in. I followed Turkey to our borrowed vehicle and hopped into the passenger seat, as he was occupying the driver’s side and glaring at me with a look that told me he would never willingly let me drive him anywhere again. I didn’t mind. I don’t think I could have withstood the disappointment of using that iPhone–slide–to–unlock lame–ass excuse for an accelerator again, anyways.

As we started in convoy across the battlefield once again, my only hope was that this battle was nearly over. It had been a long day.

They were doomed. Their defenses were gone, their entrenchments reduced to scrap, and more importantly, their wills broken. Rie’uo’abuie’ayu knew he should have rallied his troops. That’s what good commanders of history had done. He couldn’t summon the energy, though. It was hopeless, and nothing he could do would change the outcome, so why even bother? These thoughts were upon his mind even as his position was overrun.

As such, Rie’uo’abuie’ayu passed into history himself, only to be remembered as a note in a military report.

Apparently this entire confrontation was about a station. Were you aware of this, Journal, because I didn’t get the memo? It’s a shame, since I guess they had wanted it intact. Since I hadn’t been informed, and had been only given general area as to where the enemy was located, I had sent drop ship–bombs to nearly every area of the provided circle. How was I supposed to know that the center was occupied by a station that we wanted in one piece? Apparently everyone else had just naturally understood that fact, but I think they had the advantage of having been told about the stations existence in advance.

The defending forces, significantly softened, by our poor–man’s orbital strike, crumbled in mere minutes after confronting out forces and were routed in another few minutes. I thought we would just blow up the station and be on our way back to the troopships in under an hour, so it was understandable that I was disappointed and a little confused when everyone started getting out of their vehicles. I got the picture well enough when everyone started entering the station, but I was still disappointed. I had been jumping around fighting space dragons for what I estimated to be nearly 2 hours. I was sore, tired, and hungry. I wanted to go home.

Several drop ships which looked somewhat familiar had closed several entrances to the station in piles of rubble, and to my utter bemusement, a queue of soldiers formed in front of the entrances, waiting their turn to enter the station. I don’t really know much about tactics in urban warfare, but I don’t think it includes forming an orderly line in front of any structure you’re planning on entering. Our squad was near the end of the line, and it wasn’t moving quickly.

I told you I was hungry and that I wanted to go home. I was impatient, and this most recent absurdity pushed me over the edge. The thing about xenos, well, there’s a lot of things about xenos, but one of many things which seems to describe most of them is that they don’t have the diaphragm support of a human. That makes us rather loud by their standards. I like to think of it as they don’t have an appreciation for the higher end of the decibel scale like we do. I’ve been trying to reveal to them the magnificence of its pulsing grandeur, manly while in the shower as the acoustics in there are great, but it’s been rather slow in its acceptance.

My natural talent as a metal lead singer came in handy at times of impatience; however, I used it to my fullest advantage. Raising my volume as high as I could go, then forcing it a little more to “full throated roar” level, I bellowed my displeasure in one of my most barbaric and mainly displays since my abduction.

“Everybody move!”

No one understood what I said, but my intent was clear as the line split like I was some alien Moses. The xenos closest to me actually fell over. Maybe they fainted. Pathetic. It didn’t matter. Jumping over the bodies in front of me, I charged down the center of the line and into the station. The holdup was due to a token guarding force which was using the twisting nature of the stations corridors to their advantage, although their positioning could have easily been circumnavigated if our forces had just waited until everyone was at an entrance, rather than charging in at the first opportunity and then waiting for those running around to other entrances to catch up.

At least I had seen other squads moving towards other entrances. From what I had seen, I don’t think I had any right to count on something as simple as flanking maneuvers. Their positioning wouldn’t make their weapons more possible, and I was irrationally angry. It was time to try to set a record for shortest time required to take over an enemy station.

5 Years, 9 Months Ago. Celzi Alliance Capitol World.

“Valur! They did it! They officially seceded! I told you they would. I told you we wouldn’t have to put up with the Dominion much longer!” Valur sighed. Of course Xiavo would be right. He always seemed to know the current political climate and its implications, although he guessed even he should have seen this one coming. Rumblings of secession had been heard throughout the Alliance for years now, and Xiavo had said he’d heard rumors of a military buildup nearing completion, although where he would have heard such a thing was beyond Valur’s knowledge.

“Fine, you win. How much was the bet?” He really should have seen war coming, but Xiavo had challenged, and he had been reading, and it was easier to accept the challenge rather than fight it. He suspected that was why Xiavo had waited until he was in the middle of his book to ask him.

“One hundred twenty five standard credits.” Xiavo replied, a look of smug triumph on his face. Valur scoffed, “Right. Even if I was reading I wouldn’t have agreed to such a price. Nice try. Here’s your twenty five.” He transferred the reasonable sum. A look of melodramatic offense plastered over his sorry visage, Xiavo, voice dripping in sarcasm, placed his hand on Valur’s shoulder, “You don’t trust me? Me?! Your friend through thick and thin, your greatest confident, and you think I would lie? To you?! I, who consider you my brother, would even consider such an atrocity? When have I ever done a villainous thing of such debauchery? When have I led you astray?”

The moments the words left his lips Xiavo knew he had gone too far. The look of mischievous malice he knew so well twisted Valur’s face as he used his incredible memory to recall every example which demonstrated just how many times Xiavo had led him astray. “Well, there was that time we were 5, when you convinced me that someone had poisoned my rocollo treats, and that I should put them in a plastic bag and then throw them away so you have them for yourself. When we were six you took that toy from Old Captain Boorto’vluel’niabl’crixo’s gricka since it had the same control chip as your favorite simulator. That one put both of us in the hospital as I recall. When we were thirteen you reprogrammed Professor CuL’s display board to search “Dizi Mating Videos” every ric (30 minutes) but not actually display it so that no one knew it had even happened until thost horrid high–pitched squeals started issuing from the speakers. She couldn’t figure out what was happening for an entire ricta (1.5 weeks), but when she figured it out, she failed you and me three times since she just assumed I’d helped you. When we were fourteen–”

“I get it just shut up! While you’re quick to point out all the times I’ve led you astray you failed to point out that each of those times I was just trying to get you to have a little bit more excitement in your life. You read too much.”

“Really, eating all my desserts was so I would have more fun?”

“I was five, I wasn’t so selfless back then.”

“Uh–hu.”

“Regardless of what you think, you do know what this war means, right?”

“I assume you’ll enlighten me.”

“We’re joining the army.”

“What!?” Valur shouted. Xiavo had to be wrong. He couldn’t go to war! He had just asked Professor Yyxximal if he could study under him. He wanted to be an engineer, not a soldier. Surely an exception would be made in his case.

“Think! We’re going up against the Dominion! We’re an alliance of 17 species trying to secede from a governmental body of hundreds. The only reason we’ll even have a chance of winning is because of our advanced robotics, industrial strength, and that most of the Dominion’s strength is always focused on patrolling their massive amount of space. Even with that the alliance will need every able bodied adult they can find, and both of us just crossed that line. They’ll make exceptions for the top percentiles of academia, but while you’re smart, Professor CuL screwed you over. You’re not going to make it, and I have less chance than a crippled dizi put in a cage with a gricka. Mark my words, we’re going to war. Don’t turn that shade of grey, it’ll be fine. I’ve got your back.”

9 Months later

Alliance Basic Training Camp

Valur couldn’t sleep. As was often the case, if he couldn’t sleep, neither could Xiavo. Not because he kept him up or anything, it was just more often than not that anything that bothered one bothered the other, and he couldn’t stop thinking about the events of tomorrow. “Still awake?” He whispered into the darkness.

“Of course,” came the tentative reply.

Valur grunted. “I can’t stop wondering if I’ll be put with the 55th or the 32nd. I can’t imagine it will be any other. I’m not good enough to get into the 12th like you, but don’t think I did too badly on the physical. I think I have an honest shot at the 32nd. Don’t you?” Xiavo grunted in reply. Valur sighed, “Your articulation always astounds me.” He grunted again. Valur knew what was on his mind. Xiavo wouldn’t have needed to worry about his assignment like he did. Xiavo had performed excellently in every test they’d thrown at him. He would be assigned to the 12th for sure, perhaps even the 5th. That wasn’t what was on his mind then, although it was related. “She’ll probably be assigned to the same unit as you.” Valur tried to sound encouraging.

“You think?” Well, at least the response was coherent this time.

“Undoubtedly. Both of you are exceptional. Whatever you qualify for, she’ll make it too.”

“Maybe. Hopefully. We’ll see. Go to sleep. It’ll be alright, whatever happens.” Xiavo didn’t follow his own advice. Valur was the best friend a guy could hope for, and usually know what was on his friends mind, but he couldn’t have been further from the truth this time. Daseil was a good guess. She did occupy his thoughts more often than not, but that wasn’t keeping him up this time. He waited until he heard his friends snores, then crept from the barracks that had been his home for the past eight months. He walked to the Sergeant’s quarters. Relived to see the lights still on, he knocked on the door.

Several moments later he was in front of the Sergeants desk, a stern scowl on its owners face. “You have a re (5 seconds) to explain why you’re out of your barracks soldier.”

Xiavo gulped, but he knew the Seargeant liked him, and he had to try. “Sir, I wanted to ask you about postings.”

“You couldn’t wait until tomorrow, eh?” The Sergeant smiled, and some of the tension in Xiavo’s body left. “You don’t need to worry about a thing Xiavo, you were exemplary as usual. You’re to be assigned to the 5th, just like you wanted.”

“My apologies sir, but I didn’t want to know my results, I wanted–”

“Soldier Daseil was also cleared for the 5th. Don’t worry, your favorite bunkmate won’t let you leave her just yet.”

Gosh darn it; he wasn’t making this any easier. Still, when he thought about it, Xiavo knew there would never be any competition in his mind.

“Sorry, sir, but I was wondering what Valur’s results were?” At the mention of Valur’s name the Sergeant’s scowl returned.

“I’ll never understand why you protect him so, but everyone has their quirks. He sucked. He can’t shoot worth shit, his endurance is crap, and he couldn’t find food for himself in the wild without a restaurant to put it in front of him. He’s to be assigned to the 87th.” Xiavo inwardly groaned. That was where the dropouts the army couldn’t afford to let go were sent, and almost certainly, died. Not because they were put in difficult situations, but because the skill level was so low. The 87th only ever won battles through overwhelming numbers.

“One last question sir. What was my class ranking?”

“You were first.”

“So I can choose my posting?”

“Of course, but I just told you, you got into the 5th. What else would you–”

“I want to be assigned to the 87th.” The words left his mouth in a rush, and only after several moments did he add a belated “sir.” The Sergeant stared at him in utter shock. He seemed to be trying to speak, at least his mouth was moving, but words failed to leave his lips. After what appeared to be a rather difficult reboot, the Sergeant got his voice under control once again.

“Have you lost your mind?! You?! The 87th?! You’d be wasted there! Worse, you’d be ruined! I refuse! I won’t let you make such a mistake! You aren’t thinking straight, don’t you understand? You’re cleared for the 5th! The best fighting force the alliance has to offer. The elite! You could be one of the best among them, but you want to join the ranks of the military dropouts?!”

“I want nothing more than to be a part of the 5th,” Xiavo replied, and it was nothing but the truth, “But I’d rather ruin myself and be able to protect my friend rather than go on to the fifth and not be there when he needs me.”

The Sergeant continued to stare for several hocs (minutes). Finally he spoke. “You’re serious?”

“Yes, sir.”

“Then I’m putting Valur in the 32nd. With a shitload of luck he may be able to cut it there, and with you by his side he may only need a crapton. Does that mean you’ll be willing to be assigned to the 32nd?”

Xiavo smiled. The 32nd was far better equipped and manned. There Valur would be able to hide in the ranks of better soldiers, and with him as his protector, Valur would be about as safe as it was possible to be on a battlefield. “Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.” The Sergeant grunted in reply.

“It’s a shame, but at least you won’t be put with the 87th.” He seemed to shudder at the though. “You do realize this means you won’t be assigned with Soldier Daseil, right?”

Xiavo gritted his teeth. “Yes, sir. I do.”

3 Years Later

32nd Division, Battle of Tizccxi–2

Xiavo was nearing panic. The attack had gone badly, and the 32nd was still regrouping from their retreat, the 41st covering their rear. Today would be a victory, once reinforcements arrived, but it would be costly. That didn’t matter to him right now, though. Grabbing the nearest unit commander’s arm, he nearly shouted in his face. “Have you seen Valur anywher? Last I saw he was with Himel squad. Do you have any idea where they are?”

The commander seemed petrified by the Lieutenant Colonel shouting in his face, but still managed to sputter out a reply. “Last I saw Himel squad had been flanked by 3 full squads around here,” he pointed to a map of the battlefield. “They had already lost most of their guys. There’s no way anyone could survive that attack. I’m sorry, sir, Valur’s dead. I know how much he meant to you.”

“Did you see him die?” Xiavo spit in the pretentious underlings face.

Fear spreading over his features, the commander stated spluttering, but he gave his species equivalent of a shake of his head, which was all Xiavo needed. Dropping the commander, he started sprinting back towards the wavering line of the retreating line of the 41st.

“Sir! What are you doing?! He’s dead. Don’t throw yourself away like this, you still have a responsibility to the rest of your squad!” Xiavo missed that last part. The allied line had already fallen past the point the commander had pointed to on the map. He would have to sneak back to it. Stealth wasn’t something that was emphasized in training, but Xiavo thought that was a mistake. Stealth was vital in a battle, most just didn’t seem to realize it. He found the nearest patch of mud and caked it over every inch of himself. Most wouldn’t have wanted to get themselves so dirty. Screw that. It was getting dark, which was even better.

Sneaking past the main front wasn’t difficult. Everyone’s attention was fully diverted. Sneaking behind enemy lines was harder. Their mobile medical units slowly lumbered up behind the main front, and the guards would be making sure no rouge squad was attempting to pick off the wounded. Sliding through the mud, Xiavo looked like nothing more than a part of the terrain. Using the uneven land to aid in his movements, he crawled his way to where the commander had indicated. It took the better part of 5 rics (2.5 hours).

When he found the remnants of Himel squad, despair began to gnaw at the edges of his calm. It was a mess. Entrails and gore splattered a small clearing, seeming to confirm the commanders assessment of the chances of survivability. Fighting down every instinct, Xiavo started sifting through the bodies. He found several arms that could have been Valur’s, but still no body. It couldn’t have been completely destroyed, there had to be some trace of it.

There was. It was mostly intact as well. It was still breathing too. Stifling his cries of relief, Xiavo tore his field medical kit from his bag, using it to close up the wound left by Valur’s missing arm and leg. He didn’t know if he had gotten there soon enough, until Valur opened his eyes for just a moment.

“I knew you’d come.” He whispered, then lapsed back into unconsciousness.

1 Year, 6 Months later (6 Months Before the 74th’s Attack)

Alliance Barracks

“Why are they reassigning us again?” Valur asked.

“I get to choose where we’re posted for our second term since I’m a Brigadier.”

“And you chose Utgul–3 Sensor Outpost guard duty because . . .”

“It’s an incredibly valuable station. The Alliance will do anything to hang on to it.”

“Right, and the Dominion will do anything to get it.”

He had a point, but Xiavo was sure he’d made the right choice. “True, but guard duty on the station is more or less a token job. The real guard is the 16th, 18th, and 20th armored divisions, along with the Skal and Vico Vulza packs. The Dominion doesn’t have enough troops to devote to one battle to take it. It’s probably the safest place for us to be. Just watch, you’ll still be an engineer.”

“I trust you, I just wanted to make sure you had a sound line of reasoning. If there’s one thing about you I don’t trust it’s your sense of logic.”

“You wound me. Don’t worry about a thing. It’ll be the easiest 9 cycles (4 years 6 months) of your life.”

Current Day

Utgul–3 Sensor Outpost

I had this record in the bag. Seriously, this twisting labyrinth of a station just meant that the enemy didn’t see me coming around the corner, and then my reflexes took care of the rest. I was having a bit of a problem remembering which parts of the station I’d already cleared, but I figured if I just kept running and turned on an impulse I was bound to clear the whole thing eventually.

Whipping around a corner I ran face first into a heavy ray pulse. My shield had given out a few hallways back, so I took what felt like a hard punch to the face. My face had suffered worse punishment before, and I kept running, skewering the alien responsible for the offense. His group of friends didn’t have their friend’s reflexes, or aim, and their shot, if they hit me at all, struck my torso and arms, which, although it hurt, was a very familiar hurt that by now barely registered. I continued down the hall, and entered a room I hadn’t been in yet. It looked pretty important though, as there were more monitors and blinking lights than had been in any room I’d been in so far.

My eyes, however, fell upon on a small metal chute built into the wall of a small side room. Inside the little scoop at the bottom were a few of those lovely grey spheres. They wouldn’t have the calcium supplements they’d been making me take for a while now, but they were still food, and as I said, I was starving.

“Dough spheres! Oh boy! And water too! You spoil me too much!” I was pretty excited. Rushing to the dispenser I ate a sphere without chewing the correct number of times, but it was okay, because no one was watching. At least, that’s what I thought. I don’t know how I hadn’t noticed them, but two enemies were still inside the control room and watching me. I looked up just as one pointed an anti–tank ray gun at me. Those things hurt. I hadn’t noticed in time, and I took half an anti–tank pulse to the side. I think it broke some ribs.

I was genuinely scared now, and adrenaline dulled the pain and fueled my retaliation. Jumping at the one with the anti–tank gun I lined my scimitar with his chest. He dodged. He was a fast little bugger. His companion didn’t seem to have his partner’s skill, or weapon, or aim. The other guy was, just the worst. He only had a heavy, so he wouldn’t have been very affective even if he’d managed to hit me, but his shots were so far off he almost hit the other guy. I ignored him and focused on the real threat. This other guy knew how to move, and he kept positioning things in between him and myself, always moving positions and shooting at me with that infernal weapon. I silenced that as soon as possible.

He really was fast, and his positioning hindered my attacks to an annoying degree, but he was only just fast enough to dodge my wild flails which I called attacks. He, however, wasn’t fast enough to keep his gun out of my reach. I quickly managed to slice that in half, leaving him only with a pistol. He was getting tired, and my ribs were making it hard to move now. In the end I just threw my scimitar at him. It hit him hilt–first in the head, but by now I knew it wouldn’t have mattered even if it had hit him with the flat of the blade and in the shin; it was lethal either way.

What I didn’t expect upon the impact was the roar of raw fury to come from my left, followed by what felt like an actual punch. It turned out it was a punch. The other alien, an arm an and leg of which were mechanical, I now realized, used the strength given to him by his artificial limbs to attack with far greater efficacy than he had with his gun. The speed of his attacks stunned me, and I found myself defending against his onslaught for some time after his initial attack. Eventually he tired, though, and I threw him away from me so I could catch my breath. He hit the wall and slid beside his friend.

He wasn’t dead yet, but he didn’t renew his attack. Instead, he approached the body of his fallen comrade. He emitted a keening wail unlike anything I’d heard before, but I instantly recognized. Emotion is spoken by everyone, sorrow most of all. What was I doing? Why did I feel no remorse? The justifications I had long fixed in my mind: it’s war, you’re just trying to get home, they signed up for it, all seemed hollow in my ears as I said them over and over again. Was this all I was? A killing machine, blasé of the carnage he inflicted around him as he strode implacably towards his goal? Was getting home worth it if I had to wade through a river of bodies to get there?

But weren’t these soldiers? Hadn’t they signed up for it?

Do you even know what you’re fighting for? Do you even care anymore? Do you care about your morals, or lack thereof?

I didn’t ask to be abducted! It’s their fault, and I’ll be damned if I let them stop me from getting back home!

I paused. Was that my motivation, my driving thought behind my actions? I didn’t know. Seeing the alien’s pain, feeling my own confusion, I felt shame as never before. I ran from the room, running from my problems as I always had in the days before my abduction. I hadn’t changed a bit.

The alien; no, the monster, didn’t kill Valur as he lay beside Xiavo’s corpse. Valur didn’t know why. He found he didn’t care. Xiavo was dead. Killed on a post he’d said would be easy. Murdered by a creature of supernatural abilities, and Valur had failed to kill it. He wouldn’t fail again. He would find it, and he would kill it. Not today though. Today, he just had to survive. The station would soon be under Dominion hands. A drop ship had collapsed an outer wall on a corridor near the control center. He could escape through there, and with luck, avoid the Dominion in the area. He was happy Xiavo had shown him how to move quietly, though he was afraid he wasn’t very good. It would have to suffice, however. He would escape, he would find the monster, and he would end it.

Salvage18. Fireworks

By Rantarian

Adrian Saunders always took a particular Hunter vessel when the time came to restock his food supplies, and had come to call it the ’Shopping Trolley’. There was really no reason why it had initially been this ship, excepting perhaps that it had been closest to the edge of the flight deck, but Hunter vessels were equipped for hauling large amounts of meat, and had the facilities available to let them keep it fresh. He knew these facilities had previously been used by the Hunters to keep the flesh of sapients in, but that hadn’t bothered him after he’d given it a good scrub. Not like it had bothered the others.

He always kept the cloaking system activated, just in case he came up against something he really didn’t want to deal with, but today he was also scanning for other vessels in a way that would allow anyone who was looking for active scans to find him. It was important that he find someone to inoculate Jen before she went and caused an outbreak somewhere else.

He had already been out one more time to flush the ship she had been on before. He had considered sending the ship, full of plague corpses, straight into Hunter territory, but he hadn’t been ready to start engaging in bio–warfare. You never knew where a weapon like that could spread to, and the Hunters weren’t ones to go down without taking a lot of innocent people with them.

Today was focused on food gathering, however, and he still visited Affrag for that purpose as he already knew what was worth eating there. A straightforward run, with the likely fruitless search for other ships directly after.

He dropped out of warp straight into low orbit, and his scanners lit up on a dozen scouts throughout the system. His active scanners pinged them all before he could shut them off.

“Shit!” he cursed, switching the scanners back to passive. “Fuck! Shit! Fuck!”

It felt good to swear freely again. He’d been doing his best to keep a civil tongue since Jen had arrived, a holdover from his upbringing that tolerated no foul language in the company of women. His father had not been a good man, but that was one rule that Adrian couldn’t fault him on.

He clenched his teeth into a frustrated grimace as the detection systems started reporting active scans pounding the Shopping Trolley. “Can’t go back to the Zhadersil like this,” he said to the ship, although it was not about to respond. “There’s not even a way to send a proper fucking message to Jen...”

He looked down at the planet, marking out the familiar land masses, marking out the places where the clouds were heaviest. It looked as though it was time for some more camping, but if he was going to be expecting company he figured he’d make sure they knew they were unwelcome.

He just hoped that nothing happened to Jen or the Zhadersil while he was away.

Chir had borrowed a vessel after lodging a fake flight plan with the administration. It was a small vessel, capable of accommodating both himself and Trycrur, but was expensive enough that once upon a time he would have balked at the cost. He’d have balked at it now, if he hadn’t known where to find a medium–sized fortune in unused Hunter ships and known a guy who’d buy just about anything.

“We’re going to start by looking in Krditl and tracing a direct line back towards Affrag,” he had explained to Trycrur. “My hope is that we’ll find the Zhadersil somewhere along that path, but we’ll just need to keep hopping in short distances.”

“Tiresome,” Trycrur had replied. “But I see your reasoning. Do you think we will find it?”

“I hope so,” Chir replied. If only for the sake of his own bank account he hoped so. At this point having Adrian alive on the Zhadersil would be a happy bonus.

“Me too,” she said. “If the Zhadersil had been destroyed around Affrag it would have left a lot of debris, and it didn’t dump into Krditl along with the Hunter ship. A lot of sensors would have gone off if anything the size of the Zhadersil had passed through inhabited zones, and even if the military tried to black it out there’s no way they could keep it entirely secret.”

“So my hope is that the Zhadersil stopped somewhere on the same route, and remains in one piece,” Chir continued. “We’ll either find the Zhadersil, a Zhadersil–sized debris field, or nothing.”

“And if we find nothing?” Trycrur asked.

“Then we’ve wasted our effort,” Chir said grimly. “I know nowhere has put out notices of detecting an object of that size. So that would mean that it’s gone somewhere in uncontrolled space outside of scanning networks. Out here there’s no end to the possibilities.”

“And if we find the Zhadersil?” Trycrur asked. “What’s the plan?”

“We’ll land and tell Adrian that people are coming to take his ship from him,” Chir explained bluntly.

“You think he’ll be happy to see us?” Trycrur asked. “We didn’t exactly leave in the best way...”

“Adrian is not a fool,” Chir told her. “He won’t hurt us, although he may be a touch belligerent, or perhaps a bit smug. Clearly we were incorrect in that the Zhadersil had no hope of ever moving again.”

“What do you think he’s doing right now?” she asked Chir. “I’d bet he’d be building more weapons.”

“He’s probably doing something stupid,” Chir replied. “Since we’re not there to stop it.”

Adrian was doing something stupid. He was flying through Affrags lower atmosphere and periodically actively pinging the vessels in the system. By now they’d have recognised his vessel as not having any business there, although whether they’d know it was a Hunter ship was another matter.

There were two possibilities: either they’d leave him well enough alone, in which case he’d know he could warp out and take a round–about way back to the Zhadersil – which, now that he thought about it, was what he should have done as soon as he saw them all – or they’d follow him down to the surface in the attempt to take him out, and he’d have to hope they were as completely fucking useless on a Deathworld as Chir had been that first time.

Right now the ship was shuddering as he was flying it through a heavy rain storm, en route to get just ahead of it in order to land. The eyes in the sky would know the general vicinity of his landing zone, but they wouldn’t know his location well enough to paint it from orbit.

He set the ship down on a flat plain just before the storm hit. Passive scanners were already picking up objects entering geosynchronous orbit above him.

“Such a fucking idiot,” he said to himself. Some days he really did wonder how he managed to put his trousers on in the morning. “Oh well, at least if I’m going to be killed I’ll make it fucking entertaining.”

Dominion Cruiser Itrz, Geosynchronous Orbit of Deathworld

Ship Master Drzzk surveyed the deathworld below, taking into view the roiling mass of clouds that were surging steadily towards the last contact point they’d had on the unknown craft.

“Have we got an ID on that ship class yet?” he asked, turning to his systems crew, and paused as he saw the looks on their faces. “What is it?”

“The most likely match is a Hunter craft,” Systems Superior Clklict reported. “As to why it was behaving in that way, I cannot possibly hazard a guess.”

“It may be a trap,” one of his subordinates suggested, earning a hiss from Clklict to inform him to keep his mouth shut.

“It might be,” Drzzk agreed. “I’ve never heard of Hunters doing anything like that however.”

“With all due respect, sir,” Clklict said, “I haven’t heard of a Hunter ship being piloted by a Corti, either. There may be something going on down there that we need to deal with.”

“I don’t doubt that there is, Systems Superior,” Drzzk replied irritably. “I hesitate, however, to send a force down onto a Deathworld after an unknown target. I do not think so little of my peoples’ lives as to throw them away in such a manner.”

“We can’t just–” Clklict started again, stopping only as his Ship Master eyed him venomously.

“I will send down a few soldiers in a scout,” Ship Master Drzzk decided. “They will find the vessel, and when they have found it they will mark it as a target for orbital bombardment. I do not want to risk more out here than we already are.”

Zhadersil

Jennifer Delaney was busy cleaning. There was a lot to do, Adrian had certainly not lied about that – she’d have to ask him why there was a bucket of dried out shit in a prison room – and she could see that this would be the kind of work that may take days or weeks to complete. Obviously there had been the sixty–five million years without any form of cleaning, but aside from that Adrian had a tendency to make enormous messes and not clean them up.

If she was going to be stuck out here with him, that was going to have to be one habit she broke him of. She wasn’t his wife, and she wasn’t his mum, and there was no way in all of Heaven and Earth that she’d be doing whatever passed for his laundry. If he thought anything different, that man had another thing coming!

The rest she could understand. It wasn’t as though he had ever seemed to be simply taking a moment to relax when he wasn’t eating. There was always some work being done, be it hunting for food, cooking that food, or repairing the million and one things that were undoubtedly wrong with the ships. It was, to her mind, fairly astounding that he was even capable of doing anything with the ships. He had not exactly struck her as the sort of man who thinks with his head, given all his muscles and perfect physique.

Jennifer Delaney forced herself to think of something else. She knew she was attracted to him, that had been the case since she’d gotten an eyeful of him hard at work and straining his wonderful muscles, and she suspected that he’d glanced away from her before she’d caught him looking a few times. She also knew that she wasn’t about to start a relationship with a man just because he was the last possible prospect in a hopeless universe.

Although as reasons went...

She shook her head. No, that would just be mad! What would happen if it didn’t work out – as it was almost but not entirely certain to – would they just part ways with ’Oh well, it didn’t work out, maybe I’ll see you around some time’ and leave it at that?

There was every possibility that he was the last other human she would ever meet and she wasn’t about to mess that up by complicating things. Scratching that particular itch just wasn’t worth it.

She sighed as she scrubbed. It certainly would have been nice though.

“Think about something else, Jen,” she told herself. “Like the old fat bloke in marketing. Not attractive at–”

She was interrupted by the Zhadersil’s alarms going off as a Saurian voice provided some sort of message. She didn’t need to understand it to know that something was wrong.

She froze where she was, like a deer in the headlights. Alone on an ancient dinosaur spaceship with all sorts of unintelligible alerts going off. “Oh shit biscuits...”

Affrag

The sub–tropical rain was wet, warm and heavy, and an absolutely wonderful sensation to a man who’d spent his last few months washing out of a bucket. Adrian roamed the cloud–shadowed darkness of the alien forest that edged the plain where the Shopping Trolley had landed. Over the thunder he could hear the sound of spacecraft; it looked as though they had at least gone so far as to start sweeping the area by air.

But they couldn’t have had any sort of success yet. If they’d found the Hunter vessel, he was confident they would have hit it from orbit. That’s what he would have done, and he didn’t expect they were all as thick as each other.

He was about to give up on them ever coming to ground when a transport lander finally descended from the clouds, sending them roiling around its bulk as it slowed its descent. It splashed down in the mire where the water of the plains ran off onto lower ground. Just about the worst place they could have picked to land.

Just about the best place they could have picked if you were Adrian. He worked his way through the forest, drawing closer and closer to the sound of urgent, angry voices shouting above the roar of rain and thunder.

He slipped into cover behind a deadfall that dropped from forest to murk, and peered out from behind the debris. Several aliens were standing around in the mud, clearly about as fucking pissed off as they could be at this state of affairs.

“Eight outside the craft,” he mumbled to himself. “Likely to be a couple more inside.”

He figured he’d wait until the guys outside had moved off on whatever adventure they intended, then work his way in to attack the landing ship itself. From there he could get creative.

The guys on the ground appeared to finally give up shouting in disgust, and moved off as a commendably tightly formed unit in the direction of the plains and higher ground. They weren’t complete idiots, and if left to their own devices they’d probably locate the Shopping Trolley.

Adrian grinned evilly to himself. They’d be distracted long before that ever happened.

He dropped down into the muck once they’d moved out of view, then engaged the hover suit. With that he was able to float a small distance above the surface of the mire, and with a small amount of propulsion he could drift, mostly unseen, towards the landing craft.

He was there within a few minutes, with no sign of any alarm having been raised and was pleased to find that they’d left the hatch door down as a result of it being half submerged upon opening. No wonder the away party had been so mad; he didn’t even need to try as he slipped inside.

The alarm went off and two aliens – more of the Blue fucking Giraffes, the ’Rickle–prickle’ if he recalled the name of their species correctly – spun to face him. Their faces were masks of pure horror as they laid eyes on him, although he supposed he must look more like the monster of the black lagoon at this point than any sapient being.

“Right you tall fucksticks,” he said, enjoying their reaction as they realised he was intelligent. “I’ve got two options for you.”

They drew on him and fired their kinetic pulse guns. The shots felt like slaps on his wet skin.

“First option,” he continued as their horror visibly mounted. “I kill the absolute shit out of both of you.”

They fired again, more half–heartedly this time as he advanced on them. The shots hurt slightly more as he moved closer, but Adrian had been in too many brutal fights to even pay them much notice.

“Second option,” he said, now pointing his own gun at the nearest of the two. “You do one thing for me, and I let you go.”

Dominion Cruiser Itrz, Geosynchronous Orbit of Deathworld

“Lander is returning from surface at high speed,” reported Systems Superior Clklict. “They did not report any engagement with the enemy.”

Ship Master Drzzk looked at the console, his face contorting into thoughtful consideration. “They may be fleeing Hunters. Try and get them on the link. How long before they connect with us?”

“(Thirty seconds),” replied Clklict with some confusion, that was an awfully fast return from planetside, even from a Death world with a possible Hunter infestation. “I don’t see anything chasing them...”

Drzzk looked troubled. “Get them on link!”

“They’re not answering,” Clklict replied. “Could it be full of Hunters?”

“Deny it dock until we’re sure!” Drzzk commanded. “I won’t have–”

He was cut short by the impact of a landing pod ramming through the docking bay. The ship shuddered violently as the inertia system fought to reduce the vibrations. All manner of alert began to sound as the ship detected damaged system after damaged system.

But they didn’t need the damage system report; the view–screen told enough of the story that they could guess the rest. A section of the hull had been cleaved away by the force of the blow and air, plasma and debris gouted from the broken part of the ship.

“We’ve been hit by the lander!” Drzzk spat angrily. “Somebody shot us with our own landing craft! What’s the damage?”

“We’re damaged, with several key systems crippled,” Clklict relayed. “We’d never stand up to a Hunter attack right now. Sir, I suggest we warp out.”

“I don’t want to leave those men behind!” Drzzk told him. “I won’t leave them behind, Systems Superior!”

Clklict felt heavy with the knowledge of what needed to be said. “Sir,” he said slowly, “it is likely that your son is already dead.”

Drzzk’s expression darkened. “This is not about my son!” he said through clenched teeth. “This is about leaving men behind!”

“I understand sir,” Clklict continued. He had expected this excuse, but he did not relish what he did now. “In that case I must relieve you of your command.”

This is really Hambone’s universe, and it would be difficult at this point to separate it out. Plus this is the level of writing I do for fun.

I am definitely getting myself in a space to write a proper novel, however. For me the issue has always been a matter of confidence in the quality of what I write, as well as the ability to envision an ending and work towards it. That’s led to a few false starts.

All things considered, though, I would love to be in a position to just smash out novels as my day job.

Salvage19. Rogue Elements

By Rantarian

Trycrur and Chir touched down on the flight deck of the Zhadersil. With the exception of three of the other Hunter craft being missing, there were no changes to anything that they could see at least. The sweep they had performed around the outside, however, had revealed a single Hunter vessel lodged in the broken cavity on the hull, so that at least explained one of the missing craft.

“I suspect he used the conduits exposed in the wreckage to power the FTL,” Trycrur explained as they drifted past, illuminating the larger ship with the woefully inadequate lights on their own vessel. “I’m ashamed for not thinking of it.”

“It doesn’t seem to have worked very well if this is where he ended up,” Chir had replied. He’d been agitated since they’d discovered that the Zhadersil was sitting at the edge of the war front. “Although hopefully simply removing it from the Affrag system will be enough for now.”

There was air on the flight deck at least, and minor signs of recent activity that encouraged Trycrur to believe that Adrian was still alive and still in residence.

“If we had stayed, we might have prevented the ship from ending up here,” she said as they disembarked. “But it all seemed so hopeless at the time...”

“We are not to blame for seeing this as a hopeless case,” Chir replied. “It remains a hopeless case. Using other ships to provide it with power? It’s like trying to breathe life into a corpse!”

“Stop,” Trycrur said, holding up her hand as they reached the flight deck equipment store they’d left in place for convenience. Something seemed off. Things seemed... cleaner. “Does this place look as though it’s been cleaned?”

“It’s hard to imagine Adrian doing that,” Chir replied, “but I imagine even a Death worlder has a tolerance limit for filth.”

A sound from behind the equipment crates gave them pause, and they each had a hand on their kinetic pulse guns. If it were Adrian, it would hardly bother him, but if it was something else... it was always good to be certain.

“Come out from there,” Chir said cautiously, training his weapon on the crate. He fired a round at it, making it shake violently and eliciting a surprised yelp from whatever was behind it. Definitely not Adrian to make a sound like that. “Now!”

“Please,” came the voice. Female, soft and lyrical. Chir recognised the sounds as similar to Adrian’s but without the harshness to every sound. “Please, don’t shoot me!”

“Come out!” Trycrur demanded, although she was starting to get a very bad feeling about this situation. “Slowly!”

A mop handle waved above the crate, twirling back and forth in some sort of weird display. “I surrender! Please don’t shoot me!” the voice said again, filled with genuine fear.

“Just come out,” Trycrur said, more softly now. “We won’t hurt you!”

The creature behind the crate appeared to respond to this, and a red–haired head appeared from behind it. Trycrur’s breath caught as she saw it, a human face, much softer and with different colorations than Adrian’s, but a definite human face.

“Trycrur,” Chir said with concern, “tell me that humans do not self–replicate.”

“They’re bi–gendered,” Trycrur told him. “I think this is a female.”

“Do you think it’s weaker?” Chir asked, his gun still trained on what they guessed was a human female. “Does it even understand us?”

Trycrur peered at the human. “If she does, she’s not showing any sign of it, and all I can say is that she is clearly smaller and less robust than Adrian. It’s definitely weaker.”

Chir glanced at Trycrur. “Then what should we do? If Adrian has taken this one as a mate, he would not be pleased if we were to subdue her.”

Trycrur’s gaze hardened at the thought of that possibility. Of course she didn’t think of Adrian as a potential mate for herself, he wasn’t a Rauwryhr after all. If he had been, that would have been an entirely different story, but as it stood she had almost regarded him as an incredibly dangerous, wonderfully insane older brother. “Do you think she is?”

Jennifer Delaney. Mid–twenties, alone on a dinosaur spaceship, and held captive by a freakish raccoon man and its bat–creature associate. Today was not turning out so well.

She hoped that Adrian would be back soon. She didn’t doubt that he could crush these two with his bare hands if he needed to, but she did consider that she might be held hostage at gunpoint and then he’d be forced to surrender on her account. They’d be thrown into a cell together and forced to share that narrow bed–

She was getting off track. Raccoon. Bat. Prisoner. That’s what she needed to remember. Right now they’d managed to get her to sit somewhere comfortable while they pointed guns at her. It was clear to her from their agitation that they had not expected to find somebody here, and from the way they seemed to respond when she talked it was like they could understand her even if the reverse was not true.

She decided to test it. “You should both leave!” she said. “My... my boyfriend will be back soon and he’s got a mean right hook, so it is! He’ll lay both of you out like a Sunday dinner! Although come to think of it I don’t imagine you have any Sundays, do you?”

They appeared to grow puzzled, and then concerned. They talked to each other a bit more. “Okay, so that didn’t prove anything...” Jen said to herself. “Maybe if I started to talk about weapons... wait, shouldn’t the automated defense spider have killed you both by now?”

She glanced over at the robot that continued to scan the flight deck with its single ’eye’. Admittedly if it had attacked the two creatures now, she would have copped a face full of ball bearings along with them, but surely it should killed them almost as soon as they had landed. Unless Adrian’s programming skills were as poor as she suspected, or unless these two had foreseen the trap and had taken control of the robot.

The aliens had taken on a wary nature, glancing at the various defenses in case they were to unexpectedly spring to life. “If only they would,” she lamented. “Then I wouldn’t need to wait for that ape of a man. He can’t go rescuing me every time there’s a problem, you know! Even Disney Princesses only needed to be rescued once, although I’ll admit that this is more interesting than starving to death. Have you ever experienced starvation? It’s like hunger but worse–”

The Raccoon seemed markedly more agitated at this point and fired his gun meaningfully into the air.

“Well,” she said, “I guess I’ll be quiet then.”

Shopping Trolley

“This is the Shopping Trolley to the Dominion cruiser in orbit,” Adrian said over the communicator. His scans showed them still in orbit, but they’d been remarkably pig–headed about connecting the link once he’d declared himself as a human. “Look,” he said, tired of the silence, “I have ten of your men here and if you want them back you’re fucking well going to agree to a trade.”

He waited for the response again. The ’Rickey–lickeys’ had been greatly displeased by the discovery that he intended to shoot their landing craft at the mothership. That hadn’t stopped them from being extremely obedient when faced with sudden overwhelming violence. He had been pleased to discover that he away team had shared a similar attitude. They were all in the Shopping Trolley’s holding cell awaiting a response from the ship above, apparently called the ’Itrizz’. They were compliant prisoners, he had to give them that; had he been in their shoes he’d have had to be dragged kicking and screaming into the cell. It had been a little disappointing that they hadn’t done that.

“Itrizz, you fuckers!” Adrian said again, more forcefully this time. He was losing his patience. “Pick up or you’re going to have a new problem.”

There was again no answer. He sighed and initiated launch. “New problem it is.”

Dominion Cruiser Itrz, Geosynchronous Orbit of Deathworld

“We do not make deals with rogue elements,” Clklict said, although having discovered that the rogue element was a human and holding all ten of their men – or so he claimed – had altered things a bit, but raised a number of questions as a result, such as why a Human was flying a Hunter ship, and why he had attacked a Dominion cruiser without provocation.

“All ten of our men are alive down there!” Drzzk protested. “We can’t just leave them there!”

“We have no way of knowing if they’re actually alive,” Clklict said, “or that it intends to keep them that way if they are. Humans are obscenely dangerous, remember? They wouldn’t have been sealed into their home system if they weren’t.”

“This one hasn’t been sealed anywhere,” Drzzk pointed out bitterly.

“Where is that FTL!?” Clklict demanded, ignoring Drzzk’s unproductive whining.

“Damage was suffered on the relays,” his subordinate advised him. “Secondary conduits cannot carry that much power. We’ll need to hurry repairs to get it working again.”

“Then hurry them!” snapped Clklict. Sometimes it seemed as though he always had to think of everything, even when he hadn’t assumed command. Perhaps especially then!

“Sir,” said the same subordinate.

“I SAID HURRY THEM!” screamed Clklict, his temper snapping under stress.

The subordinate recoiled. “But sir... a ship has just docked.”

Adrian stepped off the Hunter ship into the weak atmosphere aboard the ship. That was what the Vacuum suit was for. The heavily armed response team was what his gun was for.

Exploding rounds were evidently a new development for them, because the survivors surrendered immediately after their commanding officer had been reduced to chunky salsa and sprayed all over them. He couldn’t fault them for logic at least, although they remained equal parts angry, humiliated and terrified. When they looked at him he could see it in their eyes, that pants–shitting terror that fucked a man up for life.

“You guys just need some fucking cement in your wheatbix,” he told them, knowing the entirety of it would be completely meaningless to them. “For now... take me to your doctors!”

“Report from docking area, sir,” the subordinate said, reading directly from the console. “About the human, sir.”

“Of course it’s about the human!” Clklict snapped. “Let me guess, he’s headed straight here? We’re about to have a confrontation with the kind of psychopath who shoots ships at other ships?”

“No sir...” the subordinate replied, his obvious confusion mounting. “He’s left.”

Clklict was confused as well now. “What? What about taking over our ship?”

“It seems like he just came to abduct our doctors,” the subordinate said. “He even returned our ten away team members, although that still leaves twenty–seven dead from the impact and further combat.”

“Well,” Drzzk interjected, “at least my son is alright.”

Shopping Trolley

“Mission success,” Adrian said as he activated the FTL. “For a given value of ’success’.”

It was true that the original intent of the mission had been to go and get some food, and connect with any ship that might have a medical officer. But, he reasoned, it was common knowledge that no plan survived contact with the enemy.

Lacking a missile he had decided to see if firing a landing craft at its mothership would have the desired outcome, and had been pleasantly surprised to discover that it very much had. He was just glad that he hadn’t wiped out the medical bay in the process.

Then they’d had the stubborn attitude of completely ignoring him when they’d learned he was a human. That had been somewhat insulting, but he supposed he might have had it coming at that point. He wondered if he might have just declared war on the Dominion and then decided that as they had largely been the ones responsible for imprisoning Earth and were, in general, galactic–scale land barons, he did not care one whit what they thought of him.

He was, then, in as good a mood as it was possible to be in wet, muddy clothing. That went downhill fast when he saw the unknown vessel sitting on the flight deck.

His eyes swept the flight deck quickly, and saw no sign of the defense systems being at work. “What the fuck is going on here?” he asked himself aloud.

It wasn’t a big ship, however, and he landed the Shopping Trolley next to it. He figured there’d be two of them at most, and with his trusty rifle he’d be able to humble the ship itself.

“Let’s see who you are,” he said, reading his gun and disembarking with it raised for shooting. He stopped as he saw who was waiting for him at the bottom of the gangway.

Chir and Trycrur, their guns aimed at Jen.

“Adrian!” Trycrur called to him urgently, surprisingly scared for being the one holding the weapon. “She can’t communicate with us! I’m afraid that if we put down our guns she’ll take us apart!”

“Adrian!” Jen called in much the same tone. “Please, don’t let them hurt me!”

Adrian let the barrel of the rifle drop, letting himself take in the full significance of the current situation. “Oh sweet merciful fuck,” he said under his breath. “Pardon my French.”

Well, I have a decent typing speed with high accuracy, but I think most of it comes out of being a ’seat of my pants’ Game Master for my mates.

I’ve managed to acquire the skill to go with the narrative flow and just see where it all takes me. It’s actually interesting to me as well to see where this goes because although I have some ideas for story elements I don’t have any idea how or if I will ever reach them.

What I’m basically saying is that is is not really conscious action for me. I’m literally some kind of storytelling machine, I just sit on my chair and put my hands on the keyboard and let rip.

Taking Back the Sky

by Hambone3110

A JVerse story.

Part 6 of the Kevin Jenkins series.

One year and seven months after the Vancouver Attack

One broadcast: +<awe; respect; statement> The Alpha-of-Alphas is here.+

Another broadcast: +<anticipation; glee; eagerness> The first human meat to the Alpha-of-Alpha’s maw!+

The Alpha-of-Alphas broadcast: +<rebuke> The quarry is dangerous. Remain focused.+

Chastened, the Brood-Guard fell into line respectfully around and behind the Alpha-of-Alphas as it emerged from its vessel. It stood nearly a head taller than even the largest of the lesser Alphas, and had undergone yet more extensive cybernetic upgrades, bonding all manner of arcane technology - reputedly of its own design - into its own flesh. The result was a mountain of metal and seething power, with seven blinking eyes gazing balefully out at the world of prey around it, covering all the angles, never resting.

Despite its size and bulk, the Alpha-of-Alphas moved in almost perfect stalking silence, a display of its long experience and skill as an apex predator. Without further communication, the Guardian Brood followed their master as it pursued the most recent contact report.

They paused as the lights flickered, and an instant later the deck heaved and rang to another impact - a stray shot from the battle in the void outside. The Dominion’s vessels were selling themselves dearly, even self-destructing rather than accept capture and the fate of all prey. But this was the first time the Swarm-of-Swarms had shown itself, and not even a third of it was committed to the battle. most was still cloaked, on standby for the event that Dominion reinforcements should arrive. By the decree of Alpha-of-Alphas, the Hunters were yet to show their full strength. That third, however, was still many thousands of ships, and the defenders had either fled or were being swept aside in their suicidal bid to protect the station for as long as possible.

The part inside found their quarry when a Brood-lesser tumbled into the corridor before them, crushed and broken, dead before it had stopped sliding.

The Alpha-of-Alphas broadcast: +<command> Release the drones.+

They did so, a swarm of insect-sized devices that would record what happened next and inject the footage directly onto the prey’s data networks. This, they knew, would prove to the prey beyond any doubt whom they should most be fearing.

The microdrones zipped up and out, retreating to the corners and ceiling of the room the dead Hunter had been thrown from, and then The Alpha-of-Alphas stalked through the door.

++

Caleb wouldn’t admit it, but he was starting to get scared. The children were hiding in a storage locker behind him, and so far he’d kicked the ass of every white freak that had come for him, even ten at a time. But he was tired - exhausted, even. Punch-drunk from so many of those weak-ass ray guns, floating in a shaky sea of stale adrenaline, bleeding from his nose and ears, bruised over practically every inch of his body, he still willed himself to stand up and face the next monster that came to challenge him.

This one, unusually, came alone. It was larger than the others, and armour-plated. It did not, however, seem to be carrying one of those pulse guns. Caleb was no idiot - he wasn’t about to assume that the monster was unarmed, and he doubted that he could have got past that armour when at his peak, let alone now. He could see the writing on the wall, and felt strangely at peace because of it.

“Time to die, huh?” he asked the monster, which surprised him by growling a reply in English. it actually spoke the English, too, he could tell the difference.

“Yesth. Ti-ime to die. M-eat to the m-aw.” it said.

“Fuck you.” Caleb told it.

He charged.

The alien raised its arm, aimed at the ground in front of him and fired, once.

He died.

++

The Alpha-of-Alphas broadcast: +<Satisfaction> The builders are to be commended. These nervejam grenade launchers work exactly as anticipated.+

The servos of its powered exoskeleton whined as it picked up the dead human by the back of his neck. The quarry seemed even heavier in death - the co-ordination and balance that had kept it upright and agile during his life was gone now, replaced by a few lingering twitches as the last jolts of the Nervejam effect rampaged around that delicately-optimized masterwork of a nervous system. All that was left was a mass of meat and bone as heavy as the Alpha-of-Alphas itself was even in its exoskeleton, and a fraction of the size.

No matter. The Prize awaited. Its helmet dismantled itself, dissolving into a swarm of construction nanites that crawled back into their hive at the nape of the Alpha-of-Alpha’s neck. It considered its limp prize for a second, and then opened its jaws as wide as they would go, bit into the human’s throat with all the strength it could muster, and - with some effort - ripped free a mouthful.

The meat was indescribable. Dense, lean, rich, full of that indefinable spark of sentience. It exceeded even the Alpha-of-Alpha’s most extravagant fantasies.

+<ecstasy> MEAT TO THE MAW!!!+

the cry was taken up among the brood, it spread to the swarm, and from there to the Swarm-of-Swarms and through them, every Hunter in the Galaxy.

The first Great Hunt had been successful.

Two years and Five Months after the Vancouver attack

Captain Rylee Jackson. It was a good name, and she hoped that people would remember it, and for the right reasons. She hoped that she would be remembered for earning this mission on skill and merit, rather than being sneered at as a diplomatic bit of political correctness, given the job just because she was a black woman.

It was a crazy mission. She’d gone to church, said her prayers, prepared herself as best she could. There was a non-zero chance that things could go horribly wrong, but all test pilots knew that. You just had to trust your sled.

“Houston, Pandora. Final checklist complete.” she intoned, her tone steadier than she felt.

“Copy Pandora. There’s no window here, Rylee, so just go whenever you’re ready for it.” She knew that her flight operator down in Houston was probably just as scared as she was, but there was that voice, the calm and steady one that said everything, no matter how dramatic, with perfect clarity and confidence. She knew that even if she disintegrated in a few seconds, that professional tone would never crack. She could become a smear of plasma across half the heavens, and add her name to the victims of humanity’s odyssey, and that voice would coldly describe her demise as a “malfunction”.

In its way, that was comforting.

“Houston, Pandora... Let’s take back the sky.”

She allowed herself a smile of triumph at not repeating Armstrong’s mistake and choking on her big quote. Still congratulating herself, she pressed the button. Two seconds and a billion kilometers later, with a ferociously ecstatic whoop, Rylee Jackson entered the history books as the first human being to outrun light.

Jenkins’ bar erupted. The entirety of the Scotch Creek base staff had crowded in to watch the moment when their two years of hard work had paid off, and paid off it had, in style. From Claude Nadeau’s breakthroughs in electrostatic field emitters that had allowed Pandora to fly on gargantuan weightless wings of pure force-field and boost itself into space for a fraction of the expense required by a traditional rocket, to Ted Bartlett unravelling the secrets of spacetime field distortion technology and inventing a distortion drive that actually worked on a reasonable budget of energy, without any awkward relativistic time dilation and without ripping apart the sun in the process.

General Tremblay smiled indulgently as the crowd of ecstatic scientists formed a circle with their arms around each other’s shoulders and launched into a drunken, cacophonous rendition of “We Are the Champions”.

“Heck of a day.”

He turned to Kevin Jenkins, who had been the one to start the song on the bar’s music system. He had fit into the base perfectly, falling comfortably into his niche as the Scotch Creek Research Facility’s resident purveyor of alcohol, caffeine, filling food and televised sports matches. Probably two-thirds of the major breakthroughs at the base had taken place over coffee and bacon cheeseburgers at the bar’s increasingly-scuffed wooden tables.

“Heck of a day.” Tremblay agreed, trying to make it sound like his heart was in it. Jenkins just handed him another coffee - black, two sugars - with an expression that said he could see straight through the general’s attempt at positivity. He was as bad as Dr. Sung sometimes.

“Shitty time for a divorce, general.” Jenkins said.

Check that. Jenkins could be far, far worse than the doctor sometimes. He didn’t have a professional code of conduct stopping him from being blunt.

“How… how did you guess?”

“Doesn’t take a rocket surgeon.” Jenkins told him. “You’ve been sitting there staring at your wedding band looking like you took a dump and found a kidney in the bowl.”

“Is there such a thing as a good time for a divorce?” Tremblay asked.

Jenkins thought about it. “When you wake up the morning after a night out on Vegas and there’s a shaved orang-utan in your bed?”

Tremblay couldn’t resist it: he laughed. Jenkins gave a satisfied nod. “how long were you married?” he asked.

“Ten years. Stefan’s a great guy and I love him so much it hurts, but… y’know, he wanted me to retire and adopt a couple of kids with him. But then Rogers Arena, this base…” Tremblay sipped his coffee as he trailed off.

“Life happens, man.” Jenkins told him. “At least it’s not boring. Be a whole lot worse for you if you were moping around at home lovesick and not knowing what to do with yourself.”

“True. At least I can focus on my work…” Tremblay smiled at that, his first genuine smile of the day, as he looked at the big-screen on the wall, where mission control at Houston was just starting to settle down from its jubilation and get back to work. “And we did good today, didn’t we?”

“You did damn good, man.” Jenkins said. “Sure, that kid Jackson’s the name everyone will remember, but she’d never have got up there without you. Hell, it was you persuaded the treaty members to unify their space programs. I guarantee that Pandora would never have been funded without that.”

Tremblay nodded, and put his drink down. “Thanks, Kevin. I needed that.”

“Anytime, Martin.”

“She has been in there for <two months> now. We think she managed to tap into a water pipe and from the smell she maybe even set up a Dizi Rat farm in there. And she refuses to come out.”

“Would you, when the galactic news is full of members of your species being thrown out of the airlock?”

“Look we weren’t going to do that. We were just going to… you know, evict her. Give her a little ship and some nutrient spheres and point her towards a nice Class Eleven somewhere. She’s from a Class Twelve, right? She should have no problem surviving there.”

Kirk issued the equivalent of a frustrated sigh. Like all Rrrrtktktkp’ch, he was fond of his Vz’ktk cousins, but they really were as dense as a bag of gold sometimes.

“I did some research on this one. She used to sell insurance before the Corti took her. She used to sit in an office with a headset on talking to people over audio-comms. On her days off, she used to fashion garments out of spun animal hair, and went swimming in a heated, disinfected pool. She may be native of a Class Twelve but frankly I think she might have starved to death on a Class Six.” he said. A thought struck him and he chuckled. “They abducted her on the way home from that pool, actually. Think she knows where her towel is?”

“Her...Towel? Uh... I don’t… nobody ever...”

“In-joke. Never mind.” It was hard being a fan of human literature sometimes.

“...Okay? Well. I don’t know how you’re going to get her out of there, nobody can fit in there except maybe for a Gaoian or Corti, and even if they could, she’s human. She broke a security officer’s leg accidentally!”

“Oh, it’s okay. I think she just needs to see a friendly face.”

The Vz’ktk security officer looked up as the door cycled to admit Maria, Heidi, and Steve, the latter of whom flipped a jaunty mock salute to the stunned officer before stooping slightly and presenting his linked hands to boost the two women up into the open ventilation duct below which Kirk and the officer had been conversing. He leaned against the wall and waited, watching the tall blue being with that unsettling binocular gaze that seemed to flicker all over him, taking in every detail.

“You brought more?!”

“Twenty-two more, to be exact.” Kirk said, secretly enjoying himself. “Don’t worry, they’ve all got disease suppression implants.”

“But.. don’t you know how dangerous...?”

“Who, them or the Hunters? They’re nice people. A little strange, some of them, and I really can’t tell if that’s because of the isolation or if that’s how they always were, but trust me, every single one’s as moral and good-natured a being as you could wish to meet. And the Hunters don’t have the first clue my little flying sanctuary exists, so far as we know. Besides, if this goes as well as it usually does, she’ll be on board among her own kind and we’ll be gone soon enough.”

“Sanctuary. You’re… keeping them safe?”

Kirk nodded. “Somebody has to take care of the poor little monsters when the galaxy’s losing its mind.” he said.

There was a scuffle from the vents, announcing Heidi and Maria’s return. Behind them was Abigail, the woman they had come to rescue. She dropped lightly to the deck in the - for her - light gravity, shot the officer a glare that wished it could be as deadly as the rest of her, and shook hands with Steve, who put a friendly arm gently around her shoulders and guided her from the room.

Kirk was secretly delighted to notice that she had a large beige towel draped over her shoulders.

“See? Problem solved. Now you can put out the word that your station is a human-free zone and the Great Hunt will pass you by, hmm?”

He said it lightly, but there was an accusatory edge to the apparently benign observation. He regretted it when the officer wilted slightly, and reminded himself that it wasn’t the poor young male’s fault - he was just following orders, in a job not dissimilar to the one Kirk himself had held only a few years ago.

On a whim he decided to repair things and sent a small currency gift to the officer’s personal network.

“Here. Get yourself some tllktrrk’nq or something. My treat. You’ll get in touch if any more humans show up?”

The officer offered a defeated gesture of assent. “Sure. Yes. I will.”

“Good. Thank you. It’s been a pleasure.”

He swept from the room. Behind him, the pressure of sheer charm that he’d been keeping up the whole time slowly deflated, and the security officer recovered himself enough to glance at his personal funds, the ceiling vent, and the door.

“What the sh’rrt.” he muttered.

++

“Okay, I’ve seen some fast-talking in my time, but you had that guy just swallowing every word you said within seconds of meeting him.” Heidi commented during the walk back to the Sanctuary. “How’d you do that?”

“Vz’ktk have an instinctive respect for the judgement and intelligence of my own species.” Kirk explained. “All you have to do is keep talking in an amiable ‘I know everything about everything’ tone of voice and they’ll agree to sell you their sister if you keep it up long enough.”

“You’re shitting me.”

“Exaggerating.” Kirk allowed. “but they really do grow up with the idea that we’re the smart ones. That builds a degree of innate respect and trust.”

The Sanctuary had been modified yet again since the Hunter Ultimatum, growing three rings of cabins that encircled the reactor, enough for four times its current population. Given that they were sized for the average species, they were huge by human standards - the beds large and luxurious, with plenty of room for floor exercises. Kirk had permanently set the gravity, temperature and pressure on those decks to mimic sea level on Earth, and left the human passengers to their own devices.

Three of the twenty-two - twenty-three, now - only rarely showed their faces, preferring to lurk up in the cabins and avoid him. The rest were happy to spend time in the large recreational area, playing games, watching movies, or just hanging out and talking. He was pretty sure there was a fair amount of sex going on in the cabins, too: months or years of isolation without seeing others of their own kind had left many of the refugees with unresolved tensions that they were vigorously and gladly resolving.

Kirk had first started researching human sexuality long ago when the Observatory was first established. What he found had initially disturbed him, and then later made him jealous. Among his own kind, the point of reproduction was reproduction. It brought emotional fulfilment and intellectual pleasure to carry out the act of continuing the species, and the act itself was reportedly pleasantly intimate and had some enjoyable sensations. Kirk didn’t know first-hand, having fathered no children.

For Humans, however, the act itself seemed to bring intense physical pleasure, as well as considerable emotional satisfaction and positive social repercussions. Like everything the species did, there were conflicting norms and etiquettes everywhere. There was a stigma to having no sex and a stigma to having too much. There was a stigma to having never had sex, and a stigma to having it prior to engaging in a legal bond-partnership. There was a stigma to sex with members of the same sex - and the fact that this was even an option had been a source of major confusion for Kirk at first - and yet most humans seemed to be to some extent inclined to bisexuality.

Then there were gender identities: ones that correlated with the biological sexes, ones the directly opposed them, and gender identities that had nothing to do with either of the available biological options at all.

The whole thing was bewildering and strange, but also exciting, and made Kirk feel a little envious. He had long since realised that for all their physical impressiveness and mental agility, humans were still just as fragile as anybody else in their own ways. To learn that they had a whole type of pleasure available to them which Kirk would never be able to experience for himself felt a little unfair.

He was wondering how it had helped them survive the conditions on Earth when his train of thought was interrupted by a call from the ship. He had left Lewis in charge of the ship’s sensors and comms.

“Kirk man, uh… like, we just got some pretty big news bro.”

Kirk hadn’t yet managed to figure out if Lewis’ speech pattern was due to the permanent influence of a Corti experiment, a lifetime of recreational narcotics, or just how he was. “Share it.”

“Uh… news from Earth, dude. Looks like our guys just went FTL for like the first time ever.”

Kirk came to a dead halt in the hallway, oblivious to the beings that were edging around the knot of three humans and past him.

"Uh... Kirk? Why are you smiling, man?"

"Oh, no reason. It's just nice when your friends impress you."

“Meeting is called to order in the chair and so on let’s get on with this. HOW did they get FTL so quickly?”

The scribe scrambled to finish the block of formalities that were the usual preface to meetings of the Dominion Security Council, and then gave up in bewilderment as the representatives of five different species all tried to speak at once.

While most of the remaining representatives just looked silent and glanced sideways at one another, one raised a huge hand and waited, radiating a patient pink.

“Councillor Vedreg?” the chairman addressed him. “You have an opinion.”

“I do.” The clamour died, and they turned to listen to him.

He took a moment to gather his shawl of office around his upper shoulders and strike a suitable statesbeinglike posture before launching into his explanation.

“We have reason to believe that a functioning wormhole beacon may have been smuggled to Earth during the early years of the Observatory program. Despite having been moved outside of the barrier, the Observatory still exists and has been monitoring spacetime distortions around Earth and its near orbit. Among the many traces we found in the subcycles preceding the launch and test flight of this human craft, were some that corresponded to the generation of experimental wormholes.”

“Reverse-engineering a working Apparent Linear Velocity drive from the temporal stasis technology contained in Hunter assault pods would have yielded FTL technology ahead of schedule anyway, gentlebeings, but when coupled with access to a working jump beacon…”

The Rauwryhr delegate interrupted him at that. “Jump beacons are useless by themselves.” she pointed out.

“For travel, maybe. For the purposes of learning the fundamentals of spatial distortion science, you could not ask for a better specimen technology.” Vedreg explained calmly.

The Gaioan delegate - a venerable male with long streaks of white around his eyes and muzzle - spoke up. “Need I remind the council that while the reforms to Dominion law concerning the status of intelligent non-FTL capable species is still being negotiated, the law has always been clear that once a planetary civilization has successfully and safely caused one living member to travel faster than light, they are official sentients and must be afforded the full rights and protection of a provisional member?” He said. “I must repeat that it is the official stance of the Clans of Gao that the quarantine field is a crime against the human race and that it should be removed as soon as possible.”

There was the general equivalent of nodding and “hear, hear.”

Vedreg’s flanks flushed a complicated medley of reds and purples. “In a purely personal capacity, Father Vyan, I agree, and I would like it on record that I voted against the proposal when it was first tabled in the Confederate Assembly.” he said. “I was outvoted, and it remains beyond my power to countermand that decision.”

Kirk’s replacement as the representative for the Vz’ktk Domain spoke up. “But it is not beyond your species’ power to ignore the Founding Charter.” she retorted. “The Confederacy is constitutionally obligated to remove that quarantine field.”

Vedreg clamped down on emotional luminscence, allowing only a forthright grey shaded with firm dark orange to show. “You are correct, of course. However…” He trailed off, searching for the correct way to phrase his next explanation.

The Corti representative finally chimed in, deploying a careful “...however?” into the conversation at the precise moment it would do the most harm to his confidence.

“However the barrier cannot be removed.” Vedreg explained.

“It must be.” asserted the Corti representative, calmly.

“I do not mean that my government is officially unwilling to remove it - though that is in fact the case - but that we do not in fact have the ability to do so.”

This was met with an incredulous silence that he rushed to fill.

“Humanity have attracted the ire of the Hunters. FTL-capable sentients though they may now be, they lack the orbital defensive infrastructure to protect themselves from the “Swarm of Swarms” should it descend upon an unprotected Earth. The best guess of our own Xenopsychologists is that the Hunters are not afraid of humanity, but are instead jealous of them. The humans have, after all, attracted considerable attention and fear in recent cycles, and the best guesses we have into Hunter psychology is that they view it as imperative that they be feared.

“The existence of a species which we, their prey, apparently fear even more than the Hunters themselves, is a direct affront to them. So, dropping that barrier would result in the almost inevitable genocide of a species that, for all their physical and mental tenacity, could not hope to survive a sustained orbital barrage.”

Again, the Corti spoke up. “A morally sound reason” he said, making the words “morally sound” carry the same weight of emotional opinion as he might have said ‘financially questionable’. “So let us hear about your inability to remove the barrier. Your own experts designed it, did they not?”

“Indeed… to defend our own systems from external military threats. Converting one into a containment barrier was done hastily by the simple expedient of programming the emitter nexus to wrap itself up inside its own field.”

“Surely it can be remotely deactivated?”

“You must understand, Councillor, this was a defensive tool. The risk that it might be hacked and disabled by an appropriately skilled communications expert would have been a military liability. The device does not communicate with other systems via anything other than a physical connection.”

The Corti nodded understanding. “Which is now impossible to establish thanks to the way it is contained within its own field.” He sniffed his disdain. “Rather an unfortunate oversight by your engineers.”

This sentiment was echoed around the table.

“The Confederacy will make all appropriate reparations to the human race of course.” Vedreg said, hurriedly.

“A safe assertion, considering that they appear to be indefinitely contained.” the Gaoian said. “The Mother-Supreme of our clan of females will be notified of this, however. If you cannot make appropriate reparations to the human race, you can at least offer all necessary steps to compensate those humans who were stolen-” here, the furred councillor shot a glare at the Corti representative, which the latter being totally failed to acknowledge “-from their homeworld and have taken up residence in the galaxy at large, and to those species and organisations that have taken it upon themselves to provide them with sanctuary and a place to live.”

“Meaning Gao, I assume.” the Domain’s representative noted, with all of a Rrrrtktktkp’ch’s dry wit.

“Among others.” the councillor agreed, defiantly. She was about to offer a sharp retort when Vedreg held up one enormous hand, flanks shaded to indicate resignation.

“The Gaoian representative speaks the truth, the Confederacy is thus obligated to compensate them.” He agreed, having spent several boring days reviewing the law and precedents that applied in this scenario, none of which had contained any help for the Confederacy. “What are the terms requested by the Clans of Gao?” he asked.

“Food supplies, nutritional supplements and medical supplies necessary to support all humans who choose to accept sanctuary on our homeworld, plus appropriate military hardware and assistance to defend our planet from Hunter retaliation.” the councillor replied, having clearly memorised the terms in advance. “An immediate cessation of the information blackout surrounding Earth and the establishment of diplomatic channels so that all stranded humans may directly contact their loved ones. Remunerative compensation to our people equivalent to ten thousand Dominion development credits per human refugee who settles on Gao for longer than two cycles, and a five-cycle waiver on our obligation to commit units to the Celzi conflict.”

“Those last two terms are unacceptable.” the Rauwryhr delegate objected, siding with the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun.

“Excessive, certainly.” Vedreg agreed. “While the Guvnurag have no grounds to appeal the first, second and third terms, my people have the right to negotiate over the penultimate term, and that last one is a matter for the security council.”

The chairman spoke. “then it is the ruling of this council that the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun Confederacy is to pay to the Clans of Gao and to any other people or organisation who harbour human refugees the following: food, nutritional supplements and medical supplies to provide for that human’s needs, military assistance and/or hardware sufficient to realistically defend them from Hunter attacks. Furthermore, the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun Confederacy is required to permit ships to approach the Sol blockade and communicate with Earth.” It said.

“The motions have also been tabled first that the Confederacy is to pay ten thousand Dominion development credits per human refugee to any species or organisation which protects them, with the motion’s opposition requesting negotiation of that amount. As many of each opinion vote now.”

There were a few busy moments while each representative made their decision.

“The second motion is that the Gaioan Clans should be granted a five-cycle waiver on military involvement in the Celzi conflict, with the opposition denying that motion outright. As many of each opinion vote now.

Again, they voted.

“As to the first motion, being the four thousand three hundred and third vote of this council, There were two votes in favour, eight votes against, and three abstentions. The opposition has it, and the requested sum of credits will be renegotiated.” the chairman sounded the little chime that ceremonially marked that a decision was complete. “As to the second motion, being the four thousand three hundred and fourth vote of this council, there was one vote in favour, twelve votes against, no abstentions. The opposition have it and the motion is defeated.”

The second chime was the signal for council scribes, aides and messenger drones to zip about the place in a frenzy of activity. The chairman raised its ceremonial rod and spoke slightly louder about the noise. “this council session will now recess until the next standard diurnal period.”

Two years and seven months after the Vancouver attack

“Civilian vessel, this is Confederacy destroyer Vugarunguvrunek. Identify yourself and state your intentions.”

“Vugarunguvrunek, this is yacht Sanctuary requesting permission to approach the broadcast point.”

“Permission granted, Sanctuary. You are cleared for one burst transmission of no larger than three terabytes.”

“Acknowledged, Vugarunguvrunek.”

Thanks to the convenient relay offered by a Corti communications monitoring station that had been installed twenty years previously, it was a trivial matter for the Sanctuary to squirt a total of twenty-five videos towards Earth. Twenty-four of them were from the human refugees, many of them tearful as they finally took the chance to relieve their loved ones’ fears.

The twenty-fifth was from Kirk.

“Kevin. I hope this finds you still alive and complaining: I know for a fact that you’re well wrapped-up in whatever’s going on down there. You see, I knew about the jump beacon.

The one you stole was trash, by the way: so I snuck a working replacement into your bag. Glad to see it worked as planned. Tell whoever you gave it to that if they tune it with the algorithm that’s on screen right now, we can start sending some of these people home.

Now, on to the really important stuff. If I know humans, you’re probably already well on your way to dropping this barrier somehow, but take it from your old friend: for the time being, that would be a very, very bad idea.

You see, a lot has happened up here since Vancouver…”

End part 6

Humans don’t make good pets part 16.2

By guidosbestfriend

Blatvec’s simple neural cybernetic implant woke him. It was only fulfilling its given purpose, but the Dominion commander still considered having it removed to have the immense pleasure of shooting it. He only had himself to blame, however, since he himself had set the time, and for good reason. The battle had only ended yesterday, and he had been so exhausted upon his return to the troopship that he had gone straight to bed, postponing the mountain of paperwork which followed even the most minor of confrontations. Technically, he should have filed the necessary reports immediately after the battle, but he hadn’t survived the 74th’s most costly and difficult conflict only to drop dead from exhaustion at his desk.

The bureaucratic bullshit of the Dominion could only wait so long, though, and ignoring it never made it disappear. He knew; he had tried before. At least he would be able to clear up some of his confusion regarding several moments during the battle. “Gurvix,” he said, grabbing the troopship’s computer’s attention, “Inform the commander from the squad recently transferred from the 109th that he’s to report to my office immediately.”

Command confirmed. Message sent.

Blatvec looked over casualty reports as he waited, which did nothing to improve his mood. All told, the 74th had suffered losses of nearly 50%, making it the most costly victory since the beginning of the war. Replacement recruits for the 74th were always slow in coming, since the level of competence necessary to serve in such a prestigious division was hardly commonplace. Thankfully, a distraction soon arrived as the Vzk’tk commander entered his office and stood smartly at attention.

“Reporting as ordered, sir.”

“Thank you, Sergeant. Please, sit. Don’t look nervous, you aren’t in trouble. If it hadn’t been for your quick and unconventional thinking, we wouldn’t be talking and the 74th would be nothing more than a name on a war memorial. First of all, I wanted to personally thank you, and I’m sure some higher ups will want to do the same. However, I also wanted to hear an account of your actions while it was still fresh in your mind. There’s going to be a lot of questions regarding your tactics and it will be easier for the both of us if I submit as detailed a report as possible. Start from your landing and go from there.”

“Before I start, sir, I need to clarify something. I wasn’t responsible for any of the . . . interesting tactics during that battle.”

Blatvec wasn’t surprised. This was a Vzk’tk after all, and history was decidedly lacking in Vzk’tk strategists of extraordinary skill, or Vzk’tk strategists, for that matter. Still, it would have been rude to say ‘I knew it!’, so he feigned surprise as he waited for the squad leader to continue his story. As the silence stretched on, Blatvec realized a continuation would require a prompting on his part.

“I’m shocked,” he lied, “If you weren’t the one who saved our asses out there, then who did?”

“Human.”

That did give Blatvec pause. “Come again?”

“Human came up with those tactics.”

“If I’m remembering correctly, Human is the soldier of unknown species in your squad. He also doesn’t have a translator, if memory serves. I’ll be honest I didn’t read all the reports I was sent regarding your squad’s members, and I don’t know anything beyond that. Is this ‘Human’ much unlike other soldiers?”

“Sir . . . he’s . . . yes. Yes he is.”

Several hours and disbelieving outbursts later

“So you just let Human do whatever he wants, then the rest of your squad follows suit?” Blatvec asked incredulously.

“It’s rather difficult to control him, but so far all his deviations from what we consider “usual” tactics have ended up helping us, and by now we’ve figured it’s best to just let him do his own thing unimpeded, since he’s going to do it whether we want him to or not.” Trxcl answered.

“Would your gesture language let me talk to him?”

“Not very well. We basically made it so that he didn’t end up attacking the wrong side or running in the wrong direction. Aside from orders and a few simple phrases, it doesn’t cover much more.”

Blatvec grunted. That would have to be rectified as soon as possible. If Human could manage such effective tactics through mere example, imagine what would be possible if he could explain the more complex ideas that were hopefully bouncing around inside his head. He’d probably have to call in most of his favors to make it happen, but if the potential rewards were anything close to what he hoped they were, this would be worth it. “I’d still like to thank him, if that’s possible.”

The Vzk’tk paused a moment longer than usual before answering. “Normally it would, but, I don’t know–” that much was obvious, “he’s been . . . different . . . since we got back. He’s usually unbearably loud right after a victory, and downright alarming once he’s slept for a large number of rics (30 minutes intervals), but today he was completely silent. No noises, no gestures, just staring at the floor in front of him. We tried to get his attention several times, and he either ignored us or honestly didn’t see us. You can go and see him for yourself if you like, but I don’t think we’d be able to get him to come here on his own, and forcibly moving him would require a hovercart. Even if you did go to him, I don’t think he’d acknowledge your presence.”

That was worrying. “Any idea why he’s acting like this?”

“None.”

+Does anyone else in your squad have ideas as to why he’s acting like this?+ But Blatvec kept his thoughts to himself.

“Could he be hurt? You said his body acts differently to damage than any other specie’s you’ve seen, maybe this is how his system deals with trauma.”

“That’s a possibility.”

“Get that hovercart and take him to the medical quarters. Unlike the 109th we have a several scanners, so if there’s anything wrong with him it should be easy to find. That’ll be all for now, Sergeant. Dismissed.” As the Vzk’tk left with a quick “Yes, sir,” Blatvec had already started calling in the numerous favors needed to secure a high–end translator for an unregistered, unknown species. He hated dealing with Corti.

Valur hated dealing with Corti, but the only species more adept with cybernetic implantation were Hunters, and he doubted they would look kindly upon the maneuver he was currently attempting at this small Corti research facility. It was very small. Only three researchers worked there. The Directorate had intended it to be a secret. The only reason Valur knew of its existence was because he had been present in the control room when the sensor station, now under Dominion control, had intercepted one of the research facilities infrequent reports.

Despite its size, it was very well equipped. Its purpose was to attempt to find none–sapient animal species which could be controlled through cybernetic implants for use in the military. Essentially the Directorate, which was backing the Dominion in the Celzi–Dominion conflict – if it could be said that the Directorate truly backed anyone – was trying to find an effective means of countering the Vulza. That was why it was based on this out–of–the–way deathworld, and while the station had numerous defenses more than capable of fending off unintelligent monsters, Valur had slipped through without a hitch.

Which was why he was currently pointing a heavy kinetic–pulse gun at two frightened Corti researchers as he stood over the dead and smoking body of an Allebenellin. It was a shame. He assumed the recently deceased sophant would have been extremely helpful in his proposed venture, but it had been too dangerous to let it remain alive.

“You’re insane!” the one on the right spluttered.

“Maybe,” Valur replied, “But that doesn’t change what I want. So are you going to do it or do I have to pulp both of you and move on and find another pair of Corti?”

“What makes you think we’ll not kill you during your proposed – and my colleague is quite right – absurd surgical procedure?” the one on the left spoke.

“Because I’m not going to be unconscious while you’re working. Local anesthetics only.”

“This station is equipped for surgery on creatures from a deathworld. Nearly every anesthetic we have is an overpowered general. The only locals we have in stock are meant for the numerous minor injuries that are unavoidable in a pit of torment such as this planet, but would impede our efficiency if left un–dulled. Those locals aren’t meant for full surgery, let alone what you are so persistently suggesting. If we were to do it, you would still be in monumental pain.”

“I understand. Doesn’t change a thing, I’m still going to need you to do it.” Valur replied grimly.

Evidently Lefty had thought his words would dissuade him from his actions. Eyes widening, the Corti emulated the splutters of his companion. “Bu– Wha– Why?”

Valur paused a moment before answering.

“It’s hard to kill nightmares without being a nightmare yourself.”

Nonplussed by his reply, the Corti only stared at him. If anything he had just confirmed his own instability in their minds. No matter. So long as they did what he wanted, he didn’t care what they thought. “Your answer?”

Their answer was to prepare the surgical equipment and necessary parts.

Valur took a deep breath before they began the surgery which would transform most of his body into a machine. It would hurt, but vengeance for his only friend, his brother, was worth it.

The nightmares would fear him.

The Ox’s Plan Part 1

by hume_reddit

[1y 5m AV]

Ayma would never get tired of bringing cubs on their first shuttle ride. Usually such trips were simple outings to the starbase in orbit around Gao, or educational visits to the odd starship, but it was always the ride up into orbit that thrilled the cubs first. They would press their furry faces against the shuttle windows and watch the ground and the clouds shrink below them, until the stars suddenly became visible. Then their eyes would aim upward, either at one of Gao’s two tiny moons, one of the space stations, or the odd starship that waited in orbit.

It was rare to see an adult act that way. But - by Xiù’s own admission - she was barely an adult, and her face was pressed so close to the shuttle’s window that her tiny nose was bent sideways. Thankfully the window was transparent crystal matrix and she didn’t have to worry about the human accidentally cracking it, not even with her strength. Ayma was happy to see her human Sister showing excitement and wonder - she’d been badly treated by her introduction to the galaxy and its peoples.

After the fateful visit to Furfeg in the city, the Mothers had learned what human misery looked like. Xiù spent most of the next few days in her nest-bed, rarely leaving the dorm and sometimes skipping meals even when Ayma would scold her for it. Unlike a Gaoian she made no noise… instead her eyes watered continuously, and Ayma found herself thinking back, trying to remember if she’d ever behaved the same way in the time she’d been with them. Had she been upset and they hadn’t recognized it?

Myun had barged her way into the Sisters’ dorm and comforted Xiù the way she would any other cub: by cuddling up. Xiù seemed to appreciate it, especially when the other cubs of her “taiji” group decided Myun had the right idea. Soon their instructor was buried in furry little bodies, chittering and jockeying for space on top of the lone alien, their weight utterly meaningless to a creature that could carrying them all simultaneously. It worked, the human making the first of her barking laughs in nearly a ten-day and finally allowing herself to be dragged to the evening meal, where Yulna all but force-fed her.

Ayma had reported Xiù’s improved spirits to Mother-Supreme Giymuy, briefly astounded when she pondered the strange circumstances that lead to her regularly exchanging holovid calls with arguably the most important being on Gao.

It had been nearly half a Gaoian year since that meeting, since the human homeworld had been caged behind an immense bubble built from energy and fear. Gao was slowly taking its place within the Dominion... and as Giymuy had promised, the new member was making a nuisance of itself regarding the enclosure of the human world. They demanded specifications on the shield, debated how long it would be in place, and championed the rights and care of the humans trapped outside. Father Vyan, leader of the Ebony Paw clan and chosen representative to the Galactic Council, had proven to be a particularly cunning member of a clan known for favouring intelligence. He’d begun subtly planting an idea into the heads of the other representatives, one by one: if the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun Confederacy could trap one species within its star system, what was stopping it from doing it to others?

It wasn’t enough to get the other members to unify and demand the Confederacy remove the shield, but it kept them from being too celebratory about its use.

If Furfeg knew about the trouble Gao was making, about the metaphorical knives being planted in his peoples’ collective backs, he didn’t mention it. Instead his periodic holovid calls to the commune - tense, hostile affairs, as Ayma still didn’t like him - merely inquired about Xiù’s health and how well she was subsisting among the Gaoians. He seemed concerned and sympathetic, but she often wondered whether he was checking to make sure the human hadn’t snapped and started murdering everyone within reach. That was what the fools in the Council thought would happen, wasn’t it?

One day he’d called to ask Xiù to come to the Council and plead for the humans in person, and Ayma found herself granting the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun some respect (much to her annoyance). It was an offer long overdue, and like any Mother, Ayma put aside her personal dislike for the big herbivore and helped Xiù prepare. She also demanded the right to go along… though she wasn’t inclined toward conspiracies - she’d leave that to the Corti - she didn’t trust leaving her friend purely in Furfeg’s hands.

“Is that the ship?” Xiù breathed, unaware of Ayma’s many worries. Her Gaori had continued to improve, and she was far more intelligible than she’d been even just half a year beforehand. She could still get lost if someone spoke too quickly, and a lot of her word choices were “childish”, which made sense because the majority of her language lessons had come from Myun.

Furfeg had cautioned them not to bother trying to correct that when preparing her for her appearance before the Council. Xiù would speak to them in Gaori; and though everyone would be hearing her through their own respective translators, the devices would hear and interpret the intonation of her words and reflect it in their output… making the human sound very young and innocent, and thus sympathetic.

It was further proof to Ayma that Furfeg was a manipulator, but she couldn’t complain this time since he was using it to Xiù’s benefit.

She bent down to see through the window Xiù was all but glued to. Above them stretched the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun diplomatic starship, Furfeg’s ship. His was a large people, and so they built large vessels - hundreds of times the length of their comfortable shuttle. An immense cylinder in space, the ship was tinted a pleasant light green, its belly bulging as though pregnant with the large transparent greenhouse that supplemented the ship’s food and oxygen stores. The ship drifted out of the window toward the front of their shuttle as their pilot altered course toward it. “That’s the Rich Plains, yes,” Ayma answered.

Xiù softly repeated the words under her breath, practicing the name. She glanced back at the Gaoian. “I never thought I’d go to space,” she said. “On Earth, it is very dangerous. Only the best and bravest go. And here I am, for third time.” She shook her head. “My brother would be much happier.”

“He studies to go to space?”

She shook her head again, laughing quietly. “No, he doesn’t study at all! Very lazy, always wants to play. He would annoy you very much.”

Ayma rocked her head back in forth in a Gaoian shrug. “Well, he is a male, they can’t help it.” Xiù laughed again.

The shuttle looped up and over the Rich Plains, swooping down toward the tail end of the ship, which had clamshelled open, exposing the vast shuttle bay. The inside was well-lit, and they could see many sapients standing inside - most scurrying around offloading provisions, but a small cadre stood in an open area, including what was obviously a Guvnuragnaguvendrugun.

“Do they stand in space?” Xiù asked, appalled.

Ayma chittered lightly. “No… there is a kinetic field, it holds the air inside. In just a moment you will feel it… see?” And they did, a soft tingling across their skin as they crossed into the landing bay, floating slowly toward the glowing landing point indicator.

The shuttle touched down with barely a thump - the pilot was One-Fang clan, and they prided themselves on their skill with ships of all sorts. The side-door to the shuttle opened upward, letting in the air of the starship; not as antiseptic as Ayma had expected, but tinged lightly with the scents of grasses and trees. It was calming - which was probably why the Guvnuragnaguvendrugun did it, she thought cynically.

The three sapients who had been waiting advanced as they climbed out of the shuttle. The huge shaggy creature who could only be Furfeg and the Rrrrtktktkp'ch beside him halted a polite distance away, while the lone Gaoian continued forward.

“Officer Regaari?” Xiù asked, uncertain but hopeful. Her Gaori had lost all accent.

The male ducked his head. “Sister Xiù, thank you for remembering me.” He repeated the gesture again towards Ayma. “Mother Ayma. Welcome aboard.”

Xiù blinked. “Oh, a translator! I’d forgotten about that. Oh, it’s so nice to hear my name properly!”

“The entire ship is equipped with translators, since it serves as a mobile embassy,” Furfeg commented. Once the Gaoian male had made greetings the other two had moved closer. “It nearly tripled the cost of the ship, or so I’m told. Miss Chang, Mother Ayma,” he greeted, nodding his immense head toward each of the females.

He gestured to the Rrrrtktktkp'ch beside him. “This is Captain Yhjjrrtknk A’tkrnnmtktk’ki, the master of the ship.” Xiù’s eyes went wide. Ayma didn’t blame her… even with the help of translators Rrrrtktktkp'ch names were a mouthful. The tall, slender alien bent its long neck toward them. Ayma ducked her head, and Xiù bent her upper body in her peoples’ gesture of respect.

Furfeg looked to the lone human. “The journey will take roughly a ten-day, and we’ll be setting off soon. Is there anything you needed?”

Xiù shrugged. “No… I don’t think so, anyway. All I have is my clothing, and I brought that with me.”

“Well, if you think of anything, let one of the stewards know. I’ve asked them to make the onboard fabricators available for your use, just tell them what you need. For now, Officer Regaari, would you show our guests to their quarters?” At his assent, the captain and diplomat turned to leave the bay.

“I thought you were assigned to the Mother-Supreme?” Ayma asked Regaari.

“I am. But the Mother-Supreme has considerable investment in this, and so she asked me to accompany you, both to represent her and to insure your safety.” Ayma nodded… apparently she wasn’t the only one to worry about the Dominion taking less care than they should of their human guest.

“Xiù?” She knew she wasn’t pronouncing her friend’s name properly, and it was strange to have the translation devices all but pluck the word from her muzzle and correct it. But she liked it… she always felt as though she was slighting the human by calling her “Shoo”, even though it was a limitation of her muzzle and Xiù never complained. Names were important.

The human was looking at the cavernous landing bay, and the unflickering expanse of stars beyond the kinetic field. A few of the stars moved… starships taking off from Gao or coming in to land. Ayma let her have the moment, and Regaari did the same (Handsome, restrained, and sensitive, too? The stars were taunting her…) After a moment Xiù’s long head-fur, held back in its usual braid, rocked back and forth as she shook her head and sighed.

“Your quarters will have windows,” Regaari commented. “You can make them as transparent or as opaque as you prefer. Shall I bring you there?”

The females agreed, reaching into the shuttle for their baggage. Ayma only had one bag, but Xiù had three… Regaari discovered the reason moments later. “Here, Sister Xiù, I can carry one of-oof!” The Gaoian male blinked at the bag which had stubbornly resisted his attempt to lift it.

It would be impolite to chitter, but some of the humour had to show in her voice. “Xiù’s clothes are weighted to compensate for the lighter gravity,” she pointed out.

“One set is fine, but three is heavy even for me,” the human said sheepishly.

Regaari stared at them for a moment. “I’ll… get a hovercart. Just a moment.”

Soon the three were walking through the huge corridors of the ship, sized as they were for Guvnuragnaguvendrugun. There were actually only about a dozen of the creatures onboard, Regaari explained… the majority of the two-hundred crew were Rrrrtktktkp'ch like the captain, or their bluer, dimmer cousins the Vzk'tk. There were a smattering of other species as well, including nearly two dozen Gaoians, operating in security.

Soon the two females were left in their respective neighbouring quarters. Ayma waited for Regaari to leave before looking around in disapproval… like everything else on the ship, it was simply too big. The tables and bed had lowered themselves to a comfortable height for a Gaoian, but the bed was so large it could have held the entire Sisters dorm back at the commune and left room for the Mothers. Gaoian females didn’t like to sleep alone, hadn’t Regaari told them that?

Unless the gesture was meant for Xiù, she supposed - a bit of privacy after so long immersed in an alien culture, an object of curiosity and concern. Ayma wouldn’t complain if Xiù was happy with the arrangement.

She unpacked her lone bag, pulling out her data tablet and recording some holo-messages to send back to the commune, letting them know they’d arrived onboard safely and warning some of the cubs - and Sisters - not to put whipped cream on everything edible. Not long after she sent the messages off the shipboard audio system announced their departure. Through the large crystal window she saw the stars tilt and begin to move, and before too long they stretched as the huge vessel entered warp.

Ayma wondered what Xiù thought of the display… she should ask. In fact, it was nearing the time for the end-of-day meal. Would she be interested in eating together? Standing up, she left her tablet on the table and walked down the corridor to the guest quarters next to hers. She didn’t think twice about simply entering… they were fellow females after all.

“Xiù, would you like to ea-whoa!” Ayma squawked as she stepped into Xiù’s cabin. The gravity was set much higher than Gao standard, and the step through the door was like falling down a stair. She flopped to the ground and wheezed as the breath was driven from her lungs.

Xiù spun from where she sat watching the stars through her window. Her eyes went wide and she jumped to her feet. “Oh! Ayma! Computer, set gravity to Gao normal! I’m so sor-whoop!”

The situation played out in reverse as Xiù tried to dash over to help her friend. Unfortunately she was in mid-step when the gravity field changed, so the perfectly-reasonable strength she used to move forward suddenly became nearly twice what was needed; the human was launched into the air, arms wheeling, and landed with a heavy thud just in front of Ayma.

“Um… ow.” Xiù blinked. “Sorry. The steward said the gravity in here could be set to something more like Earth, so I was trying it out.”

Ayma waved a paw. “I’m unhurt. I should have expected this. I was just coming over to ask if you wanted to share the end-of-day meal together.”

“Um… I’d like that.” The two stared at each other from their respective positions on the floor. “We don’t have to tell Myun about this, do we?” Xiù finally asked.

“I won’t mention it if you don’t.”

“Deal!”

They decided to eat in Ayma’s quarters, settling in around the vast table next to each other after placing their orders with the ship’s galley. They’d briefly pondered eating with the other Gaoians on board, but Ayma didn’t feel like putting up with a bunch of males who would likely trip over themselves trying to impress her, and Xiù simply didn’t want to be stared at.

Xiù left choosing their food to Ayma, who was pleased to see a number of Gaoian dishes available, and some alien meals she was familiar with and liked. Still feeling a bit spiteful, she made a point of ordering the most expensive and elaborate meals, since Furfeg and the Dominion were footing the bill. It didn’t take long at all for a Vzk'tk steward to appear at the door, pushing a small hovercart with a pair of trays and a pair of containers holding water and talamay (which Ayma kept carefully away from the human…). The galley had also been warned of their human guest, judging from the small plate of nutrition spheres that were included.

Soon both females had their trays and drinks, and Ayma sniffed appreciatively at the fried jalmin fish, a delicacy on Gao she’d only ever experienced once. Steamed vegetables occupied the side, and the flatbread was still warm. Her mouth watered in anticipation.

Xiù squinted at Ayma’s platter. “Why does yours look different?”

The Gaoian Mother looked at her friend’s meal - which should have been identical - her ears flicking back with surprise. Then she scowled. “Steward, what in the stars is this?”

He’d been tapping on his portable data tablet, likely marking off their food as delivered. His long, blue-tinted neck turned his head to Ayma at her tone. “Pardon? Is something wrong?”

“This fish is raw! Did the cook forget something? Or do you have a malfunctioning auto-chef?”

“I…” The Vzk'tk fidgeted with the data tablet in his hands. “W-we heard that the human ate her meat raw…”

Ayma’s ears pressed backward. “Where in the galaxy did you hear that?” she asked in an appalled voice.

Xiù rubbed her temples. “Not even on my own planet, and people are still mistaking me for Japanese.”

Ayma didn’t know what Japanese was, but she’d ask later. She glared at the steward… as far as she was concerned, this was merely the latest in a number of slights the humans had to deal with from a galactic society that seemed to want to believe them to be savages. She put the cover back on Xiù’s meal and pushed it back across the table. “Obviously your information is incorrect. Take this back and have the cook prepare it properly.”

The steward bobbed his head, stammering apologies and all but fleeing the guest quarters, pushing the hovercart ahead of him. Ayma growled quietly.

Xiù was looking at her, wide-eyed. “Wow. I don’t even have the nerve to ask for extra sauce at Swiss Chalet.”

“I’ll ask you what that is later. For now, here… we’ll split this plate, and when that dimwit comes back we’ll split that one, too.”

“Okay. Mind if I dip my nutrition spheres in that sauce?”

One day done, one battle fought. To Ayma’s quiet relief Xiù asked to sleep in the room with her… she’d “gotten used” to the dorm at the commune, and the strange quiet of her quarters was jarring. The next morning she raved about the shower, though she was somewhat disgruntled to learn that it had been included for the sake of the Corti.

They settled in for the journey, trying to avoid boredom. Xiù practiced and revised her speech to the Council… Ayma reviewed her lesson plans for the cubs. Regaari would sometimes drop by to check up on them, and afterwards Xiù would always give her a smug, knowing look if Ayma’s eyes lingered a bit too long when the guard left. Oddly, Furfeg made no visits, though perhaps he was busy arranging things in his shipboard office.

It was late in the evening on the third day of their journey. Xiù had taken advantage of Furfeg’s offer and asked the fabricators to make her some more clothing, at Ayma’s encouragement (again, to soak Furfeg and the Dominion as much as possible). A nervous Rauwryhr had taken her specifications and returned with several variations of long, loose clothing of strong and smooth fabric. The cloth shimmered a rich red in the light and had been trimmed with gold threading, and when Ayma asked her about the design she simply explained that it derived from her native culture on her homeworld, a more elaborate version of the clothing associated with gung-fu.

The Rauwryhr seemed surprised by the praise Xiù heaped upon her, as if she’d expected the human to ignore or dismiss her efforts. It was not a reaction that went unnoticed by the Gaoian Mother.

Ayma watched Xiù admire herself in the mirror. The new clothing did look quite fetching, she thought… although a furred species would likely find the weight of cloth on their shoulders maddening. She was happy with her overalls, although she was pondering asking for some more made from the same fabric.

Suddenly, the deck became the ceiling, and both females were launched into the air. Xiù cried out, and Ayma screeched. She could hear the metal bones of the Rich Plains groaning, and through the window the stars spun. She was suddenly very appreciative of the huge bed when it caught her as the gravity fields reversed again. Xiù wasn’t so lucky, crashing against the table which buckled under the human’s weight, sending her sliding off to roll onto the floor.

A low, pulsing tone rang through the ship… the audible alert. The communication panel next to the door had turned mauve, the galactic standard colour of distress.

“Ow… what… what was that?” Xiù asked nervously as she climbed to her feet. “Ayma, are you okay?”

“I’m fine,” she replied. “You?”

“I’m okay. What happened?”

“Possibly just an engine failure,” Ayma replied, “it happens rarely. We’re tumbling… give it a moment, the helm officer will correct-” She lost the ability to speak. She hadn’t wanted to think about it, hadn’t wanted to compare the sudden stop of the Rich Plains to the only other time she’d felt a starship get torn out of warp - when Trig’s mercenaries had hijacked the ill-fated colonial ship Winter Coat. But as the stars slowed in their nausea-inducing spinning out the window and a wide, predatory-looking ship came into view, she found her experience terrifyingly accurate. “Oh no-”

“What? What is it? Who are they?” Xiù asked, and Ayma could hear the fear in her voice.

She looked over at her Sister, her ears folded against her skull. “Hunters.”

+<Pleasure; accomplishment> Alpha, the prey vessel has been caught by the grav-spike! The projection of its trajectory between the fur-face world and the prey-meeting station was accurate!+

The Alpha looked over at the beta as it stood to give its report. In theory it didn’t need to stand; in fact, it could have spoken to the Alpha from anywhere on the ship with but a thought. Still, it was good for its subordinates to clamour for its favour. +<Acknowledgement; approval> Very well. The trap was well-laid. You may have second taste of the hunt.+ The beta broadcast its pleasure wordlessly over the cybernetic network that connected all the hunters on the vessel.

Theirs was a large pack, thirty strong, and the appetite of so many hunters was great… as was their ambition. A large pack meant large prey, and the herbivore vessel they’d caught was large indeed. The Alpha had a particular fondness for the meat of the large, shaggy herbivore prey… there was so much of it, and the creatures were terrified when isolated, which sweetened their meat exquisitely. The Alpha ground its multiple rows of teeth in anticipation, eager for that first bite.

But first… the harvest. +<Excitement; command> Take us in! Prepare to breach! Meat to the maw!+

Regaari was reaching for his pulse rifle almost before the Rich Plains had finished tumbling.

It was possible it was a simple engine failure - one that would be embarrassing for the captain, requiring a day or two of repair before the ship could be underway again. But Regaari was not assigned to the ship to deal with incidents which were merely embarrassing.

He’d been sitting at his desk in his quarters, filling out reports on his tablet, when the gravity went wild. He was lifted out of his seat, his legs bumping against the table and giving him just enough time to grab hold of it, his claws automatically unsheathing to grant him more purchase. Then the ship had leveled out, hurling him down to the deck. He scrambled to his feet, pulling breath in through bruised ribs.

His quarters had no windows, so he grabbed his rifle from the storage rack and stormed out into the corridor. The crew of the ship scrambled around him, roused from what they’d thought would be easy third and fourth shifts. Regaari didn’t know the expressions of aliens well, but he was certain there was more than alarm in the faces of the Vzk'tk and Rrrrtktktkp'ch who dashed past him… there was fear.

Fortunately there was a Gaoian among them… a young One-Fang, possibly the shuttle pilot who had delivered the females. “Brother!” Regaari grabbed hold of the boy before he could dash by. “Brother, what happened?”

The young male ducked his head. “W-we’ve been torn out of warp, Brother!”

He resisted the urge to snap that that was plainly obvious… the youngster looked on the edge as it was. “Torn? Not an engine malfunction? Who attacks us?”

The One-Fang’s ears were flat against his skull. “H-hunters, Brother!”

Regaari felt his heart go cold, then clenched his teeth, discarding the reaction as useless. “Go to the Armory. Fetch yourself a weapon and as many of the portable kinetic barriers as you can carry. Bring as many of the Brothers as you come across, and meet me at the landing bay.”

“The bay?” The young male blinked. “Are we evacuating?”

The set of Regaari’s muzzle was grim. “No. That’s the most likely place the Hunters will breach the hull. Bring our Brothers, and be ready to fight.”

“Hunters? That’s a Hunter ship?” Xiù asked, her voice timid. They’d watched as the big Hunter vessel - not a swarm ship, but larger than a standard pack-ship - thrusted toward the disabled diplomatic ship. The Hunter ship was wide and flat, with thrusters on the back and a breaching tube mounted on the front like a grotesque proboscis. When the big Guvnuragnaguvendrugun ship had shaken, Ayma had known that that tube was now piercing the hull, and Hunters were invading.

“Ayma? What do we do?” Xiù demanded.

The Gaoian Mother looked at her friend, more frightened than when the Winter Coat had been hijacked and the mercenaries had begun murdering the crew. “T-there’s nothing we can do… the security forces will fight them. We just need to wait-” She didn’t want to think about how even a normal pack-ship was more than a match for the Rich Plains’ sparse crew.

Her doubts must have shown, because Xiù looked down at her hands, which had clenched into fists. She glanced back up at the other female. “I have to help.”

Ayma’s muzzle dropped open. “Xiù, no… you did well against Locayl and Mjrnhrm, but these are Hunters… every race is terrified of them, for good reason!”

“Then that means they’ll need my help even more! Ayma, I-” She blinked, struggling for words. “I’ll be back. Okay? Stay safe.”

“Xiù!” Ayma grabbed at her arm, but she might as well have been trying to hold back a starship. Xiù dashed out into the corridor; her braid snapped back and forth as her head turned to note which direction almost all the crew were running… and then she ran in the opposite.

Regaari had called the Hunter breach location perfectly… the Hunter ship had pierced the Rich Plains in the landing bay. The large armoured proboscis on the front of the ship had stabbed through the ship’s hull, rocking the entire vessel and knocking the defenders from their feet. Then the front of the tube had opened, and Hunters had confidently strode out, the pulse guns bonded to their arms already spitting death across the landing bay.

As soon as the hull had been breached the defenders had thrown down their portable kinetic barriers. Essentially a baton half a Gaoian’s height, the device would hover at chest level and project a barrier down to the floor. They were a Gaoian innovation, he was proud to say… far stronger than a harness, the barrier could take numerous hits from anti-personnel weapons, and even stand up to anti-vehicle weapons for several shots. The barriers formed a bulwark around the Hunter entry point, and the Rich Plains’ security forces huddled behind them, shooting when and what they could.

Unfortunately the Hunters were savage but not stupid, and they would cover each other whenever one lost its shield. Combined with the Dominion tendency to scatter their shots, the defending forces had only managed to kill a single Hunter. Meanwhile Regaari had already seen five of the security forces die, including two Brothers. More Hunters were advancing from the breach, and while the barriers were strong, they would eventually deplete.

It was not the Gaoian way to lie down in defeat… and this was particularly true when fighting Hunters. But it was looking like going down fighting was the best option available to all of them.

“Regaari!” a voice called across the landing bay.

He looked up, shocked, as Sister Xiù dashed across the landing bay. She moved at an incredible pace, and she had enough sense to keep to cover behind the parked shuttles where she could, but the landing bay was vast, and there were huge swaths of open space. Her shout had drawn the Hunters’ attention, and kinetic blasts rained around her. Most had no hope of hitting her… but luck always played a factor, and a single shot struck her in her upper torso. The human was knocked sideways, but didn’t slow; she barreled toward Regaari, diving into a roll as she neared.

She barely avoided him as she slid out, and he heard the barrier strain as she bumped against it. She blinked at him. “Are you okay?”

“What in the stars are you doing here?” he demanded.

“I’m here to help!”

“Help? Help? This is a firefight! How can you help? You don’t even have a weapon!”

“I am a weapon, if the Dominion is right! Let me help!”

She poked her head over the barrier to look. He spit and seized her arm. “Stay down! They’ll take your head off!”

“I can take a hit, you just saw that!”

“Oh, really? How many hits can you take? How many to your head, or your eyes?” Her skin turned pink, which was odd, but he assumed that was how humans showed embarrassment.

“How many are there?” she asked nervously.

“On a Hunter ship that size? Twenty… maybe thirty.”

“Can you fight that many?”

Regaari turned to her, and his jaw was clenched. “Sister Xiù, we could not fight even ten.” He glanced down, ashamed. “I’m sorry. We will make them work, but the outcome is certain.”

The two hunched as kinetic pulses hammered their weakening shield. Regaari pulled out a nervejam grenade, thumbing the activation stud. Two countdown lights turned green, then he hurled the device up and over the shield. He didn’t see the final light turn red to indicate activation, but he heard the shriek of the Hunters as it fired its neural-disruptive pulse among them. He voiced a soft chitter of satisfaction as he heard at least one of them slump over. The sound encouraged the other defenders, who popped up over their own respective shields and laid down a sheet of kinetic pulses. He nodded in approval: Make them work indeed!

He turned to Xiù, who was clutching her head. “Sister Xiù?”

“That hurt, whatever it was.” She rubbed at her head.

“Nervejam grenade. Basically a neural disruptor.” He winced. “We were told that humans were highly susceptible to such attacks. It appears to be true.”

She stared at him despite the noise of battle around them. “Why would you be told that?” She shook her head. “Nevermind, I don’t want to know.”

Regaari stood to lay down some fire. He was a reasonably good shot, but the Hunters weren’t stupid - he’d hit one and knock down its shields, but another would step in and shield its broodmate, returning fire and forcing him to duck. Xiù stared at nothing as he did - her skin was pale, but he didn’t know what that meant with her species. His military instructors often cautioned against assuming you knew what an alien was thinking - they were, by definition, alien - so he didn’t bother to guess what was going through her mind.

The worth of that advice was proven a moment later, as he couldn’t believe the words that came out of her mouth: “I’ll distract them.”

“What?”

“I’ll distract them! Get ready!”

“Sister, wait!” He grabbed her arm as she stood, and got his first taste of just how strong she was as he was nearly lifted from the ground. “Xiù, wait!”

Thankfully she hesitated from where she was about to leap the shield barrier. “I can do this! I can make some ruckus, make them turn their backs to you!”

“Are you mad? Are you suggesting I sit here and let a female dash into harm’s way? It isn’t done!”

Her face flushed pink. “Since when are you chauvinist? I’m not even Gaoian!”

He tightened his grip, but he doubted she even felt it. “You are a Sister of the Clan of Females, and it is my duty as both a Brother and as your guardian assigned by the Mother-Supreme to shield you!”

“Your life is not worth less than mine! If you die, they’ll get me anyway!” She paused, and her voice shook as the continued. “I don’t want to do this, but you need me to do this. Just… y’know, make the best of it.”

He tried to come up with a coherent argument, but his paws were empty. She was right… anything she could offer could save all their lives, and if even half the rumours of her abilities were true- “Fine. You have every right to fight for yourself. But take these.” He pulled the bandolier of grenades off and handed them to her. “Just press this button here to activate them. You’ll have about four breaths before it activates, so make sure it’s far from you when it does.” She timidly took hold of the bandolier. He held on to them until she met his gaze. “Remember: they’ll hurt you from further away than they will the Hunters. Get away when you use them. Mother Ayma wouldn’t forgive me if you were hurt.”

She barked her little human laugh, though it was weak. “Funny, I was thinking the same thing about you.” He gave her a puzzled gaze as she slung the bandolier over her shoulder. “Give me some covering fire?”

He nodded, standing, his pulse rifle at the ready, flinging white bolts across the bay. Two more Hunters had emerged to replace the one he’d managed to kill, and almost before his third shot they were turning their cybernetic pulse rifles at him. He was saved by Xiù flinging herself over the barrier, jumping so far and high she seemed to fly. When she landed she rolled, coming up into a run, straight at the Hunters.

The fearsome aliens paused, as astonished as everyone else in the bay… nobody charged a Hunter pack! Their weapons were soon turning toward her until Regaari forced them to split their attention, opening fire with his own weapon. He managed to land a pair of pulses on one Hunter, knocking down its shield and crushing its shoulder. It hissed and returned fire with its remaining arm, and as he ducked he felt the kinetic pulse pass close enough to pull at his fur.

The other defenders had stopped firing - which was probably for the best, Regaari thought, because Xiù was already in among the Hunters. A pulse blast narrowly missed her, and she jumped at the one who’d fired the shot. Both her feet crashed against its torso, and even a Hunter shield couldn’t take such an impact. It shattered with the sound of snapping electricity and the big alien, half-again as tall as she was, was sent flying into its partner behind it. Judging from the distorted shape of its torso, it wouldn’t be getting back up.

Xiù fell straight down onto her back, then flipped back up onto her feet in a single move no other species could emulate. A Hunter aimed at her and she dodged aside, not leaping but surging along the ground as if sliding along a rail; her arm hooked the dreaded alien’s own and pulled it aside, and the Hunter found itself firing several pulses into a broodmate trying to attack from the human’s other side. Even the six-legged creature couldn’t resist stumbling as the human tugged on the captured arm, her other hand sweeping upward to chop the Hunter’s throat. The terror of sentient beings across the galaxy everywhere collapsed, gurgling for breath that wouldn’t come.

Ten seconds, three Hunters dead. But more were emerging from the boarding tube, and whatever communications method the seven-eyed monsters used, they were aware of her presence. They exited firing, their heavy pulse rifles pounding and crushing the bodies of their dead broodmates as Xiù ducked behind the bodies, the pulse fire passing over her head or splashing against her fleshy shelter.

Regaari realized he’d been standing dumbfounded, and he was damned lucky the Hunters were more interested in the human… he’d offered them plenty of opportunity to take his head off!

At least he wasn’t the only one, and he covered his embarrassment by snarling at the others, “Don’t just stand there, shoot at them!” He lifted his rifle and peppered the Hunters with fire. The other defenders did the same, raining pulse blasts down on the Hunters from all directions. The attacking aliens collapsed their formation, drawing together to to overlap their kinetic shields.

Xiù dashed out of her cover, heedless of the shooting from in front and behind her. One of the Hunters aimed its arms at her, but she didn’t slow as she ran right at it. When the Hunter fired she fell to her knees, sliding easily on the smooth fabric of her Gaoian-made overalls, letting the twin bolts of energy pass a bare armlength over her head. She bent backwards far enough that her long head-fur trailed on the floor behind her, sliding completely underneath and between the legs of the Hunter. When she emerged from the other side she sprung immediately to her feet, dashing between two more Hunters. Then she disappeared into the depths of the place no rational sapient being wanted to go: a Hunter assault ship.

The three Hunters and the two just emerging turned to follow her, dismissing the other defenders as insignificant. It was then that the nervejam grenade Xiù had left behind in the middle of the group went off. Only one Hunter was killed outright, but the others lost control of their bodies long enough for the bolstered defenders to bring them down, one by one.

For a brief moment the bay was quiet. The Vzk'tk slumped with relief, and even a few of his Gaoian brothers lowered their weapons. “Keep your weapons up!” he snapped, and was pleased to see them jump. He pointed at two of the Vzk’tk - the most useless members of the group as far as he was concerned, but he’d be accused of speciesism if he asked to trade them for more Gaoians. “You and you, get the wounded to the medical bay. Do it now, we don’t know how much time she’ll have bought us.”

Xiù ran through the tall, wide corridors of the Hunter ship, trying not to think about how utterly terrified she was, or how she really didn’t have a plan beyond “get inside, make a mess”.

The ship wasn’t as big as Furfeg’s, but every ship was huge from her perspective, and the corridors seemed to stretch on forever. Unlike the diplomatic ship, which was well-lit and coloured with pleasant whites and blues and polished metal, the Hunter ship was utterly alien, with softer light, darker colours, and the air was humid like a jungle.

She’d met two pairs of Hunters once she’d gotten inside and managed to kill them. She didn’t have to think about using lethal force this time… these aliens ate people. They grabbed ships out of space, murdered the people inside, and ate them. Every human notion of good and bad she’d had, all the silly, shallow ideas of what was important… thrown away. She knew what evil was now, and everything else was just trite.

She rounded a corner and nearly collided face-to-chest with a Hunter. There were three this time, and they reacted swiftly to her appearance. The one in front of her was too close to shoot at her, so it swung its arm, trying to hit her with the gun that seemed to grow out of its flesh. She blocked the blow, guiding it up and over her head, her other hand slamming into the creature’s torso. The shield collapsed under the first blow, and she hit it again with the back of her forearm, crushing the flesh underneath. The aliens had thick skin, like moist, white leather, and it was as disgusting to touch as it was to look at, but whatever was inside would crack and crumble.

The Hunters made no sound as they broke and died… and somehow that was almost worse than cries of pain.

They were communicating somehow, though… and learning. She spun, her foot lashing out to crush the foreleg joint of the Hunter nearest to her - but even as she did the third shot her, hitting her in the thigh and lower back. If ordinary pulse guns felt like a hard punch, then the ones the Hunters carried felt like being kicked; she cried out and fell along with the alien she’d hit, more pulses passing over her head. She rolled behind the fallen Hunter, using it as a shield. It wasn’t dead, and thrust an arm at her, but she smacked it aside with her foot, scooting toward it even as she coiled her legs. She thrust out like a piledriver into the Hunter’s chest, the alien lifted clear from the ground and thrown into its remaining partner.

She scrambled to her feet before the remaining alien could dig out from under the body of its broodmate, slamming a straight beng quan punch in the center of its seven eyes. The alien collapsed, a noticeable dent in the center of its face.

Xiù panted, wincing as her hand braced against the sore spot on her back; her thigh felt like it was cramping. She wasn’t given any time to rest, however - she could hear the heavy footsteps of yet more Hunters approaching. She turned and ducked through a nearby door that slid open at her approach, dashing inside the room in the hopes they’d pass her by.

It was a cold room, and she swallowed a shriek as she saw the contents: pieces of meat. She was in the Hunter pantry, she realized, and quietly sobbed as she recognized what was left of a Gaoian hanging from hooks on the wall. And that wasn’t the only horror: she saw blue-giraffe aliens, and a huge piece of an alien that looked like Furfeg, and yet more of no species she could identify. She smelled frost and other, worse things, and she covered her mouth because she didn’t trust herself not to cry out or vomit. Tears ran down her cheeks and across her fingers.

Evil. The Hunters were evil, and every one she killed made the universe a bit better. She closed her eyes and swallowed against the lump in her throat.

On the other side of the door the footsteps came to a stop… obviously the Hunters were examining their own dead. Her heart raced, and she almost expected the aliens to find her from the sound of it! Thankfully the door remained closed, the Hunters either not thinking she’d hide, or thinking she wouldn’t hide amongst the dead of species she called friend. They did not speak, making no sounds that could have been language or otherwise, and she wondered if they were telepathic or something.

After a few moments the footsteps faded away, following her path backwards, and Xiù mentally apologized to Regaari and the others. The pain in her leg was only just fading, and she was sure she would have a massive bruise on her back for the next few days… assuming she survived.

When she was sure she could walk without limping she poked her head timidly out the door. No living Hunters waited… only the three dead ones. The aliens hadn’t posted a guard or even moved the dead ones. Did they care so little about their own? Or maybe the Hunters were just busy… busy hunting.

Hunting her. What was she going to do? Think, Xiù!

How did she get into this situation? She was an actress… a student actress! Her dreams of being a action-girl film star seemed so far away and utterly stupid… she was being forced to live the reality, and suddenly Wei’s video games seemed so much more practical than being able to quote Shakespeare. She might be stronger and faster, but there was only one of her, and they had the guns.

For a panicked, giddy moment she wondered if she should go with her strengths… maybe she could put on a play for the Hunters! Romeo and Juliet, maybe, and get Regaari and Ayma to help. The Hunters probably preferred Hannibal, though-

Xiù stopped the silly thoughts in their tracks, although it did help her calm down. She shifted… the air was so humid her shirt and overalls were sticking to her. The Hunters seemed to like so much moisture in their air that it fell from the vents in wispy clouds-

Xiù blinked. Then she looked up at the vent near the ceiling. The grate covering it nearly was twice the width of her own (admittedly slender) body, with metal holes she could stick her fingers through. It was secured with a dozen small bolts, and she wondered how well they’d hold on if she pulled.

Maybe the movies weren’t useless to her. She was the alien here. The “xenomorph”. No guns but plenty of physical advantages. “They're coming outta the walls. They're coming outta the goddamn walls. Let's book!” ...Everybody liked Hudson, and Xiù found herself liking him a little bit more. She wondered if the Hunters had a loudmouthed clown in their group; if she found him, she’d let him live.

Until then… In the lighter gravity, she sprang up to the vent, her fingers grasping the grate and pulling. The metal pressed against her fingers but didn’t cut her as she pulled, and with a shriek of tortured metal the cover pulled loose, dropping her back down into a soft landing. She jumped back up and pulled herself in, carrying the grated cover inside and hiding it.

It was time to do things the Alien way.